Da da da da dum dum da dum dum
Da da da da dum dum
Baby, you the best 'cause you worked me out
I keep building walls up but you tear 'em down
I'm fighting, I don't wanna like it but you know I like it
But you know I like it, like it, like it, like it
Used to always think I was bullet proof
But you got an AK and you're blowing through
Explosive, you don't even know it, I want you to know it
I want you to know it, know it, know it, know it
All of them other boys can walk away
They ain't even in the game
'Cause they know that you own it
You got this swag, you got this attitude
Wanna hear you say my name
'Cause you got me...
Flying with your love
Shining with your love
Riding with your love
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
One hit with your love
Can't quit with your love
So sick but so what?
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
Everybody wants what I got with you
'Cause I'm standing on top with a killer view
Inspired feeling like a million, I'm one in a million
I'm one in a million, million, million
I ain't even here, I'm in outer space
Like I'm Venus, you're Mars in the Milky Way
It's crazy what you're doing to me, how you do it to me
How you do it to me, to me, to me
All of them other boys can walk away
They ain't even in the game
'Cause they know that you own it
You got this swag, you got this attitude (la la la la)
Wanna hear you say my name
'Cause you got me...
Flying with your love
Shining with your love
Riding with your love
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
One hit with your love
Can't quit with your love
So sick but so what?
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
You got it yeah yeah you got it
I could slow it down speed it up how you want it girl
all night long and I don't even care if you sing my songs wrong
First date, first base; second date, second base;
Third date, you're looking at me funny
You got a hard shell but the middle's so yummy
Flying baby I'm shining baby I'm riding with your love
One hit, baby. I can't quit, baby. I'm so sick but so what?
Flying, baby. I'm shining, baby. I'm riding with your love
(I'm on top of the world)
Flying with your love
Shining with your love
Riding with your love
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
One hit with your love
Can't quit with your love
So sick but so what?
I feel like I'm on top of the world with your love
Da da da da dum dum da dum dum
**Subtitled by Kashyap**