Subbed by Makoto77
I told you not to look for me.
Please, Father.
That's all I have.
The only proof of what they've done.
But she looks so...
Human.
But don't let yourself be fooled.
She wasn't conceived naturally.
They found a
But how did they...
No, please.
I can't...
I can't talk about that.
What I can tell you...
is that the pregnancy happened quickly.
She'll be in her teens now.
They're just waiting until she's old enough.
Old enough for what?
Now, please.
I can't do this anymore.
I can't.
But please don't let it touch me again.
Father?
Father Harris?
Hiding won't absolve your sins.
You think I want to be forgiven?
I don't want to be forgiven, Father Brennan.
I just want it all to be over.
You'll understand...
soon enough.
Father, are you all right?
I'm fine.
-I'm Father Gabriel.
-Hello.
Cardinal Lawrence sent me to fetch you.
-Oh, sure. Thank you.
-Let me help you with that.
He's in the car outside.
I have heard so much about you.
feel like I already know you.
Maggie!
I'm so happy to see you.
Me too.
It's so beautiful here. It's like a
Well, wait till you see the actual city.
Look at you. It hasn't been a year...
and somehow, you've found a way to grow up
even more.
I'll show you to your
So, what do you think?
It's wild.
Everything's so different.
Every street that we pass
there's something to look at
I just wanna explore.
Isn't it beautiful?
What better place
for you to be taking the veil?
It's wonderful to see you, Maggie.
Even when you were little,
I knew you were destined for great things.
See if you can get around them, Damiano.
These protests have picked up recently
I'm afraid.
What are they protesting?
For the workers,
it's about conditions and wages.
But for the students, well...
it's a rejection of authority...
even the church.
The world is changing, Maggie, very fast.
The younger generation no longer turn to us
for guidance, I'm afraid.
But it's a challenge we've embraced.
Perhaps you'll play your part
and help earn back their trust.
I'll try.
This is Sister Silva, the Abbess.
And she'll take good care of you.
Hello.
Welcome to our family.
Thank you.
eCome with me.
Come. Come with me.
Let me give you a tour.
We're so happy to have you here.
This way.
We take care of girls.
Babies to 18 years of age.
The state has contracted with us
to take in many unmarried women...
Our doctor will likely deliver this baby
within the week.
This is Margaret Daino from America.
and she keeps all the children smiling.
And they all seem very happy.
I should see what the trouble is.
Of course
Amen.
Ave Maria is my favorite, too.
I'm Margaret.
Hi.
What are you doing?
Get off of me!
There you are.
Have you been behaving yourself, Carlita?
Carlita.
Did you do that drawing outside, Carlita?
The one where the girl's floating
above the other girls?
I thought it was very nice.
Thank you.
Come.
It's safer
hurt another child
hurt another child just yesterday.
Rome has become a bit dangerous
with the protests.
who demonstrates in both deed and word...
the truth that every life, no matter
its conditions, is precious and unrepeatable.
Lord, speak to every human heart
and fill it with the conviction...
Margaret's one of our
worst-behaved children...
Then you must tie her to the bed.
Here. Let me show you.
Hi.
You must be Margaretta.
Yes.
I'm Luz.
Did I wake you?
No, no.
I was having a nightmare.
First night nerves?
If we can't admit how we are feeling...
our dreams do it for us, right?
I just figured a little exploration
is healthy before the big day.
So how does a girl from...
So how does a girl from Pissfield
end up in Italy about to take the veil?
And we got pretty clos
well, I was somewhat of a
I don't know. I guess...
I mean, I used to get punished a lot.
I'd get so convinced sometimes
that what I was seeing was real...
But then Cardinal Lawrence
came to the orphanage...
He really helped me to see
that all that stuff was just in my head.
this warm wind came...
out of nowhere.
And suddenly it was
as if His voice was all around me.
Inside me even.
And He told me it didn't matter
if I had no earthly home...
Yes, but even with the most handsome milkman
in town
we still had a whole group of us
who took the veil together.
Yes. Now, instead, girls go off to college
And Margaret...
Margaret will be alone in the chapel, too.
Don't wony. I'll warmt
Warm up? What is this "warm it up"?
No, no, no. Shy American.
Say it with passione.
Okay. All right.
What does it mean?
"I am a teacher and I love to teach."
Margaret. There you are.
I'm sorry I scared you.
Come on.
I have something to show you for tonight.
You're gonna love it.
Oh, my God, you look hot
What do you mean, naked? You look gorgeous.
Up with your foot.
The other one.
Don't be nervous. Can you stand?
Because your whole life you've wanted
to give yourself only to Him, right?
You're a very beautiful girl, Margaretta.
And you have to understand that
about yourself.
To the bravest girl I know.
Go.
Do you still feel your feet?
No. Not when I'm drinking.
Too hard.
Inglese, per favore, no?
If you can.
I'm Alfonzo, and this is Paolo.
Hi.
We can buy you a drink if you want.
Excuse me.
Can I have a sip of that?
-Eat it?
-Yes. Eat it.
I was watching this movie
with my mother yesterday.
-Yeah?
-And...
and was with Barbara Streisand, and I just...
I don't know. I love her and...
-Barbra?
-I love Barbara. Yes...
I mean, it was the part
with the "Hello, gorgeous."
Hello, gorgeous.
Gorgeous.
with clashes between the far left
and far right groups escalating rapidly.
The unrest has caused widespread damage
to property...
and has left several people injured.
Italian authorities are struggling
to contain the violence and restore order.
Public transportation, factories,
and schools are heavily affected...
I'm guessing
you've never drunk like that before.
I didn't, like, embarrass myself
or anything last night, did I?
No. No.
You were well-behaved.
Mostly.
Okay. I found you
before anything got out of control.
And for the record, I was a very nice friend.
You came home with me.
Thanks.
But it wasn't easy pulling you away from him.
What do you mean? I didn't...
Let's just say you took my advice to heart.
You were a very brave girl, Margaretta.
It's our little secret. Okay?
I'm sorry. Do I know you?
My name is Father Brennan.
I apologize for startling you.
Please sit with me.
This will only take a few minutes.
Your name is Margaret Daino.
You work at the orphanage.
I don't understand. How do you know that?
It's about the girl. Scianna.
-Carlita?
-You must be very careful, Margaret.
Bad things will start to happen around her.
Evil things.
No, I have to go now.
No, no. Please, please! Come see me tonight.
Saint Rita cloister, room 42.
Good morning, farfalla.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Just a little tired, that's all
Where's Carlita?
She's in the bad room.
Dirty.
Carlita, she's locked in a room.
That's right.
She bit Sister Romano just this morning...
so she had to go to the bad room.
This room is suffocating.
It's not meant to be pleasant.
The things we do aren't always pleasant...
Do you wanna talk
about why they put you in that room?
Back then, I used to think that there
was something really, really wrong with me.
What did you do?
Well, I guess at first, I tried to run away.
But it didn't fix the feeling.
That's what I like about you, actually.
What?
I think that you feel
the same way that I felt.
But you're not scared, you don't run away.
You just...
You raise your little claws, and you fight.
Carlita, go to your room, okay?
I'll be right there.
Everything looks all right.
You did say you didn't eat much
in the morning.
May be low blood sugar.
Sorry? Margaret, what for?
You wouldn't be the first to faint
witnessing the birth of a child.
Frankly, I'm surprised
it doesn't happen more often.
The miracle of life can be a messy business.
You guys mind if I join?
What's this?
Carlita, did you do this drawing?
This part is mine.
It's a boy.
I don't think that
that's very appropriate, Sister.
You all right?
Here. Let's go for a walk.
-Join the group.
-Oh, not today, girls.
-Come on!
-Okay.
No, no, no, not me.
It's all right. It's okay.
You ready?
It's all for you.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, don't. Don't!
Margaret. Come in.
Something happened, didn't it?
Yes.
You mentioned the name "Scianna."
That's right.
I assume you know these people.
The priest is named Spiletto.
Yes, I've seen him.
Turn it over.
The baby in this photo is Carlita?
And this is why she's in danger?
The truth is there are two Churches.
The one that follows the teachings of Christ,
the one that you and I are part of.
The Church that will turn a blind eye
to torture, to rape.
What do you think that Church
is most frightened of?
We are living in unprecedented times.
Look at what's been occurring
in your very own generation.
A culture that is outspoken, rebelling.
Sometimes violently.
People are turning away from the church
in droves.
And Margaret, you know as well as I do...
Now, how do you control people
who no longer believe...
in your stories of fire and brimstone?
So, a small, but very powerful group
of priests and bishops...
just enough
to drive people back to the Church.
My contacts within the Church
are very limited.
That photo is all I have to go on.
But I believe the baby girl in the picture...
The mother of what?
Yes.
My God. You're crazy.
Though if I am right...
Carlita would have been born on the sixth day
of the sixth month at 6 a.m.
It's the mark of the Devil
which she will have on her body.
I don't understand
why you're telling me this.
They're keeping her files at the orphanage.
Locked away.
I need to know how she was born.
What do you mean, how she was born?
Listen to me, Margaret.
There is a beast they're mating.
-I have to go now.
-No, no, Margaret.
the evil inside her
will do whatever it takes to stop us.
But we're not talking about a human child!
It's almost June 6th.
Look, we haven't a lot of time
and I need your help.
No, you need a doctor.
I'm sorry that I can't help you.
Will you let go of my arm?
Margaret.
-Hi.
-How are you feeling?
I need to talk to you about Carlita.
Do you know anything about her history...
or how she came to the orphanage?
Not off the top of my head. Why?
Do you know where I could find
that kind of information?
I'm afraid this is not really my area,
you know?
Why do you keep staring at me?
I'm not.
Will you come with me?
Come on.
need to talk to you about something.
I just want you to know
that you can trust me, okay?
Has anyone ever done anything to you...
that might have scared
or upset you?
don't know.
What don't you know?
Sometimes I get this...
And I can't tell if they're real or not.
When I was younger...
I used to have these...
They were so terrible that I...
convinced myself that they were real.
But I learned that those thoughts...
Just tricks that my brain
was playing on me...
How can you know that for certain?
Carlita.
Carlita. I'm sorry.
There you are.
A riot's broken out.
We must go.
Listen. It's all right, girls.
It's okay. Stay close to me, okay?
Carlita!
Sister Silva would like to see you
in her office.
Perhaps I should have put it this way.
We think it might be time for you
to take a step back.
Cardinal Lawrence told me
about your troubles growing up.
Perhaps being around Carlita
is not what's right for you.
And her illness must not infect us...
as her caretakers.
I'm not ill.
I understand how hard you had to work...
to get to where you are.
It would be a shame to give it all up now.
I am the only one who cares about her.
-You don't let her play with the other girls.
-I've told you...
-You keep her in the bad room.
-...we're only doing what's right for her.
The girl is sick in the head.
Because of you!
If there was any doubt in our decision...
you've all but confirmed it.
And, Margaret...
you will keep your distance from Carlita.
Or there will be consequences.
Stop the car, Luca.
I can just walk home from here, okay?
Just leave me alone, please.
Sorry. I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Just look for the mark.
Okay.
All right. Oh, God. Okay.
All right.
Hey, call an ambulance.
-Help me.
-I'm gonna help you.
-I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
-I know. Okay.
-I'm scared.
-Paolo, you're gonna be fine, I promise.
No, no, no. You're not gonna die,
you're gonna be okay.
Come with me, Carlita.
Okay, you go to the bed.
I am so sorry that I didn't believe you.
But I believe you now.
Okay?
I'm gonna keep you safe.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Margaret.
-Margaret.
-You stay away.
-I know what you're doing.
-We don't want to hurt you.
Just put that down.
I know what you've done...
with the babies.
You stay away! No!
-Remain calm!
-No, no, no!
No, no, no!
Not in there! Not in there! Not in there!
No! No! No!
Please let me out!
Breathe. Breathe.
...conviction: I am wanted.
I have a task in history.
I am accepted. It is good that I exist.
Let every human heart experience your love.
It's not real.
It's not real. It's not real. It's not real.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
We have to go. I found the files.
It's just me.
Yes. I know. I know.
All right, all right.
Father Gabriel. Margaret.
How?
Well done, Margaret. Well done.
Were you followed?
I don't think so.
Luca, Margaret's driver, brought us.
We can trust him. He's keeping watch outside.
You two know each other?
We have to go get her.
No, it's not safe.
She's the one
who's not safe right now, Gabriel.
It's only a matter of time
before they realize we've got these.
And when they do, they will come for us.
is to prove what they've done.
Otherwise, no one will believe a word we say.
There's so many of them.
Too many.
I had no idea they'd gone to such lengths.
They've only birthed females.
They've all died except for Carlita.
After all these years, so many failures...
They believe the only way is for the beast
to mate with its own offspring.
I told you,
it's the photo from Carlita's birth.
Carlita doesn't have the mark on her head.
What are you talking about?
I've seen it.
You see? Carlita.
then all we have to do is find a baby
with the mark on its scalp.
She's been a ward of the Church
her entire life.
Carlita must be too young...
so they brought Margaret back to Rome to..
You touch me again, I'll fucking kill you!
I'm so sorry this is happening to you,
my child.
They will be coming for you.
If I am pregnant...
then I need it out of me.
I need it out of me now.
Margaret...
you all right?
This doctor knows what he's doing?
Wait. Stop. What are you doing?
Don't stop.
Make like you're heading for the main road...
and then turn off before the arch.
What's happening to me?
I can't tell if this is real or not.
This is very real, Margaret.
Can you untie me?
Soon.
Soon it will be all over, I promise.
The very first moment we met,
do you remember what I said to you?
That you, Margaret, were the bravest girl
I'd ever known.
Now you know how special you are to me.
The baby you're about to bear
will redeem the Church.
Your whole life, you've been searching...
He was always there with you.
I'll be right here.
Stay down.
Please help me. Please.
Please untie me, I'm in pain.
I'm in pain. Please.
Help.
Help me, please.
Please help me.
Help me.
Help. I'm in pain.
What is it? A boy or girl?
There are two.
And the other?
A boy!
We have him.
I'm his mother. I'm his mother
We all need the comfort of our mothers
in the beginning.
Don't we?
You did so well, my child.
He would be so proud of you.
Can't you hear Him telling you?
No, I only hear my own.
Margaret, give me the baby.
Just give me the baby.
No!
Burn everything.
Leave them both to die.
The man you are looking for.
The US Ambassador to Rome.
He will be the new father.
He and his wife will suffer a tragic loss...
and his wife will suffer a
He and his wife will suffer a tragic loss.
and be in need of a child.
The boy will inherit their privilege...
and power.
Soon, his darkness will spread...
and the world shall be saved.
Subbed by Makoto77
Baby, you're supposed to eat them.
Like that.
What are you doing?
No, no, no. Here.
This.
You want one?
You want it?
Give it to Mama. Give it to Mama.
Give it to Mama.
I'm so sorry, Margaret.
I tried just to leave you be.
You need to go.
Now
I came to warn you.
They know you're alive.
You weren't supposed to survive.
None of you were.