Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women....
and blessed is
the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
Now and in the hour of our death.
Amen.
No, no.
No, no, no.
No.
Help.
No, no, no.
Please...
help.
No.
Help.
I'm sorry, but how long is
this going to take?
I have to say my vows tonight....
And I really can't be late.
Do you speak English?
Sorry for the wait.
It's extra work now when
someone arrives...
without a return ticket.
Parli italiano?
I asked if you are learning Italian.
I'm trying, but it's a
lot harder than I thought.
So this monastery, did it
ticket bought for you?
You are very young to become a nun, aren't you?
What a waste.
Look at her.
It's a different life, right?
It must have been a difficult decision
must have been.
I don't think of it that way...
As if it were a decision.
Good.
I hope you find what you are looking for,
Sister Cecilia.
Apologies.
I am Deacon Enzo. Please come with me.
Thanks.
How much further?
We are almost there.
This way, Sister Cecilia.
Sister Cecilia.
Reverend Mother.
Your eyes radiate
the light of the Holy Spirit.
As if the angels delivered you directly
from heaven.
We have been anxiously awaiting
your arrival, my dear.
Excuse me.
She says you are beautiful.
Thank you. I am Sister Cecilia.
Isabelle.
Isabelle, would you take
Cecilia to her room?
I have to help our sisters with the
preparation for tonight's party.
Know your place and do as I say.
I will take you to your room.
Our Lady of Sorrows
was founded in 1632...
As a refuge for elderly sisters
for their transition to heaven.
It's really beautiful.
-Yes, it is.
Good morning, sisters.
And we work hard to
to keep it that way.
The last days of our sisters....
must be in a pleasant environment
to distract them....
Of all sickness and suffering.
All this was built on the
catacomb of St. Stephen.
Catacombs?
It is off limits.
Hello, sisters.
This is our new novice,
Sister Cecilia.
Hello.
In the case of the one in the wheelchair,
her tumor has metastasized.
So we expect her to meet God by
the end of the week.
You talk about it so casually.
Death here is part of
daily life.
Have you seen my daddy?
Yeah, let's go find him, all right?
It is best to just
play along with their delusions....
unless they become violent.
Be careful with this one. She bites.
Excuse me.
Living quarters for caregivers....
Are down there and up there.
Morning prayer begins at 05:00,
't communal meal is afterwards.
And if you have dietary restrictions....
Then we cannot accommodate them.
And this room is yours.
Thank you, sister.
I feel honored to serve with you.
You are very sweet.
Thanks.
I don't mean that as a compliment.
I'm sure this must feel
must feel...
but this is our life.
And I assure you, the work is hard,
physically and emotionally.
So if you are here to find yourself ,
then there are easier ways.
I'm not.
Tonight you don't have to take your vows yet
to take your vows yet.
You can still change your mind
and God will forgive you.
I think he has
sufficiently prepared.
The ceremony begins at 5 p.m. in the chapel.
Don't be late.
Hello.
-Hello.
Excuse me.
-No, it's fine.
I am Cecilia.
I'm Guendalina.
You can call me Gwen.
My room is there.
Where in the US are you from?
Just outside Detroit, Michigan.
Are you from here or...
Closer to Milan.
You are far from home.
Yes, my parish is closed.
Was the priest in trouble?
-No.
No, no, no, nothing like that.
Just a low turnout.
And that church was my family, my home.
When I left, I felt
pretty lost.
But then Father Tedeschi
contacted me.
Yes.
He has a talent.
Detecting broken birds.
Oh, I didn't mean to offend you.
I think we might all be
problem cases or runaways.
What do you fall under?
Both.
Next time, you can
lock the door if you want.
Thanks.
Sister Cecilia.
Fr. Tedeschi,
it's nice to meet you in person.
We all feel so blessed
That you are here.
How are you doing in Italian?
So, so.
It's fine.
I'll translate for you.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Let us rejoice,
for the wedding of the Lamb has come....
And his brides have made themselves ready.
Sister Cecilia.
Do you promise to follow Christ...
By living a life without
material possessions?
Do you promise to free yourself from the
desire for a human relationship
And you will follow Him with joy
When He returns...
and a vow of poverty,
chastity and obedience?
I do.
May God give you the strength to fulfill your
vows faithfully and joyfully.
May you let His light shine
So that the world can see it.
How do you feel?
Vol.
Yeah, we don't really have anything
like this at home.
Cecilia, this is your home.
I know.
I felt the same way when I started here.
I didn't grow up with the
desire to become a priest.
My first career was in the
sciences, biology.
I was almost twenty years in...
and I couldn't understand the world better....
than when I was in Sunday school.
And then God showed me a path.
He brought me here.
This is where I needed to be.
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry.
After two glasses, I can't stop
talking about myself.
I'm very sorry.
-No, it's okay.
It's okay.
-And what about you?
I can imagine it was a
difficult decision.
I mean, yes, it seemed so far away.
But the odds in the US...
I didn't feel like God had
had saved me for that.
If it's too personal...
No.
When I was 12 years old,
there was a section...
of the Saginaw River that was always freezing.
And no matter how cold it was,
I always walked on the ice.
And then I took off my gloves
and placed my hands on the ice.
And then I kept them there until
I didn't feel them anymore.
I don't remember the ice breaking.
I remember only this sharp
pain of cold.
The paramedics,
tried to resuscitate me....
but my heart stood still for almost seven
minutes.
That sounds frightening.
I know God saved me for a reason
saved me...
but I think I'm still
looking for what that reason is.
Would you please excuse me now?
Hello?
Are you okay?
I'm going to get help.
Cecilia.
Reverend Mother, I am so sorry.
I heard her crying and...
It's okay.
Sometimes we get caught up in emotion.
You have a question.
Okay.
What is this place?
Saint Helena, Mother of Constantine,
brought this back from Jerusalem.
Here.
He suffered on the cross.
Suffering? This is the...
Yes.
For you. For us.
For our sins. For our redemption.
We suffer.
In the name of His love.
It is a gift.
Suffering is love.
Are you okay, sister?
In the name of the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It has been three days since my
last confession.
I was...
I was careless last night.
I drank too much wine and made a fool of myself
embarrassed myself in front of Mother Superior.
I promise to conduct myself with grace
conduct because I have nothing
would rather than belong here.
I'm afraid I've already messed things up.
I am sorry for this...
Desires.
Hello?
Good morning, sisters.
Today begins a new life.
But this new year
will not be easy.
You will question your purpose.
You will doubt me and
why you have come here.
And some of you
won't have the spiritual...
have endurance for this life.
What did she say?
God is good. God is great.
God, my head hurts.
Too much blood of Christ?
Do you think this is funny, Sister Guendalina?
No, forgive me.
This side of the room belongs to me.
The others, will
serve at Sister Isabelle's.
No.
What a blessing to be able to
guidance.
Eat your plate.
There is work to be done.
It seems that the
battery of her vibrator is dead.
What is that supposed to mean?
Oh, nothing. I really like her.
I'm super excited.
Clean their backs thoroughly.
And if the consistency of their
droppings doesn't seem to match....
let Dr. Gallo know.
Hello.
The larger items we want to
forward...
and the shorter items to the rear.
That way, the wind can blow underneath.
First, you need to make sure that
your knife is properly sharp.
Otherwise, you run the risk of making
a big mess.
Sorry. I can't.
In the name of the Father and
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Blessed...
Holy.
We all adore you.
Sister, let's get you to bed.
Blessed Saint Cecilia.
Good night, sister.
It could have been worse.
She could have slapped you.
Gwen, I'm not kidding.
She had scars on the bottom of
her feet.
It's not what you thought it
would be, isn't it, this place?
No, it's definitely different.
However, it is better than where I came from.
What do you mean?
There is a boy.
There was a boy, I mean.
What happened to this boy?
He hit me.
I hit him back.
When I left him
I went to a support group.
There were these nuns there.
And I thought, these women have
a very good life.
They have a place to live, a job
where they can keep their clothes on....
and don't have to worry about anything.
So I signed up.
Wait, so you don't even believe in God?
-Of course I do.
Life is so cruel.
Only a man can be responsible.
Oh, my God, I was kidding.
Are you okay?
I don't feel good.
I'm going to call a doctor.
Sister Cecilia. Come with me.
Your Eminence.
Sit down.
Can you please tell Cardinal Merola
tell your vows?
My vows?
-Your vows.
I swore three vows when
I arrived here...
Of obedience, poverty and chastity.
He asks if you...
-I understand.
I did.
I have been obedient, Your Eminence.
Have you kept your vow
of poverty?
Yes, I don't own anything.
I lack nothing.
Did you stay chaste?
I'm sorry, why are you asking me this?
It's okay.
Just answer the question,
if you like, Cecilia.
Of course I have been chaste,
Your Eminence.
Did you, before you arrived here,
sexual intercourse with a man?
Sexual intercourse with... no, no.
Have you ever had sexual intercourse
had with a man?
I have not broken my vows and have
never had intercourse with 'any man or woman.
You will not be punished.
We just want to know the truth.
I'm not lying, Reverend.
What's going on?
When she arrived, Dr. Gallo,
did you examine her then?
Her hymen was intact.
It was never touched.
What do they say?
Mother Superior, have there been
visitors, in recent weeks?
No.
What are you looking at?
One last time.
Have you ever had sexual intercourse?
Why are you asking me this?
You are expecting.
This child is...
immaculately received.
With God as my witness...
we have been blessed with a miracle.
He believes you.
It is a miracle.
Why did he, of all the women
in the world, chose me?
You told me who saved your life....
Who sent you on the path that
led you here.
Cecilia, you were looking for a reason.
God has saved you.
This is it.
Blessed are the meek....
For they shall inherit the earth.
You are no longer allowed to work.
Remember that your only job is the baby.
How long would it be before
they started calling you Mary?
It should have been me. Bitch.
Isabelle. Isabelle.
Sisters.
Stop.
Release her.
No. No, no.
We have to try again.
They should try again with me.
The heart rate is stable.
There is no bleeding.
Be praised.
We'll do some blood tests
to check for problems.
But he seems to be fine.
But I'm not okay.
Eminence, Isabelle said that she
it had to be her.
Why would she say that?
Isabelle has been losing her
battle with her mental health.
And in beholding
you and the miracle...
it obviously triggered something,
whether it was jealousy...
She tried to drown me.
You are right.
And I will make sure that this never
happen again.
I want to go to another doctor.
Why? Dr. Gallo...
Cares for old women.
I want to go to a real hospital, please.
He is a licensed obstetrician.
Thursday through Saturday
I do deliveries at Cosentino.
A hospital is not what you
need right now. You are in perfect health.
I just puked out one of my teeth.
Hospitals are not the safest places.
We don't want you to get sick.
Or that some of it leaks out, you know.
The safest thing to do is to stay here
until the Savior is born.
God bless you, young mother.
Isabelle.
Go away all of you.
I said, go away.
Cecilia, you have to stand up for yourself.
Gwen, shush.
-Open your eyes.
I don't trust this place.
I don't think we can just leave.
Cecilia, you are five months pregnant....
And you haven't even been in a
hospital.
We can arrange this.
How can we trust
on what's inside you?
Maybe God is...
-God has nothing to do with this.
Sisters, is something going on?
I see that you...
Don't touch me.
Rock on.
How can you guys just
stand there like nothing happened?
Cecilia is pregnant and we don't know how.
Isabelle committed suicide.
What the hell is going on?
Sister...
Leave me alone.
I know when a man is lying to me.
And all of you, every one of you,
lying your asses off.
Let go of me.
No.
Let go of me! I said, let go of me.
"For Satan himself often disguises himself
as an angel of light."
Gwen.
No.
No, no.
Let me go.
No.
No, I beg, please.
Blessed...
Holy.
Please help me.
We have to get out of here.
You will never leave here again.
What is happening?
-I don't know.
Mother. What's the matter?
-I don't know, Reverend.
God in heaven.
Call Dr. Gallo.
-I can't, it's Saturday.
Call him. Something is wrong.
I don't get it, it's Saturday.
We have to take her to the hospital.
No.
-You have to go. Now.
-Enough, I'm calling an ambulance.
Stop.
Something is wrong.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to.
What do we do if she dies along the way?
We must hold out hope.
It doesn't look good.
-Then we will pray.
Yes.
I understand.
Stop the car.
-What?
What are you doing?
Row.
Drive through.
Clean yourself up.
Are you embarrassed now?
Now?
Where was your shame when you
put a dead animal inside yourself?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Making us believe that the
miracle has died in you.
What do you have to say for yourself?
God will never forgive you.
I want to apologize if
any of my actions scared you.
And I want to assure you that you are
are safe.
What have you done to me?
When you look at this, what do you see?
Some people might just see
an old piece of iron, a rusty nail.
For those of us who know...
we see the evidence of Jesus' sacrifice....
A symbol of his suffering.
And for 2,000 years,
that's all it was.
But we took a closer look
and we found blood...
tissue, small bone fragments,
a genetic code.
All we had to do was
't crack the key to resurrection.
You are insane.
I will show you.
It has taken us 20 years of trial and
getting up ...
20 years for God to give us the knowledge
and the perfect fruitful vessel.
Is this what is in me?
No.
These are all our failures.
What is in you is our success.
I left the field of genetics
because some people...
disagreed with the ethics
of my experiment.
So many people have such a limited
view of its potential.
But here in the church, here they understood
that a simple procedure
could bring us salvation.
You are playing for God.
I'm not playing God.
Do you know what it's like to watch the
miracle to see die...
In the mother's womb, to abandon God again and again
forsaken again and again....
but still find the strength
to keep going?
This is my calling.
And this, this is yours.
No.
What are you doing?
What's going on?
What is that?
What are you doing?
Please, stop.
Stop, stop.
Stop.
May you never stray again.
No.
No, no.
Stop.
Blessed are the meek....
No, no, no.
Please. No.
...for they will be the earth...
-No, no. Please, no.
...inheritance.
-No, no.
No.
Wait.
Sister Cecilia.
How long have you had your eye on me?
Please confess.
Was it since the accident?
What will happen when it is finished?
Do you think it, will save the world?
Or terminate?
That's what Revelation says, right?
This is not God's work.
Well then.
If this is not the will of God ,
why doesn't He stop us?
It could happen any day now.
He moves.
I'll be right back with her medicine.
Would you be willing to do that?
Yes.
I'll be right back.
Such a beautiful mother.
And those eyes. Like sunflowers.
Blessed child, it is all
part of His plan.
You will save us.
Blessed are the meek,
for they shall inherit the earth.
God damn.
Oh my God.
Cecilia, what did you do?
Cecilia, this solves nothing.
If you die, we'll find another one.
You can end this.
All you have to do is
bring our Savior into the world.
No.
Cecilia.
Let go of me.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary...
No, no.
Mother of God, pray for us sinners....
Now and on the hour...
No.
Fuck you.
Subtitles: DUTCH SUBS.
Hail Mary...
full of grace.
Mary, full of grace.
Hail Lord.
The Lord is with thee.
Hail Mary...
full of grace.
Mary, full of grace.
Hail Lord.
The Lord is with thee.
Hail Mary...
full of grace.
Mary, full of grace.
Hail Lord.
The Lord is with thee.
Hail Mary.