The Lonely Island Ft. Akon - I just had Sex
Album:Turtleneck & Chain(2010)
Sometimes
Ohhhh
Something beautiful happens in this world (Akon...)
You don’t know how to express yourself so(The Lonely
Island)
You just gotta sing..
I just had sex! And it felt so good! (felt it so good)
A woman let me put my penis inside her!
I just had sex, and i’ll never go back..(never go back)
to the not-havin’-sex ways of the past
Have you ever had sex? I have - it felt great!
It felt so good when i did it with my penis
A girl let me do it, it literally just happened..
Havin’ sex can make a nice man out the meanest!
Never guess where I just came from - I had sex!
If I had to describe the feeling: it was the best!
When I had the sex man my penis felt great!
And I called my parents right after I was done
Oh hey, didn’t see you there. Guess what I just did?
Had sex, undressed- saw her boobies and the rest
Was sure nice of her to let you do that thing
Nice of any girl ever- now sing!
I just had sex! And it felt so good! (felt so good)
A woman let me put my penis inside her!
I wanna tell the world!
To be honest I’m surprised she even wanted me to do it
Doesn’t really make sense, but man screw it!
I ain’t one to argue with a good thing
She could be my wife- (that good?)
The best 30 seconds of my life!
I’m so humbled by a girl’s ability to let me do her
‘Cuz honestly I’d have sex with a pile of manure
With that in mind, the soft, nice smellin’ girl’s
better
‘Cuz she let me wear my chain and my turtle neck
sweater
So this one’s dedicated to them girls
That let us flop around on top of them!
If you’re near or far whether short or tall
we wanna thank you all for lettin’ us fuck you all!
She kept lookin’ at her watch-
(Doesn’t matter, I had sex!)
But I cried the whole time-
I think she might of been a racist-
(Doesn’t matter, I had sex!)
She put a bag on my head-
(Still counts)
I just had sex! And my dreams came true- (dreams came
true)
So if you had sex in the last 30 minutes then you’re
qualified to sing with me!
I just had sex! [everybody sings]
And it felt so good! (felt it so good)
A woman let me put my penis inside her! ( I wanna tell
the world)
I just had sex, and I'll never go back..[never go back]
to the not-havin’-sex ways of the past.
yeahh...