[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
[INAUDIBLE ARGUING IN GERMAN]
[HEATED ARGUING CONTINUES]
[LOUD YELLING]
[DISTURBING HIGH-PITCHED SCREECHING]
[ARGUING CONTINUES DOWNSTAIRS]
[SCREECHING CONTINUES]
[DOOR CREAKS]
[ARGUING CONTINUES]
[LOUD SLAM]
[DISTANT WHIMPERING]
[DISTURBING SCREECH]
[WING BUZZ]
[LEAVES RUSTLE]
[ON THE PHONE, IN GERMAN]
You lost your adolescent already?
This will complicate matters...
A young one is on the way,
but the mother will be harder to control
without a nestling around.
[EERIE MUSIC, DOOR SLAMS]
[ENGINE HUMMING]
So, who is the woman
in the station wagon?
Beth.
Mr. Keenig...
"Herr König."
Herr... Konish?
'Ö.' It's not an 'E.'
'Ö.'
"Herr König."
[GIRL, COMPUTER VOICE]
Where's Gretchen?
Gretchen and the movers
are right behind us.
Okay, so, she's not your mother?
No, she's Beth.
Ah, okay.
And what is going on
with your sister?
She deaf or something?
No.
But she can't speak.
It's fucking annoying.
[ENGINE HUMS, TURNS OFF]
You okay, honey?
The nice man who owns this place
will take us to our new home.
Oh!
[IN GERMAN]
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Mr. König.
Ah, very good, Luis!
You've been practicing, huh?
How was your journey?
Oh, very pleasant, thank you.
We almost forgot how beautiful
it is here.
Ah, we almost forgot
how beautiful you are, Beth.
Oh, stop!
[LAUGHS] Keep going!
Gretchen, come say hi.
Gretchen.
[GRETCHEN]
What's up?
[BETH]
Oh, Jesus.
[MR. KÖNIG] Nice to meet you.
Willkommen.
Thank you.
No, thank you, Beth.
We are so glad to have you back.
And please do not worry
about your late arrival.
I completely understand.
[BETH] We have something for you.
[LUIS] I'm sorry.
It's...
The original sketch.
We drew that up
the night that you showed us
the land you acquired.
Beth, that is...
[LAUGHS] Well, we will display this
in the new guest lodge.
Oh! [LAUGHS]
[MR. KÖNIG] You know, you two lovebirds
stumbled into my nest
almost eight years ago to the day.
And I believe there were more
than just architectural plans
that were conceived this day.
[EVERYONE LAUGHS]
[MR. KÖNIG] Hello, Alma.
[COMPUTER VOICE, IN GERMAN]
Hello. It's nice to meet you.
[IN GERMAN]
- The pleasure is all mine.
[IN ENGLISH] Your German is already better
than your father's, huh?
[COMPUTER, IN GERMAN] - Yes.
[IN GERMAN] - Ha! She said yes.
[LUIS] Ja, ja.
[EVERYONE LAUGHS]
[GIRL, ON PHONE]
Hey, Gretchen. How are you holding up?
I wish we could have spent a little more
time together after the funeral,
but I get it.
You're all over Europe
with your dad's family, huh?
Don't forget you have a band
that needs your voice.
Anyway, I'm sending you the new mix.
I knew your mom would have loved it.
[MUSIC STARTS PLAYING]
[DOOR CREAKS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[BUTTON CLICKS, MUSIC STOPS]
[TOILET SEAT FALLS]
[FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE]
[SCREEN TYPING SOUNDS]
[LOUD SLAM, HANDLE BANGS]
Beth? It's occupied.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[STALL DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SCRATCHING AND BANGING SOUNDS]
Gretchen, let's go!
Herr König is taking us
to the new house.
Can you sit with Alma this time?
[EERIE RUMBLING NOISE]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUFFLED VOICES]
Car? What?
Car what?
[KEYS RUSTLING]
[DOG PANTS, BARKS]
[BIRDS SQUAWK]
[GRETCHEN] What?
[BIRDS SQUAWK, DOG GROWLS]
[LOUD GROWLING]
[WOMAN] Hello there!
My name is Bonomo.
I'm your neighbor.
I have my hands full.
Oh, me too.
Are you the housekeeper?
No, I'm a daughter.
Oh, really?
Haven't heard about you.
Are you from England as well?
No, I'm not.
Why would you have heard about me?
[KÖNIG] I told...
[GRETCHEN, HUSHED] Jesus.
Forgive me, my dear.
Didn't mean to startle you.
I told Dr. Bonomo about your family.
Dr. Bonomo is the medical superintendent
of the local hospital
and also the chronic disease
treatment facility,
which I am also funding.
This is Gretchen.
Gretchen.
Yeah.
Gretchen is from the United States.
It has been decided that
she is moving in with her father.
What a pleasant surprise.
[VOICE RECORDING] Hi, you have reached the
Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it.
[BEEP]
Hi, mom.
I know this is weird, um...
But it's good to hear your voice.
Going with dad was a bad idea,
and I miss our house.
I'm short on money, but I'm gonna try
to come home soon.
[KNOCKING]
[LUIS]
I know it's been tough.
But we are very happy you're here.
[KNOCKING]
[MR. KÖNIG] Excuse me.
Gretchen, my dear.
I, uh...
I've been thinking, for a young woman
like you there's, uh...
not so many things to do
here in the summer, and so...
I have a little idea.
A proposal.
How would you like
to come work for me at the resort?
[LUIS] Oh, Herr König...
[MR. KÖNIG] Well, it's an easy job,
and it will give you
something to do
while your parents build
a new resort for me.
I could use some more
English-speaking staff.
[LUIS] Herr König,
I think Gretchen...
I would pay you
an appropriate salary, of course.
[LUIS] I don't...
[GRETCHEN] Yeah, sure. I'll do it.
Oh.
Schön.
Wonderful.
Come by the reception tomorrow.
[WOMAN] Here's your ID badge, sir.
Would you like to pay
with cash or credit card?
Cash, or credit?
Cash.
[WOMAN, WHISPERING]
"That will be 45 euro for a single room."
Uh, that will be 45 euro
for a single room.
Oh, and this is Beatrice
and I am Gretchen.
- [IN GERMAN] Can I go now?
- [IN FRENCH] No.
You can help me teach Gretchen
how to sell things in the shop.
You have to be polite and friendly,
even if the guest is rude.
And remember to put up the sign
if you go to the bathroom.
But if you have any real trouble,
just call the boss.
He lives up the resort street,
on the hill.
He lives in a vacation bungalow?
No, he has a villa way up there.
He bought the hotel,
and so the bungalows are basically
in the front yard of his villa.
Weird, right?
Super.
[WOMAN RETCHES AND PUKES]
[PANTS]
[MAN, IN GERMAN]
I'm so sorry.
[IN GERMAN] No problem.
[HUSHEDLY] This happens sometimes.
[MR. KÖNIG]
How's your first day, my dear?
Can't complain.
And how is your German coming along?
Not good.
This is okay.
You know, there are
English-speaking schools
over the border, in Italy.
[WOMAN COUGHS IN THE DISTANCE]
Well, I'll be along to pick you up
in one hour.
Oh, I have my bike.
Oh?
No.
No, no, no.
No, it will be too dark
on the country roads by then.
This is why you will not work late.
You will help Beatrix
with the peak times.
[BEATRICE] What?
I thought we were going to split
the evening shifts.
[MR. KÖNIG] You have a car.
I have a life, too.
Beatrix, I will not get drawn
into another debate with you.
I don't wanna have
a debate with you.
No. Every time I raise
an issue with you,
there is something
you have to say about it.
- I do everything you ask!
- No.
What? I work every day late shifts!
You're blasting your Scheisse music
on the car radio on your way to work.
I hear it across the forest.
This is a nature reserve
and you are disturbing the wildlife
with your 'boom, boom...'
[VIBRATING FLUTE SOUNDS]
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[LOUD, BOOMY MUSIC
ON HEADPHONES]
[GUITAR STRUMMING]
[GRETCHEN, SINGING QUIETLY]
They can dance on the carpet...
[LOUD MUSIC ON HEADPHONES]
[RUSTLING LEAVES, BIRDS,
SHARP SCREECH]
[SOFT STRUMMING]
[LOUD MUSIC ON HEADPHONES]
[HOSPITAL BRACELET RATTLES]
[DISTANT SCREECHING NOISE]
[SCREECHING CONTINUES]
[LOUD RHYTHMIC SCREECHING]
[WHEEZING, THROBBING]
[LOUD MUSIC ON HEADPHONES]
Hey, Alma!
What the fuck are you doing?
[LOUD MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SCREECHING, RAPID THROBBING]
[SCREECHING FADES OUT]
[LOUD MUSIC]
Hey, Alma!
What the fuck are you doing?
[LOUD SCREECHING, THROBBING]
[MUSIC, SCREECHING, THROBBING]
[SLASHING, THUD]
[MUFFLED MUSIC, PANTING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[BETH] Gretchen, turn it down!
Alma?
[BETH] Shh, it's okay, it's okay.
[BEATRICE]
What happened to your face?
My father's daughter scratched me.
Your sister?
- She's not my sister.
- Oh.
Come on now.
I'm sure she really wants you
to be her sister.
She had a chance at getting one
but she ate her twin.
It's called vanishing twin syndrome.
It's when one fetus dies
in the early stages of the pregnancy
and then the surviving fetus
absorbs the dead one.
I always thought
it was kind of badass.
But yeah, she's a bitch.
Okay.
Another reason to not have kids.
Thanks for finishing my shift.
Erik and I haven't been
on a date in ages.
Here's my master key.
There's only one. Don't lose it.
And at 10 p.m. sharp you lock
everything up like I showed you.
[WHISPERS] And boss doesn't need to know.
It's fine.
Okay.
[IN FRENCH] Good luck tonight!
Uh-huh.
[SLAM, BELL RINGS LOUDLY]
Can I get a room?
May I see your ID or passport?
Can't just ask for my name?
Um...
Is it just you...
or are you here with a partner?
We have special rates and amenities
for couples and newlyweds.
For now, just me.
Okay.
I'm Ed.
[ED] What's your name?
I'm Gretchen.
You look like
you don't belong here, Gretchen.
I won't be here for long anyways.
[ED] You like music?
Sure.
Then you should come to Paris.
Okay.
[COUGHS, VOMITS]
Hey!
[CAN CLANKS ON THE FLOOR]
Is this normal?
It's only my second day.
[ED] Better go check on her.
Uh-huh.
[PHONE RINGS]
Resort Alpschatten...
[MR. KÖNIG, IN GERMAN]
Beatrix, why are you still at the hotel?
I can see the light from...
Gretchen?
- Yes.
- Where's Beatrix?
Uh, I stayed longer
and let her leave.
But I know how to lock up,
it's no trouble.
Gretchen.
I want you to lock up the doors
and wait for me,
and I'll come pick you up
right now.
Uh...
Yeah, Herr König, it's fine.
There's a confused guest
and I need to go check on her.
But I have my bike here,
so you don't need to pick me up.
Gretchen, listen to me carefully.
I need you to lock the doors...
[PHONE RINGS INSISTENTLY]
[PHONE CONTINUES RINGING
IN THE DISTANCE]
[WIND, BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[WIND AND BIRD NOISES GET LOUDER]
[BUTTERFLY KNIFE JINGLES]
[LIGHT SWITCHES TURN OFF]
[PHONE RINGING]
[GRETCHEN] Fuck no.
[CAR TIRES SCREECH]
[MR. KÖNIG, IN GERMAN]
Yes, okay. Call me back.
[IN GERMAN]
Damn it.
Shit.
Gretchen?
[MUSIC BLARING ON HEADPHONES]
[DISTANT MUFFLED SCREAM]
[IN GERMAN]
Where are you?
Where are you? Come here.
[HIGH-PITCHED FLUTE NOTES]
[BLOOD-CURLING SCREAM]
[HEAVY ROCK MUSIC]
Hello!
Please let me in!
Ja?
Please let me in right now!
Please!
[IN GERMAN] - Yes, yes, coming.
[MUFFLED THUD, RINGING EARS]
[IN GERMAN]
I told you I'm coming!
[POLICE SIREN]
[ERIK] I started bleeding.
The woman stood there
until the police arrived.
I was chased.
[STAPLER STAPLES]
Fuck!
It's really important that
your statement is as accurate as possible.
The receptionist,
she stated that she did not see
any woman in the parking lot.
May I suggest...
we change the last part into...
"The woman stood there until
Mrs. So-and-so entered the room...
"Then the police arrived."
That is so much better.
I think...
you are the victim of a prank.
[LUIS] Everybody
is very nice here, honey.
It's best we run some tests,
but this is actually very common.
- Dad.
- Gretchen?
What happened?
Did you fall?
Yeah, that's not the important part.
Your sister had some kind of seizure.
We need to get her checked out.
Dad, I was attacked.
By who?
I don't know, the cops think
it was a prank...
A prank?
Did somebody hit you?
No, I fell, but...
[BETH] Gretchen?
She fell, it's okay.
[DOCTOR] We are going to do an MRI...
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[DR. BONOMO]
It might be childhood epilepsy.
Epilepsy?
It might be?
It means it might be genetic and
not caused by an injury or tumor.
The cause itself isn't life-threatening.
- Well, that's good.
- Yeah.
The better news is I'm the superintendent
of the chronic disease
treatment center up here.
What's causing the seizures?
There are many possible
triggers for a seizure in a child.
Fever. Certain lights.
Certain sounds.
A change in hormone levels.
But Alma is too young for that.
Has there been a stressful event
or disruption in your family lately?
[VOICE RECORDING] Hi, you have reached the
Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it!
[BEEP TONE]
[GRETCHEN]
Mom, this place is completely fucked.
Alma keeps freaking out, and they say
she has epilepsy or something.
I think Dad is blaming me.
[REGISTER DINGS]
I'm coming back home.
I got the money.
[MAN] What happened to you?
[GRETCHEN] Jesus.
Uh, I don't wanna talk about it.
I'm police investigator Henry Lando.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions about the...
incident last night.
Which one?
You told the police
that you were chased by a woman.
I don't wanna talk to you.
Excuse me?
Um... excuse me.
There's another guest waiting.
I think there's something wrong
with my air conditioning.
Could you come see me
when you're done?
Fine.
I'm checking out.
Oh.
Okay.
You didn't charge me.
Don't I have to pay for the room?
Um...
No, you don't.
Do you smoke?
[LIVELY MUSIC]
[ED] You coming?
[GRETCHEN] Yeah, just give me a minute.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GRETCHEN] I have a house
back in the States.
I just need to get to an airport.
[ED] Well, lucky you.
We have one of these in Paris.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ED] And then the woman went
into that weird pink bungalow.
I wasn't going in there.
That pink bungalow
is called the "Lover's Nest."
[DISTORTED SCREECH]
...and then the woman
went into that weird pink bungalow.
I wasn't going in there.
That pink bungalow
is called the "Lover's Nest."
[DISTORTED HUMMING]
[DISTORTED SCREECHING]
[DISTORTED]...and then the woman
went into that weird pink bungalow.
[DISTORTED] I wasn't going in there.
[SCREECHING, RUMBLING]
Watch out!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[LOUD CRASH AND THUDS]
[HISSING SMOKE]
[MUFFLED, DISTORTED MUSIC]
[MUFFLED GROWLING]
[GROWLING GETS LOUDER]
[LOUD SCREAM]
[GRETCHEN MOANS]
[HOODED FIGURE SCREECHES]
[GRETCHEN YELLS LOUDLY]
[GUNSHOTS]
[MACHINES HUM IN THE BACKGROUND]
[MR. KÖNIG] Do you smell this?
Yes.
Or are those molecules binding
to a receptor in your nasal cavity?
Got me.
And are you...
right now, in this moment...
are you putting your slashed skin
back together yourself?
And what makes you think
you can take charge of the rest?
Hm?
If I were you...
I would stay home
until my body was done
growing back those cells.
I wouldn't want to get hurt even more.
As if I was stuck in a loop.
Can you... do this?
Good.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Apology accepted.
Luis.
What are you doing?
I'm getting my stuff.
What? You aren't going
to sleep in the bed?
I mean, they said we can...
I can't sleep here again, Gretchen.
I've got work to do.
Beth has been watching Alma
while I've been here looking after you.
I have to go home and give her a break.
Please don't leave.
You'll be fine.
There are people in here all the time.
No, there's not!
It's deserted all night!
It's fine.
You'll be home soon.
What if she comes back?
Gretchen, stop it!
But why? I'm not making this up!
I don't want to hear
any more about this shit.
You're making it
very difficult for your sister.
I wasn't high.
Oh, you were!
You were tested.
You stole money from Herr König
and then you ran away
with a complete stranger.
I can't force you to do anything.
You are almost eighteen years old.
But you don't have a job anymore
and you will not be getting an allowance.
If you wanna run away,
you take your fucking bicycle.
[VOICE RECORDING] Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it!
[BEEP]
[GRETCHEN, CRYING]
Mom? Mom...
Mom, I really wanna come home.
It's really bad.
I wanna come home.
[INDISTINCT TALK]
[ED] Where's Gretchen?
[GRETCHEN, ON PHONE]
Or what do you think?
[ED] Where's Gretchen?
[GRETCHEN, ON PHONE]
What do you think, mom?
[SOFT MUSIC]
[HENRY] I told you to come see me.
I saved your life.
I saw the woman.
You saw her?
And you didn't tell anyone?
They think I'm crazy.
I need you to help me find that woman.
She's wanted for murder.
And I expect her
to come for you again.
I can protect you.
If we find her...
I personally take you
wherever you want to go.
[DR. BONOMO]
Does Alma listen to music often?
[BETH] She loves music,
especially since Gretchen
moved in with us.
[HENRY] Now...
And this is extremely important.
Nobody must know about this investigation.
I don't know who to trust.
[DR. BONOMO] Loud music has showed to
trigger seizures
in people with Alma's condition.
[BETH] Alma?
Dr. Bonomo says music, no more.
[GRETCHEN] It's just music.
[LUIS] You going out?
[SIGN LANGUAGE]
That's very cool.
[BETH, SIGN LANGUAGE]
No, it's not.
[RADIO STATIC]
A month ago,
a married couple on vacation
had rented this cabin.
A cabin not far from here.
The husband told the police
that in the evening
he lost consciousness.
When he woke up...
he found a strange, blonde woman
in his bedroom.
Along with his wife,
who he found unconscious.
The blonde woman's voice
had a hypnotic effect on the man.
He chased the woman into the woods,
but she got away.
When the husband returned to the cabin,
his wife had choked on her vomit.
Jesus.
Dude...
The other night, a half-naked woman
came into the reception,
and she wasn't responding to anything.
Where was she staying?
[GRETCHEN] The Lover's Nest.
[HENRY] You're right.
The next bungalow is not in use.
[GRETCHEN] I didn't know
stakeouts were gonna be so boring.
When are we gonna see some action?
[HENRY] Almost 11.
Be on the lookout
and listen for anything strange.
[INDISTINCT TV NOISE]
[DOOR OPEN AND CLOSES]
[BEATRICE CLEARS THROAT]
[IN GERMAN]
What are you doing here?
[IN FRENCH] What do you think?
You imbecile!
[IN GERMAN]
We can't, not here. We're leaving. Now!
[IN FRENCH] Why? I'm cleaning this
fuck-pad all the time!
[IN FRENCH]
I beg you!
You'll have to make it up to me.
[IN FRENCH] I promise.
[IN FRENCH] Okay, fine.
[IN FRENCH]
Let me dry my hair, then we can go.
[BUTTERFLY KNIFE JINGLES]
[BIRD SQUAWKING ECHOES]
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[BEATRICE, IN FRENCH]
I know how you can make it up to me!
[THROBBING, PIERCING SCREECH]
[PULSATING SCREECH]
[SCREECH ECHOES IN THE DISTANCE]
[GROWLING, SCREECHING]
[IN FRENCH] Erik, I know
how you can make it up to me!
[SCREECH ECHOES]
[PULSATING SCREECH]
[IN FRENCH] Erik, I know
how you can make it up to me!
[PULSATING SCREECH]
[THROBBING, RATTLING]
[GROWL]
[SCREECH DWINDLES AND FADES OUT]
[SCRATCHING]
[FIGURE SCREECHES,
BEATRICE SCREAMS]
[COCKS GUN]
[TENSE MUSIC]
[OOZING SOUNDS]
[GROWLS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[SCREECHES]
[TENSE MUSIC]
[GUNSHOT]
[INDISTINCT TV SOUNDS]
[GRETCHEN GASPS]
[HENRY] She'll choke.
Last time I was too late.
[BETH] Gretchen?
Did we wake you?
[MR. KÖNIG]
All the owls have individual calls
so that they can understand each other
over long distances.
And maybe we can make a secret call
so that we can understand each other.
Now, I brought you something.
I know that you will like this.
[BETH] Gretchen, come sit with us.
Gretchen?
I'm so sorry, did we wake you?
No.
Okay, good.
Please join us.
I went out last night.
[BETH] Where did you go?
[GRETCHEN] The resort.
What were you doing there?
I was with Trixie.
Huh.
I didn't know Beatrix
was working late last night.
She wasn't.
She was really confused.
Come to think of it,
a lot like the guest
we spoke about over the phone
the other night.
Hm. I will look into this.
Why is there nobody
working the reception after ten?
Seems like a lot of people
need assistance after ten.
It doesn't make sense economically.
That's stupid, it's a hotel.
[LUIS] Gretchen!
I can show you the numbers if you'd
like. It's not so interesting, but...
Maybe another time.
It's quite the place you got here.
Gretchen, what's the matter?
Why did you bring us here?
Your parents are planning a...
A new resort, I know.
Why do we have to live here?
[LUIS] Gretchen!
- Because it's pretty outside?
- Calm down right now.
[RECORDER NOTES]
You are here because
your family belongs here.
That's a fucking weird way to put it!
Gretchen, that's enough!
What has gotten into you?
I don't know dad!
I'm just reflecting on this very
fucking weird living situation
that everybody just seems
to be cool with.
Out!
Now!
Great.
[MR. KÖNIG] No, no, Luis.
A gentleman knows
when it's time to leave.
You need some family time,
I understand.
[BETH] No, Herr König,
we don't want you to leave.
It's okay, thank you
for the wonderful afternoon
and I wish you a good evening.
[LUIS] I'm very sorry.
[MR. KÖNIG] No, Luis, we are
so very happy to have you here.
We've been desperately eager
for you to be here.
And Gretchen, if there is
anything that... bothers you,
don't be afraid to...
talk to me.
Oh, I leave your package just here.
Oh... it was a surprise.
I was not supposed to say anything.
I am so sorry.
What package?
It has your family name on it.
[LUIS] It was your mother's stuff.
The small stuff, at least.
I received it this morning.
I... your father should perhaps
change the address on the counter...
What is it doing here, dad?
I sold the old house.
It was... still my house.
And I put the money
in an account for you.
I... I didn't want you
to get worked up again...
[VOICE RECORDING] Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it.
[BEEP]
[GRETCHEN, ON RECORDING]
Mom, I really wanna go home.
[SNIFFS] It's really bad.
I really want to come home.
What do you think?
What do you think, mom?
[ANGRILY]
What's your take on that, mom?
[SOBBING]
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Next message.
Hello Ms. Vanderkurt,
my name is Alma.
I'm calling you
because of my sister, Gretchen.
Gretchen calls you
when she feels bad,
but you never answer.
I can hear her from my room.
I'm worried.
If you get my message, I want you
to call Gretchen back on the phone.
You can tell her that you love her.
It would mean a lot to her.
It would make her happy.
If you'd like to,
you can come visit us.
You are always welcome here.
[TAPE CLICKS]
[MR. KÖNIG] Good, you're packed.
Do you even know how to drive?
Where is everybody?
They're at the hospital
with Dr. Bonomo.
Alma had a very strong seizure.
It's your fault, Gretchen.
You know that.
You terrified her.
I want you now to write
a farewell note.
Then we will pick up
some money for you at my house
and I'll drive you to the station.
The last train leaves in one hour.
Bring your bike.
You like it?
Sure.
You know it? A common cuckoo.
A magnificent creature.
Common.
Ah. But its behavior is not.
Its nature is quite remarkable.
A nature modern man
destroys by disregard.
Some species need our help
to survive and reproduce.
I'm a preservationist, you know?
[CLOCK TICKS FAINTLY]
[MR. KÖNIG]
Oh, come along now.
I want you to understand
who you got involved with.
Herr Lando here
was trespassing on my property
with an illegal firearm.
[GRETCHEN] What are you doing?
He's a cop.
No, he's not.
Not anymore.
You see, Erik here...
he's actually a policeman.
He has access to police files.
Herr Lando was recently discharged
when they found out
he was investigating a case,
one that he is personally involved with.
Okay, Erik. I think it's time
to take Herr Lando to the police station.
Gretchen, let's get your money.
This way, please.
Come along, now.
[EERIE AMBIANCE]
[GRETCHEN COUGHS VIOLENTLY]
[MR. KÖNIG PLAYS THE RECORDER]
[MR. KÖNIG, ON SPEAKER] You are a
liability, Gretchen. I can't let you out.
What the fuck did you spray me with?
Just pheromones.
I am giving you the chance
to be of great use
in our quest for preservation.
The adolescent needs to be trained.
Consider yourself lucky.
[GRETCHEN SCREAMS]
[DR. BONOMO] It's a mild sedative.
[BETH] What?
It'll make Alma sleep through the night.
I'm staying here tonight.
[LOUD SCREECH, THUD]
[MR. KÖNIG, ON SPEAKER]
These creatures can't speak like you or I.
But when trained,
their song can be dizzyingly persuasive.
[THROBBING, SQUAWKING]
[RUMBLING]
[GIRL SCREECHES]
[THROBBING, RUMBLING]
[SCREECHING AND THROBBING]
[MUFFLED THUD, RINGING]
[SCREECHING, THROBBING]
[GIRL HISSES]
[MR. KÖNIG, IN GERMAN]
No, no! Stay focused!
[SCREECHING]
[THROBBING AND RUBBING]
[GIRL PANTS AND MOANS]
[IN GERMAN]
That's enough for today.
Come here.
[SCREECHES]
Ah, ah, ah.
[MACHINES BEEPING]
[WHISPERING] Something is not right.
[BETH SOBS]
[IN GERMAN] It is always something of a
confirmation of my dreams
and good
intentions.
Gretchen, your parents need to hurry up
with those construction plans.
This one needs her own
mating grounds soon, no?
And you know what else
she needs, Erik?
What happened to Herr Lando's wife
must not repeat itself.
I'm very sorry for what happened
to your wife, Herr Lando.
But this one's mother
wandered off my area of authority.
She got nervous
when this one left the nest
before we had another offspring
ready to replace her.
There were family matters
prolonging my endeavor.
Actually...
Are you aware that
you have had the good fortune
to witness three laying ceremonies
as of now?
Wow.
Most people don't get
to attend a single one.
And those that do
don't remember that they did.
A sacred process that keeps
an ancient creature alive and well.
A magnificent creature
whose approach to family
is beyond human comprehension.
Which brings me back to you, Erik.
You will get Beatrix ready to conceive.
Consider your mishap last night
a dry run.
[MUFFLED GUNSHOTS]
Erik?
[IN GERMAN]
I told him, not in the house.
[GUNSHOT]
Shh...
Oh.
[IN GERMAN] Stay here.
No, no, no, no.
You should be on your side.
You could choke, my dear.
Nein!
[GIRL WHIMPERS]
[LUIS] Honey?
Honey, what's wrong?
I don't feel so good.
[DR. BONOMO] Take this.
[DR. BONOMO, IN GERMAN]
Everything's fine.
[IN GERMAN]
[HENRY] I think they
impregnate women at the resort.
After my mom died,
I accidentally called our house...
and I heard her voice
on the answering machine.
It kind of helped,
so I kept calling.
Maybe you can do that too.
[CUCKOO CLOCK RINGS]
Do you know what this bird is famous for?
This bird lays its eggs
in the nests of other bird species
and then lets those birds
raise its offspring.
No! Not in here!
[GRETCHEN CHOKES AND COUGHS]
[GRETCHEN COUGHS]
[TENSE MUSIC]
Your parents spent their honeymoon here?
How old is your sister?
[PHONE VIBRATES]
Gretchen?
Yes, I am fine.
We are in the treatment center
by the hospital.
If you come back in the morning,
Alma won't even know you were gone.
[LUIS] Alma is going to
stay here for the evening.
Dr. Bonomo is going to monitor her sleep.
[GRETCHEN] Dad?
Beth and I are coming home.
Dad, I really need
to talk to you about...
What is it, Gretchen?
We can't trust them.
Gretchen, we can talk
when we're home.
[HENRY] I told you I will protect you.
Get ready.
What's wrong with Beth?
[DR. BONOMO]
Dr. Bonomo, June 21st.
This is homo-cuculidae, Alma.
Astonishing resemblance
to her surrogate mother, Beth.
The surrogate mother's distress
grows in close proximity
to the biological mother.
Thus both host parents
have been removed from the premises.
Compared to animal brood parasites,
homo-cuculidae developed
a unique evolutionary trait.
Instead of leaving their offspring
in the care of a host,
homo-cuculidae returns
to claim their young.
Contact with the biological mother
speeds up the process
of the offspring's physical development
and its abilities significantly.
We are about to initiate
the first close-distance encounter
with the biological mother.
[MACHINES BEEPING]
Brood parasites.
They don't impregnate.
They implant eggs.
My wife and I tried to get pregnant.
I was supposed to fertilize that egg.
Like your father...
on his honeymoon.
[GRETCHEN]
And then what do they do?
Release them into the wild.
When the mother shows up...
I end this experiment.
What about my sister?
That is not your sister.
[MR. KÖNIG] Two.
Yeah, the sister of the young woman
and a rogue police detective.
Yeah, I am afraid we must commence
definitive measures immediately.
She's dead.
The feather I wrote my name with.
The plumage of the apportioners.
[IN GERMAN]
We're in the middle of an experiment.
What happened? You're bleeding.
[IN GERMAN] - The recordings you made
behind my back...
Are they still under the staircase
at your house?
Yah.
[IN GERMAN]
I'm sorry, Danielle.
[GUNSHOTS, WOMAN'S SCREAM]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
No! No!
[HENRY] I'm not going to hurt you.
[KNIFE CLATTERS]
[HENRY MOANS IN PAIN]
[HENRY WHEEZES]
Alma. Alma?
Alma, we have to go.
We have to go now.
[TENSE MUSIC]
Just stay right here.
[SCREECHING]
[SCREECHING, THROBBING]
[OOZING]
[KNIFE CLATTERS]
[SCREECHING STOPS]
Cover your ears and stay close to me.
[HEARTBEATS]
[SCREECHING]
[SCREECHING FADES OUT]
Alma?
[MUFFLED GROWL]
[GROWLING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[THUD]
[HOODED WOMAN WHIMPERS]
[SCREECHING,
PULSATING THROBBING]
[MUFFLED SCREECHING]
[COPYING MACHINE WHIRS]
[TAPE CLICKS]
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYS ON EARPHONES]
[LIGHT SWITCH CLICKS]
[MUSIC GETS LOUDER]
[HENRY GROWLS]
[MUSIC CONTINUES,
DROWNS OUT ALL SOUND]
[MUSIC CUTS ABRUPTLY]
[GRETCHEN GASPS]
[GRETCHEN CRIES OUT IN PAIN]
[THROBBING]
[SCREECHING CONTINUES]
[WOMAN SCREECHES AND HISSES]
[STABBING SOUND]
[WOMAN WHIMPERS]
[GARGLING]
[WOMAN WHIMPERS SOFTLY]
[GUNSHOTS ECHO]
Herr König!
She's dead!
Mom is dead!
[MR. KÖNIG, SNICKERING]
Where's your machine gun, my dear?
Is it under your cast, huh?
Why me?
It's not about you,
you little brat.
This is nature.
She is supposed to be focusing...
on reproduction and breeding.
And you are competing
for resources with her offspring.
Our process here ensures
that each new generation we breed
is more powerful than the last.
And my dear,
when I am done with you
and reunite Alma with...
[EMPTY MAGAZINE HITS THE GROUND]
[DISTANT SCREAMS AND GUNFIRE]
[RIFLE COCKS]
I'm sorry.
[SIGN LANGUAGE]
I would never hurt you.
[MR. KÖNIG]
Stay away from her, Alma.
[SIGN LANGUAGE]
We have to leave now.
My mom called.
[SIGN LANGUAGE]
She got your message.
Will she come to visit?
No.
S-She... can't.
But she says thank you.
Thank you, Alma.
[SOFT, SOMBER MUSIC]
[BOTH GIRLS SNIFFLE]
Thank you, Alma.
I really need your help.
[GRETCHEN] Henry!
You said you'll protect me.
I stand by it.
Did you ever tell your wife
you'd protect her?
What?
Did you tell her
you'd protect her?
Did you?
[CRYING]
- Yes!
Okay, we are coming out now.
[TENSE MUSIC]
[MR. KÖNIG] Alma!
I need you to come
to me now, my angel.
[HENRY, DISTRESSED] What are you doing?
She's one of them!
[MR. KÖNIG] Alma!
[GRETCHEN] I don't think so.
[MR. KÖNIG] Come to me.
[HENRY] She will be.
[HENRY] She will become!
[GRETCHEN] I don't think so.
[MR. KÖNIG] Alma!
[HENRY] We need to find out
how many there are.
[GRETCHEN] I need to take my sister
away from this place.
[HENRY] Stop!
[MR. KÖNIG] Let her go.
[MR. KÖNIG] Let her go,
she's destined to become a mother.
[HENRY] She is not your sister!
[MR. KÖNIG]
They stopped reproducing before.
They will go extinct without preservation.
[HENRY] Oh, they will go extinct.
[MR. KÖNIG]
Hundreds of years of research.
This is the will of the apportioners.
[MUFFLED] Let her go.
[MUFFLED] You don't know
what you're doing!
[THROBBING]
[ALMA SCREECHES,
RISING IN INTENSITY]
[DISTORTED SCREAMS]
[SCREECHING FADES OUT]
[SIMULTANEOUS GUNSHOTS RING]
[GRETCHEN BANGS AGAINST DOOR]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[CAR HUMS]
[SOFT ROCK MUSIC]