When I first hear
the word "jaws",
you know, I just think
of a period in my life
when I was much younger
than I am right now.
And I think, because I was younger,
I was more courageous, or I was
more stupid. I'm not sure which.
So, when I think of Jaws,
I think about courage and stupidity.
And I think of both of those
things existing underwater.
I had been thinking for years
about a story about a shark
that attacks people,
and what would happen if it
came in and wouldn't go away.
I hadn't done anything with it really.
Then, in 1964,
I read a story about a shark
fisherman off Long Island
who caught a 4,550-pound great white shark
off the beaches of Long Island.
I thought, "Wow! What would happen if one of
these things came in and wouldn't go away?"
Again, I didn't do anything
about it until 1970 or '71,
when a publisher finally said,
"That's an interesting story.
"I'll pay you a couple of
dollars if you'll put it on paper."
So that's how the idea began.
One of the many accidents that
happened with Jaws was the title.
We had no idea of the title.
I had thought for months about titles.
I probably had a hundred.
Some of them were pretentious:
The Stillness in the Water.
A Silence in the Deep.
Leviathan Rising.
A lot of them were Françoise Sagan titles.
You know, terribly
pretentious and very personal.
There were The Jaws of Death
and The Jaws of Leviathan.
They all sounded dramatic or
melodramatic or weird or pretentious.
We came up to 20 minutes
before production.
My editor and I were
lunching at a restaurant
called The Dallas Cowboy in New York.
I said to him, "Look."
This was Tom Condon.
"We cannot agree on a word that we like,
"let alone a title that we like.
"In fact, the only word that we even
think means or says anything is 'jaws.'
"Call the book Jaws".
He said, "What does it
mean?" I said, "I don't know.
"But it's short, it fits on a jacket,
"and it may work."
He said, "Okay, we'll
call the thing Jaws."
At first, nobody knew what they had here,
including myself.
It was a first novel.
It was a first novel about a fish,
and it had no great prospects.
But Tom Condon, the editor at Doubleday,
sensed that there was more here
than just a first novel about a fish.
So it was sent out
to the Book-of-the-Month Club
and The Literary Guild
and Bantam and other paperback houses.
The first response was
from the Book-of-the-Month Club,
which made it an "A" book, meaning
it is selected for a main selection
or it is in the running
for a main selection.
Suddenly people began to think,
whoops, we may have something more here
than just a first novel,
which nobody will read,
and a first novel about a
fish, which who cares less.
Then the Reader's Digest
selected it as a selection
and the Book-of-the-Month Club
made it an "A" book, main selection.
Then Bantam bought it for what
was then an enormous sum of money,
$575,000.
Then it went out to the movie auctions.
And, in those days, we're
now talking many years ago,
it went to Zanuck and Brown
at Universal for $150,000.
Which was, to me, the moon.
I had no money at all.
I had, in the bank, $300.
Both Dick Zanuck and I
saw or heard about the book
at identical times.
I heard about it from a small
card in the fiction department
of Cosmopolitan, edited by my wife,
Helen Gurley Brown,
which gave a brief description of the
plot of this novel by Peter Benchley,
and then said, "Might make a good movie."
We both read it overnight,
got on the phone with each
other the next morning and said,
"We don't know how we can possibly do it."
But we decided we must
have this, whatever it takes.
This is the most exciting
thing we've ever read,
and we'll figure out later
how we can make it.
Had we read it twice, in my opinion,
we never would have made Jaws.
Because anybody with a
modicum of production knowledge
would know there was no way to get a man…
Get a shark
to leap on the stern of a
small boat and swallow a man.
How were we going to do this?
Were we going to do it in animation?
Who was going to do this?
We never thought about it.
We just loved the book.
We thought it would make
a very good movie.
The deal was subject to a meeting
with Mr. Benchley.
Who we'd never met before, actually.
And the agency also very much wanted us
to tie a director of theirs,
one of their clients,
into this whole package.
So we had agreed to… I'm not
going to mention this person's name
because this is not a flattering story.
But we had agreed, in our anxiety,
to secure the rights to the book
to put on this person as a director.
There was a director, and I
really don't remember who it was,
who kept saying, "I've always
wanted to make a movie about a whale."
At the end of it, Zanuck
said, "That's the end of that."
When the director who
was going to direct a whale
was vanquished from our sight…
And here was Steven
Spielberg. Director, filmmaker…
Sugar/and Express,
right within sight of us.
Steven actually… And there
are many versions of this.
Steven will tell you his,
probably the true one.
I just remember seeing a very
large, you know, block of pages
that said Jaws on it, and I
didn't know what that meant.
What was Jaws?
Was it about a dentist?
Was this, you know, was it…
Because Jaws did not have a…
It was not in the national
consciousness at the time.
It was just a word. It was
kind of an unusual word.
I remember borrowing a
copy to read over the weekend
and discovering I was
completely uninformed,
not knowing that it was a
book about a great white shark.
A predator off a beach
in a kind of, you know,
Cape Cod-esque town.
I had no idea this was about to become
one of the best-selling
books in the nation.
I read it, and I said to myself, "Wow,
"this is just like a movie I just made
"about a truck and a hapless driver,
"called Duel."
Of course I'm young and
I'm stupid and I'm saying,
"Duel. Gee, that has four words…
"Duel has four letters
and Jaws has four letters,
"and they're both about these leviathans
"Preying upon everyman."
I saw such a comparison between Duel,
which I had done previous to
Sugar land Express, and Jaws,
I said to myself, "This is kind of the
sequel to Duel, only it's on the water."
I got very interested in it because,
coincidentally, the producers of Jaws
had just been my producers on
my first feature, Sugar/and Express,
Dick Zanuck and David Brown.
I asked them if this was
something I could direct next.
The first thing Dick Zanuck
and David Brown said to me is,
"We want to get rid of the back stories.
"We want to make this
an A-Z adventure story.
"We do not want to have
any of that involvement
"with a romance between
Hooper and Mrs. Brody.
"We don't want to talk about the
Mafia or about anything like that.
"We want to make this a
straight-line adventure story."
Peter Benchley did a very
good adaptation of his own novel.
Then Peter kind of turned
it over to me and said,
"Here it is.
Do with it what you want."
At that point, I didn't quite
know what to do with it,
'cause it wasn't the movie
I wanted to make next.
I quite didn't know the movie I
wanted to make from the novel Jaws.
I knew about the third act,
and I knew about the first act.
I just didn't know about the second
act, which was going to be a 60-page act.
I remember sitting down
and writing the script myself.
Doing an entire draft
myself, from beginning to end.
Which I haven't shown to very many people.
And I don't even think I have it anymore.
But I remember a few
of the scenes did survive
the movie, and wound up in the film.
But it was more of an exercise for me
to become familiar with what
I wanted Jaws to become.
It was an exercise
that was very beneficial
because I suddenly
had a vision of the film
even though I didn't
possess the skills to write it.
David Brown and Dick Zanuck both suggested
that I go to Howard Sackler,
who had written The Great White Hope.
We went from Peter Benchley to a
writer by the name of Howard Sackler.
Who was a Pulitzer
Prize-winning playwright
who wrote The Great White Hope.
He had been working
on something else for us.
He also was an expert scuba diver,
and scuba dived all around the world.
Was very familiar, as is
Benchley, by the way…
Great diver.
Very familiar with sharks
and underwater activity.
Howard Sackler specifically
asked not to have credit.
He only had a limited time
to give to the film.
Therefore, he said, "I don't want credit."
But he was, I think…
Spielberg would say he was very important
in that terrible phrase
of motion picture-making:
He "broke the back of the story."
Sackler broke the back of
the movie and got me to say,
"Yes, I'll make this movie
next. I'm committing."
Then came something
that's not been recorded
in the history of Jaws.
The Screen Actors Guild contract
was about to expire at
the end of June of that year.
It could have been 1973,
perhaps, whenever the year was.
The studio decreed that
no movie would be started
that could not be finished
by June 30 of that year,
because they didn't want to be struck.
That is, that photography was completed.
Steven Spielberg, Richard Zanuck
and I met at the Bel-Air Hotel.
And Steven said,
"I don't have a script yet.
"You're asking me to
start this movie in April?"
Whenever it was, I don't
know, maybe this was February.
He said, "I don't have a script."
And I said, "Who can we get?"
He said, "There's a man
named Carl Gottlieb.
"I'm thinking about him for the movie.“
I was hired first as an actor because,
if I was going to be on
the set, I could at least help
in the improvisations and crowd scenes
and finding stuff to do in the moment,
which had been my job on stage
at the Committee as an improviser.
Steven thought that
would be useful to the film
to be able to go with the flow
and find things on the set and improvise.
In fact, some of the best lines in
the film are improvised by the actors
based on their characters in the script.
I asked Carl Gottlieb, who was a
friend of mine, to come in to do a polish
and to actually help me…
If I wanted to improvise scenes,
Carl would be there to help organize
the improvisation and put it on paper.
I said that we have a
chance to make a movie
that's going to do for the ocean
what the shower scene did to Psycho,
in terms of affecting a generation
with, kind of, a fear of the water.
To this day, when people
come up to me and learn
that I worked on the screenplay
of Jaws, and talk to me about it,
inevitably, the first thing they say is,
"That summer I didn't go swimming."
Or "I've been afraid of the
water ever since that movie."
Or "I'm always thinking of
sharks when I go swimming.
"In Hawaii, I don't go swimming
at all." I hear that to this day.
So, surprisingly enough,
that was my first reaction
to the script and the story.
It's the thing that appears
to have carried through,
and is one of the overwhelming
impressions that we made.
It's, you know, become popular culture.
When you do a straight-line
adventure film like Jaws,
anything that doesn't contribute
to the suspense or the humanity
or the horror, has to go.
I wanted to introduce
Quint, not in his boat,
laughing at all the yahoos on shore,
in that one little visual
where the Orca goes by
with Quint laughing and chuckling
at the tiger shark that
obviously isn't the predator
that's been killing all
the people in the vicinity.
I had another thing that
I'd written in my script.
As you recall, I wrote
an entire script of Jaws
after Benchley and before Sackler.
And this was one of the
scenes that I had written.
That Robert Shaw, or Quint, is in a
movie theater watching Moby Dick
on the island of Amity
at the local movie house.
He's laughing all the way
through it. He can't stop laughing.
It's so silly, the mechanical white
whale, Ahab with his big harpoon,
stabbing the whale as
he's lashed to the belly,
and the whale sounding and
coming up again, and he's still…
This mechanical figure is still sticking
the mechanical harpoon in the whale.
I just had Quint laughing hysterically.
Laughing so hard
and so sort of maliciously
that people get up and start
leaving the theater until he's all alone,
and his laughter can be
heard right down the street.
That was in my script.
But in trying to get the rights to Moby
Dick, which Gregory Peck controlled,
Greg wasn't opposed
to the use of that scene that way in Jaws.
He just claimed that he wasn't
really proud of Moby Dick.
It was not the proudest
moment in his body of work,
and just didn't really want
us to either make fun of it
or just include it at all in the movie.
So we could never get
the rights to use Moby Dick.
It's part of the film making process.
You write stuff you think you want to see.
Then you sit down and analyze
it, for all kinds of reasons,
for dramatic reasons,
it's hard to fit them in.
Or for production reasons, or
sometimes they're redundant.
For example, the guys on the
pier, one of them losing his leg.
Well, we have a guy losing
his leg elsewhere in the film.
So, it was, you know,
one lost leg too many.
It would have given
the shark a matched set.
For us, it was not as useful to the
plot. It would have been repetitive.
I had this idea that
there's a harbormaster,
and he's in his little shack.
There's all these sailboats.
It's night.
There's about 20 sailboats
with just their masts sticking up.
The harbormaster in my script,
he's watching a movie with Glenn Ford
called Don't Go Near the Water,
which I thought film
aficionados would get off on.
They'd say, "Clever. He's
watching Don't Go Near the Water."
Meanwhile, in the back you
notice, as he's watching this movie,
one mast starts to go like this.
Then the ship next to it,
that mast goes like this.
Then the third mast goes
like this, and the fourth mast…
Until all of a sudden you see,
in sequential order,
something is traveling beneath
the keels of all these sailboats,
and all the masts are moving,
getting closer to the harbormaster.
As the harbormaster goes down to
clean out his coffeepot in the harbor.
As he gets down there
to clean out his coffeepot,
he, of course, is taken by the shark.
That was a scene that
was in my original script
that we just basically
couldn't afford to shoot.
In its place, I wrote this other scene,
which was also in my original script,
that slid over to this one,
which is the pier.
The two fishermen who
take the Sunday pot roast
and a huge chain and a large
Texas Chainsaw Massacre-style hook,
and toss it into the current
and the tide takes it out.
Of course, the shark takes the
bait and the pier comes right off.
The guy comes off the pier.
The reason I wanted the scene
in the movie was for one shot.
Not seeing the shark was important
to me because it was scarier.
In my opinion, seeing the pier
going off, stopping and turning,
and the pier itself coming
back for the swimmer…
Charlie, take my word
for it, don't look back!
Swim, Charlie!
I've heard that Steven wanted to have
the old couple from Sugar/and Express,
whose car was stolen,
turn up in their car in Amity.
What's the story?
The missus and I just had
our car taken by an ex-con.
Claimed he was a workingman.
Was it a green Buick?
Seafoam green, 1956.
Road master, B-O-W-44.
Stole!
- You Alvin T. Nocker of New Frankfort?
- Oh, yes, sir.
Now you're talking.
Yes, sir.
You just stay put.
I wanted them to be passing through Amity.
Maybe even going to the beach
and spreading out a picnic blanket.
Even fantasizing and saying…
Perhaps Mr. Nocker blows up an inner tube,
and we get the idea that maybe
he'll go out in the water with his wife.
I thought, "This movie's too hard to make.
"I've got to stop making
it harder on myself."
We thought that
to legitimize the movie,
there should be
some real shark footage in the picture.
We had anticipated having
much more in the picture
than actually ended up being in it.
So we sent a second unit
down to Australia.
Ron and Valerie Taylor were
engaged in order to shoot
real shark footage off of Australia.
Which they were well experienced at doing.
My recollection is they were
involved with Peter Gimbel.
I may be wrong about that.
Blue Water, White Death.
Blue Water, White Death was and is
the finest documentary
ever made on sharks.
It was done by Peter Gimbel
with Ron and Valerie Taylor
and Stan Waterman.
They went with Rodney Fox
down south in Australia,
and they found the great white shark,
and they did a documentary that
stands alone 20-some years later
as the pinnacle of shark documentaries,
no matter what else has been done.
The producers asked Peter Gimbel
if he would do the camera work on Jaws,
and Peter said, "No, I won't do the
camera work, but I'll direct for you."
We said, "But, Peter, you've only
directed sharks in a documentary.
"We're going to have actors."
He said, "I don't care.
I want to direct."
So Peter Gimbel never got
to be associated with Jaws.
We joked about it many times.
Peter said, "Sorry, I can't
work on the production for you,
"but there are a couple in
Australia, Ron and Valerie Taylor,
"who have experience
with the great white shark.
"Why don't you contact them?"
Sure enough, Universal
Pictures contacted Valerie and I.
I said, "Yes, I think we can
do the underwater shooting
"of live sharks in South Australia."
So they flew me to America,
and I spoke with Steven
Spielberg and Joe Alves,
and met the production team over there,
and explained what I thought we could do
with the real, live great white sharks.
But I explained that our sharks
were only about 14 feet long,
whereas Jaws was about 26 feet long.
I had this idea of doing a miniature cage
and putting a little person into a midget…
Into a miniature cage.
And taking the little person…
That would have effectively
scaled the shark up
and added another, you know, nine feet
to the overall length of the shark.
That kind of made sense to me.
But I was looking for a little person
who was in scale with the cage
and was interviewing
a number of little people.
I remember this tenacious gentleman
who came in to see me, bleeding.
I said, "Why are you bleeding?"
He said, "I was afraid I was going
to be late. I really want this job.
"I got into a traffic accident in
front of the main gate at Universal."
I said, "You did?" He said, "I
came here to have the meeting."
I said, "Did you leave
the scene of the accident?
"You're not supposed to."
We sent him back to the accident
to fill out the report with the police.
I remember I was thinking,
"What a brave man."
And, "He really wants this job."
And I was…
I was young and courageous
and stupid, and I hired him.
His name was Carl Rizzo.
Hollywood sent us this little
man, and he couldn't dive.
He had spent most
of his life riding horses,
doubling for children in
films like National Velvet.
He'd doubled for Elizabeth Taylor.
We had to take him out
and stuff him into a cage
and dangle him into
the cold, southern ocean,
and have big, huge, monstrous
sharks swimming around him.
He was very much afraid,
and we had a lot of difficulty
getting him into the cage, which
is probably quite understandable.
We did have two dummies,
because we were supposed
to have somebody in the cage
when the shark broke it up.
But we had Carl, and he was much better.
He looked better in the
cage, and moved around a bit.
We'd been working for about a week,
and we still hadn't got the shots
of the shark attacking the cage.
They don't normally do that.
They'd rather attack a bait.
There were three sharks
in the area at the time,
and two of them were fairly timid,
but one of them came in
and he was a big, strong shark,
and he swam around.
We had the small cage, the
half-size cage, hanging on a bridle
attached to a winch
on the deck of the skippy.
He swam over it and got
his nose caught in the bridle
and tried to swim forward
and became trapped.
When a white shark is trapped,
it goes crazy, and
that's exactly what he did.
Ron was filming underwater,
and actually, that's how we
got that footage, and they used it.
They wanted someone
in the cage at the time,
but there was nobody in the cage.
So they changed the script
to suit that sequence
because it was so dramatic.
It looked like the
shark was destroying the cage,
and, in fact, it did.
It did a lot of damage to the cage.
It broke it away from the small boat,
and the whole lot came
tumbling down past me
and crashed down onto the bottom.
That was the scariest thing, I
think, I've ever seen underwater
because the whole lot was crashing.
I could see the shark and the cage
all crashing around down on the bottom,
and I thought we were
going to lose the cage.
Of course, it had been
broken away from the boat.
The shark got out and swam away,
but there were two other
sharks still in the area.
And there was no way that
I could swim out of my cage
and attach a rope.
So what we did, we lowered
my cage down onto the bottom,
and I put my feet through
the bottom of my cage,
and picked my cage up, almost
like a lady pulls her skirt up,
and walked the cage and myself
over the bottom about 50 feet
to the other broken cage,
which was lying on the bottom,
tied it to my cage,
and then I signaled for them to
pull us both back to the surface.
Then why don't we have one more drink
and go down and cut that shark open?
Martin?
Can you do that?
I can do anything.
I'm the Chief of Police.
Roy Scheider was interesting,
the story of how I cast him.
Because here's a situation where
I was going after other actors.
I went after a whole series of actors
before him, a lot of them unknowns.
People that no one had
ever heard of before,
but I was familiar with,
from seeing Serpico.
There was an actor in Serpico
I kind of liked,
and another actor on an
off-Broadway play I had just seen.
But the studio and Zanuck and Brown
were urging me to get a name in this part.
I was having trouble
finding a name that I liked,
and who would do it.
I remember I was at a party one night…
And my agent brought me over
to be introduced to him.
He was having a conversation with
a writer named Tracy Keenan Wynn.
As I approached,
I heard a conversation that
went something like this…
"We're going to have to have this
giant shark come out of the water
"and land on a boat
and crack the boat in half."
And then I was introduced
to him and he said hello.
He was very polite, nice, pleasant.
Then, as I was walking away, they
picked up this conversation again.
I remember saying to my
agent as we walked away,
"Those guys, they gotta be kidding.
"A giant shark that cracks a boat
in half?" I thought they were loony.
I told him the entire story.
At the end of the story he said,
"Wow, that's a great story.
What about me?"
I looked at Roy and I said, "Yeah,
you know, you'd be a great Chief Brody."
'Cause I had loved Roy from
The French Connection,
where he played Gene Hackman's partner.
And that's how that came about.
Could you tell me how I
could find Chief Brody?
Who are you?
Matt Hooper. I'm from
the Oceanographic Institute.
Richard Dreyfuss wasn't
my first choice either.
I went to Jon Voight first,
and he said no.
I think I'd interviewed Timothy Bottoms.
I interviewed a number of actors.
Perhaps Jeff Bridges.
I was a big fan of the entire
cast from Last Picture Show.
I remember saying if I could
just get every member of the cast
to say no to me to play
the Hooper character,
at least I will have gone to one
of my favorite movies of all time,
to have gone out after that group.
So I think Bridges and Bottoms,
and I think we got turned down,
or there were unavailability problems.
In the movies these things happen.
People want to do it and they can't
because they're booked
into something else.
I remember Dreyfuss…
I cast Dreyfuss because
I loved American Graffiti,
and I had seen him in that.
And George Lucas was
the person who said to me,
"Why don't you cast Ricky
Dreyfuss? He'd be great."
He told me this movie
that he wanted to make,
and it was really a shocker.
Even as he was telling it to me as a tale,
it was a great, exciting story.
These three guys alone on the boat,
and the shark attacking the boat and…
At the end he said, "You
want to make this film?"
And I said, “No."
And he said, "Why not?"
And I said, "This sounds like
it's going to be a great movie.
"I'd rather watch this movie than shoot it
"because it's going to be
a bitch to shoot."
And I said… And he was surprised.
I said, "I just wouldn't do well under
these circumstances," so I said no.
Then a few months later, I went to see
the opening of a film I'd done in Canada.
It was the premiere of a film called
The Apprenticeship of Duddy Kravitz.
And I saw myself,
really for the first time
in the lead in a movie,
with my face 15 feet high,
on screen for 90 minutes,
and I had a heart attack.
I had a total nervous
collapse. I thought I was awful.
I figured that I'd better
get a job really soon.
So I called Steven.
I said, "If you still want to
offer me that job, I'll take it."
And he said yes.
So, in essence,
I came crawling to Martha's
Vineyard for the part.
I don't want no volunteers.
I don't want no mates.
There's too many captains on this island.
$10,000 for me, by myself.
For that you get the head,
the tail, the whole damn thing.
My first choice to play Quint
was Lee Marvin.
I wanted to go for
Lee Marvin to play Quint,
but Lee Marvin wasn't interested.
I think what I heard was, he
wanted to go fishing for real.
He took his fishing seriously,
and didn't want to go fishing
from a movie boat with cameras.
That wasn't his idea of a vacation.
It turned out not to be anybody's
idea of a vacation, making Jaws.
My second choice was Sterling Hayden,
who I thought would make an amazing Quint.
He had an Ahab quality about him,
and he had actually clone a movie
years ago, where he played a whaler
with a harpoon that he
carried around with him.
A very imposing character.
I was a big fan of his,
certainly from Dr. Strange love
and, you know, the
two Kubrick films he did.
And, as it turned out,
he couldn't do it either.
I forgot actually what the
reason was he couldn't do it.
And there were other actors
who wanted to play Quint,
and then Dick Zanuck and David
Brown suggested Robert Shaw.
It was their idea, because they had just
worked with Robert Shaw in The Sting,
which they produced, and loved him.
I'd screened two movies I'd already
seen of Shaw's, just to refresh my memory.
One oi them, of course,
was A Man for All Seasons.
He was spectacular in that.
Based on that and, of course,
From Russia with Love…
That great fight scene
where he played the
nemesis of 007 in the train.
I said, "Wow, I wish I had
thought of it. It's a great idea.“
So he, fortunately, said yes.
Robert was one of the most
powerful people I've ever met.
Incredibly intense.
I mean, it was something
that radiated out of him.
He was a remarkably
gifted actor and writer.
He was also, unfortunately,
the most extraordinarily
competitive person.
Unnecessarily competitive.
I think that probably, if anything,
that was his flaw.
You got city hands,
Mr. Hooper.
You been counting money all your life.
All right, all right.
Hey, I don't need this.
I don't need this working-class-hero crap.
You're not going to do this
aboard the ship are you, Mr. Quint?
Michael, did you hear your
father? Out of the water now!
Now!
The first person I cast for the
movie, in fact, was Lorraine,
who I'd loved in a TV
movie I'd seen her do
called The Marcus-Nelson Murders,
starring Telly Savalas and herself,
I believe, as Telly's in that.
I thought she was a very natural actress,
almost improvisational in her style.
She brought a realism to the movie,
and to that family, which I had wanted.
Ellen is very clear to me
and always has been.
You say Roy Scheider in his character
feels guilt because of the children.
I'm a mother, I'm a wife, and I'm Jewish.
What could be clearer to me than
how to make somebody feel guilty?
This is something that I do in
my sleep. It's what I've trained for.
And I have two sons,
just like Ellen Brody.
The suggestion that I made
to Steven at the time was
to try to develop the script,
so it had the same kind of
linear simplicity that Duel had.
I thought that was
a reasonably good prototype
to follow.
And I remember some time later,
my wife was upset with me…
I put upset in quotes.
Because a lot of the stuff that
we took out had to do with affairs
that this particular character,
as I recalled, had in the book.
Of course I was upset about it,
but I was very happy to be cast.
Martin, it's all psychological.
You yell, "Barracuda!" and
everybody says, "Huh? What?"
You yell, "Shark!"…
we've got a panic on our
hands on the Fourth of July.
Murray Hamilton I've been a fan of,
from The FBI Story with James Stewart
to The Graduate and that great
scene, you know, with Dustin Hoffman,
where he tells Dustin to go
off and sow some wild oats.
I just always wanted to work with him.
I was a big fan of his, and saw
him instantly as the mayor of Amity.
So, I didn't have to
go through nine actors.
He was the first choice for that part,
and I was lucky enough to get him.
I have to talk
to Mrs. Kintner.
Because this is turning into a contest.
It's not just the Gazette. She's
advertising in out-of-town papers.
People all over New England
are going to know about it.
The most painful
thing I've ever done as a writer
is to take my part as an actor
and make it smaller and smaller,
until it was almost gone.
Even though I had good billing,
I didn't follow through on screen
with the amount of screen time
I would have liked as an actor.
But it was better for the script that
my character not be there so much.
Amity Island has long been
known for its clean air, clear water
and beautiful white-sand beaches.
But in recent days
a cloud has appeared on the horizon
of this beautiful resort community.
A cloud in the shape of a killer shark.
One of David Brown's geniuses was
to realize he could play upon the egos
of writers, actors and other people
who are not in the movie business
by convincing us that only
by our appearing in the film
could the film achieve its true greatness.
So he came to me and said
would I consider, possibly
as a favor to him, being in this movie?
Well, to a person who's done television
for four years to be in a feature film?
This was not exactly a request
that I found it difficult to accept.
So I said, "Sure!"
This was pure ego.
Why not be in a feature film?
It was no stretch for me.
It was no risk for him
because I was a television
interviewer professionally, anyway.
So I could do very little wrong.
He wasn't asking me
to play an emotional scene.
I was doing what I did for a
living, so it worked out very well.
If there was a secondary
purpose to his request,
and David is so wonderfully
gracious that you never know
whether he's just being nice to
you or there's something underneath,
it would have been that because
of the publicity surrounding the book
and surrounding the movie,
it couldn't hurt to have me
in the movie, in some category or other.
In Amity Island, this is Alan Cray.
I want to try that end again.
Okay?
And there you have it. Two different
opinions by two men of goodwill.
But here in Amity, it seems it's
the public that's making up its mind.
On Amity Island, this is Alan Cray.
All right, Murray, that'll do it.
Cut!
Save if!
When it came down to
where we would shoot this film,
we sent Joe Alves, our
production designer, out with a team
to give us some ideas and
some photographs and pictures of
where this town
should be shot, including Jamaica.
We thought of Jamaica primarily
because of the clarity of the water.
We could do underwater
work down there, do it all there.
And one of the places, obviously,
that they went, among others,
was the island of Martha's Vineyard.
Which, believe it or not,
had never been photographed
by a feature film before.
They had very strict rules
and regulations there,
and had always kept movie companies in.
So it really was a question
of talking them into letting,
at the height of their season,
letting a big movie company come in there.
Martha's Vineyard did present
the problem that this pristine place,
unchanged since the 18th century,
didn't particularly care
for a movie invasion.
They didn't like to see
an artificial shark
parked in a channel
where their homes faced it.
And the only set that we built,
which was Quint's shack,
we had to post a bond
with the town authorities
that everything would be
replaced exactly the way it was.
The billboard in the picture…
They put up a billboard
and some kids have come along
and made a prank out of it, painted it
with the shark and "Help" and so forth.
We had to put up that billboard
one morning, shoot the scene,
and take it down at the end of the day.
That was the only way we could shoot that.
There could be nothing done…
We could do nothing to alter the landscape
or the beautiful harmony
that existed on the island.
The real attraction of Martha's Vineyard,
you couldn't see with the naked eye.
It was the only place on the East Coast
where I could go 12 miles out to sea
and still have a sandy bottom only
30 feet below the surface of the water,
where we could put the shark sled
and the mechanical shark could function.
So Martha's Vineyard was chosen
less because it was a picturesque village.
I could've shot this movie in Sag Harbor
or Montauk or a number of places.
It was because of that sandy
bottom 12 miles offshore.
It was very important that no matter
what direction my cameras turned,
I didn't want to see land.
I felt…
My fear was, the minute the
audience saw land, they'd say,
"This is getting pretty intense out here.
"Just turn the boat around and go
toward that land that we keep seeing."
I wanted the audience
to feel very cut off,
like they couldn't run back to shore,
'cause there was no shore to run back to.
I was tipped off by somebody on the crew…
We were still here at the Universal lot.
That Steven was going to come in,
and he was really thinking
about withdrawing
'cause he was very concerned
about the way things were going.
The shark wasn't working.
It seemed hopeless.
The script was far from perfect.
And a few weeks before, he had
had some T-shirts made up
with a big shark on it saying "JAWS."
And so
knowing what he was
coming in to talk to me about,
I put on a T-shirt.
I put on this T-shirt and was sitting
behind my desk when he came in.
And just seeing me there, I think,
in front of the desk with this T-shirt…
And I was saying, "This is the greatest.
"We're going to kill them with this.
"It's great, and you're
going to be great for it."
It kind of lifted him back into it.
Steven is the most
enthusiastic man I've ever met,
and it brought back that enthusiasm.
What's your name again?
Chrissie.
Where are we going?
Swimming!
I started doing
stunt work, and I specialized in water.
A lot of times when the
water stunts would come up,
I got into doing the water stunts also.
Steven Spielberg was a
little bit leery having me
because I wasn't an actress per se.
After the first day of shooting…
We did the beach scene the
first day, the party scene at night.
We got along wonderful after that.
Whatever I did, he liked.
It was great. He was a
great person to work for.
Come on in the water!
I thought that what could really
be scary was not seeing the shark
and just seeing the water, because
we all are familiar with the water.
Very few of us have been
in the water with a shark,
but we've all gone swimming.
The idea of this girl going swimming,
and the audience going swimming with her
would have been too
extraordinary if, like a leviathan,
the shark had come out of the water
with its jaws agape, and come down on her.
It would have been a
spectacular opening for the film,
but there would have been
nothing primal about it.
It would just have been a
monster moment that we've all seen.
I really wanted to do it without
seeing the shark in that case.
I wanted the violent,
jerking motions to just
start to trigger our
imaginations into either
thinking about what's happening
below the surface of the waterline
or blocking what was
happening below the surface.
The first jerk down Steven did.
He had a cable that came
to the front of my stomach
and went to an anchor that was
laying on the bottom of the ocean.
Then he just sat, and
when he wanted that pulled,
he just would pull.
I could feel him pulling down,
and I'd just throw my head back even more.
They wanted to put me
on an electric winch,
and I prefer not to use an electric winch
because if any of the line
overrode and came to a stop,
I might not know it and I
might not be able to get out of it.
Being they're pulling me back and
forth in the water, I wanted more control.
So we used manpower.
They put cutoff Levis on and
had cables running from me,
out to the side to two pilings,
and then all the way in to the beach.
What they would do is, we put
marks on the beach and the guys,
we'd have five or six guys on each line,
and they would run back
and forth from mark to mark.
So I didn't have the hard work to do.
I just sat there and got pulled around.
The guys were running
back and forth on the beach.
And that's what made my body
move back and forth in the frame.
When I would feel my hips
getting pulled the opposite way,
I'd just throw my arms out of
water very violently the opposite way.
So, physically, I could make it
look more violent than what it was.
It hurts!
I went to a marine store
and bought a safety hook
that you'd use on a sail,
on the halyard of a sail.
I put it onto all the cables
that they hooked to me.
So that, any time during this scene,
if I got in trouble, if I got water,
if I got hurt, God knows what happen,
I could pull one of those strings,
and I was free and clear
and could come to the surface.
So it allowed me, if I got
in a spot, to free myself.
How would anybody know if I
was hurt or I needed anything?
I'm out there screaming like a fool.
Oh, my God!
In the scene where I
was pulled into the buoy,
Steven said, "Let's
have you say something.
"We'll have you say The Lord's Prayer.
"Don't the Catholics say
something if they're going to die?
"They say something they're
going to say in the confessional,
"asking God to forgive you
for all your sins."
Unfortunately, I hadn't been going
to church for the last few years,
and I could not remember it.
I swear there were eight Catholics on set,
and between the eight of us
we couldn't come up with it.
I felt very bad.
Oh, God, help!
Please help me!
We looped the film.
A lot of stuff we couldn't do
because of the noise made.
So you go into a looping studio.
The idea was, how are you going
to sound like you're in the water
sitting in a studio?
So we came up with the
idea of getting a baby bassinet
and filling it with water.
So I'm sitting on the sound stage,
with the film up on the screen,
on a stool with my little bassinet,
and Richard Dreyfuss came in.
I came to visit Steven or I
came to do my own looping.
I'm not really sure now.
It was so long ago.
I walked in and Steven had
this beautiful girl's blond head
reared back like this,
and he was pouring water
down her throat like this.
And telling her to scream
her bloody lungs out.
Which I thought was a rather
interesting way to spend the afternoon,
but not particularly comfortable for her.
But it does work for the movie.
The reason they were doing it
was to make the appropriate sound.
They couldn't do it any other way,
so he just poured that
water down her throat.
Oh, Jesus.
The problem was,
they brought the hand to me
and they said, "Here's
the dead girl's hand."
I said, "Wow, it looks like
shiny plastic. It looks fake."
They said, "After a
body's been decomposing
"for a day on the sand,
with the sun coming down,
"it takes on that look."
I said, "You might be clinically right,
"and a pathologist might look at that
"and admire that moment in Jaws,
"but to me, as an audience
member, it looks fake.
"It looks like plastic."
We tried putting powder on it
to get the reflective shine off.
We couldn't do that.
So I said, "Well, screw it."
I believe I turned to someone
and said, "Let me use your arm."
Kind of like we do when we're kids,
we bury our parents in the sand.
I kind of buried her in the sand,
and just had her hand sticking out.
We made up part of the arm,
so right up here,
it looked like it had been
bitten off, kind of a subtle way.
Then there were these sand crabs that
we collected and put all over the arm.
They were kind of lethargic
in their movements.
To this day, when I see Jaws,
I always have this different vision
of 10 times as many crabs
moving 10 times as fast,
trying to feed on the arm.
Later I was able to do that
in Temple Of Doom,
when I was able to get the bugs
to do what the crabs couldn't do
15 years earlier.
The death of the Kintner boy, and
all the paranoia, tension and suspense
leading up to the actual
attack when he's out on the raft,
I, in my mind, wanted to do in one shot.
In trying to figure out,
in a perfect world,
how could I have done that
in one sustained shot,
I came up with the idea
to have bathers with
different-colored bathing suits
walking in front of the camera
that would wipe off Roy Scheider.
The same color in the reverse,
moving in the other direction,
would wipe on what he's looking at.
Which, even though
it wouldn't be one shot,
would give more of a seamless feeling
and much more of a clear point of view
that you knew who was looking at who.
All this must be from the
police chief's point of view.
The scene's about him.
It's about his reaction.
It's not about the
Kintner boy being killed.
It's about the chief of
police, his fear of the water,
his chief responsibility
to protect the public,
his fear that there is a shark out there,
and he knows it's out there,
and these people
are going swimming anyway.
Did you see that?
Hello.
Hello back, young fellow.
How are you?
Craig Kings bury was a local
on Martha's Vineyard,
and he was quite a character.
He himself was a movie and a book.
Had I not gotten Robert Shaw
and had I met him in an open casting call,
I might have come close to flirting
with the idea of using him to play Quint.
Because he was the purest version
of who, in my mind, Quint really was.
When I met him, he came
up with this great dialogue.
I kept increasing his part.
Just by meeting him I said,
"I want you to be in my movie,
"and you can make up your own dialogue."
He made up the stuff when
he's in the boat and he says,
"You're gonna wish your
mothers never met your fathers
"when you start piling
into those reefs, boy."
Wait till we get them silly
bastards down in that rock pile.
There'll be some fun.
They'll wish their fathers
hadn't met their mothers
when they start digging the bottoms out
and slamming into them rocks, boy.
There's no shortage
of drunks on the island.
Craig Kings bury had the
distinction of being the only guy
who was driving under the
influence a team of oxen.
And was loaded and smashed
and driving these cows around.
Just in talking about fishing
and sharking and this and that,
Craig gave me some great lines.
One of the lines was,
"It's not like going out there to
catch bluegills or Tommy cods."
That's Craig's line.
I'll catch this bird for you.
It ain't going to
be easy. Bad fish.
Not like going down to the pond
and chasing bluegills or Tommy cods.
This shark, swallow you whole.
Craig Kings bury, because he played
Ben Gardner, got to have his head
life-cast for the mold
for the severed head
that appears in the film.
The thing that really has lasted
through the years with Steven and me
is a very private code.
At the dinner table scene,
I improvised something
about a Cousteau show I had seen.
And years later, 20 years later,
Sid and I were given an award
by the Wiesenthal Center,
and Steven was the one who
presented it on their behalf.
He talked about Sid and
all the things he's done,
and presented his whatever,
and then introduced me and told
about the things that I've been doing.
Then, as he turned to me, he said,
"Lorraine, remember the sea otter?"
Marker.
Did you ever see the television special,
the Cousteau special on sea otters?
Sea otters, where the mother
was killed in front of the baby.
The baby saw it with his eyes.
You could see the tears
coming down his face.
It was the most incredible thing
I have ever seen. It was terrible.
Mikey wanted us to
adopt the sea otter. It was…
I've never been this moved by
anything on television. It was really…
It was special.
So…
You're going on the Aurora. You're
going to live there 18 months. Wow.
It was disappointing to me
it wasn't in the movie.
Not as disappointing as not having
a sex scene with Richard Dreyfuss,
but it was disappointing.
Shark! A shark!
I was going to be a victim in the estuary.
I'm in a little rowboat.
The way they shot it the first time,
I'm in the shark's mouth
with a blood pack in my mouth.
I'm going on top of water,
underwater, spitting blood out,
and I'm trying to make a lot of movement,
but it was very awkward
the way this seat was.
I was trying to make a lot of
movement like I was in the shark's mouth.
Going underwater, top of water.
Then I see
Roy's son staring at me.
As a last-ditch effort, the shark
is heading right towards him.
I just make a move to
grab him, and I let him just…
I just touched him and let him go,
and then I go underwater and disappear.
What happened in that scene is,
it was so violent and so horrendous
that they couldn't use it. It
was just too violent, period.
I was in this bucket seat,
strapped into it,
and the shark fin was behind me on a sled.
I had the kid in my arms, and I
was gonna take him underwater.
Then I let him go, and
the sled went underwater.
Teddy Grossman is in
the jaws of the shark.
The shark's underwater.
And Teddy, like the maidenhead on a ship,
is traveling toward
this kid, vomiting blood.
That's much more horrible
than what I had done,
you know, in the first third of Jaws.
I just didn't like it.
It was too bloody.
I thought it was in
bad taste, so I cut it out.
Come on, Chief. This
isn't no Boy Scout picnic.
See you got your rubbers.
I asked Robert to
give Lorraine a hard time
inside the scene,
'cause he's really sort of
putting down Chief Brody.
He thinks Chief Brady's a sissy.
He's putting down the fact
he's all in rubber.
He says, "Are you glad you
brought your rubbers, Chief?"
And he's always doing this to everybody,
to Brady's character,
to Brody and to Hooper.
And so I asked him to chide Lorraine,
and in the middle of the scene
he made up this little poem that went,
"There was a woman named Mary
Who lost her virginity
"Not a bad record for this vicinity"
Whatever it was, when it was over,
I said, "You gotta help me clear this.
"If that's from a song,
"we just can't use that
without paying for the rights."
He said, "I don't think we'll be sued.
I got it from a tombstone in Ireland."
That's where he found that little ditty.
"Here lies the body of Mary
Lee Died at the age of 103
"For 15 years she kept her virginity
"Not a bad record for this vicinity"
If they don't like you
going out, they'll love you coming in.
For Jaws, I
wanted the color red to be the blood
and not to be a bandana
around someone's neck
or a plaid over shirt
or the letters on a boat.
The only red I wanted
in the movie was blood.
I told the production designer,
Joe Alves, at the very beginning,
"When you're designing the picture
"and finding your colors, don't find red.
"Just allow red to be the blood."
And, in a sense, I think we stuck to that.
I think that's what happened.
We did have red wine,
but it's a bit symbolic.
Keep that chum line going, Chief.
We got five good miles on it.
When the shooting started at sea,
the production got a lot more difficult.
That's when they started
worrying about wind and weather,
when they could spend a day on the ocean
and get six seconds of usable film
because of boats on the horizon,
because of malfunctioning shark.
The problems of shooting
at sea are enormous
because the wind, the waves,
everything is moving
and nothing stays the same
for more than 50, 60 seconds.
I would set up a shot and
I'd get my camera all set.
Suddenly the electrical barge
would start drifting,
the tide would be moving this way,
and the camera barge
would start drifting this way,
and the Orca would start
moving around on its two anchors.
Before you knew it,
we were all out of position.
It took another hour and a half
to re-anchor and get set again.
Just when we got set, sailboats
from a regatta would come in.
You're shooting
towards the horizon, right?
And the camera has got the horizon.
Then all of a sudden
we would see a little sail.
And as soon as that sail
was in the shot, we had to stop
and wait till it went
all the way across here,
which took an hour and a half.
And hope that at the end
of that hour and a half,
another one didn't come.
So we were always like…
As the sailing ship went off,
we were going, like, "Ready?
Speed. Action!
"No, there's another one!
Oh, God damn it!"
I mean, that put three hours
a day onto our schedule.
I'd sit there saying,
"Do I wait here for an
hour for the regatta to pass,
"or do we turn 18 to 25 anchors,
"move everything to look
in this direction?"
We used to do calculations and say,
"It'll take an hour for the
regatta to get from here to here,
"and an hour and 10 minutes
"to get all your anchors
and look back this way.
"Let's wait for the sailboats
to move out of the shot."
It was just frustrating for all of us.
Everyone got seasick. Sooner or later,
everybody got seasick.
Robert was really, really seasick one day.
And he had to shoot a line,
a very simple line.
The line was, "Hooper,
you idiot, ain't you watching?"
Okay? He had to be
helped into the chair.
And anyone touching him…
It hurt him just to be touched.
And we were all hoping that he'd get it.
Nobody was critical.
Nobody was mocking.
Nobody was standing apart
and pointing fingers.
We all knew exactly what he
was feeling. He just couldn't help it.
But we also knew that he
wouldn't be able to do this,
that this scene, however
small and of-the-moment,
would not get done today.
Steven set up the camera.
Robert was here, and he had to
turn into the camera to say this line.
He was… He literally… He went…
I mean, it hurt.
Steven said, "Action."
Robert turned around,
and with a power that
put me through the wall,
he went, "Hooper, you
idiot, ain't you watching?"
Ho open you idiot,
starboard! Ain't you watching it!
And I swear to God, everyone went…
And then Steven said, "Cut!
Print!" And Robert went…
Collapse.
You're going to need a bigger boat.
One of the most remembered
and oft-quoted lines in the movie
is Roy Scheider saying,
"We gotta get a bigger boat,"
which he improvised on the set,
and I acknowledge that as a writer.
I'm pleased that he said that.
The line, "We're gonna
need a bigger boat,"
has become part of the language
for people who are faced with
an insurmountable problem.
That's a 20-footer.
Twenty-five.
Three tons of him.
The studio was overloaded with
their own effects projects at the time,
Hindenburg and Earthquake.
Marshall Green, the
head of production, said,
"Take it, find someone to do it."
So I started interviewing
various effects people,
and I went to Disney's and other places
that do mechanical objects,
animals and what have you.
I wasn't having any luck.
Everybody was telling me,
"It can't be done.
"It would take three
years in development."
I heard about this guy that
had been retired for some time,
who did the giant squid in
20,000 Leagues Under the Sea.
And his name was Bob Mattey.
So, when I met Bob,
I didn't get the usual
pessimistic attitude,
"You can't do this.
"You can't make this full-size
shark and shoot in the real ocean."
Instead I got this very enthusiastic,
"Yes, we could do anything."
Probably
the reason that Steven and I decided,
in a naive sort of way,
that we were gonna build a full-size
shark and shoot the real ocean
and not a tank or not a miniature…
Maybe that was lack of
experience or whatever,
but everyone kept telling us
we couldn't do it.
So when I found Bob Mattey,
who actually had made
some of these giant creatures,
very enthusiastic about it,
it was very encouraging.
It had to be a formidable shark.
And we made various sketches of
30-foot sharks and 20-foot sharks,
and came up with the… A
reasonable size would be 25 feet.
Very formidable, yet not Moby Dick.
There have been sharks that have
been sighted that have been that size,
and they've actually caught
some that were 21 feet.
So it was a credible
animal we were making.
Doing the initial studies
of the great white shark,
I went to the Steinhardt
and I borrowed this set
of jaws which was huge.
It's an 18, 20-foot shark.
We made our shark larger
by another five or six feet,
but we kept everything in proportion.
Teeth. When I started
doing the actual drawings
for the construction of the shark,
we used everything in proper proportion.
Getting the right personnel
was sort of like…
It reminds me of The Magnificent Seven
where you're picking six great guys,
six big guns.
We heard of this young man
in the plastics section
by the name of Roy Arbogast.
He was an expert
on rubber forms and new
plastics, and things like that.
So we decided he would
be perfect to make the mold.
There was Richie Helmer and Bill Short,
who were excellent in electronics.
All this had to be
electrically-activated valves
that would work the rams
and various things of that type.
We were using hydraulics
instead of pneumatics because“.
Excuse me. We were using
pneumatics instead of hydraulics
because we didn't want
an oil break in the water.
So we had to get hydraulic experts too.
Then we had Mike and Gary
Woods, who were excellent welders.
So we assembled this team,
and they started on
the frame of the shark.
So we were working from the
outside in and the inside out.
We were separately modeling the shark,
and then, at the same time,
they were making the skeleton,
and we hoped that
they would all fit together.
And there was a time element.
The time element was this…
It was that it was already
the first of the year in 1974,
and we knew we would have a
summer window in which to shoot this,
especially that we're gonna go back east.
We decided to shoot this in the
area it was written for, New England.
So we had a time element there.
We built the shark
and tested the shark dry.
We were asked to make comments
about the mechanical shark,
and I think it helped them
to a certain extent.
Because I think they had too
much animation in the shark.
The shark, in reality,
moves in a very smooth, leisurely manner.
I can remember it sort of coming
up out of the water like that,
very fast vertically,
and they don't do that.
They sort of come up…
It's a slow… It's not really
slow, but it looks slow.
They took our advice,
and I know that it made a
big difference to the end result.
We had a number of
different shark components.
We had the full shark, which
I called the "great white turd."
We pulled it along in the water.
It was often on this huge
gantry like a crane arm.
When the crane arm was
tucked at the 30-foot bottom,
you couldn't see the shark.
But when the crane arm… As
quickly as they could blow the ballast
and force the arm out of the water,
the shark would rise out of the water.
The shark could be gimbaled
separately on the arm
to have an attitude change
at the top of the crane arm.
We had that. We had just a fin
that was pulled through the water.
We had a left-to-right shark
and a right-to-left shark.
The left-to-right shark, of course,
had no left side.
It was all scooped out.
And vice versa for the other shark.
Bob needed some area like this
that he could get all those hoses
and wires and stuff,
and have access to all
the mechanical stuff here.
Whatever needed to be repaired.
If we were shooting this
one with the hole here,
we could only shoot from the other side.
So this would be the left-to-right shark.
The idea still was to
try to convince the world
that we were using real sharks
or a great deal of real sharks.
So we didn't want the world to know
that the monster was really mechanical.
And also, we realized
that a mechanical monster
is only good when it moves.
When you take a still photograph of it,
it's gonna look phony under
the best of circumstances.
Somebody snuck in somehow into
the warehouse while we were shooting
and took a picture of one of the sharks.
And I remember getting
very agitated about that.
And none of us could understand,
because we really were very
careful about the secrecy element,
almost became paranoid about it.
But, in itself, the fact that
there was such secrecy surrounding this
created a great deal of interest.
That's a much-maligned shark,
and I'm kind of responsible
for creating a lot of the
badmouthing about the shark.
Because the shark was frustrating.
It didn't really work all the time.
It didn't work hardly at all.
I remember, in particular,
being on our barge,
watching the first shark test,
at which time the shark simply sank
to the bottom of Nantucket Sound.
And we felt that our careers in
motion pictures had gone with it.
Frogmen were delegated to recover
it and bring it back to the surface.
Everything that could
go wrong with a shark
went wrong with the various sharks,
the various types, head, fin, tails.
The ocean was so brutal on the mechanics.
All the pneumatic tubes,
all of that special equipment
was being dashed
and brutalized by the ocean every day.
There were all these radio
mikes all over the island,
the Universal radio mikes.
So wherever you were on the island,
you could hear the radio mikes.
They were always saying,
"The shark is not working.
"Repeat.
The shark is not working."
No matter where you were, and for months.
We just waited around.
We just waited and waited.
I remember every day, about
the 50th or 60th day of shooting,
the crew would come over
to me, and they'd all ask me,
"When are we going to
be done with this movie?"
And I would honestly say to them,
with complete sympathy for the question,
"I don't know. I don't know when
we're going to finish this movie.
"We could finish it if I get
fired and dragged off the movie.
"Somebody else could come and
finish it. Maybe they'll shut us down."
Show me the way to go home
I'm tired and I want to go to bed
I had a little drink about an hour ago
And it's gone right to my head
I remember how we got tears in
our eyes when we sang the song.
Show me the way to go home
I'm tired and I want to go to bed
Which is sung in the film
by the three principals.
I remember looking around
at Charlsie, the script girl,
and other people on the set
with tears in their eyes,
not because it was
a sweet, emotional scene.
That had become their mantra.
All they could think about
was, "What was home like?"
They missed their kids, and
they missed their backyards.
They missed their families
and their lifestyles.
And, in a sense, that's why I
always saw myself in the negative.
I saw myself as James Cagney
in Mister Roberts,
not letting the crew get to shore.
By the way, the crew did get to shore.
They got to shore every
Sunday that we had off.
We shot six-day weeks.
But I never left the island.
The reason I never left the island
in all those seven months of
shooting on Martha's Vineyard
was because if I left the island,
I was certain I would never come back.
The delays and the ocean
and the fact that we'd been on the
island for four or five months now,
we were all getting a little strange.
There was a…
I don't know if it was a charity
dinner or not, but it was a function,
a splendid buffet of wonderful food.
There was this tremendous
buffet of desserts,
strawberry shortcake and Boston cream pies
and chocolate eclairs and napoleons
and some Jell-O, and
also gravy and potatoes.
I'd said to Rick Fields,
who is Verna Fields' son,
"Suppose there was a food fight?"
And he said, "What do you mean?"
I said, "Well, you know, just
start throwing some food."
Roy started it.
Roy threw a big glob of mashed
potatoes and gravy right into my face,
and before I could recover
and throw something at him,
Richard Dreyfuss, I think, took his
dessert and threw it into Roy's face.
Right center, nose, eyes,
mouth, the whole thing.
Roy turned and he took two or
three desserts, threw them at Richard.
Richard ducked and it
hit somebody behind him,
and it was a bit of a Three Stooges brawl.
I remember Dick and David
got up and left right away.
They saw what was coming.
In about 30 seconds, we were actually
standing, hurling food at each other.
And it was a melee after that.
Just food all over the floor, all over…
The help that was there
serving dinner, they came out.
They laughed like crazy.
I don't know if some of the townspeople
appreciated it as much as we did,
but it was a tremendous
blowing off of steam.
I remember Richard and Roy,
covered in food,
running out to the Kelley
House swimming pool
and diving in the water.
And all this once-yummy food,
like Technicolor silt,
rising to the surface of this
otherwise turquoise pool.
I remember saying, "What
the heck," and I jumped in too,
and washed myself off.
But that was what happens in the Navy
when you just aren't given shore leave.
Let that be a lesson.
The decision to continue filming
Jaws was a very shaky one.
Our technical people,
what Steven Spielberg
was fond of calling "our
special defects department,"
wanted us to stop
so they could perfect it.
Dick and I, battle-scarred
veterans of the movie wars,
knew that you never take
the film out of the camera
because they may never
let you put it back,
particularly with a movie like this.
Even if we got one-sixteenth of a
page of script a day, you kept moving.
Steven, at one point, considered
moving our whole crew to the Bahamas,
where the waters were
tranquil and everything,
and we weren't in favor of that.
"Just keep shooting.
"Keep shooting and make do
with what you've got."
This whole system with the barrels,
that kept the shark alive.
When those barrels came up,
the shark was there,
and that really saved us.
It saved us, or we'd still be there
waiting for the shark to work, really.
Finally, after all this,
it was maybe September,
we got the shark to
raise out of the water.
That was that one shot with Roy Scheider,
and it just barely worked.
Okay.
Good blood.
And action, Roy.
Slow ahead.
I can go slow ahead.
You ought to come down
and ladle some of this shit.
And down!
And cut!
And then one day you heard
this, "The shark is working.
"Repeat.
The shark is working."
The shark worked well enough that we,
for a while there, had
the biggest hit of all time.
I really owe the shark a lot.
More than I want to take
away from it right now.
And I owe Bob Mattey
and his team a lot as well.
The shark in Jaws,
and all subsequent editions,
was always called Bruce.
The reason it was called Bruce
is because Steven named him that
after his lawyer, Bruce Ramer.
I didn't make jokes about it. I
never called the shark Bruce. Ever.
I Still don't.
There was one Orca,
which was originally called the Warlock.
It was a boat that was purchased
by Joe Alves, the production designer.
He chose the boat, and I liked the
boat a lot, but I didn't think it was…
It didn't have enough character to it.
Joe agreed, and Joe actually
replaced the entire wheelhouse
with one of his own
design with larger windows,
'cause they were too small.
Joe and I both wanted larger
windows so we could see out.
So everywhere you were inside the boat,
the ocean was breathing down your neck.
Rather than looking through a
porthole and saying, "The ocean."
That could have been a processed shot.
So I wanted really big
windows in the wheelhouse,
in the main cabin.
Joe reconfigured the boat to
give it a little more personality,
squared off a little bit more than
the original boat we bought was.
We were shooting about
75 yards, I'm really not sure,
off the coast of Chappaquiddick Island.
Robert, Roy, myself,
Freddy Zendar, the boat wrangler,
and an ancient sound man with a Nagra.
What happened was, we were pulling
one of the barrels away from the boat.
They had put a little eye hook
into one of the boards,
just below the surface, just
below the waterline, like a shiv.
So the rope would go through the shiv,
and it would seem to pull
the barrel toward the Orca,
as if the shark was
heading toward the Orca.
The problem was,
the motorboat went so fast,
it pulled the shiv and the planking
out from the hull of the Orca
and, of course, the water rushed in.
And we started to sink.
No kidding.
Water started rushing onto the boat.
Freddy Zendar jumps up from the
hold cursing and screaming in Austrian,
and starts to power the boat
as fast as he could
toward the beach of Chappaquiddick Island,
hoping to be able to ground the boat
before it sinks and we have no Orca.
There's only one Orca.
In the meantime, we're in six-foot swells,
and Steven Spielberg is
trying to send safety boats
to get us transferred off the boat.
"Get the actors off the boat!"
I remember John Carter, who
won an Academy Award, by the way,
for best sound for Jaws.
He picked up the Nagra
and held it over his head
and said, "Fuck the actors,
save the sound department!"
I have this image to this day of John
sinking, holding the Nagra over his head,
the water up to John's
ankles, up to his knees,
boats scrambling to pull
everybody off the sinking Orca,
and John with his Nagra going under.
There was a certain level
of executive indifference
to the sound department's lifespan.
"Get the actors off the boat!"
It was funny.
We lived.
We had lost the camera. The
camera was on the boat, too.
It went underwater.
Bill Butler said, "You know, in a sense,
"the developing solution
we use is a saline solution.
"I think this film's going to be
okay if we can rush it to the
ab."
We got on an airplane with a
bucket of water and the film in it,
took it to New York and developed it.
Didn't lose a foot.
Bill Butler created
equipment just to make Jaws.
He created a camera platform that
according to the tides or
where you wanted your lens,
could go just below the surface
or way above the surface of the water.
He designed it and
had it built for the movie.
He also created…
He had to create the water
box, where you put the camera.
But he reconfigured the water
box so it was easier to get the focus.
Your hand in there so you could pull focus
and still have the water lapping the lens.
I wanted this movie
to be just at water level,
the way we are when we're treading water.
We don't see water three feet off
the water. We see water like this.
I wanted to get the camera right down
to where the human point of view
is most accustomed to being
when you're swimming.
That's why I shot
at least 25% of the movie
from that water box that
Bill Butler reconfigured for us.
When it came time to do Jaws…
They hadn't done a water
picture for several years,
and the old-fashioned way of doing
a water picture was to use a gimbal.
It weighs about 400 pounds.
It's very clumsy.
It does keep the camera level aboard ship,
but it's too clumsy to do a
film the way they do films today.
And so I chose to hand-hold the camera.
When Steven heard about this
he was rather shocked,
because he didn't really
want a hand-held picture.
But he didn't realize
that I didn't really mean
to do a hand-held film
in the terms that they
then used or thought about
hand-held on land,
but rather to use the knees
and the body to take
the roll out of the film.
And so we gave that a try,
and it worked very well.
After he saw a demonstration,
he decided that was the way to do it.
As a matter of fact, Jaws ended up
being a film shot mostly hand-held.
One thing I remember
more than anything else
has nothing to do with
the direction of the picture,
but has to do with the
incredible contrasts of light.
You'd see a scene being shot.
From one angle it's dark,
from the other angle it's light.
Sunshine, fog.
I remember thinking to myself,
"My God! How are you
gonna cut this together?
"How are you ever gonna get the color
"to bear anything resembling a match?"
I'd never seen…
The islands and oceans have
such incredible differences.
The ocean is green, it's blue, it's black.
Sometimes the sky was blue instead of
the overcast gray look
that we really wanted.
When we got back to LA,
we had to take it into the lab
and get rid of the blue.
At the time, the special
effects people didn't really have
a good way of pulling the blue out
of the film without affecting the faces.
We wanted the faces to remain untouched.
And so I decided to try something
that they hadn't tried before,
which was simply to use
black-and-white film,
the type they do letters with,
which is either black or it's white,
expose it for the very
bright sky with a blue filter,
and take only the blue of the
sky out and leave the faces alone.
It happened to work very well,
and we were able to match
shots very well that way.
Want to see something permanent?
That was Robert's idea.
Robert Shaw said, "I've
got this tooth that's fake."
He pulled his cap off and
the little nub was under it.
He said, "Can I take that off
"as an addition to
the scar-comparing contest?"
Mr. Hooper, that's
the U. S. S. Indianapolis.
You were on the Indianapolis?
The Indianapolis speech
about the atomic bomb that had
been taken from Tinian to Leyte
which, for me, is my
favorite part of Jaws,
this speech that Shaw gives about that.
That was conceived by Howard Sackler,
who only really wrote a short paragraph
as Quint starts to talk about one
of the reasons he kills sharks today
is what sharks did to him and
his shipmates back in 1945.
It was a wonderful scene
that I kept trying to get
Howard Sackler to expand.
But Howard felt shorter was better,
and never would elaborate on it.
One day I was talking to John Milius,
and I said, "Could you make this longer?
"Because I think it's a speech,
"not just a couple of short paragraphs."
John said, "Sure, I love the
speech. It's a great idea. I'll try."
So John sat down and wrote page
after page in long hand,I believe,
and sent me an actual,
original longhand version
of a very long Quint speech,
which was essentially too much,
but, pared down, it was gonna be great.
When Robert Shaw read it…
Shaw, who himself had
written Man in the Glass Booth,
was an accomplished playwright.
Shaw said, "It's too hard for me to play.
"There's too much John Huston
in some of this dialogue.
"Huston could say this, but I
can't say it as well as Huston.
"Let me have a chance at rewriting it."
So then Shaw rewrote Milius,
who had rewritten Sackler,
and the speech in the movie
is basically Shaw's version of
Milius' version of Sackler's version.
Very first light, sharks come cruising
so we formed ourselves into tight groups.
You know, kind of like old squares
in a battle like you see on a calendar
like the Battle of Waterloo. The idea was…
the shark comes to the nearest man
and he starts pounding,
hollering and screaming.
Sometimes the shark would go away…
but sometimes he wouldn't go away.
The final telling of the Indianapolis tale
was one of the most riveting…
Sometimes when you're
watching another actor tell a story,
you're making up your interest.
When Robert told that story,
I couldn't keep my eyes off him.
In both the book and the
early versions of the script,
Quint is harpooning the shark,
his leg gets caught in the rope,
he gets dragged over the side
to his death, where he drowns and
is probably bitten too, as far as I know.
He dies the way Ahab dies in Moby Dick.
It always seemed to us that if Quint
is gonna die, he should be bitten.
The best would be if he
could go mano a mane
and stab the shark, which he does.
His formidable human talents are no match
for the formidable
shark talents of the fish.
So we chose the ending
that we have in the movie,
which is that he slides into the great
jaws of the fish and gets chomped.
And Scheider sees it and is terrified.
The second Orca that was
constructed was built just to sink,
and then pump air back in the ballast
and it would come up for take two.
And then sink a second time, or
as many times as we had to sink it.
That was for the shot
where the boat starts to sink,
and Roy Scheider has to
climb out the flipping window
and climb the mast as the boat goes down,
and he only has one final
opportunity to succeed.
Damn it!
The most interesting conflict
happened between me and Steven
when it came to the
discussion of the ending.
He said to me, "The ending
of the book is a downer.
"The shark gets stabbed with a
harpoon, can't hold up the barrels,
"and eventually drowns,
spins slowly to the bottom,
"and the movie or the book, the
story ends. The characters are saved.
"That is not a big, rousing ending.
"I need a big, rousing ending."
So he said, "Here is
what I propose to do."
And he told me the ending he had in mind.
I said, "Steven, that is completely
unbelievable. It can't happen.
"A shark does not bite down on a scuba
tank and explode like an oil refinery."
He said, "I don't care."
He said, "if I have
got them for two hours,
"they will believe whatever I do
"for the next three minutes,
because I've got them.
"I want the audience on
their feet screaming at the end,
"'Yes, yes! This is what
should happen to this animal!"'
Which reminded me, in
retrospect, of the Bill Goldman thing,
which is that reality may be
great and truth may be wonderful,
but none of it holds a
candle to believability.
If the filmmaker has done his job
and brought you into
believability, he can do anything.
Play by the rules. Set the
rules, but follow the rules.
And that's exactly what Steven did.
He was right, I was wrong,
in this entire argument.
His ending brought people
to their feet screaming,
"Yes, yes! This is
the way it should be!"
And it may be incredible,
but it was the right thing to do.
Smile, you son of a bitch!
In Duel, you hear the sound of…
In fact it was a dinosaur growling
from an old "B" dinosaur picture,
when the truck went over the cliff,
'cause I had always imagined the truck
to be a bit like a T-rex chasing a car.
I used the very same sound effect in Jaws.
Almost as a bit of just a reminder
that there was a kinship
between both stories,
as the shark is sinking to
the bottom of the ocean,
after it's been exploded
by the compressed air.
One of the great
pieces of Spielbergian genius
was the fact that at the
end of the movie Jaws,
the Richard Dreyfuss character pops up
and they swim to shore together.
This brought cheers, of course.
It was what the audience wanted.
I used to hate the water.
I can't imagine why.
When I finally did leave the island,
just before the last shot, which
was the blowing up of the shark…
I left the island for two reasons.
One, I heard the crew wanted
to throw me overboard.
I didn't know whether they were going
to throw me overboard in cement slippers
or throw me overboard via the poop deck,
one bounce, and then into the water.
Or whether it was going
to be just into the water
with a two-foot sandy bottom.
I didn't know what they were gonna do,
so I thought I'd get out quickly.
I remember when I got to Boston
on the ferry.
We spent the night in Boston, and
the next day we were scheduled…
Dreyfuss and I had to fly back to
Los Angeles on American Airlines.
I vividly recall
getting into my hotel room
and having a complete anxiety breakdown.
I mean it's a complete…
I don't know what you would
call it. It was a breakdown.
I couldn't stop shaking.
My jaw was clenched.
I couldn't open my mouth.
I was getting electrical
shocks through my brain
like I was having seizures.
I know this sounds really melodramatic,
but it's exactly what happened.
Something neurological, emotional…
Something was happening to me.
It was a full panic attack,
which I don't remember ever
having at that level before.
I remember calling Richard up.
He was in the pub downstairs
and Richard came up with me.
I just said, "I'm in
really bad shape, Ricky."
Rick said, "Don't worry. We'll be on
the airplane tomorrow." Which we were.
My recollection is that we
showed a cut version of the film
with one big sequence missing,
without Johnny Williams' music,
in a projection room at Universal Studios.
And when the lights went on, there
was no reaction at all, as I recall.
I recall turning around and saying,
"Well, Sid, what do you think?"
He said, "It's okay."
Well, "okay" was like
being given one-half a star.
"Okay" for 159 days?
Of course it was only "okay."
It didn't have Johnny Williams' music.
It didn't have some major underwater stuff
that we filmed in the tank at MGM Studios
in order to get very
close angles underwater.
We couldn't get…
The waters in Martha's
Vineyard, both cold and murky,
wouldn't allow us to do
much underwater stuff.
Metro had this great Esther
Williams tank, as it used to be called.
So the reaction was, "Go
get the rest of the movie."
When they came back
from Martha's Vineyard,
they realized that they didn't have
the footage, as I understood it,
that they needed, of Hooper
and the shark together in the cage.
So I was called.
A friend of mine, Jesse
Wayne, recommended me.
He was called first, and, not
being a certified scuba diver,
he spoke to Tom Joyner, the
assistant director, who then called me.
I went in,
and we went down to Culver City
to MGM Studios, and
shot it in a tank down there.
There were three inter-cuts
for the sequence
where the shark attacks the cage.
One, of course, was Dick Warlock,
who was the stunt person inside
the cage subbing for Richard Dreyfuss.
The second was the Rizzo
shoot with Ron and Val in Australia.
And there was Frank Sparks,
whose eyes I actually used
to substitute Richard's eyes
because Rich was unavailable
for shooting the inserts.
So when you see
the Richard Dreyfuss scream,
that's not Richard's face,
those aren't Richard's eyes.
That's a guy named Sparks.
Help!
Down in the tank was a metal apparatus
that the shark was attached to,
where it could move forward,
backward, sideways, up and down.
So it had pretty good
movement, real natural movement.
It was operated by a special effects man.
His name is Whitey Krumm.
As Whitey was looking in one window,
watching the shark from
the side with the controls,
Mr. Spielberg was around the other side,
or a quarter of the way around,
looking at it from another perspective.
He was looking at the shark
coming directly at the cage,
and they communicated with each other
via headphones and a microphone.
Okay, here we go. Attack.
Bring it out now!
Bring it out!
Okay, attack!
Attack!
Okay, bring it back and bring it in again.
Bring it back and then bring it in.
Yeah, bring it out!
Bring it out!
Now bring it in.
Bring it in again.
Now, cut!
Once again, right away.
Yeah, next time. Okay?
Good grief.
Am I in trouble with Jaws?
In Jaws trouble?
Verna was great. We used to call her…
Our affectionate nickname for
Verna Fields was "Mother Cutter"
because she was like our
mom and she cooked for us,
and she told us great
stories of Peter Bogdanovich
and all the films that she cut with him.
She was just a great person.
She was a very charismatic person.
She was the most charismatic
person on Jaws, her and Robert Shaw.
Except she never came out to sea.
She was always in her cutting room.
It was frustrating for
Verna, for two reasons.
One, she never had enough film to cut.
Because on a good day, I get five shots.
On a good day at sea, five shots.
On an average day, about
three. On a bad day, none.
Verna didn't have a lot of film racing
into her cutting room to put together,
so she had to be on the
island for seven months,
with very little to cut.
Verna didn't have the film
until we finished the movie.
That's when Verna's work got started.
Verna and I worked every day
on the picture at her house,
in her little cutting room by
the pool, and she did a great job.
What am I looking for?
We're looking for a nice place to
show that Quint refuses to slow the boat.
Quint, it can't take that much pressure!
That's the spot, Steve.
I had always wanted to be in
business with John Williams, all my life.
When he said yes to Sugar
land, and we became friends…
Obviously, I wanted him to
do every picture I ever made,
and Jaws came second.
When John saw the movie,
he called me up on the phone.
He said, "This is like a pirate movie."
And he said, "I think we
need pirate music for this
"because this is primal, but
it's also fun and entertaining."
This idea of characterizing
the shark musically,
these low, thumping
ostinato notes in the bass,
were the result of a very
simple idea that I had.
I thought that the shark
should be represented
by something in sound or in music,
probably music, because there's no
sound underneath the water, we thought.
Today you might do it with sound effects.
I thought a driving thing in
the bottom of the orchestra
might indicate the
mindless attack of the shark.
It's all instinct. There's no
real intelligence behind it.
It's an unstoppable…
This thing comes at you. You
can't fight it off without destroying it
because of this
relentless drive that it has.
When he finally played the
music for me on the piano,
he previewed the main Jaws theme.
I expected to hear something
kind of weird and melodic,
kind of tonal, but eerie
and of another world,
almost a bit like outer space,
inner space under the water.
And what he played me instead,
with two fingers on the lower keys, was…
At first I began to laugh.
I thought he was…
He had a great sense of humor.
I thought he was putting me on.
And he said, "No, that's
the theme to Jaws!"
I said, "Play it again."
He played it again.
And he played it again,
and it suddenly seemed right.
But when I first heard it, it seemed wrong
because it just seemed too simple.
And so simple… Often the
best ideas are the simplest ones.
And John found a signature
for the entire movie.
One could alter
the speed of this ostinato.
It could be note, note,
any kind of alteration
of speed, to very slow,
very fast, very soft, very loud.
All these things could
manipulate the moment
to illustrate that the shark was
at the highest pitch of
frenzy, or something lower.
And this simple dramatic device
seemed to be what we needed.
Part of the genius of John Williams
is how he spots music and
how he places music in a movie.
That's sort of something
that's never discussed
about the art of composition.
The placement of that composition.
And John did not want music
to celebrate a red herring.
He only wanted music to signal
the actual arrival of the shark.
There were opportunities
to advertise the shark with music,
and also opportunities
when we don't have the music
and the audience has
the sense of an absence.
They sense the absence of the
shark. They don't hear the thump.
We've conditioned them to do that.
But then you may go one step further.
We know now the shark really is there,
but we haven't advertised it with music,
so his attack comes out of silence.
Now, because you're conditioned
to have the music every time,
when you don't and the shark
arrives, it's even more terrifying.
It's one of the beauties
of the film medium
that when you combine music
with this kind of visual thing,
you can get this association
in people's minds.
I think if you did it musically
just in a concert piece,
it wouldn't have the same effect.
It's the combination of
the visual and the situation.
This being the shark, or the
knifing scene in Hitchcock's Psycho,
combined with the notes.
That combination of sound and image
forming a memory,
which can then be referred back to.
As you do with an
audience that now hears it,
and a child will scream in terror
because of the association
that's been created.
Ho open where are you?
My favorite cue in Jaws
has always been that barrel chase,
where the shark approaches the
boat and they harpoon the animal
and he takes the line out
and the barrels lift off the boat
and the music accelerates
and becomes very exciting.
Show.
Time.
What were you doing? You knew I had
to get a clean shot right in the head.
All right, let's see how long
that barrel takes to bring him up.
The boat turns to follow the
shark as he's pulling the line out,
and the music becomes very heroic.
There's a Korngoldian
fanfare, if you like, of triumph
as they're going through
the waves chasing the shark.
Bring another barrel!
I'm coming around again!
Suddenly the shark dives down.
The music deflates and gets
slower and slower and softer.
The deflation and
disappointment of the realization
that the shark hasn't been captured.
It's all illustrated in this
one area where the music
is able to follow all that
dramatic outline and punctuate it.
Without that score,
I believe the film would have
only been half as successful.
The score was clearly responsible
for half the success of that movie.
Jaws certainly was a hallmark in
my career. It changed it very greatly.
I had done
I don't know how many films,
dozens, before that,
and certainly hundreds
of television shows.
As a matter of fact, I'd even won
an Academy Award before Jaws
for having been music
director of Fiddler on the Roof,
for which I did all the
arrangements and underscoring
and conducting of that
movie in 1970, I think it was.
Jaws, for me, was the first Academy
Award that I received for my own music.
So that was a very significant
moment in my career,
as it would be for anyone's.
The first test of Jaws took place,
as I wrote in my own book,
in Dallas in a shopping center.
Dick Zanuck and I were extremely nervous.
Would the shark get laughs?
Everybody knew that had read a
newspaper, that it was not a real shark.
What would happen?
And I remember circling
around that theater,
and we noticed a crowd.
Of course we weren't very subtle
with what was put on the marquee.
It was like, "The biggest
fish story you'll ever see,"
or something very clever
that attracted attention.
After all, Jaws was
a number one bestseller
and had a lot of media attention.
And so we went and had a very stiff drink.
We went into the theater,
and the screams started,
and they never stopped.
And we were pinching
each other. It was incredible.
I thought the whole roof,
ceiling of the theater
was going to collapse
because of the noise, the
shock and the screams so loud.
And it didn't die down, so that we…
You couldn't, literally, hear the dialogue
for the next, maybe minute
because there was…
People were screaming repeatedly.
And there was such
excitement in the theater.
I remember elbowing Mr. Brown,
who was sitting next to me,
and he was elbowing me back,
and said, "We're in. We did it."
We knew with that first
scream that it had worked.
When the shark came out of the water,
when Roy Scheider was chumming and said,
"Why don't you come down
and chum some of this shit?"
The shark comes out.
I had designed, hopefully, a
laugh that would turn into a scream.
So I used the word "shit."
I added that line
because in those days, back in 1974,
the word "shit" was an easy laugh.
Now it's used so much
nobody laughs anymore.
Then it wasn't used that much.
It instantly got a nervous
laugh from audiences,
often an embarrassed laugh. With
younger people, a rebellious laugh.
I was trying to change a laugh,
ramping up into a scream.
And it worked.
It was my proudest moment
at the whole preview.
They laughed when they heard "shit,"
and when the shark came out
that laugh sustained itself
into a humongous scream,
and popcorn went flying.
It was amazing, and it made
me greedy. I got so greedy.
Because earlier in the movie,
when they find Ben
Gardner's head in the boat,
I hadn't timed it right,
and Richard turns around…
That's where the head's already there,
and there was no reaction
from the audience at all.
So I was scratching my head
after the preview.
I was extraordinarily happy.
The numbers were the highest
numbers in Universal's history,
the executives were happy, we were happy,
the audience loved the picture.
And I was greedy.
I said, "There's one more
scream we can get into this movie
"if I can figure out this thing
with Ben Gardner's head."
The studio wouldn't give me more
money, though they were ecstatic.
They said, "It's fine. Don't fix
something that's not broken. It works.
"Don't mess with it, or you'll
improve this into a failure."
So I went and spent $3,000 of my own money
to have some art department people
build a balsa-wood side of a boat
to match the Ben Gardner
boat we had shot before,
cut a hole in it and got the
same Ben Gardner head,
the Styrofoam head, latex and Styrofoam,
and had it underwater.
And this time, simply, when the
double for Rick came to the hole,
I used several timings, I shot
it about nine different ways.
One time I shot it,
he comes through the hole
and the head comes out.
Another time,
he comes through the hole and
the head comes out at the same time.
Another time, the head comes
out and he's not even in the shot.
Then the camera goes
really close to the knife,
taking the tooth out,
the head comes out there.
I did it a whole bunch of different ways,
and then I went to the dubbing room.
We were already remixing
little changes we had made.
And I cut it in and I tried it out
on all of the sound effects editors,
the music editors and the dubbers.
And I showed them one way, and they said,
"Interesting. It's better
than what you had."
Another way, no reaction.
And then one way, nobody screamed,
but they all kind of suddenly said,
"Oh, yeah. Wow. That
surprised me. I didn't expect it."
It was simply a matter of timing.
And the moment that works the best,
which is the moment in the
movie that the dubbers reacted to,
is the moment where he gets to the hole,
and then the head comes out.
There's just a bit of a pause.
And I just remember we then
took the film to Long Beach.
I think at the Lakewood Theaters.
And we had a second preview there
with that extra scene,
that extra moment in.
And it got a humongous scream.
Bigger than the scream in Dallas when
the shark came out, with Roy chumming.
And popcorn flew even higher,
and people came out of their seats higher.
And I was thrilled until at Lakewood,
we got to the scene that
got the previous big laugh,
where the shark comes out of
the water when Roy's chumming.
It got a big scream, but it was only 50%
or less of the scream we got in Dallas.
So that preview was a smash preview.
The scores were higher, the
studio was flying on cloud nine.
They'll make a fortune with
the movie, they keep saying.
And I'm scratching my head thinking,
"Now what did I do to make
that second scream less?"
And I realized it was a no-brainer.
The audience didn't trust me after the
first scream at the end of the first act.
They were surprised, and
then they were looking out
for shadows and things
coming out from behind things.
And they were defensive and
ready for some kind of a shock.
The rating of Jaws was a real cliffhanger.
Richard Heffner, the
chairman of the rating board
of the Motion Picture
Association of America
that tells parents
what to expect on movies…
It was essential to the MCA/Universal
financiers and distributors
that Jaws get a "PG" rating,
meaning "parental guidance indicated,"
but it meant that children
could come and see it.
Whatever the ratings board said
to Sheinberg and Wasserman,
they told Dick and David, who
came to me as my producers
and said, "Steven, in order to get
not an 'R' rating, but a 'PG' rating,
"you need to cut some frames
from the leg coming down."
I was happy to do it, as they
didn't ask me to cut the leg out.
They just asked me not to let the
leg hit, bounce, gush blood, settle…
Because I was really sort of studying it.
So I cut about a foot and a
half to two feet off that shot.
You'll see the leg.
Just when you see it severed
and it just starts to hit
the silt bed, we cut away.
And finally, a "PG" was awarded.
Our argument was very simple
with Heffner and his board.
Nobody impersonates a shark,
unlike films of violence.
No one is going to get up
and eat somebody.
Nobody's going to drag
someone down in the water.
What happens in nature is
part of childhood's experience.
Anyone who's read Grimm's
Fairy Tales… Red Riding Hood.
Little Red Riding Hood is one of
the scariest stories ever written,
and children are regularly terrified.
After the film was distributed,
I don't recall any letters from children…
About children having bad dreams.
I had many about adults having bad dreams
and never going by the water again.
And so the rating, to the
great relief of MCA/Universal,
was, in my estimation, rightly
given "parental guidance."
"May be too intense for
some children" was on the ads.
Of course, all that did was bring them in.
I saw the film in its final version
when it played at the
Rivoli Theater in Manhattan,
which was a huge theater
with a great big screen.
And members of my family
and guests were invited.
Watching the audience react
to it was wonderfully exciting.
I mean, they just laughed
and they screamed.
They did everything
that we hoped they would do.
I happened, by coincidence, to be
next to the Newsweek researcher,
who was next to the Time researcher.
At the moment when Roy turns aft
and the shark comes out of the water,
and he utters that great
line that I wish I'd written,
"I think you're gonna need a bigger boat,"
the Newsweek researcher
jumped out of her chair
and landed on the upturned
pen of the Time researcher,
thus having a double screamer going.
I thought right then,
"We have a fairly successful
movie going on here."
There was applause at
the end of the movie.
The movie ends, we're
swimming away, it says "The End,"
and they went crackers.
Everyone went berserk.
However many people are in that theater…
I couldn't even tell you.
Pretty big theater.
They went nuts.
And then they sat and they
watched all of the credits,
every last one of them, and nobody moved.
And then they applauded again.
And I've never seen that.
And I remember walking out
on the sidewalk at the end of it.
I looked at Dreyfuss and he looked at me,
and he ran over and
he jumped up in my arms
and he said, "We're sensational!
"We're great!
We're terrific!"
And I said, "Yeah."
At the end of that evening I walked
out and I ran into Dreyfuss in the street,
and we went to a bar,
and all Rick could say was, "He did it!"
And I said, "Who did it?
What are you talking about?"
He said, "Spielberg
did it! He did it!"
It was a hell of a moment.
I felt so proud that I was in that movie,
and so proud for Spielberg.
I remember getting on
the phone with notes.
I was saying, "And you gotta
do this and you gotta do that."
He was very pleased.
Well, Jaws went on to become
the biggest picture of
all times at that time,
surpassing the $100 million mark,
which had never been done before.
And I remember Universal
marketing department
would take an ad out
with the shark and the titles
of the various pictures that had beaten us
and held the records.
And the shark would
devour each one, each week,
whether it be The Godfather
or The Sound of Music,
finally Gone With The Wind.
Until we were up on top
of the surface, number one,
and we became the
biggest picture of all time.
This was before even a
foreign release of any kind.
We busted right through
the $100 million mark.
And it was a phenomenon.
It really was a phenomenon.
When a movie has the
success that Jaws had,
it becomes more than an entertainment.
It becomes part of the popular culture.
And Jaws was no exception.
We had really wonderful
political cartoonists
like Conrad using the image of the shark
as a metaphor for political
behavior in Washington.
We had sketches on Saturday Night Live.
Chevy Chase did a great
Land Shark. I remember that.
And then John Belushi,
blessed be his memory,
did a fabulous impression of Dreyfuss.
You don't think of Belushi and
Dreyfuss being anywhere similar,
but when Belushi put on a
blue knit watch cap and said,
"This was no boating accident,"
you got a laugh out of it.
The first shot of Airplane!
By the Zucker brothers uses a shark theme.
It was a combination of elements
that were all so instantly identifiable
because everybody knew what they were.
The shark's theme became
a synonym for danger.
Just all those elements just
became part of popular culture.
Every time I'd fall asleep,
I dreamt I was on the third
or fourth day of shooting.
I'd wake up with an electrical
explosion in my brain.
My heart beating, can't catch my breath,
looking around the room,
where am I? Disoriented.
I'd calm down, get a glass of
water, go back to sleep again.
Same dream. I'm on
the fourth day of shooting,
and I know I've got another 146 days left.
And I'd wake up again.
Same thing.
And this thing was just haunting me
all night long till I didn't get any sleep.
So Jaws was a fun movie to
watch, but not a fun movie to make.