Okay, time to eat.
Let's see, open the app.
I'm gonna get a double pepperoni pizza,
order breadsticks and, well, lasagna,
yeah.
New item alert, jalapeno breadstick quick
bites.
Huh, it might be nice to have something in
the salad family.
And do I want dessert?
Ooh, I'm gonna be naughty, butterscotch
bedino.
Okay, I'm gonna have five.
Delivery, because of that saying, now
please.
Eh, all right, that oughta be til
breakfast.
Oh, hey, wait, are you guys early or am I
late?
No matter.
I have got a real treat for you today.
No, not a treat for you.
Okay.
Anyway, about the treat, can I just say,
you will not be disappointed.
It's a story about me that no one's ever
heard before, featuring someone in my life
you've never met.
I don't know about you, but color me
intrigued.
Oh, yeah, drone delivery, welcome to the
future.
You know, to really understand everything,
I'm gonna have to take you back to where
it all began.
You don't want anything to take away from
the flavor of the cheese.
And like every great story, it all started
on a dark and stormy night.
Wait here, Junior.
I'll be right back.
Oh.
Hi there, little buddy.
Hi.
You hungry, little guy?
You want a little more?
Whoa, you are a hungry little guy.
That was a quick dinner, Senor John.
You must have been very hungry.
Can I bring you anything else?
Uh, yes.
Some lasagna?
Yes, lasagna for one.
Uh, yeah.
You know what? No, make it family style.
Very good.
To go, please, Vito.
Okay, everybody.
Where do you go?
Stand up and see.
Join with us.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, I'm dancing.
Excuse me. Pardon me if I hate this.
Oh, no.
John!
Take out for John!
Your takeout is ready, Senor John.
Yes, one familia-style lasagna to go.
You eat alone too much, John.
You should get on the dating apps.
-There's bumble, tinder, gluten
-free singles, hot sauce, passions.
And you should spend serious money on
premium memberships.
Bye!
Oh, hey.
Well, that was an interesting dinner that
you had.
Well, I guess, um, this is where we say
goodbye.
Oh, you're really cute, but I can't have
pets in my apartment.
So, I'll see you around, okay?
Go on.
Oh, no.
No, don't cry, don't cry.
Oh, oh.
No, no, no, no, no.
No. Oh, no. Oh, no.
You don't have a home, do you?
Excuse me, but you see, back in old
Napoli, that's Amore.
Amore, that's Amore.
And that's how I adopted John.
-So, I moved John out of his apartment to this nice little two
-bed
-two
-bath in the suburbs.
As soon as he understood the ground rules,
well, let's just say, we were living the
dream.
And once we were settled in, I even let
John get a pet.
Odie became my most trusted ally.
He was kind, gentle, and most importantly,
my unpaid intern.
Oh, yeah, as you can see, life here is
pretty near perfect.
Yeah, except for…
Time to go to the vet.
We're gonna need the big scale.
Does she need to announce it to the whole
office?
No, please, no. Ow, it's so hot. Ow, it's
really hurting. Ow, ow, ow.
And that's why we should go from Sunday to
Tuesday.
Okay, where were we?
Wakey, wakey, eggs and bakey. Good
morning.
What? Where'd you get that chair?
I think I was meant to be here tonight
because I was meant to meet you.
I think we were meant to be. That's what I
meant to say.
You had me at the word meant.
We're gonna run like the wind. Faster,
harder, more insane.
Odie, yeah, can you put this back to
normal?
There you go. Just let the pepperoni's
healing powers work its magic.
Oh!
You saw nothing.
Up until that moment, my life was a
perfect souffle.
Little did I know it was all about to
collapse.
Imagine yourself distract you or max out
your credit card by excessively placing
online food orders.
I swear.
Huh? Huh? Who said that?
Huh? Odie. Odie. Odie!
It's time for my midnight snack.
Thank you, good sir. Your kindness will be
rewarded.
What are we feeling like tonight, huh?
French, Italian, Chinese, cupcakes,
Chinese it is.
Odie, shape everything from the bottom two
shelves into a dumpling.
Night night snacking.
Not good for digestion.
Odie, I'm dreaming again. Slap me across
the face.
Nope, still dreaming. I must be really
deep in this one.
What do you want? You want money? I don't
have any money, okay?
Who carries cash anymore?
-I've got John's credit card number. Memorize 555
-238
-575521. Did you write that down?
Expiration code is 555.
The cat is out of the bag.
I really hope this kidnapping plan works
or she'll put us down.
With her insults and cutting observations.
I think this is a case of mistaken
identity.
We must be looking for another gorgeous,
lovable kitty cat, right?
Hey, where are you going? Come back!
Odie, I'll handle this.
Alright you guys, I'm giving you to the
count of three to get back here and let us
down.
One, two, three.
Four, five.
I am not kidding here!
Three hundred and eight.
Three hundred and nine.
Three hundred and…
Yeah, they're not coming.
It's over.
Am I dead?
Are you an angel?
Please, take me.
-I am ready to go to that… to that all
-you
-can
-eat buffet in the sky.
What? Listen. I'm going to swing you out,
cut your ropes and drop you safely to that
landing below.
Wait, what? That seems a tad risky.
Is there another plan that doesn't involve
cutting a rope over a forty foot drop?
No tag. We gotta get out of here before
they come back.
We need to go. Come on, Junior.
Wait here, Junior. I'll be right back.
I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
I'll be right back.
You.
Hey, Junior.
Who is he? This is Vic, my father.
Look, Junior, I know how you might be
upset.
Upset? Why would I be upset? You only
abandoned me in an alley as a kitten. I'm
probably just overreacting.
No, no, not her.
Okay, follow me, Junior.
No, no, no, no. You lost the privilege of
telling me what to do a long time ago.
Hello, Vic.
Dang it.
Scarecam!
Oh, you should have seen your faces.
Okay, boys. Show me.
Hello, Vic.
Post that ASAP.
What? Hey, Jinx. I haven't seen you since…
Well, no hard feelings though, right?
Oh, I don't think so.
I'm a hugger.
Part of me wants to be mad at her for
kidnapping us, but you gotta love her
energy.
Where are my manners?
Chop, chop, gentlemen. Look alive.
Perfection. You know, I was so delighted
that you accepted my invitation here
tonight.
-Well, throwing us in a burlap sack wasn't exactly an e
-vite.
Vic, you're so quiet.
-Are you feline sad? Cat got your tongue? Would you prefer a mu
-mo, sir?
Excuse me. How do you two know each other?
Let me handle this, Junior.
-Oh, don't Junior me. You may call me Garfield, Mr. Garfield, or G
-Money.
-Okay, whatever. No G
-Money. Anyway, can somebody please tell me what is going on?
I'll take this one.
What?
I'm from a small town outside London that
you've probably never heard of.
Oh, I scratched and clawed my way through
hard times to come here with one dream.
I wanted to be seen.
I wanted to matter.
I was a failure.
The winner!
And then, I met Vic and his crew. They
were outcasts, losers, thugs.
We didn't have much, but we had each
other. We became a real family.
Vic and family. I know this is going.
Excuse me, Garcon. When might we expect
appetizers? Perhaps in a mouze bouche?
And then, one night, we were about to make
our biggest score. Enough milk to last us
for weeks!
Vic!
Jinx, I tried to come back for you. You
have to know that.
Oh yes, you get an A for effort.
So what happened next?
Imagine Alcatraz, but smellier.
It was cold. And lonely. And stinky. So
very stinky. I can't overstate that
enough.
But it gave me purpose. I needed to get
out. I just needed help.
So your purpose was to escape jail and get
involved with charities?
Nope. My purpose was… revenge.
Oh, I see. I went the other way with it.
I'm kidding. Another cat would be bent on
revenge, but I'm a…
How do you put it?
-Evolved, compassionate, and incredibly self
-actualized.
Bingo! I had such trouble finding him, and
when I discovered you were his son, I had
no choice but to kidnap you to lure him
here.
Listen, I totally get it. It's all part of
being associated with Vic.
So what do you need from him to make this
right?
I simply want him to pay back the quart of
milk I lost that night. And we'll call it
even.
I can do that. What he can't do is raise a
child.
Just one quart. Just one quart. Done.
For every day I was in the pound.
What now? Nice twist. Well played.
How long were you in the pound again?
Four years, seven months, and two days.
Oh, that long? Alright, I'm gonna do the
math here in my brain. The way you do that
is…
Odie. 1675 quarts of milk. Exactly right,
Odie. We both came up with it at the exact
same time.
Where am I gonna find that much milk?
-Well, I suggest you go back to the place you double
-crossed me. Lactose Farms.
Wow. Well, good luck, Vic. I'll leave you
two to work out the fire print. We'll just
see ourselves out. Odie?
Uh, no. You're all going to do this.
What? Why me? He's the one who abandoned
you.
Yes, but this is more than a one-cat job.
-Yeah, but I'm sure Vic has a whole crew of low
-life cat burglars he could ask.
Oh, I'm sure he does. But if I'm being
completely honest, seeing how miserable
you make one another brings me endless
satisfaction.
Oh, well, thank you for your honesty. And
if I don't go?
You can stay and have a playdate with
Roland and Nolan.
Okay, boys. Go play!
Ma'am, I think this is an opportunity to
take a deep, cleansing breath and repeat
your anger management mantra.
Anyone else have any objections?
Nope, I'm good. Thanks for the
opportunity.
Excellent. Now you boys have 72 hours.
Or else.
I can't believe this is happening. I don't
see you for years.
And when I do, you pull me into a life of
crime.
I had this reunion playing differently in
my head, too.
That's the difference between us, because
I never wanted to see you again.
I totally understand your anger, but give
me a chance to explain. You see, I'm not
the bad guy you think I am.
A good guy doesn't leave his kid in an
alley.
It wasn't like that.
It was exactly like that!
No, it wasn't. Let me tell you…
No, no, I don't want to hear it. This
whole thing with jinx. This is your mess,
not mine.
Come on, Odie.
Can't let you do that.
We'll be watching you.
Like a hawk.
Is today a Monday? Because it feels an
awful lot like a Monday.
It's Thursday.
Not to me it's not.
Look, I know this isn't ideal, but we have
to do this.
So let's just try and make the best of our
time together.
Our time together? What are you talking
about?
Once we get this milk, I want you out of
my life. Forever.
Alright, just relax.
Lactose Farms ain't nothing but a sleepy
little mom and pop dairy.
This will be a quick grab and go. You'll
be back home before you know it.
So how do we even get to Lactose Farms?
It's way out in the country.
You ever jumped a train?
I've never jumped.
Well, if jumping a train is too hard, just
say it.
How hard can it be?
Exactly!
This is gonna be fun!
Garfield? Odie? Hello?
Garfield, how many times have I told you
to close the refrigerator door?
Wait, there's food on the floor.
He's never left food on the floor.
Garfield?
Garfield? Garfield? Garfield? Garfield?
Garfield!
Our best shot at jumping on the train is
here.
Hold on a sec, I'm just taking in the wind
speed, the direction of the sun, and
various angles.
Yes, I say we jump the train from right
here.
Didn't I just say that?
We've been on television a million times,
we'll need a hundred feet of rope.
Uh-huh, rope, yeah, okay.
We'll throw the rope over that branch,
right there.
Can you follow me?
And then, timing it just right, we swing
over as the train passes by and land on
top of the car.
Or we can do this!
Odie, jump boy!
Part of me wants to help him.
No, this is how he learns.
I don't know, it's kind of pricey. How
does it handle?
I'll take it!
See? I told you this was going to be fun.
You and I have different definitions of
fun.
Oh, finally, hello!
You've reached Find My Pet. If your pet is
lost, we're here to help.
Hi, yes, great! Okay, my orange tabby and
my dog are both missing, and I need your
help.
Please, listen carefully, as our menu
options have changed.
If you'd like to hear this call in
Spanish…
What?
Come on.
What do I press to talk to a real person?
346.
Garfield, where are you?
Okay, I think you've got to figure this
out.
Jinx, you can't be trusted. And you've got
to keep Junior safe.
You've got to figure out a way to get him
out of this.
Tell me, is it a burr? It hurts. You
pulled my hair.
Is it a bug? A bug?
Ow, owie, owie, owie, owie, owie.
Howdy.
You know what, Junior? This is going to be
good for you.
What will be good for me?
What are we doing?
We're about to steal a truck full of milk
from a dairy to pay back a deranged cat.
What part of that is going to be good for
me?
All of it! You can't even imagine the life
lessons you're going to learn.
Oh yeah, name one.
But for starters, you already know how to
get on a moving train.
I found it funny.
All I'm saying is that to break into a
dairy is going to take a few skills.
-I'm guessing a rounded, mush
-filled, overly pampered indoor cat like you doesn't have.
So, we need to toughen you up.
Toughen me up? Hey, I know tough, Vic.
You've obviously never been in an Olive
Garden that's run out of breadsticks.
Anyway, I'm never going to need those
skills you're talking about.
But you'll have them.
I'm never going to break into a dairy or
anything else.
Ever again.
You are missing the point.
You're going to learn to improvise, stick
on your feet, develop moves that'll come
in handy out there in the real world.
I wouldn't be in the real world if it
wasn't for you.
Too rude. You'd still be hanging upside
down in the mall.
No, I would be asleep at home.
I'd be out on life all together.
Look, I'm just a dad trying to teach his
son some skills.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no. You can't make
up for five years of not being around.
Ah, yes I can.
No, you can't.
I think I can.
In fact, you can't.
You really can't.
With your attitude, I can't.
Okay, whatever. Dad, wow, great lesson.
I'm done talking to you. You do not know
me. You don't know the first thing about
me.
I am not pampered. I'm not anything you
think I am.
Okay.
I'm just gonna say that blanket is not the
best idea.
Ah, fantastic. Thank you. I'll take it
from here.
Ah! Ah! They're everywhere! Get them off!
Get them off!
Get them off me!
What are you doing?
What'd you do?
See the chips. Spiders hate them.
See? Another life skill learned.
I think the words you're looking for are,
thank you pops.
No, the word I'm looking for is…
Oh, here's that stop.
Nelly, where?
Oh, Odie, you'd think he'd see that
coming.
Quaint. Just a simple little grab and go.
Okay. Okay, so they've done a few upgrades
since I was last here.
Stop being so dramatic. All we have to do
is climb the fence.
Wait, is that Otto?
Who? Otto! Of Otto and Ethel?
Uh, no clue who you're talking about.
He's one of the mascots of lactose farps.
See?
On the side of the barn?
I'll bet he knows how to get into that
place.
Leave him alone. Seems to be in a period
of meditation. Or depression.
Yes, he does.
This calls for tact, sensitivity, and
diplomacy.
Oh yeah? Where we supposed to get that?
I have it. In spades.
Watch. Maybe you'll learn something.
Excuse me. You're Otto, right?
Hmm.
I'm Garfield. A pleasure.
Go away.
I just wanted to say I am a huge fan.
I have eaten everything that has a picture
of your face on it.
I'm not that guy anymore.
I even loved that recalled probe alone
from a few years back.
Yeah. Anyways, here's the thing. Me and my
crew back there.
We were in a bit of a bind. Got ourselves
in a situation.
Long story short, we could use your help.
You're a fan, huh?
Oh yes. Big time.
Then sing the jingle.
Wow. I don't really sing on command. I'm
not a circus animal.
Sing it.
Really?
Black toast farms. Black toast farms.
We've got milks, butters, creams, and
cheeses.
More spirit.
As much as you want. As much as it
pleases.
Livelier.
Come and take a look and see what we got.
Cause what we got is a whole lotta lot.
Ha ha. Bop chee bop. Bibbidi bop bop chee
bop.
Tasty goodness is our motto. Brought to
you by Atlanata.
What was that for?
I hate that jingle.
You could have just told me to stop.
Let's go. Kids are waiting.
Odie, come back. Leave him alone. He might
punch you.
Was that Ethel?
A few years back, old man lactose was
forced out of business.
The corporation that took over separated
me from my Ethel.
Ethel!
You are my day!
You are my night!
I was put out to pasture.
She was put on display as part of the
tour.
I tried to get in there to break Ethel
free, but they stopped me every time.
Now I only see her six seconds twice a
day.
We feel you, Otto. Let's go, Junior. We'll
find another way to break in there.
What could you possibly want from that
place?
A couple quarts a meal.
A couple thousand quarts.
Good luck.
We'll take any helpful hint you have.
Pass.
I'm telling you, it's a life or death
situation.
I hope you've notified your next of kin.
What if we can get Ethel out? Or get you a
commemorative pin?
Where are we going to find a commemorative
pin?
Now pay attention. Here's the perimeter of
the plant.
And here are the two places you need to
go.
First, the truck with your milk is back
here.
And this delicate buttercup is my Ethel,
my North Star.
And reason for living is being kept by
those barbarians in a petting zoo.
Located here.
This cricket represents the electrical
room.
This snail, the refrigeration room.
This toadstool is the loading dock, where
you'll find the keys to the trucks.
Wait, what's the pinecone?
The pinecone is the cheese and butter
room.
Ooh! Cheese is my love language.
Now, for this briefing, I've done a quick
reading of your personalities
and have chosen tokens to represent each
of you.
You are the majestic bullfrog.
Oh, yeah. That feels right.
You are the curious and clever chipmunk.
And you…
Wait for it…
…are Roadkill.
Huh? What? Oh!
No, I get it. That's a good one, Otto.
Giving your new best friend Roadkill.
Seriously, though, what's my real token?
That is your real token.
Now, if you have any chance of succeeding…
Excuse me, can I switch to something
living?
Like the snail or the cricket?
You should have spoken up sooner.
At this point, it would be too confusing
to switch.
Sooner? But you just told me this five
seconds ago.
Come on, Roadkill. Focus.
Oh, really?
You give Vic the majestic bullfrog,
you give Odie the curious and clever
chipmunk,
and then you give me your new BFF,
Roadkill?
I mean, it feels disrespectful. Not gonna
lie.
What makes you think he's dead?
My eyes. I have eyes and can see.
It's a possum.
Their masters are playing dead.
-Well then, little Daniel Day
-possum here should do Shakespeare in the park.
Things aren't always what they seem.
You're right.
But in this case, they are.
What's the big deal? Possums play dead.
Oh, do they, Otto? Do they play dead? Do
possums play possum?
Is that what they do?
Yes. Possums are very clever.
Yeah, I'm sure he was until the day he ate
a pickup truck.
Just ignore him. Please, continue.
I'll just put this back where you had it.
The straightest line to the loading dock
is through the snail here,
then the cricket there, cut through the
toadstool and onto the rock.
Each of these rooms have their own set of
unique challenges.
Well, why can't we just go straight
through the pine cone?
You don't want to go through the pine
cone.
Looks like the straightest shot is through
the pine cone.
You like walking with those feet, do you?
You a fan of unimaginable pain and misery?
Then go through the pine cone.
Stay away from the pine cone.
Got it.
Once you're inside the facility, you will
enter the electrical room.
There you will locate the air vent, pop
the grate, and climb up.
Then you'll crawl through a maze of vents
and drop down to the refrigeration room.
-Next, you will need to hurl your body over a 30
-foot drop to a series of hand runs.
You'll propel yourselves hand over hand
and drop down directly into a loading
dock.
From there, you'll locate the keys to the
milk truck.
Drive that truck to the west pasture of
the complex.
Cut the lock on the gate and find the
closest thing we have to an angel here on
Earth.
You'll escort my sweet Ethel onto the
truck and drive her to freedom.
It's going to take mad skills to get that
milk and free my dear sweet Ethel.
Clearly, this one is qualified for the
mission, but I have some serious doubts
here
about all of this.
He's pointing to you, roadkill.
Let's get to work.
Stupid roadkill.
Hey! I'm working here!
Uh, definitely a Monday.
Your call is fairly important to us.
If you've lost a cat, please press 1.
If your cat is orange, please press 2.
This doesn't really accomplish anything,
but gives you the false sense that we're
engaged with you.
Aw!
Alright gentlemen, I've made a list of
skills that you'll need to master in order
to break into lactose farms.
Number one, develop lightning fast
reflexes.
You tell Garfield there's a plate of pasta
on the other side of that wall and you
will see lightning reflexes.
Yeah, no, no, no. Depends what kind of
pasta.
This pebble represents danger you may
encounter.
You need to grab it before it grabs you.
Ha! It grabs me.
I snatch the pebble from my hand.
Too slow!
Ow! What was that for?
Being able to grab the pebble could be the
difference between life and death.
Alright, let me try that again.
Ha! Got it!
Ah! Now what was that for?
It's never just about the pebble.
Come on junior, everyone knows that.
Your head's got to be on a swivel at all
times.
Gotta be ready for anything.
I was ready. He changed the game.
Sounds like someone's making excuses.
And what was that about being ready for
anything?
You were dissecting me!
Might I suggest putting your head on a
swivel?
You should have seen that coming.
Toes on the line.
Guard your grill.
Cover your stomach.
There are surprises around every corner at
Lactose Farms.
You need to stay alert.
Too slow.
A baby could have seen that coming.
You'll never make it through Lactose Farms
if you can't survive this.
Are you for real? What kind of dairy is
this?
The kind of dairy that requires teamwork
to survive.
Danger could be anywhere, gentlemen.
You've got to be ready to outrun it.
Here comes the babe!
Left, right, left, right!
You're confusing me.
Shhhh!
I think I'm gonna need rehab.
If this is going to work, these two have
to be on the same page.
I'm out of ideas. You got any?
Can't believe I'm out in the middle of
nowhere getting beaten up against my will
by a former celebrity steer.
Odie?
Can you tell my son to please stop
whining?
Odie, can you tell Vic that I collapsed on
this tree first and that he needs to find
another one?
Odie, can you tell my son that I will
gladly find another one when I get the
feeling back in my legs?
Odie, can you tell my father that he
wouldn't be lying in pain if he let a
better life and didn't create problems for
himself?
Could you please inform my son that he
should focus on fixing his own issues?
Odie?
What?
What'd you do?
After all I've let you do for me.
What is this?
Hey! Watch it!
What's the problem, Vic? Is this bothering
you?
No!
Vic!
I don't mind it either!
I could watch this all day.
Stop pulling!
I'm not! You're pulling!
If I was pulling, you would know it!
Why does everything you do always end up
hurting me?
Hurt you?
All I ever did was try to help you!
Oh, you sure? Because every time you're
around it ends up with me in pain!
Odie, these ropes are not funny anymore!
Maybe if you were a little more open to
seeing me, things might be better between
us.
Oh, you do remember you were the one who
left me in an alley, right?
You don't know what you're talking about!
Then please, enlighten me.
This is about to get real.
Oh, that's right. You're normally never
around to actually defend yourself.
No back door to slink out of this time.
First you abandon me, then years later you
pull me into a life of crime.
Well, classic father of the year stuff,
Dad.
You know, why would I ever think that
seeing you could be anything other than a
train wreck?
I did not leave you in that alley!
Oh, you did! You told me you'd come right
back! You never did!
No! That is not what happened.
Oh, please. You're probably on the run
from someone like Jinx and I was in the
way.
No. No, that…that night…that night was
different.
Hey, shoo, shoo! Get out of here!
Wait here, Junior. I'll be right back.
Oh, hey, get out of here!
Hey, how you doing? Yeah, yeah.
Uh, I had to show you a cat. Yeah, yeah,
digging in the trash.
Yeah, heh, heh, heh.
So what you up to now, huh? Still taking
it easy?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
What? Oh, no, you're kidding. Really?
Oh, yeah, yeah. It's been raining here for
a while now.
Heh, heh, yeah.
Yeah, I'll see you then. Okay, bye.
Bye.
I…I never knew.
I know. How could you?
Why didn't you ever come visit me?
I did.
A million times I came to knock on your
door and I'd see what a great life you had
with Jon.
And so I just…thought it was better if I
kept my distance.
I sense a positive breakthrough in your
relationship. Am I wrong?
Good. After an extensive evaluation, I
have concluded that you two are, in fact,
ready to move forward with this mission.
We are? How is that even possible?
Mathematically, it isn't.
But given your present levels of
incompetence and overall lack of basic
skills…
I have determined it would take roughly 17
years to get you both properly ready for
this job.
And since we have less than 48 hours,
you've passed.
Congratulations.
Mm-hmm.
Alouette, gente, alouette. Alouette, je te
plumerai. Je te plumerai la tête. Je te
plumerai la tête.
Il a tête. Il a tête. Alouette. Il a tête.
Ahem.
She's really losing it.
Yes, what is it?
They're ready to rob the dairy.
Perfect. Everything is going to plan. Now
it's time to make a call.
Excuse me, you keep that thing in your
folds? That is so disgusting.
You! You dial the number and put me on
speaker.
Hello?
Hello, Blacktoast Farms.
It's come to my attention that there'll be
an attempt to rob one of your dairy trucks
tomorrow.
It's not important who I am or how I came
to know this.
Just think of me as a concerned citizen
intent on fulfilling my civic
responsibility as well as…
Uh, Chief?
We may have a situation.
Well, okay then. Let's go have a look-see.
This is the third time they've called.
It just sounds like some cat prank calling
us.
If it were a dog barking, I'd be on board
for a prank.
Them dogs are born for mischief, they just
are.
Not cats.
Oh no. Cats mean business.
I repeat, there will be an attempt to make
off with one of your milk trucks tomorrow.
I suggest you take appropriate measures to
prevent this brazen thievery. What an evil
genius I am.
Well then, still seem like a prank to you.
That last part did a little.
What's our next move, Chief?
Our next move is for me to go back to my
office and formulate an ingenious plan.
Then you go get my car waxed.
Well, well, well. Would you look at that,
Margie Malone. We're having company
tomorrow.
I guess I better take out my finest china
to serve a heaping plate…
…of justice.
What are those for?
For us to communicate. Once you're inside,
the belly of the beast.
Okay, don't we need something more like
radio headsets?
Indoor cat. These are better.
It just feels like bluetooth would be
better.
These are better than bluetooth.
They're equal. And I don't have to pay for
the brand.
Gold Eagle to Chipmunk. Do you copy?
Of course you can hear him. He's standing
three feet away from you.
Oh, I see you sprung for the binoculars.
Now, we just need to find…
…a way in.
Anyone ever told you that you take a lot
of dramatic pauses when you speak?
Yes.
Mmm.
Hello, everyone, and welcome to the one
and only Lactose Farms.
If you will all gather around me, we'll
begin our tour and head into the heart of
the farm.
I know you're here. I can feel it.
Show yourself.
Today, you will discover the answers to
all of your dairy questions,
including the most asked dairy question of
all time,
our curds the way.
Ballfrog, Chipmunk, Roadkill, do you copy?
Are you kidding me? They actually work?
You should take this to Shark Tank.
Now remember, the only way to get the keys
to the milk truck and free ethylene
detected
is by sticking to the path I mapped out
for you.
If you deviate from that path, you will
trigger security and all bets are off.
Understood?
All right, look alive. The electrical
access door should be coming up on your
left.
Okay, this way.
Hey, hey, look. There it is.
Okay, we're in.
Continue through and locate the air vent
at the end of the hallway.
That will take you to the refrigeration
room.
Factory workers, your fifteen minute break
begins now.
Oh, your feet need a deep rinse.
That's a hold up, Junior. How do you get
through this? You're bigger than me.
Am I?
Yes.
Well, the vent doesn't agree.
Try sucking in your gut.
I am.
Try sucking in your butt and your gut.
No! No! No! No! It's a alarm!
Bullfrog, what's happening now?
We fell out of the vent into a room that
looks like it's full of heavy machinery.
Son of a cud.
You and the pine cone.
Jiminy Davis! The perp is the cat!
And this one looks like it could eat us
out of business.
Oh Vic, Vic! Look! There's the loading
dock!
No, Junior! Don't move!
What? Why?
We're in the middle of the pine cone!
Otto told us to stay out of the pine cone!
Oh stop, there's no pine cone. Otto's a
bit of a worry ward.
I can walk to the loading dock from here.
No, Junior! Junior!
Oh, cheddar. Probably one of my top 26
favorite cheeses.
What do you think happens when that gets
to zero?
Bullfrog! What's happening now?
Roadkill got catered way into the pine
cone!
Listen to me. You have to carry on with
the mission.
Get to the loading dock before the workers
return from their break,
or you'll miss your only chance to get
that truck.
No, no, no! No, no, no, no!
Shred sequence initiated.
Cody! Thanks buddy, but I'm pretty full
from the cheddar.
Oh! Jump off! Yeah, yeah. Good idea!
Oh good, he's safe.
Hang on, where am I going?
Fondue! Fondue!
Junior!
That was too close even for me.
Thanks.
Yeah, I couldn't let you have all the fun.
Workers, your break ends in five minutes.
Okay Otto, we're in the loading dock.
Where are the keys?
They should be hanging on a pegboard on
the far wall.
What do you mean we have a problem?
Uh, pegboard's empty.
Empty?
Now would you look at this.
Three misguided stray pets trying to steal
a truck of milk.
It's never a dull moment at this dairy, is
there Margie?
Well, you're looking for these, aren't
you?
Well, here you go then.
So how's this gonna play out fellas?
The easy way or the hard way?
Well, just so you know, I'm up for either.
Follow my lead.
Huh? What?
Who's next then?
Otto, a security guard has the truck keys!
Crazy eyes? Tragic sense of fashion?
Yeah, how did you know?
Marge Malone.
Otto!
She's not just my nemesis, she's also my…
enemy.
Love to hear about it, but right now, what
do we do?
Get those keys. I'll create a distraction
so you can get out of there.
Come here, you!
Did you see that? That's indoor cat style.
Gah!
No, no, no, no. You're not getting away.
I've already called the pound.
Your days of thievery end today.
Jim, sorry about this.
Sorry?
For what?
Vic?
What are you doing?
Vic! Don't you go! Vic!
Please!
Send security to the loading dock.
You do not want to try me today, mister.
Welcome back.
Victor?
Oh, hey, Jinx. Why are you here? I was
bringing this to you.
Were you? Really?
Yeah, of course I was. That's what we
agreed to, right?
So, you and me square now?
Not quite.
There's still the matter of those five
years I lost because of you.
What? But I thought this settled that.
It was never about the milk.
It was about you getting caught trying to
steal it and being sent to the pound. Like
I was.
You see, Vic. I needed you to suffer. Like
I did.
I see. And I'm guessing you have an idea
about how that should happen.
As a matter of fact, I do.
I can't believe he did that. He ran out
and he left me.
Again.
I thought he'd changed, but it was… it was
a lie. All of it.
How could I have been so stupid?
Oh…
Oh, come on, kid. Don't beat yourself up.
Vic, man. We've all been burned by Vic.
Yeah, that's right. He's burned every cat
I know.
Oh, yeah. The one thing about Vic you can
count on is that you can't count on him.
Tell me about it.
Yeah, I'll tell you about it. Long story
short, we all used to run in the pack
until we had to kick him out the crew.
Like I said, couldn't count on him.
Sounds about right.
He'd leave in the middle of a job just to
go see his kid.
Yeah, he said he wanted to check up on
him. Make sure he was doing okay.
But get this. He'd never actually visit.
He'd just sit across the street from his
kid's house in a giant oak tree.
That never happened.
He'd watch that kid eat and eat and eat
and eat.
He'd put a notch in the park and eat every
time he was there.
Yeah, sure he did.
He'd go every Sunday night, rain or shine.
Said it was his kid's family dinner night.
Wish I had a family.
Okay, hate to tell you guys, I guarantee
that never happened.
Okay? You all fell for another one of
Vic's lies.
We all have.
Because that's what he does best.
Where?
Odie! Odie! How did you get out? Quick!
Pick the lock on my cage!
Garfield! There you are!
John! Take me away from all of this!
You can't imagine what I've been through.
You want this one too?
Oh, yes I do.
You sure he's yours? He didn't have a tag.
Oh, he has a tag.
I have a collar and a tag? How long have I
had those?
Okay, I'm just gonna need you to hold.
I will not hold! I am done holding!
John, who was on hold is dead! Do you
understand?
That's right. I'm back, baby.
I was just talking about you, wasn't I?
Oh, I've missed you too.
Pookie!
I have a lot to tell you. You're never
gonna believe it.
Crazy stuff happened. I slept outside.
Twice!
I know! Me! Oh, and I got you this
commemorative pin?
Dinner time!
Talk later!
Say when?
Never, John! Bury me in cheese!
I have two more in the freezer. Let me
know when you want them.
I'm gonna go check on dessert.
Oh, I apologize in advance.
The eating you're about to see will not be
pretty.
And if you have young children, this would
be a good time for them to leave the room.
Oh, I know, I know. We're coming back.
I just need to check something out first.
He put a notch in the bark.
Every time he was there.
Ah!
He left a notch.
Yeah, right.
He was here.
He saw me grow up.
Oh, ow! Wow, that really stinks. I don't
know why I didn't think it would.
Give me a second.
Vic loves us. Me first, of course, but
then you, too. But me? A lot! And first!
Wait, but if he loves me…
Us? Why would he let us get captured at
the dairy?
Unless…
He wanted us to get captured!
Yes, he knew that Jinx wasn't gonna let
him off the hook, but if we got caught,
we'd get sent to the pound, and John would
come to get us!
Don't you see, Odie? He was trying to save
us!
We have to go save my dad.
And here's your favorite dessert, Mt.
Canditoa!
Uh, guys?
Oh, come on!
What is this?
Half a star for Mama Leonis?
She's a monster.
She's gonna tie him up, take him on a
train…
She's going to throw him off the Mile High
Bridge!
We're gonna need help.
Who can we call?
-You got a lot of waxy buildup. What's your Q
-tip for Dean?
You're right, you're right. We can deal
with that situation later.
Hello? Hello? Is anyone there? Hello?
I can see you someplace.
Otto! Otto? Please, listen.
I want to make good on our original deal,
but…
But I need a favor first.
Otto, are you still there, or are you
taking a dramatic pause?
I'm listening.
You know, Vic, you only have yourself to
blame for this.
Right. Look, there's got to be some way
for me to make this right.
I mean, I know we can think of something.
Oh, there is.
And you will.
So once I get on the train, I untie Vic
and we jump off right as the train gets to
the bridge.
Correct. Chipmunk will be waiting for you.
Confirm your status, Chipmunk.
If you don't jump right as the train gets
to the bridge, you'll miss the net.
Got it. It's getting close.
Have you considered throwing a rope over a
branch and just swinging onto the passing
train instead?
You watch too much TV.
I've never watched TV.
Well, this weighs much better than your
rope idea.
Better than the versatile, reliable rope?
Look, I've studied the science. I know
what I'm doing.
And you think you can battle these
villains on your own?
Oh, yeah. I have a plan.
Odie, make the order.
Now get ready to fling me in the direction
of that moving train.
Get ready.
If I don't make it back, tell my story.
Rokyo, you're too high. You're going to
miss it.
No, no. This is how you do it. It's called
the ricochet approach.
It won't be long now. I can't tell you how
excited I am for what's about to happen
next.
Dad, I'm here to rescue you.
No, no, no, no, no, Junior. Get out of
here.
I'm going to untie you and we're going to
jump off the train.
Just leave me and go.
I didn't come this far just to turn
around. Let me untie you.
You're ruining everything.
Quick, this way.
Oh, you half-weight. Get them.
The bridge is coming up. We got to get to
the caboose now.
What? What?
Just follow my lead.
Oi, kitty cat. Did you expect to take us
on all by yourself?
No, I brought takeout.
Whoa.
I never understood the purpose of salad
until this exact moment.
Go, go. Now.
Get after him.
Oh.
Ow.
Yeah, in case you were wondering, I do my
own stunts.
Me and Tom Cruise.
Junior.
Whoa.
Stop him.
Now, that's amazing. I can't feel my
tongue.
Roadkill, are you at the caboose ready to
jump?
Dad. Dad.
Jump, Junior. I'll catch you.
What do we do now?
We do this.
See you, everyone.
The net's too tight.
Roadkill, the net is too tight.
I heard.
Hello again. Welcome back. Now, where were
we?
Don't throw them over just yet.
I want to find the perfect place for them
to make the biggest splat.
Hey, Junior. Junior.
Get ready. Almost there.
I'm sorry my rescue didn't work out.
No, you gave me another chance.
That's all that matters.
Now, now. Drop them now.
What are you waiting for?
Their love for one another indicates that
despite their current circumstances,
they are at peace because they are
together.
So?
If the point of your revenge was to hurt
them, it has done the opposite.
It's actually textbook irony.
And we're no longer comfortable with your
plan.
You two are still as weak as you were when
I found you sniveling in the pond.
No one will adopt us. I never grew into my
fold.
I hide behind them because I'm socially
awkward.
Please, somebody love me, even though I
can't sit still for more than ten seconds
and have the attention span of a bloody
goldfish.
We did everything you ever asked of us.
I even spoke with this ridiculous accent
to make you feel more at home.
But no more. I'm New York, loud and proud.
I love myself the way I am.
And I'm a big, brave boy, baby.
And I've been working on my attention
span.
Is that a hot air balloon?
You two.
What? Yes!
You have a beautiful body, sir.
Oh dear.
Rope. Versatile. Reliable.
There's something about your cadence that
really throws me, but thank you.
Tossing me off the train.
I did not see that coming.
Well, when you live in the wild, you gotta
keep your head on a swivel.
Right.
It's basic outdoor cat 101 and that head
bird poop on it.
Hey, you good roadkill?
Not quite. There's one last thing to take
care of.
Cut to…
It was a dark and foggy night.
The air was damp and heavier than a broken
heart.
On nights like this, you can't swing a cat
without hitting shady characters making
shady deals all over town.
Oh, but this night was going to be
different.
Justice was about to be served with the
helping of retribution on the side.
Is that the package?
It is.
Then we have a deal.
No one will come looking for her?
Nope. I did what you said. I burned her
paperwork and then shredded it and burned
it some more.
It's like she never existed.
Except for the image of her face and
millions of dairy products.
This never happened.
Agreed.
Oh, save it, cat fancy. I know you planned
the milk truck heist and then tried to
throw those innocent cats off a train to
cover it up.
The boys told me everything.
You are my day.
You are my night.
Well, this is us.
Right. You're home.
Listen, I just want to say I'm sorry.
What are you sorry for?
For misjudging you.
Oh, well, thanks.
-Well, I just wanted to apologize to you for
Everything bad that happened to us the
last three days?
You know, you had your hand on a few bad
decisions back there too.
Yeah, I'm sorry for dragging you into my
world.
This is where you belong.
Here was John and…
What's your name again?
Odor?
So, um…
Yeah, I should go.
Yeah, yeah. I mean, unless you'd want to
come in.
Nah, nah, nah. I don't think that would
work.
I'm an outdoor cat.
Right, sure, sure. No, I just, I figured-
No, no, no, no. I get it.
-But you know, I got this thing on the other side of town I gotta go do, so
I'm very busy too.
See you around then?
You know where to find me.
In the kitchen?
Well, take care.
And remember, stay out of the pine cone.
What? You heard him.
It's for the best.
Ah! Ah! You're back! What is going on? Are
you okay?
I was so worried. I was going to add more
locks to the door, you know, try to keep
you in,
but then I thought, well, what if they
wanted to be outdoor pets? Do you want to
be free range?
Oh, I really missed you guys and I gotta
say it's great to be together again, the
whole entire family.
Give me that. I asked him to stay.
He wanted to leave.
You heard him. He said he had to-
Fine. I'll be right back.
Wait, wait, what?
Am I using trigger words that I'm not
aware of?
So you coming in or do we have to bring
food up there to you?
I'll come to you. I just need to finish
something up here.
You know, those notches show how much you
love me.
Is that what you think they mean?
Yeah.
I was just counting how many slices of
lasagna you ate.
My medium is cuisine. My colors are
flavors. My palate is my palate, if you
will.
Dinner is served.
Wow, son, I didn't know you could cook.
Ah yes, pasta is my paint and the dinner
plate is my canvas.
Oh, that's where that went.
I've had worse.
Thank you, Garfield.
Is he going to be coming around for dinner
often?
Yeah, he's family.
What? Why do I have a takeout bill for
6,000 drone deliveries?
Let it roll.
I wish I could have had a warning, but
I've got things to do, people to see.
Everybody wanna get a piece of me, so I
tell you what I do.
I let it roll when your body can't catch
the feeling, when your feet are stuck on
the ceiling.
When your rhyme runs out of reason, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Ahh!
I don't know where to go.
Still in the field and I'm back on the
run. I came in the party to have me some
fun.
I ride with these cats so I'm never alone.
DJ, please, could you play my song?
Wobble the wiggle, I slide off the back.
Pay no attention, my head in my hat.
Surprise the minute.
Ride some wrists and slide with me, the
sky's the limit.
I let it roll.
I let it ride.
L-I-G, L-I-G.
I let it go.
Let it go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Let it roll.
I let it ride.
When I'm spinning out and don't know where
to go, I let it roll.