commercial concert
Gee him in his hand.
I'm there, huh?
Oh, yeah, and then what part?
I'm facing Tr See
Whoa.
I need to get heavy
What the world needs now is love, sweet love is the only thing
That is just to know what the world needs now
It is love, sweet love, you know my death for so
But for everyone, tell me about it
Well I don't need another mountain
There are mountains and the inside is enough to cry
There are oceans and rivers and not to cross
Enough to last until the end of time
What the world needs now is love, sweet love
It is the only thing that is just to know what the world needs now
It is love, sweet love
TF
Oh, sorry.
Nothing good about it.
Get out!
Oh, it's all right.
No, get out.
Let's go, boys. Let's get this shoulder over.
Get out of here.
We need to find a mess on him.
Put your clothes on.
What the fuck?
You got a joke for me today?
Oh, my God.
All right, let's go, guys.
Fuck.
Get him out the ground.
Move this fucking ass!
Fuck you!
Get the fuck out of here, Sam!
Get out of here, boys!
Yeah, it's been a crazy career, what?
I can't make it down the mountain.
You got a big day today. You better put on a heavy face.
Let's go, Arthur.
Come on, Fleck.
If only you're fancy lawyer, blame him and leave your late.
She knows what you like me, right?
Take Fleck, you got a joke for us today?
Yeah, it's been a while, hasn't it?
I'm sorry.
Let's go!
Back to fuck up, Kevin.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
From the line.
Fleck, you.
I'm sorry.
Fleck, you got a joke for me.
Go.
All the kids done since he got here is fucking smile.
Today, all of a sudden he bites Moran.
Because nobody likes Moran, he was a guy for a stay for like eight years before he got here.
He's still a fucking tent.
Fleck, you got a joke for us today?
I already asked.
I got a joke for you.
Why didn't you tell me the dog was Patrick?
Clean yourself up.
You like that one, Arthur?
Let's go.
Why didn't you tell me the dog?
Why didn't you tell me the dog was a cat?
Why?
I'm sorry.
The other half lives.
Could have been all yours if you hadn't killed Findings, no.
I love the show and it's portfolio.
I'm gonna get it.
Moira.
Hey.
Come on.
Jesus Christ, you couldn't get him a fucking umbrella.
Get her on there.
Today we're meeting with Dr. Beatty.
Remember her.
She's gonna be videotaping you this time
so we can show it at your competency hearing next week.
And if they find you competent,
and they will, they always do.
Then we're going to trial.
You need to be in an actual hospital
with actual doctors.
Not as department of corrections.
Bullshit.
Those thugs.
Dr. Beatty thinks
that with everything that happened to you
in your childhood,
it caused a split.
This fragmentation in you
to help me cope with your pain.
She believes you have another person
living inside of you.
And it was this other person
who committed those crimes.
Do you understand what that means, Arthur?
I'll be asking you a few questions today,
Arthur, okay?
Maybe you don't remember some things
or you're confused about what you did.
I'm here to help you try and sort out what happened.
Arthur, I'm not here only to help with your defense.
I'm here for you.
But for me to do my job,
I need you to be candid with me.
Does that make sense?
Can I have a cigarette?
Of course he can.
Who?
Yeah!
Let's start with the first incident, okay?
The three men who have costed you on the subway will bully you.
Did you feel like they triggered something painful from your past, your childhood?
Do you remember any of what happened?
Did you black out, see bright lights?
Okay.
How about Marie Franklin?
What if anything do you remember about that night?
The music.
That's good?
After that is good?
Can I tell you what I remember about that night?
I remember.
You came out just as Joker.
And I remember Joker dancing to that music.
Right?
I really like his band.
My mom and I used to watch it.
They show together.
She like Marie Franklin as well.
They stole a handsome look at those bare-wood ones here.
Is that your mother's voice?
Do you often hear her voice in your head?
I was alright.
Did it change at all after she died?
What does that mean?
Did you...
This other part of you...
Joker...
Did it come out more after she died?
You lived together, right? In a one-bedroom apartment?
Maybe I could talk to Joker about it.
Would he like to talk to me?
I don't know.
Hey Arthur!
Arthur!
The guard said, you wanted to show me how to kiss.
They said Joker's a really good kisser.
Nobody's ever gave me a kiss before.
You know, Ricky knows no one in.
No hesitation.
I gotta be honest with you Arthur.
I wouldn't have took you for a hopeless romantic.
Let's go!
You chose it. Line up back to him.
You're a really serious...
I haven't been serious.
In the Bible.
It wasn't that hard either.
And since they made that TV movie about you,
everybody's still a thing here to star.
How about you Arthur?
Do you still think you're a star?
I bet you do, don't you?
I said that's life.
Not right now, sir.
That's a million.
That's life.
That's a lot of people say.
I'm a king.
I've been up and down and over and out.
And I know one thing.
Each time I find myself in flames, I know my face.
I just take myself up and get back in the race.
And I'm funny, and I'm funny.
And I can't deny it.
Many times I thought I'd come now.
But my heart was fine.
But if there's no winch, it'd come to see a drive.
I'm gonna roll myself up in a big ball.
In my...
Let's go.
You are the...
Shut down at the cannon this morning.
I'll let these things...
Let's go.
Oh, when the saints go marching in...
I wanna be in that number when the men are at the party day.
This is a time when the men are happy.
We're singing together again.
We're singing together.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
A group I want you to welcome Arthur to play.
Now I know it's odd to have an inmate from E-Warden here,
but I've been assured he's been a model patient without any incidents.
I know this might feel strange, Mr. Flick, a new environment.
You see, we use music in this class to make us whole,
to balance the conflicting forces, the...
the fractures within ourselves.
All I ask is that you sing, if and when you're ready to sing.
Okay, let's go.
I'm on this radio.
I can't wait.
I know it's...
Is it really you?
Yeah?
Yeah, I want to go.
Yeah, I can't sing.
I got the world on a string, second on a rainbow.
Got this string around my finger.
And then we'll sleep.
Arthur.
I know.
So what's a nice guy located in a place like this?
I can't find people.
More in my financial television.
What about you?
I set fire to my parents apartment building.
Actually...
I'm six.
No, we must probably come in my mother.
I should have done that.
My mother had me committed.
She says I'm psychotic.
You know, most of us, that TV movie they made about you like 20 times.
Yeah.
Really bad?
Don't want to let me watch it.
It was good.
It was really good.
I grew up in the same neighborhood.
Me and my friends used to take that staircase to school every day.
My parents didn't give a fuck about me either.
My father beat the shit out of me.
Well, guess what?
Knock knock.
Sorry, kid.
Your dad was killing a car accident.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
If only those friends could see me now.
When I first saw Joker,
when I saw you and Murray Franklin,
the whole time I was watching, I kept thinking,
I hope this guy blows his brains out.
And then you did.
And for once in my life,
I didn't feel so alone anymore.
Forget your troubles.
Come on.
Get happy.
Better chase all your cares than play.
See, hallelujah.
Come on.
Get happy.
And before the judgment.
Son, you're shining.
Come on.
Get happy.
Lord, he's waiting to take your hand.
Sing hallelujah.
Come on.
Get happy.
Hey, Jackie.
You wanna know what I've ever read most from being on Murray Franklin show?
What's that?
That I didn't shoot first to let him ask me questions later.
That a joke, Arthur.
Yeah.
How long it took was you getting a little old-fashioned?
Thanks, pal.
That's good to medication.
Not guilty by reason of insanity makes no sense in this case.
And his...
A flag.
He acts violent.
You're in the noise.
I'm in the noise.
I'm in our city.
But I'm in our city.
I'm in the noise.
I'm in our city.
But all over the country.
I'm in the noise.
Our friends are million people.
Judge says he's confident to stand trial.
I'm still in the noise.
He's fucking new.
These people...
They believe Arthur Fleck to be some kind of...
Marvin.
Well, he's not.
Arthur Fleck is a monster for you exactly what he was doing.
And our office will be seeking the death penalty.
Thank you.
Oh, that's...
Yes, sir.
You hear that, Fleck?
The death penalty.
They're gonna fry you out of here.
How does that feel?
For once in my life,
I have someone who needs me.
Someone I've needed so long.
For once,
I'm afraid
I can go where life leads me.
Somehow, I'll know I'll be strong.
For once I can touch
For my heart used to dream of
Long before I knew
Someone more like you
Make my dreams come true
For once in my life,
I won't let sorrow hurt me
Not like it's hurt me before
For once I have someone
I know will desert me
And I'm not alone anymore
For once I can say this is mine
You can't take it
Long as I know I've got love
I can take it
For once in my life,
I've got someone who needs me.
For once I can say this is mine
You can't take it
Long as I know I've got love
I can make it
For once in my life,
I've got someone who needs me.
For once I can say this is mine
You can't take it
Long as I know I've got love
I can make it
For once in my life,
I've got someone
Who wants in my life,
I've got someone who wants in my life
I'm entering Arthur
How's it make you feel?
You scared?
No.
Stay.
We died, don't you?
Ha ha ha ha ha
Ha ha ha ha
Ha ha ha
No, you cannot give any statements to the press, even if Kellerman asked you to.
You know they've been out there all week.
This evening, they want to talk to me.
I told you before, I forgot that an exclusive interview next month, right before trial.
Okay, but, but Kellerman asked me to make a statement now.
He was letting me go to this meeting night. You're like an old person.
What are you telling me you have?
Come on, last time.
Okay, um, yeah, I'm sorry, after that.
I told you.
Okay, let's move it.
Hang on, Frank. He's signing my book.
Like a quick Arthur, I don't want to miss the beginning.
But, in court, the fortune when they rise in the house.
Easy now.
Let's go.
I'm using the whole musical. I'm sick of these articles and barriers between the musical and the drama.
Well, then you certainly don't need me.
Yes, we do, because you can be greater than you ever were.
We are going to make her explode on the fear to seem like a skyrocket,
not just in the old tray barf with the top hat diet tails, but a great asset to the degree of his power.
Then you've told me a hundred.
I'm not kidding.
Don't you?
I know that.
Everything's going to work out.
Shh.
Well, what do you think I am? What do you think they are?
What do you think they're the other? Is it all entertainment?
Believe me.
There is no difference between the magic rhythms of Bill Robinson's immortal feet you said before.
All right, all right.
Well, what did Bill Robinson do? He doubts him the stairs, didn't he?
Now, I happened to play either, but the King of the same stairs was the difference when all the ideas were.
Show me the laws, let those comic and burn, let's deny, show you, let's entertain her.
We're all, and uh...
Aah!
Look at this song.
Everything that happens in life can happen in a show.
You can make a laugh, you can make a cry, anything, anything can go.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Once MedUSHED And the H ASAP smiteenerrrrah
Let's go!
Yeah!
They could see me now, that little king of mine.
Ohhhhhh!
I'm looking at your smile and it's a healthy sign.
I'd like the stumble bones to see for a friend.
The kind of tough, poor, first free,
I'm going to show you how you do it.
I can't believe that.
I told you when we get out of here.
That crazy.
All I can say is, wow, just look at where I am.
Tonight I landed in pop, right in my car, love jam.
What I said, I'm the only gal.
I'll never believe it if my friends could save me.
Oh, fuck!
God, this is me.
Susan, this is our family now, won't it?
If they could see me now, that little dusty group.
Chicks around this million dollar to give to a Roman elbow
and the cream of the prop to ever send their ain't no one at the time.
I'm going to think the same as that,
which I must say is,
each to pick an unknown gal,
which I'll look down at me,
but I'll still go well,
calling gal, no, never believe it if my friends could save me,
if my friends could save me,
if they all could go to jail.
Oh!
Get the fuck off!
No!
That's all.
That's the bottom of the left.
I want to play games on my watch, Arthur.
Who weeks is all of you?
Oh!
Julia, stay.
MUSIC
Take my hand
Stay here, my friend.
I'll find my way back to you.
Here and all, I know somehow
we tell a story that's true.
In our minds, we'd be just fine
if it were only us two.
There might say that we're crazy,
but I'm just still alive with you.
There's my guy.
I'm in a row right here.
Yeah.
One of the cards let me in.
I'd do anything for you,
but we don't have a lot of time.
Come here.
Can you get up?
Come into the light.
They're sending me home.
Why?
They're saying you're a bad influence on me.
Good.
This is going to be good for us.
Now I can be at your trial every day.
I can see you every day until you get up.
No, no, no.
I'm not.
We're going to build a map.
Wait a minute.
You're perfect.
I want to see the room.
I'm not.
Look what they did here.
It's just us now.
You need to start taking your medication.
I'm over to you.
I'm over here.
Keep going.
Here.
I'm over here.
What are you going to ask me about?
Besides, no.
Hopefully about your life and your conditions are really like in this place.
I'd ask you about me.
She's been out there giving a lot of interviews about you and about herself.
Good.
I love her.
She gets me.
Arthur, this is a chance for you to show a different side.
Show a different side of yourself.
The public can see who you really are.
I don't think you should smoke.
I think it makes you a cavalier.
We need to use this time to show people that you're human.
They need to understand you are sick, delusional.
You're not joker or girth or fleck.
Hmm?
Don't worry.
You're going to be great.
Arthur!
Are you okay?
It's not too late to cancel.
So, uh, you want me to call you Arthur or the joker?
Mr. Myers, you know we have an agreement you can't call him joker, it's Arthur.
Arthur, fleck.
Are you ready, buddy?
She has to leave now.
You can watch from behind the glass, but you can't be in here.
Brain's up.
Well, Patty, um...
I was going through a lot back then.
Um, I don't really remember much from that night.
Uh, blacked out, saw bright lights.
I was having a hard time knowing the difference between what was real or not.
Oh, please?
You did it on live TV pal.
It wasn't getting any more real than that.
How do you all remember from that night is I was going to kill myself on television.
I thought Murray was playing a part in my show, but he was a bad actor.
So he got what he deserved.
The last joke, if we can call it a joke.
You get what you bleeping deserve, that's what you said.
That's not funny, that's not funny.
You're right, I thought it's a little better one.
You're trying to be funny now?
Yeah.
Do you deserve to die?
The DA is calling for the death penalty.
You just said that you wanted to kill yourself on TV, so tell us.
You still want to die?
Well, at the time it certainly could have had these dreams for a little bit.
Um, but that's not me anymore.
That's not...
That's not who I am?
That wasn't really you.
No, that's not...
That's funny, that's straight.
That's not what I'm saying.
Your defense is...
It was the Joker who did it.
An insanity.
Okay, I don't know what other defense...
This alternate personality, this killer clown in you killed Murray.
Who am I speaking to now?
Which one of you is here?
The poor, low IQ author Fleck, or the Joker who go to the bunch of no-bit punks?
Do you really care?
You don't.
You just like Murray, you just like everyone.
You just...
You want sensationalism, you don't care about...
You just want something about my mistakes, and what's about the things that I did in the past,
what about who I am now?
Not how I'm different now.
That's what we should be talking about, Patty.
Okay, okay.
We should take a break.
We're not taking a break.
Come on.
Okay, so...
Tell us.
What's changed, Arthur?
I'll tell you what's changed, Patty.
I'm not alone anymore.
Right.
The girl who was singing, the night you tried to escape.
I wanted to try to escape.
Miss Harley Quenzel.
You two put on quite a performance that time.
Oh...
She didn't really sign through, isn't she?
You told me.
I mean, don't you think it's all...
I don't think it's a little too much.
A little much.
She's a fool, and I won't hide in her head.
But a fool can have her trust.
I'm in love, and don't ask her with.
I thought they'd been on.
Those the same old sad sensation.
Really, I've not slept a wink.
Since this half-punt.
In the torsion, put me on the blink.
I'm wild again.
Be wild again.
A semperine when we're in,
child again.
He wished...
Father, and be wilder.
Have I?
That's my heart, but what of it?
She is cool.
I agree.
She can love, and I love it.
Oh, wrong, wrong love, song.
I'll sing to her.
Things spring to her.
And long for the day,
that I cling to her.
Be wild.
I'll ever have you well knew.
Hey!
You're not mine.
We'll be back with more of Arthur Fleck.
And from what was was her son?
The murder trial of Arthur Fleck will begin today.
Assistant DA Harvey Dent is preparing his opening remarks
in what some are calling the trial of the century.
And once the protests, please will be on high alert,
to closing surrounding streets and setting up barricades for crowds that can reach in the thousands.
And be asking me, this is what you can when there's a complete breakdown in social services,
and don't get me started on this media frenzy.
All right, Denise, you're on the air.
Thank you for taking my call.
Enough is enough.
This idiot doesn't deserve a trial.
He should be sent straight to the chair.
An example should be made out of.
And we have a problem with you, too.
Good evening.
Home?
But away from her.
Oh
Listen
Okay
There is
Hey, shut the fuck up
I
Court is now in session the honorable judge Herman Rothwax is decided
Morning ladies and gentlemen, please be seated
William please invite the jury in
Are you all right mr. Flack
Everything okay? Here's your majesty. I'm just looking for someone
Please mr. Flack sit down I
Realize there's a lot going on
But this is still a court of law
Any and all outbursts will not be tolerated and applies to everyone in this courtroom
Cindy please call the case the people of the state of New York versus Arthur Flick case number GC
Oh
Walling down
actor
Where the hell would this mean?
That's entertainment
The lights on the lady and ties on the bride
With the guy on the side or the fold
Where she gives it a role
It's my view that there is absolutely no evidence that Arthur Fleck suffers from multiple personality disorder
Or that he ever behaved in the role of joker as a separate personality dissociated from himself
Doctor? In your opinion, concerning the work he did on this case
Do you believe Mr. Fleck suffers from a mental disease or defect?
No. In my opinion, he's not psychotic or unable to test reality
I think he was sane when you committed these crimes
In fact, I believe he fakes his mental illness
Why?
And if he's, uh, faking it, as you say
Then what is your opinion on the defendant's mental condition?
I believe he has four relatively minor and quite common mental disorders that involve long standing sadness
Narcissistic self-centeredness, friendlessness
And indifference to the feelings of others
This is a very disturbed individual
But I can't give you any kind of psychiatric defense
For you. Thank you, Dr. Love
Nothing further, Your Honor
Your witness, Ms. Stewart?
Dr. Lou, good morning
Good morning
How long did you interview Arthur Fleck for?
About two hours
It's actually 89 minutes
Tell me, how can you say for certain that Arthur isn't mentally ill?
How can you be so sure after just 89 minutes that this joker isn't a distinctly separate and split personality from him?
That that's not who he is
Well, I also reviewed all the test results, psychological tests, neurological and medical tests
And in my view, it's just a performance
Did you read the records from the Department of Social Services
That show that when Arthur was seven years old, they returned him to his abuser's home
His mother's home
I did, yes
And when you interviewed him for 89 minutes
Did you ask him why social services didn't believe the horrific stories a seven year old boy told him about the physical and sexual of abuse he suffered?
Yeah
Applause
No, I didn't ask him about that
So you want us to believe that after spending just 89 minutes with Arthur Fleck and reading through his records and tests from the same government agencies that abandoned him
You want us to believe that you can say with absolute certainty that Arthur doesn't suffer from any serious mental illness
That he didn't need to retreat into fantasy and create another identity to protect that scared, vulnerable
Seven year old boy from all the trauma and abuse he suffered
And that that identity didn't come out again
When he was attacked and tormented by three drunk bullies on the subway
Applause
After I woke up this morning, I thought, Murray, Murray, Murray
And then there's Murray, funny, right?
Then I remember Sophie, I had enough of it
Your Honor, again, my client's personal diary is privileged
Overroaled, again, as long as Mrs. Kane limits her comments to Mr. Fleck's personal private jokes to remember my quiet
These are your words, she's reading
And it's up to the jury to determine what to make of them
Please proceed
Mrs. Kane, please continue reading from the highlighted portion
Then I remember Sophie had another dream about her, forgot it
I almost never dreamed, what do I got to do to remember?
That's Sophie Dumont, Mr. Fleck's neighbor whom he was obsessed with
What was that date? November 17
Well, the record show, November 17th is the date of Mr. Fleck stabbed Randall Kleinman Hoffer to death
The very same day that he shot and killed Murray Frank
Now, I know it's not your area of expertise, but you have read all of Mr. Fleck's journal before, correct?
Yes, I have
And, in your opinion, does this sound like a different voice?
Like a different personality, wrote this?
No, it sounds like Arthur
Go on
He often wrote about his fantasies
And the women he had imaginary relationships with
And of course his jokes
There are always a lot of these unfunny jokes
There's justice, so I don't think she's even qualified to do that
You know, you're making him out to be a fucking idiot in there
He's never gonna get out if he keep this shit up
Ask her why she has me sitting so far away from him
Let's not do this here
Do you see all those people out front?
Who do you think they're here for?
How many T-shirts is Arthur Glenn on?
How many signs?
It's the tale of the century and she doesn't even know who her own client is
Can you see how sick he is?
How much help he needs?
He's not sick
He's perfect
You don't really think he's just gonna walk out of here, do you?
Yeah, he's gonna walk right out of here
With me by his side
And they want
And then we're gonna build him out
A what?
And a little help
What does that mean?
You're not listening
We can win in this case
And she's gonna fuck it all up
No, you're not listening
Please look now for me
She had a chance what I've been through
What are you talking about?
We're from the same neighborhood
She lost her father, you know
Her mom was awful to her
She had a commitment
So just give her a break
Okay, leave care of us about you, sure
I know
She didn't grow up in your neighborhood
She lives on the Upper West Side with her parents
Her father is not dead
He's a doctor
She voluntarily committed herself to the hospital
And then just checked herself out
When she wanted to
She didn't check herself out
Arthur
I was a bad influence on her, so they separated us
Did she mention she went to grad school for psychiatry?
You wouldn't get it
My point is
She's playing you for a fool
I'm sorry, I just
I know what it's like to love somebody
But I don't think he can believe a word she says
From MTV Studios
It's the
The
There's a light
I'm turning on a light
There's never a shot on me
All of the holes I've to be
Living with you
There's a way
Everybody says
To do each and every little thing
What the dust brings
If I ain't got you
Oh you don't know what it's like
Baby you don't know what it's like
To love somebody
The way I love you
Baby baby baby baby baby
You don't know what it's like
Baby you don't know what
What happened?
Well you weren't even looking at me anymore
You were making it all about yourself
And the song is about loving me
Now look who's making it all about themselves
So you're saying it's not about us?
It is
But we're singing for them
That's why we're here honey
As I got the speech suspicion
That we're not giving the people what they want
It's okay baby
You're right
Let's give the people what they want
Use it
Let's take a moment to
As the honeymoon over
First night
Everything went back
If you knew what it is
Just talk to me
It's chiels
I can't look for anything
I'm in the back
I've always Braised
You don't know what to do
Just though
Pause
Okay
Look
I love you.
A couple of weeks back on TV and already acting like you're on the joint.
What the fuck are you two doing sitting on our bleachers?
We said they're your bleachers.
Rippy, what the fuck has gotten it to you?
You heard me.
Up.
Just so I just saw you in front.
A little lady friend.
I'm not a lady.
I'm a lady.
A little lady friend.
All right, enough. Get up, both of you.
In fact, get a visit.
You're acting like I tell you.
Moving.
Every day of the casual.
You're a fucking wack job, flack.
I'm a wack job.
Hey.
Five minutes.
How you holding up?
Everything okay?
Did you, did you hide in me?
Sure.
I mean, everybody lies a little.
I'm a wack job.
Maybe not from the same neighborhood as me.
Dad's a doctor.
You rich?
I just wanted you to like me.
You really checked yourself in here?
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Just because you wanted to meet me?
Just to meet you.
And you could just really let her.
Then said what? I'm nobody.
I've been done anything with my life like you have.
You really watched that TV movie made about me 20 times?
Probably more like four or five.
It wasn't actually good or do you lie about that too?
It was great.
My lawyer says you're playing me for a four.
You're in a four.
Can't you say what she's doing?
They're laughing at you in there.
She doesn't care about you.
I do.
Do you know I moved into your old apartment building to make us a home for when you get up?
Did you learn to tell you that?
You did?
I don't want to live there.
I'm pregnant.
What?
Why do birds suddenly appear?
Every time you are near.
Just like me.
They love to be close to you.
Why do stars fall down from the sky?
Every time you walk by.
Just like me.
They long to be close to you.
On the day that you were born, the angels got together and decided to make a dream come true.
So they sprinkled mondust in your hair, cold and starlight in your eyes of moon.
That is why all the girls in town follow you all around.
Just like me.
They long to be close to you.
Did you think he was going to hurt you or your daughter?
I did.
Yes.
You believe he was dangerous?
He broke into my apartment.
You call it police?
No.
His mother told me that he had problems his whole life, but that he wouldn't hurt a fly.
And was the man who broke into your apartment that night?
Was he different in any way from the Arthur Fleck you and you?
I didn't really know him.
I saw him in the lobby, the elevator a few times.
Like I said, I knew his mother a little bit. She was really sweet to my daughter.
I missed your mond. Why is it that you didn't want to come here and testify today?
Why did you initially ignore our subpoenas?
Well, after Arthur did what he did, the press wanted to talk to me about it.
And then I was a character in that awful TV movie they made.
And then all these people, some foreigners I guess, like the people outside started showing up at my work.
And harassing me, blaming me for what happened to Arthur.
So I was afraid for my safety, for my daughter's safety, we moved out of the city.
Well, then why did you finally decide to comply?
I should have called the police that night.
Then maybe all those people wouldn't have been.
Maybe they wouldn't be dead now if I did.
Thank you. No more questions?
Your witness, Miss Stewart.
Miss Duman, what happened after you asked Arthur to leave your apartment bed?
He told me he was having a bad day. The name he left.
So, he never heard or even threatened your daughter?
No. And did you watch him on TV on Marie Franklin the following week?
He did.
And did that seem like the same man who was sitting in your apartment that night?
Did he sound the same or even look the same?
No, I mean, he was wearing clown makeup.
And while Arthur's mother was being so sweet to your daughter,
what was she telling you about her own son?
She told me that there was something wrong with Arthur, and that he lived in a fantasy world and that he had this laugh.
She told you it was a dumb laugh.
That's what she called it. His dumb laugh.
Yes.
What else did she tell you?
That she made up a story when he was a kid, so that he would feel better about it.
So that he would stop crying so that he wouldn't kill himself.
What was the story that he was put on this earth to bring joy?
Something like that. So I should call him happy.
And she couldn't believe that he faced his whole life around this made up story.
He was a straight clown and he wanted to be comedian.
She made fun of him for doing that.
She just thought it was ridiculous that he thought he'd make people laugh.
And she said Arthur was funny at all.
But she told you that he had been giving out a test to teach us all about it.
It's always the token.
In her pack, there's always a lonely cloud.
The poor laughing through the folds on his back.
And everyone laughs when he's down.
There's always the fun about him again.
But he's only funny by mistake.
And everyone looks at him.
Just the same.
They don't see his lonely heartbreak.
They don't care as long as they're just a fool.
As foolish as he can be.
There's always a joke about that's the rule.
But fate feels better than I seem.
The joke for me.
They don't care as long as they're just a fool.
As foolish as he can be.
There's always a joke about that's the rule.
But fate feels better than I seem.
The joke for me.
As me.
Yeah.
That he had never had a girlfriend.
And he thought he was probably his first ever.
I can't do this anymore.
Don't you want to be a pooch eventually?
No, you may not.
I want to borrow my lawyer.
Excuse me.
I'd like to represent myself.
You're fired.
Arson, let me do this.
This is fail.
You don't even believe in fail.
I'm sorry.
David.
It's great.
Thank you.
Hey, go touchy.
I'm so fucking proud of you.
You should see it out there. They're all going crazy for you.
You did it.
I know. We've asked you to read a walk or something.
You know I never went to a first school.
I said no touching.
You can do anything you want. You're Joker.
You're a good guy.
Good evening. It's 40 degrees at 6 o'clock on this Wednesday, November 8.
I'm Stan L. Brooks and here's what's happening.
Chocking developments at the trial of Arthur Fleck downtown today.
Fleck the accused killer, also known as Joker, interrupted testimony
in the court.
Then he kissed her goodbye.
Afterward Fleck was extensively questioned by Judge Herman Rothwax.
The right of self representation is not a license to abuse the dignity of the courtroom.
You can hear all your emotions, Mr. Fleck.
Judge Rothwax reluctantly approved Fleck's request to represent himself.
As long as he agreed to stand by counsel, a decision that both Fleck's now
and his report and assistant DA Harvey Dent disagree with.
It's really tragic. Arthur believes he has all of these supporters, but they don't care about him.
They care about Joker.
He is not dealing with reality. He's mentally ill.
It just convinced him it got him, but would have won this case.
Fleck knows what he's doing. He knows he's losing.
We can't look at it.
He's a kid.
It's almost like Arthur's flying.
He has a little bit of a try on the most of the month, but he's weird.
Very weird.
Hey, sit down.
Sit down.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, when they say take a fuck out, record.
I'm gonna have to get in a hot, win the same thing.
I'm gonna have to get out.
Get out.
All right, so's over.
Hell, no.
And the same thing for our game.
One, two, three.
So far, it's the same.
Oh, my God, the same thing for our game.
And the same.
One, two, three.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
After reviewing all the case law that offers precedent, Jensen versus Superior Court being
the most relevant, I've reluctantly decided that Mr. Fleck does have the right as an
attorney to dress himself how he likes as long as he doesn't cause disorder or
interfere with the functioning of the court. I will not allow this proceeding to become
as unruly as it is outside and I will not let you turn this into any more of a
circus than you already have. Mr. Dent, call your next witness.
The state calls Gary Puddles.
Beleth, you please escort Mr. Puddles to the stat.
Please raise your right hand. You solemnly swear that the testimony you're about to give
is the whole truth and nothing but the truth to help you God.
Good morning Mr. Puddles. Thank you for being here.
It's one last question sir. The person who you saw stabbed Randall Kleinman Hoffer to death.
Are they in this courtroom here today? Yes.
Can you point them out to all of us and describe this clothing?
You said right there at the table wearing a red suit and clown makeup.
May the record reflect the identification of the accused, Your Honor.
Yes it will. Nothing further, Your Honor.
Your witness Mr. Flack.
Mr. Puddles. Gary Puddles?
Tell me sir, is that your God given name?
Yes.
Hey, Billy, your last name is Puddles.
Why sounds like a joke.
Well it's not.
You expect us to believe that your last name is Puddles. Puddles?
Mr. Flack, where is this going?
As I said, I'm not going to let you turn my courtroom into a circus.
Okay, but with all the respect your holding on, you think it's a little late?
Don't try my patience.
Mr. Puddles.
This afternoon you testified that you saw me stab Mr. Kleinmanman Hoff in the neck a couple of tops. Correct?
Kleinman Hoff, yes, I saw you.
Mm, and what else did you see that day?
You're stabbing him in the eye and blessing his head into the wall many, many times.
Yes, but Randall was a bit of a bully wasn't he?
Didn't this end, Don?
No.
Never mind.
Gary, did you catch my ass on the lorry-freitling show later that time?
No, I didn't.
No?
But I remind you that you were under oath.
I was locked up at the police station in an interview room.
So I thought you might come and kill me.
I was there, they went there, they kept me there all night.
Isn't that cone beaming, Mr. Puddles?
You didn't see the show?
You didn't see anything?
I had to say, I can't believe it.
Mr. Fleck, okay.
When you were in my mama's apartment, God rest your soul.
When as you say you saw me, bass Mr. Kleinman, whatever's heading to the wall many, many times,
did I seem crazy to you?
Did I seem like a different person or was I the same old joker that I own?
Oh, so don't do this to yourself, it isn't you.
It isn't me.
So you don't think this is me?
Or maybe, maybe it can really was.
But I'm inside of it.
So maybe you want a million, maybe no one was.
Because nobody knew I existed.
But look around, look at all these people, everyone outside, these cameras.
Who do you think they see, Mr. Puddles?
Joker.
Oh, sweet child, what you are proving here today is that you are no different than any of those people that underestimated me.
From Murray Franklin to those goddamn fat stupid girls in awesome, I think that they could treat me like trash.
But I will no longer allow you or you or you or any of you to keep me down.
I am free!
Why are you doing this to me, Arthur?
What?
Gary, I like you.
I told you I wouldn't hurt you and I didn't.
Not hurt me.
I couldn't go back to work.
I still can't sleep.
I'm scared all the time.
I never used to be scared.
I'm scared right now, here.
It's you in front of me.
I couldn't do anything that day.
I felt so small.
It was reminding me how powerless I really am.
Oh, you got a flare for the dramatic.
You're tugging at my heartstrings, little Gary.
No more questions, Harlan?
Do you know what that feels like, Arthur?
You were the only one at work who never made fun of me.
You were the only one who was nice to me.
I said, no more questions, Harlan.
Very well, Mr. Post.
I never thanked you for your testimony.
Please step down, you're excused.
Mr. Dent, call your next witness.
We're not calling anymore witnesses, your Honor.
That is the state's case.
The state rest.
Very well.
All right, Mr. Fleck.
At this point, you may mount your defense.
The defense rest is very, Your Honor.
Are you?
Mr. Fleck, you don't want to put on any defense.
No, Your Honor, the defense rest.
No, no, no, no, no. That's all, folks.
All right, all right.
All right.
That's enough. This is the court of law.
Both sides having rested.
This court will recess until tomorrow morning at 9.30.
Man, I'm too short of it.
What about the idiot?
You're gonna fight with your myself.
They gotta stop it?
No, they don't get down everywhere!
And they'll stop it here once a year?
They got in there, right back?
They don't get down away.
That's enough.
It's really when they chain up your defense.
What's with this role?
Be careful, you just don't get up there.
No, I want to increase the force faster.
I want to make a difference.
Now, for six.
You press the cover.
Well, you know that every stop DNA is going to Mauiplier now.
We're gonna move forward.
They start, oh, I will
Gonna build a mountain
Gonna build a night
I don't know how we're gonna do it
Only know I could not try
Gonna build a so heavy
From a little hell
And I know long way out
And it comes in that mountain
Yeah, yeah, yeah
I'll take you up the mountain
And have you been waiting for them?
Gonna build a mountain
From a little hella
For you, thank you, and you
You're welcome, I'm with you
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah
Oh, yeah, look at that mountain
Look at that mountain
Gonna build a mountain
Oh, oh, oh, oh
2-1 left in a Hamilton
Come just go, go
Just drive all the animals
And have you been waiting for that
I'm gonna build a mountain
Be a lot of ya
And everyone's gonna be inside
Long build
Long build us
Long build us mountains
Lets build it
You're planted, planted, planted, planted
Overreamed and fallen down
You can Agriculture!
No, no, no
No, no
No, no!
week
Dancing in the moonlight
Everybody's real
I want my pride
It's just right
I want to say
Everybody's dancing
Like a fool
You can't take it
You stay up tight
If you see me
I'm gonna get you
I'm going to
You know, send my bullshit
I can't
Still busting my balls
I'm always good
See you fellas on the morning
Uh oh
I'm gonna show it all
Huh
See you in the morning
Why is everyone so upset with me
Look at your ass
Come on
I'm gonna turn you out
I will see you in a photo
I'm the fucking queen of sheep
Oh, come on now
Let's go
Yeah
Get up
Grab his legs man
Let's go
At the goal we have big shot on TV
We need not to sell that
Stand him up
Alright
You want your joke right?
You really think
I'm not gonna dance in that suit
I'm not gonna hear face makes you panicking
You have no fucking idea
What it takes
But a little bit of joy into this fucking place
Let me tell you what I used to do about my mother
You could drop the act
Because we know it's only after the day
Okay
It's only to be some guys
Yes, alright
And I asked her
I said mom
Why are you just playing with your abusive boyfriend
And she said
He's not on a beat
I told you that right man
He's almost on your own
I'm gonna try to get off of her by the joke first
Let's go there, go
Get up, get up
Fuck off
Okay, let's fucking ride
Get up, get up
Fuck off
You're business, fuck off
What'd you do to him?
Let the fuck off, Ricky
Thanks for coming, Jackie
This guy's coming
Go in the States
Go, fucking, fucking
What I want to be in the number
Get the States
Go, fucking, fucking
Get in the
No, no, no
No, no
Come here, Kevin
Get in the
Fucking company
I'm not getting asked for you
Are they talking now?
He's up?
I'm going to go
Can't break out of the shot
Fuck off
Hey, shut up
That's a ticket
He's up
Hey
What's going on?
How are you?
Docy
Hoo
Doesak
thin
I've got the world on a stream, said no in a rainbow,
thought that string around my finger,
what a world, what a life I'm in love.
I've got a song that I sing, I can make the rainbow,
anytime I move my finger, lucky me, can't you see I'm in love?
Life is a beautiful thing, as long as I hold that string,
I'd be a silly, so I'm sore, if I should ever let it go.
I've got the world on a stream, in love, said no in a rainbow,
thought that string around my finger, what a world.
Yeah, there ain't no other girl that I need.
Roll, roll, roll, roll, light, hey, now I'm falling down.
Mr. Plight, your closing statement.
A word of caution, this is not a comedy club, you are not on stage.
Excuse me.
You need a short recess, sir.
I'm not on stage, I'm not on stage, I'm not on stage,
I can't do this anymore, because I can't be, are you want me to be?
It was all just a fantasy.
There is no joke of it, it's just me.
I killed six people, I wish I didn't, but I did.
Nobody knows, but I also killed my mother, but I'm tall over her face, and smother her dead.
I just want to blow it all up, and start a new life.
Not, not, who's there?
What the fuck?
All right, there's a fuck, who?
He is probably leaving left to death a beam, and left your reporter, and which case you can just fuck off. Thanks.
Hi, it's me, Arthur.
The jury's already come back with a verdict, to about less than an hour, so, you know,
I didn't let me call you to see if you'd come back, because I want you here.
And then we need to go.
If you go away from a sunny day, and you might as well take us on away, all the birds that flew, and the bright blue sky,
when our love was new, and our hearts were bright, and the day was young, and then I was long,
and I'm a little bit stressed still, but the night bright's on.
If you go away, but if you stay, I'll make you a day like no day has been, or we'll be again, or out of the rain,
we'll sail on your touch, I'll talk to your eyes that I love so much, and if you go, go I won't cry,
all the good is gone, and the world could find you away, and get the power of going.
And so we will now take as we wait to hear the word and do a trial of our peace, and I think it will be the first time.
If you go away, as I know you are, there'll be nothing left, and the world will all be lost, just to empty,
all of these days, at the empty home, I'll sail on your face,
I'll live in the shadow of your dark, I'll talk it, I'll get me, not inside.
Go away.
As a reminder, regardless of the verdict, I will not tolerate any outbursts of any kind.
For a person, you may begin.
In the matter of the people of the state of New York versus author flick, case number GC07193.
As to count one, we the jury find author flick guilty as charged with murder in the first degree against Maurice Franklin, so say we all.
As to count two, we the jury find author flick guilty as charged with murder in the second degree against Randall Klimann Hopper, so say we all.
As to count three, we the jury find author flick guilty as charged with murder in the second degree against Randall Klimann Hopper, so say we all.
Go away.
Stand down.
Hey, let's get them out of here.
Need it.
Con
Where's the body of your ass?
Hey, get down!
Stay down!
Get down, dude!
Down the fucking ass!
Try it!
Stop!
Get down!
We have devastating news to report right now.
A massive car bomb has gone off in downtown Gotham,
exploding just outside the county courthouse.
Over thousands have turned out to hear the verdict of the Arthur Fleck trial.
Details are still coming in.
Continue to stay tuned as we bring you the latest updates on our news stories.
Fuck!
Lock your name!
Put around it!
It's red, it's okay!
It's on now!
This is just a thingy man.
I'm gonna go to your home.
Fuckin' silly down now!
Irene?
Our do censations!
No!
Mark!
We haven't got the ahead of you,
Sam!!
Yeah this is the Ntimeur plays at home now the sale.
cabin?
Okay, it's you.
You got your hair.
Someone below the courthouse.
I'm free.
We can go.
You hear me?
Someone below the courthouse.
We can go.
I escaped.
We're not going away, Arthur.
All we had was the fantasy, and you came up.
We were never going anywhere.
Now that's what I'm going to fall in love with,
I'm going to see you by them, or are you friendly?
No.
No, you're not.
There is no joker.
That's what you said, isn't it?
I can't.
Please, we're having a baby.
The show that is really shown, sounds you out.
I stop.
With a kind of glow when you say,
As you go on your way,
That's entertainment.
I don't want to say anymore.
A song that is winging along for this.
With a touch of the minutes.
That's not true.
In all that we had dreamed,
That's entertainment.
Goodbye, Arthur.
Don't you?
Is it not?
Come, my little bit of a brainer.
I will end you.
Don't you? Is it not?
Come, my little bit of a brainer.
I will end you.
Oh, I'm all going to do.
It is true.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
I'm coming.
Nice shot, Arthur.
What? Let's go.
We got a visitor.
No phone.
Let's go.
Hey, Arthur.
Hold up.
Can I tell you a joke I came up with?
Is it quick?
Yeah, I can make it quick.
So, a psychopath walks into a bar and sees this famous clown sitting there, all alone.
Totally drunk, it's pathetic.
I can't believe you're here, he says.
What a disappointment.
I used to watch you on TV.
What can I get you?
And this clown turns and says,
Well, if you're buying you can get me anything.
Perfect.
Psychopath says, how about I get you what you fucking deserve?
Stop!
Open!
Open.
Over home!
Oof.
That's why that's what people say.
You're riding high in April,
Shut down in May,
But I know I'm gonna change there too.
When I'm back,
I'm tapping to hold up
That's life
Funny as it seems