Subs by KalEl82
What's your name again?
Chrissie.
Where are we going?
Swimming.
Slow up. Slow down.
I'm not
drunk! Slow down!
Wait. I'm coming.
I'm coming.
I'm definitely coming.
Whoa.
Hold on. Whoa!
I can swim.
I just can't walk
or undress myself.
Come on in the water!
Take it easy.
Oh, God, help!
Please help me!
I'm coming.
It hurts!
...local
fishing reported good.
Amity Boat Rental
Yard's opening early
to prepare for the
annual seasonal rush.
This is WISS...
How come the sun
didn't use to shine in here?
We bought the house in
the fall, and this is summer.
Somebody feed the dogs.
Right.
Do you see the kids?
They must be in the back yard.
In Amity you say "yard."
They're in the "yard,"
not too "far" from the "car."
How's that?
Like you're from New York.
Mum, I got cut. I
got hit by a vampire.
You were playing on
those swings, weren't you?
Those swings are dangerous.
Stay off there. I
haven't fixed them yet.
I think you're going to live.
It's not the prettiest
thing I've ever seen. Hello.
Yes. Can I go swimming?
Yeah, but let me
clean this thing off first.
What do they usually do?
Wash up, or float up, or what?
Oh, no.
Keep them there.
I'll be out in about
15, 20 minutes. All right?
Dry you off. Okay.
Go on, get a Band-Aid.
Got to
go. Missing person.
Season hasn't started.
Nobody's even here yet.
Listen, Chief...
be careful, will you?
In this town?
Hi, Dad.
Wait a minute. Let me get on.
I want my cup back!
You'll get it.
Wave goodbye. Bye.
Nobody saw her
go into the water?
Somebody could've. I
was sort of passed out.
You mean, she ran out on you?
No, sir.
She must've drowned.
Look, I reported
it to you, didn't I?
You live here?
No. Hartford.
I go to Trinity. My
folks live in Greenwich.
Your folks were
born here, right?
Yeah, I'm an Islander.
They moved off
when my dad retired.
You an Islander?
No. New York City.
You here for the
summer? Come on.
Hold it.
Oh, Jesus.
Well, you're up awful
early. Is the Chief in there?
Chief, what have you got on?
If this new filing
system is to work,
you must keep outdated
stuff off my desk.
Just the pending,
all right? Yes, Chief.
We got a bunch of calls
about that karate school.
It seems that the 9-year-olds
from the school have been
karate-ing the picket
fences.
Chief Brody's office.
The medical inspector.
The Fire Chief wants you to
go over the Fourth of July...
Polly, I want a list
of the water activities
that the city fathers
are planning for today.
Right away. Hendricks!
Where do we keep the
"Beach Closed" signs?
We never had any. No?
There's a dead truck with New
Hampshire plates in front of my store.
Just have him fill out
the form. Just fill it out.
Look what the kids did to
my fence. 8 and 9-year-olds...
Glasses? Yeah, glasses.
I'll call you later in the
afternoon. I promise.
This stuff ain't going
to help me in August.
The summer ginks
come down here in June.
You haven't got one
thing on here I ordered.
Not a beach umbrella, not a
sun lounger, no beach balls.
If I can't get service...
Chief, Polly sent me to tell you
that there's a bunch of
Boy Scouts out in Avril Bay
doing the mile swim
for their merit badges.
I couldn't call them in,
there's no phones out there.
Okay. Come on, get out of there.
Take this stuff
back to the office
and get to work on those signs.
"Beaches Closed. No Swimming.
By order of the Amity P. D."
Let Polly do the printing.
What's the matter
with my printing?
Let Polly do the printing.
Chief Brody!
What have you got there?
Listen, we had a shark attack
at South Beach
this morning, Mayor.
Fatal. I have to
batten down the beach.
Albert, come
on, you kook. Keep your arms up.
Charlie, take me
out to those kids, will you?
Martin, you're going to shut down
the beaches on your own authority?
What other authority do I need?
Technically, you
need a civic ordinance
or a resolution by a board of...
That's just going by the book.
We're really a little anxious
that you're rushing into
something serious here.
This is your first
summer, you know.
What does that mean?
I'm only trying to say that
Amity is a summer town.
We need summer dollars.
If they can't swim here
they'll be glad to
swim at the beaches
of Cape Cod, the
Hamptons, Long Island.
That doesn't mean we
serve them a smorgasbord.
But we've never had that
kind of trouble in these waters.
What else could've
done that to that girl?
A boat propeller?
I think possibly, yes,
a boating accident.
That's not what you
told me on the phone.
I was wrong.
We'll have to amend our reports.
And you'll stand by that?
I'll stand by that.
Martin, a summer girl goes
swimming, swims out a little far.
She tires, fishing
boat comes along...
It's happened before.
I don't think you
appreciate the gut reaction
people have to these things.
Larry, I appreciate it. I'm
just reacting to what I was told.
Martin, it's all psychological.
You yell, "Barracuda!" and
everybody says, "Huh? What?"
You yell, "Shark!"...
we've got a panic on our
hands on the Fourth of July.
Okay. You can take us back now.
Here's mommy, here.
I'm going to get my raft
and go back out in the water.
Let me see your fingers.
Alex Kintner, they're
beginning to prune.
Just let me go
out a little longer.
Just 10 more minutes.
Thanks.
There
are no Islanders.
None of them are
from the island.
It's just a big bother.
They're bringing in...
All I want to know...
I just want to know
one simple thing.
When do I get to
become an Islander?
Ellen, never.
You're not born here, you're
not an Islander. That's it.
Nantucket Ferries...
...to Amity, Martha's Vineyard
and Nantucket islands.
Monday to Thursday, 8:40,
15, 5:45 and 6:00 p.m.
Starting July 1 , 8:30 p.m...
Come back here.
But don't bother him.
Come right back. Okay. I won't.
Martin, I know you got a
lot of problems downtown
but I've got problems at the
house I wish you'd take care of.
One, I've got some cats parking
in front of the
house, I can't get...
And that garbage truck next
to the office, that's terrible.
What I need is a red zone. It's a
simple thing you can take care of.
You've done it before.
Come here a minute, please.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Listen, if the kids going in
the water is worrying you
they can play out
here on the beach.
It's all right. Let them go.
It's cold.
We know all about you, Chief.
You don't go in the
water at all, do you?
That's some bad hat, Harry.
Chief Brody, you are uptight.
Come on. That's it.
Oh, do you know the muffin man
The muffin man
Tippet!
Did you see that?
Blood!
Everybody out!
Get them out!
Michael, get out of the water!
Alex?
We don't even know if
there's a shark around here.
I can't argue with
you. I can't talk to you.
I have to talk to Mrs. Kintner.
Because this is
turning into a contest.
It's not just the Gazette. She's
advertising in out-of-town papers.
I suggest we move back to council
chambers where we'll have more room.
I'm responsible for
public safety here.
Then go out tomorrow and
see that no one gets hurt.
It's a small story. I'll
bury it as deep as I can.
The ad will run on the back
along with the grocery ads.
Right in here, please.
Move on in, please.
Why do you insist
on playing the heavy?
I have a point of view and I think it
speaks for many of the people here.
Not only me, because I have the
motel. How do you feel about it?
Let's have some order.
Let's have order, please.
Any special questions?
Is that $3,000 bounty on
the shark in cash or check?
I don't think that's funny.
I don't think
that's funny at all.
All right.
That's private business between
you fishermen and Mrs. Kintner.
Martin, would you please...
Chief Brody.
I just want to tell you
what we're planning so far.
What
about the beaches, Chief?
We're going to put on the extra
summer deputies as soon as possible.
And then we're going to try and
use shark spotters on the beach.
Are you going to
close the beaches?
Yes, we are.
We also plan to bring in experts
from the Oceanographic
Institute on the mainland.
Only 24 hours.
I didn't agree to that.
Twenty-four
hours is like three weeks!
You all know me.
Know how I earn a living.
I'll catch this bird for you.
It ain't going to
be easy. Bad fish.
Not like going down to the pond
and chasing bluegills
or tommy cods.
This shark, swallow you whole.
Shaking, tenderizing.
Down you go.
And we got to do it quick.
Got to bring back the tourists
that'll put all your
businesses on a paying basis.
But it's not going
to be pleasant.
I value my neck a lot
more than $3,000, Chief.
I'll find him for $3,000, but I'll
catch him and kill him for $10,000.
You got to make up your minds.
Gonna stay alive and ante up,
gonna play it cheap and be
on welfare the whole winter.
I don't want no volunteers.
I don't want no mates.
There's too many
captains on this island.
$10,000 for me, by myself.
For that, you get the head,
the tail, the whole damn thing.
Thank you very much, Mr. Quint.
We'll take it under advisement.
Mr. Mayor, Chief,
ladies and gentlemen.
Oh, God, you scared me.
Oh. Oh.
You know, Ellen, people don't
even know how old sharks are.
I mean, if they live 2,000,
3,000 years... They don't know.
Enough.
You're not going to even
be able to go to sleep tonight.
Here. Come on.
Thanks.
Oh.
Want to get drunk
and fool around?
Oh, yeah.
Mikey really loves his present.
Where is he?
Sitting in it.
Good God.
All right, Michael,
out of the boat!
Tied up to the jetties,
sitting in the boat.
I'm helping Michael.
Get out of that boat!
Hi, Dad. Just a
little longer. Please?
It's his birthday.
I don't want him on the ocean!
He's not on the
ocean, he is in a boat.
He won't go in the water.
I don't think he'll go in the water
again, after what happened yesterday.
All right, now don't say that.
I don't want that to
happen, you know that.
I want him to read
the boating regulations,
the rules, before he
goes out on his own.
Michael, did you hear your
father? Out of the water now!
Now!
I'm tired. Let's
stop before someone reports us.
Don't worry. The Chief
lives on the other side of the island.
Am I coming in straight?
Don't worry about
it. Just keep rowing.
We better
catch something,
this is my wife's holiday roast.
Don't worry about it.
$3,000 buys an
awful lot of roast.
Come and get it.
The tide's taking it right out.
Can't we go home?
He's taking it.
Go!
Charlie, take my word
for it, don't look back!
Swim, Charlie!
Come on ! To me, boy!
Come on, Charlie! Swim!
Come on, Charlie, keep
coming. Keep swimming.
Come on, a little
more. Atta boy.
I can't get up.
Give me your hand, Charlie.
Help me!
Get
your feet out of the water!
Can we go home now?
So then Denherder and Charlie
sat there trying to catch their breath
and figure out how
to tell Charlie's wife
what happened to
her freezer full of meat.
That's not funny.
That's not funny at all.
Mrs. Kintner must've put
her ad in Field & Stream.
Looks more like The
National Enquirer.
All right, hold it. Hold
everything. I said, hold it!
Hello.
Hello back, young
fellow. How are you?
Say, I hope you're not going
out with those nuts, are you?
The Weetock boats
gotta move out first.
You have to move out
or he can't get out at all.
Don't raise sail, you're going
to luff it. You got a paddle?
I got a paddle.
Scull it out of here.
Officer, wait a second.
How many guys are you
going to put aboard that boat?
Whatever's safe, right?
Yeah, well that ain't safe.
Watch it, that's dynamite.
What are you doing with that?
Where are you going with that?
I'm going on the boat.
Please, help me get those
guys out of the boat, will you?
Sure. Come on.
Gentlemen, the officer
asked me to tell you
that you're
overloading that boat!
Go on, get out of here.
You ain't
going. What do you care?
Can you tell me if there's a good
restaurant or hotel on the island?
Yeah, you walk straight ahead.
They're all going to die.
Listen to me. We've got
some road block signs outside.
You've got to get
somebody to help us.
Yeah, get those road block
signs out on the highway.
Because we've got more people
down here than we can handle.
What're you doing there? These
are your people. Go talk to them.
They aren't my people.
They're from all over.
You see all the license plates?
Connecticut, Rhode Island, New
Jersey. I'm all by myself out there.
What happened
to the extra help...
It's not until the
Fourth of July.
Till then, it's you and me.
You know those guys
in the fan-tail launch?
None of them are getting
out of the harbor alive.
That's what I'm saying.
You know their names.
Talk to those clowns.
Everyone's having
a good time today.
Tell me about it.
Polly, I'll get back to you.
Could you tell me how I
could find Chief Brody?
Who are you?
Matt Hooper. I'm from the
Oceanographic Institute.
Oh, for Christ's sakes. You're
the guy we called. I'm Brody.
Oh. I'm glad to
meet you. Me, too.
I know you got a
lot on your hands.
What can we do for you?
The best thing to do
is to see the remains
of the first victim,
the girl on the beach.
Okay, fine. Just bear
with me, will you?
Sure.
Wait till we get them silly
bastards down in that rock pile.
There'll be some fun.
They'll wish their fathers
hadn't met their mothers
when they start
digging the bottoms out
and slamming into
them rocks, boy.
Get away
from there, you goddamn fool!
What's the matter with you?
You want to swamp us,
you crazy son of a bitch?
What are
these guys doing out here?
What are they doing back there?
They're chumming right now.
What the hell is that?
They're tracking the shark.
$3,000
divided four ways is what?
Watch
your starboard. Jesus!
Let's show Mr. Hooper
our accident.
"Victim identified as Christine
Watkins, female Caucasian."
And here's the way we have it.
"Probable boating accident."
The height and
weight of the victim
can only be estimated
from the partial remains.
The torso has been
severed in mid-thorax.
There are no major
organs remaining.
May I have a glass of water?
The right arm has been severed
above the elbow with
massive tissue loss
in the upper musculature.
Thank you very much.
Partially denuded bone remaining.
This was no boat accident.
Did you notify the
Coast Guard about this?
No. It was only
local jurisdiction.
The left arm, head,
the shoulders, sternum
and portions of the
rib cage are intact.
Do not smoke in here.
Thank you very much.
This is what happens.
Indicates the non-frenzy
feeding of a large squalus
possibly longimanus
or Isurus glaucus.
The enormous amount of tissue
loss prevents any detailed analysis
however, the attacking squalus
must be considerably larger
than any normal squalus
found in these waters.
Didn't you get out a boat
and check these waters?
No.
Well, this is not
a boat accident.
And it wasn't any propeller.
It wasn't any coral reef.
And it wasn't Jack the Ripper.
It was a shark.
I wanna go AP and UPI. I want
to get on the state wire services.
See if Boston will pick
it up and go national.
Call Dave Axelrod in New York
and tell him he owes me a favor.
This is the shot I want with
everybody and the fish in it.
Guys, could we
please get organized?
I want to get a
picture for the paper.
Now, can we just have the...
Ben Gardner get this?
No, we caught it.
That's swell.
It's a beauty.
Guys, please, I
need a picture for the paper.
Clear out of the way, please.
Just the guys that caught
the fish. Open it up a little bit.
I want to get a picture
of the guy with the fish.
Come on. I need a
picture for the paper.
Could we get the sign, please?
Kneel down, just
like in high school.
One row kneeling,
one row standing.
Come on, just
get out of the way.
Young fellow, could you
step out of the picture?
Take your rake with you.
We're ready. Thank you.
Can you get that,
please.
How's that?
Larry, you won't believe it.
What kind of a shark is that?
I don't know.
I think it's a mako.
It's got a deep throat, Frank.
Yeah, but what kind?
What kind of shark?
Tiger shark.
A what?
We can start breathing again.
Is Ben getting
plenty of pictures?
Oh, you bet he is.
What is this bite radius crap?
That is a big mouth.
You stuff your frigging
head in there, man,
and find out if
it's a man-eater.
All I'm saying is that it
may not be the shark.
It's just a slight...
I want you to meet Matt. This
is Larry Vaughn, our mayor.
Matt's from the
Oceanographic Institute.
Nice to meet you.
Terrific, huh, Mayor?
There are all kinds of
sharks in the waters.
Hammerheads, white
tips, blues, makos.
And the chances that these
bozos got the exact shark...
There are no other
sharks like this here.
It's 100-to-1.
I'm not saying that this is not
the shark. It probably is, Martin.
It's a man-eater. It's
extremely rare for these waters.
But the fact is, the bite
radius on this animal
is different than the
wounds on the victim.
I want to be sure.
You want to be sure.
We all want to be sure, okay?
What I want to
do is very simple.
The digestive system of
this animal is very slow.
Let's cut it open.
Whatever it's eaten
in the last 24 hours
is bound to still be in there.
And then we'll be sure.
It may be the only
way to confirm it.
Look, fellows,
let's be reasonable.
This is not the
time or the place
to perform some kind of a
half-assed autopsy on a fish.
And I am not going to stand
here and see that thing cut open
and see that little Kintner
boy spill out all over the dock.
Chief Brody?
Yes?
I just found out
that a girl got killed
here last week.
And you knew it.
You knew there
was a shark out there.
You knew it was dangerous.
But you let people
go swimming anyway.
You knew all those things,
but still my boy is dead now.
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
My boy is dead.
I wanted you to know that.
I'm sorry, Martin. She's wrong.
No, she's not.
All right, fellows
let's cut this ugly
son of a bitch down
before it stinks up
the whole island.
Harve, you and Carl take it out
tomorrow and dump it in the drink.
Come here.
Give us a kiss.
Why?
Because I need it.
Get out of here.
Can I help you?
The door was
open. Mind if I come in?
I'm Matt Hooper.
Oh, hi. Ellen Brody.
Your husband's home? Yes.
I'd really like to talk to him.
Yes, so would I.
Come in. Can I get
you some coffee?
No. Nothing, thank you.
Oh, wine. How nice.
How was your day?
Swell.
I got red and white. I didn't
know what you'd be serving.
Oh, that's nice.
Is anyone eating this?
No.
My husband tells
me you're in sharks.
Excuse me. Yes. I've never
heard it quite put that way.
But yes, I am.
I love sharks.
You love sharks?
Yeah, I love them.
When I was 12 years old,
my father got me a boat
and I went fishing
off of Cape Cod.
I hooked a scup and
as I was reeling it in
I hooked a 4.5 foot
baby thresher shark
who proceeded to eat my boat.
He ate my oar, hooks,
and my seat cushions.
He turned an inboard
into an outboard
scared me to death,
and I swam back to shore.
When I was on the
beach, I turned around
and actually saw my
boat being taken apart.
Ever since then, I have
been studying sharks
and that's why I know that I'm
going to go to the Institute tomorrow
and tell them that you still
have a shark problem here.
Why do you have to
tell them that? Sorry.
I'm sorry, I thought that...
You told me the
shark was caught.
I heard it on the news. I
heard it on the Cape station.
They caught a
shark, not the shark.
Not the shark that
killed Chrissie Watkins.
And probably not the
shark that killed the little boy.
Which I wanted to prove
today by cutting the shark open...
You may want to let
that breathe... Nothing.
You know, you'll be
the only rational man
left on this island
after I leave tomorrow.
Where are you going?
I am going on the Aurora.
The Aurora? What is that?
It's a floating asylum
for shark addicts.
It's pure research,
18 months at sea.
Martin hates boats.
Martin hates water.
Martin sits in his car when we
go on the ferry to the mainland.
I guess it's a childhood thing.
There's a clinical
name for it, isn't there?
Drowning.
Is it true that most
people get attacked
by sharks in three feet of water
about 10 feet from the beach?
Yeah.
And that before people
started to swim for recreation...
I mean, before sharks
knew what they were missing
that a lot of these
attacks weren't reported?
That's right.
Now this shark that swims alone
what's it called? Rogue.
Rogue, yeah.
This guy, he keeps
swimming around
in a place where
the feeding is good
until the food
supply is gone, right?
That's called territoriality.
It's just a theory that I
happen to agree with.
Then why don't we
have one more drink
and go down and
cut that shark open?
Martin? Can you do that?
I can do anything.
I'm the Chief of Police.
We start in the alimentary canal
and open the digestive tract.
Just like I thought.
What?
Came up in the Gulf
Stream, from southern waters.
He didn't eat a car, did he?
No.
Tiger shark's like a
garbage can. It'll eat anything.
Somebody probably
threw that in the river.
That's it.
I've got to close the
beach, call the Mayor.
You got a bigger
problem than that, Martin.
You still got a hell
of a fish out there
with a mouth about this big.
How do we confirm
that by morning?
If he is a rogue, and there's
any truth to territoriality at all
we got a good
chance of spotting him
between Cape Scott
and South Beach.
Where are you going?
To find him. He's
a night feeder.
On the water?
We're not gonna
find him on the land.
I'm not drunk enough
to go on a boat.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not. Yes, you are.
I can't do that. Yes, you can.
I'm telling you, the crime
rate in New York will kill you.
There's so many problems, you never
feel like you're accomplishing anything.
Violence, rip-offs, muggings.
The kids can't leave the house.
You've got to walk
them to school.
But in Amity, one man
can make a difference.
In 25 years, there's never been
a shooting or a
murder in this town.
No kidding? Want a pretzel?
Where are we?
We're right in the stretch
where he's been feeding.
Can you get The Late
Show on this thing?
No, it's a closed
circuit TV system.
I have underwater
cameras fore-and-aft.
Who pays for all this stuff?
The government? The Institute?
This stuff costs a lot of money.
I paid for this mostly
myself, actually.
You're kidding. No.
You rich? Yeah.
How much?
Personally, or the whole family?
Doesn't make any sense. They
pay a guy like you to watch sharks?
Well, it doesn't
make sense for a guy
who hates the water to
live on an island either.
It's only an island if you
look at it from the water.
That makes a lot of sense.
What is that thing doing?
Well, it's a fish finder.
It's probably just a school
of mackerel or something,
all clumped together.
Wait a minute.
There's something
else out there.
What is it?
About 100 yards,
south-southwest.
That's
Ben Gardner's boat.
You know him?
It's all banged up. Sure I
know him. He's a fisherman.
What happened?
Martin, I gotta go down
and check their hull.
Wait. Why
don't we just tow it all in?
We will. I just got to
check something out.
Hit the lights for me.
Let's tow it in.
Don't worry, Martin.
Nothing's going to happen.
What am I supposed
to do while you're gone?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
Don't touch any
of the equipment.
I'll be back in two minutes.
This is a great white,
Larry. A big one.
Any shark expert will tell
you it's a killer, a man-eater.
The situation is that
apparently a great white shark
has staked a claim in
the waters off Amity Island.
He'll continue to feed here as
long as there's food in the water.
There's no limit
to what he'll do.
We've had three incidents.
Two people killed within
a week. It'll happen again.
It happened before.
The Jersey beach, 1916.
Five people were
killed... In one week.
Tell him about the swimmers.
A shark is attracted to the exact
kind of splashing and activity
that occurs whenever human
beings swim. You can't avoid it.
Opening the beaches on the Fourth
of July is like ringing the dinner bell.
Look, Mr. Vaughn
I pulled a tooth the
size of a shot glass
out of the wrecked
hull of a boat out there.
It was the tooth
of a great white.
It was Gardner's
boat, all chewed up.
I helped tow it in.
You should've seen it!
Where is that tooth?
Did you see it, Brody?
I didn't see it. He
dropped it on the way in.
I had an accident.
And what did you say
the name of this shark is?
It's a Carcharodon
carcharias. It's a great white.
You don't have the tooth?
Look, we depend on the
summer people for our very lives...
You won't have a summer
unless you deal with this problem!
We have to close the beach
and hire someone to kill the shark!
We have to tell the Coast Guard.
You'll have to contact
the Shark Research Panel.
You'll have to ring
this entire harbor!
I don't think either one of you
are familiar with our problems!
I think that I am
familiar with the fact
that you'll ignore
this particular problem
until it swims up and
bites you in the ass!
Wait a second ! There are two
ways to deal with this problem!
You either kill this animal
or cut off its food supply.
We have
to close the beaches.
Brody?
Sick vandalism.
That is a deliberate mutilation
of a public service message.
I want those little
paint-happy bastards caught
and hung up by
their Buster Browns.
That's it. I won't waste
my time arguing with a man
who's lining up
to be a hot lunch.
I'm gonna see you later, Brody.
Don't do this. He's not...
What we are dealing with here is a
perfect engine, an eating machine.
It's really a
miracle of evolution.
All this machine
does is swim and eat
and make little
sharks. And that's all.
Why don't you take a
long, close look at this sign?
Those proportions are correct.
You'd love to prove
that, wouldn't you?
Get your name into
the National Geographic.
Larry, if we
make an effort today,
we might be able to save August.
August? For Christ's sake,
tomorrow's the Fourth of July!
We will be open for business.
It'll be one of the best
summers we've ever had.
If you are concerned
about the beaches,
do whatever you have
to, to make them safe.
But those beaches will
be open for this weekend.
I want to know how many
men you're going to send.
There is no need for
me to come to Brisbane
when I have a great
white shark right here!
We need men to
patrol the swimming area.
We've got to have help.
Anybody with a gun or a boat.
Monday!
Is Chief Federal
Officer Feldman there?
He's the little guy
with a crew cut.
Operator, isn't there
a phone on the island?
Could you connect me, please?
Come on, get him!
Careful on the beach.
Brody to Gotcha, do you read me?
The guys from the TV station
on the mainland are here.
All right. I'll get
to them later.
Brody to Scutbucket,
please come in.
Brody to Daisy, do you read me?
Fascinating
Rhythm, do you read me?
Come in, Hooper.
What do you see?
Nothing here, Martin.
And nothing on sonar.
Amity Island has long been
known for its clean air, clear water
and beautiful
white-sand beaches.
But in recent days
a cloud has appeared
on the horizon
of this beautiful
resort community.
A cloud in the shape
of a killer shark.
That is very shocking in the outfield.
Two balls, one strike,
runners at first and third...
Fly ball, deep left field.
Jerry Christian goes back,
running back near the wall
and he takes it for the out.
Oh, hi, Larry.
Why aren't you in the water?
I just put some
suntan lotion on,
and I'm trying to absorb some...
Nobody's going in.
Please, get in the water.
Mike, come here.
Listen, Mike. Do
me a favor, will you?
You and the other
guys take the boat
and put it in the pond instead?
The pond is for old ladies.
I know it's for the old ladies,
but just do it for the old man.
Please?
All right.
Thanks.
I've got Sean.
Michael ! Wait!
Michael, I don't
like you no more.
I can stand Harry, you know...
Daisy, this is
Hendricks. Anything?
Thought I saw a shadow. Over.
Hendricks, this
is Daisy here. I don't see anything.
False alarm. Must be this glare.
I'm pleased and happy to repeat
the news that we have in fact
caught and killed
a large predator
that supposedly
injured some bathers.
As you see, it's
a beautiful day.
The beaches are open, and
people are having a wonderful time.
"Amity," as you know,
means "friendship."
My God!
Jesus Christ! Fin ! Shark! 350!
Get in there
as fast as you can!
Red one.
Martin, get them the
hell out of the water.
No whistles!
Everybody, please,
get out of the water.
Everybody
out of the water.
Don't push!
Everybody out of the water, please.
Come on!
I
want them out of there, guys.
Give an answer, please.
What's going on out there?
He made me do it.
He talked me into it.
Please, move back. Give
these people some air.
Please, move back.
Martin, it's just a hoax. There
are two kids with a cardboard fin.
Is everyone there okay? Everyone
get out of the water all right?
Folks, we had some practical
joker down there with a fake fin...
Shark! A shark!
It's going into the
pond ! Shark in estuary!
Now what?
Michael's in the pond.
It's going in the pond !
Somebody do something ! It's in the pond!
Hurry up, get that done.
I can't do a damn thing.
Get that rope undone. You
gotta untangle that up there.
I'm doing it!
Hey, fellows, haul in
your sheet. Make it fast.
You guys okay over there?
In the pond!
Somebody
get a gun and shoot it!
Doesn't anybody have a gun?
Is he dead?
No, he's not. He's in shock.
Doctor said he's
okay. Mild shock.
He can go home in the morning.
Thank you.
How's my big kid?
I'm all right.
You going to miss me tonight?
You can watch television.
Want me to bring
anything from home?
My cars.
What about ice cream?
Coffee.
Want to take him home?
Back to New York?
No. Home, here.
I'm sorry, I'm truly sorry.
You got a pen, Larry?
Yeah, a pen, you know.
'Cause you're going
to do what you do best.
You're going to sign this
voucher so I can hire a contractor.
I don't know if I
can do that without...
I'm going to hire
Quint to kill the shark.
August? What?
What are you talking about?
Summer's over. You're
the mayor of Shark City.
People think you
want the beaches open.
I was acting in the
town's best interest.
You were acting in
the town's best interest.
That's why you'll
do the right thing.
That's why you're
going to sign this,
and we'll pay that
guy what he wants.
My kids were on that beach, too.
Sign it, Larry.
$10, 000.
$200 a day, whether
I catch him or not.
You've got it.
Get the Mayor off my back so I
don't have more of this zoning crap.
You've got that.
One case of apricot brandy,
and you buy the lunch.
Two cases. And you get
dinner when you get back.
Champagne,
pte de foie gras,
Iranian caviar, and
don't forget the color TV.
Chief, you try this. Made
it myself. Pretty good stuff.
Thanks.
Here's to swimming
with bow-legged women.
Excuse me, Chief.
Can't get a good man
these days, under 60.
All gone at least 35 years.
Don't drink that.
Mr. Quint...
You're gonna need an extra hand.
This is Matt Hooper. I know him.
I've crewed three Trans Pacs.
Transplants?
He's from the
Oceanographic Institute.
And an America's Cup trial.
Mr. Hooper, I'm not talking
about pleasure
boating or day-sailing.
I'm talking about working for a
living. I'm talking about sharking.
I'm not talking about hooking
some poor dogfish or sand shark.
I'm talking about
finding a great white.
Porkers? Talking about porkers?
Just tie me a sheepshank.
I haven't had to pass basic
seamanship in a long time.
You didn't say how
short you wanted it.
How's that?
Give me your hands.
Dogfish?
You got a $5,000 net and
you got $2,000 worth of fish in it.
Along comes Mr. Whitey, and
when he's finished with that net
it looks like a
kiddies' scissors class
has cut it up for a paper doll.
You got city hands, Mr. Hooper.
You been counting
money all your life.
I don't need this. I don't need
this working-class-hero crap.
You're not going to do this
aboard the ship are you, Mr. Quint?
Maybe I should go alone.
It's my party. It's my charter.
Yeah, it's your charter, it's
your party. It's my vessel.
You're on board my vessel,
I'm mate, master, pilot
and I'm captain.
I'll take him for
ballast, Chief.
You got him.
"Straight-jet, killing lance.
"Tail rope, eye splice, M-1
, handy billy, pliers, irons.. ."
Sample bottles,
dye marker, flares, safety float
temperature gauge,
spear guns, SMG...
What are you? Some kind
of half-assed astronaut?
Take that stuff down below
and you lash it secure, all right?
Jesus H. Christ!
When I was a boy,
every squirt wanted
to be a harpooner
or a swordfisherman.
What have you got here? A
portable shower or a monkey cage?
An anti-shark cage.
Anti-shark cage?
You go inside the cage?
Cage goes in the water? You go
in the water? Shark's in the water.
Our shark.
Farewell and
adieu to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
For we've received orders
for to sail back to Boston
And so nevermore
shall we see you again
Did you take your Dramamine?
Yes.
I put an extra pair of
glasses in your black socks
and there's the
stuff for your nose,
the zinc oxide and
Blistex is in the kit.
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn women today,
they can't handle nothing.
Young girls just
ain't quite smart
like their grandmothers were.
That's got to be Quint.
Colorful, isn't he?
He scares me.
Don't use the
fireplace in the den...
What am I going
to tell the kids?
Tell them I'm going fishing.
Break it up, will
you, Chief? Daylight's wasting!
Front, bow. Back, stern.
Better get it right,
squirt, or I throw your ass
out the little round
window on the side!
Come on, Chief. This
isn't no Boy Scout picnic.
See you got your
rubbers.
"Here lies the body of Mary
Lee Died at the age of 103
"For 15 years she
kept her virginity
"Not a bad record
for this vicinity"
All right, Commissioner,
fasten your safety belt!
If you see a shark,
Hooper, swallow!
Up periscope. Rig for depth
charge. Stand by fire drill.
Damage control report.
Nor'easter coming, bad
news for Madison Avenue.
I'm tired of that.
How's the missus, Chief?
If they don't like you going
out, they'll love you coming in.
Keep that chum
line going, Chief.
We got five good miles on it.
Who's driving this boat?
Nobody. The tide.
One time, I caught a
16-footer off Montauk.
Had to stick two barrels in him.
Two to wear him
down and bring him up.
Nowadays, these kids,
they take out everything.
Radar, sonar,
electric toothbrushes.
Jesus H. Christ.
Chief, best drop
another chum marker.
Damn it, Martin!
This is compressed air.
What the hell kind
of a knot was that?
You pulled the wrong one!
You screw around
with these tanks,
and they're going to blow up.
Yeah, that's real
fine, expensive gear
you've brought out
here, Mr. Hooper.
I don't know what that bastard
shark's going to do with it.
Might eat it, I suppose.
Seen one eat a
rocking chair one time.
Next time, you just ask
me which line to pull, right?
Little brown eel
comes out of the cave
swims into the hole
comes out of the hole, goes
back into the cave again.
It's not too good, is it?
Nothing's easy, is
it? One more time.
Little brown eel...
I got it!
What? Get behind me.
Hooper, reverse her!
Taking a hell of a lot of line!
Chief, get the scoop out
of the bucket! Wet the reel!
Hooper, reverse her!
Duck your head down. We're
swinging. Get behind me again.
No more water. I don't
want you to drown me.
Hooper, you idiot, starboard
! Ain't you watching it!
Hooper, neutral.
Where'd he go now?
He ain't fooling me.
What's he yanking on now?
Go on, try it.
I don't know, Chief, if he's
very smart or very dumb.
Jesus...
He's gone under.
He's gone under the boat. I
think he's gone under the boat.
Yeah, it's too easy.
He is a smart, big fish.
He's gone under the boat.
Keep her steady, now. I
got something very big!
I don't think so.
Chief, put your gloves on.
You put your gloves
on, both of you!
Getting ready to run out again.
Quint, let it go.
Maybe you're a
big yahoo in the lab,
but out here you're
just supercargo!
If you don't want to backstroke
home, you get down here!
You don't want to listen
to me, don't listen to me.
It's not a shark.
The wire's showing.
Unbuckle me.
Get the other side.
It's a tuna or swordfish
wasting our time.
Take this rod.
Hooper, give the
Chief a hand, will you?
Right!
Oh, shit!
It may be a marlin or a stingray
but it's definitely a game fish.
Gaming fish?
Marlin, stingray bit
through this piano wire?
Don't you tell me
my business again.
You get back on the bridge.
Quint, that doesn't
prove a damn thing.
It proves one thing, Mr. Hooper.
You wealthy college boys
don't have the education enough
to admit if you're wrong.
What's the point?
Hooks and lines?
You lose one, you rig one.
Twelve minutes,
south-southeast, now! Full throttle!
Aye-aye, sir!
You see, what I do, Chief,
is I trick them to the surface.
And then I jab at them.
I'm not going to haul
them up like a lot of catfish.
Hooper, full throttle!
I don't have to take
this abuse much longer.
Your head's bleeding.
First aid there.
Start that chum
line again, will you?
Let Hooper take a turn.
Hooper drives the boat, Chief.
Stop playing with
yourself, Hooper.
Slow ahead, if you please.
You heard him. Slow ahead.
Slow ahead.
I can go slow ahead. Come on
down and chum some of this shit.
You're going to
need a bigger boat.
Shut off that engine.
That's a 20-footer.
Twenty-five.
Three tons of him.
We're going to need
a bigger boat, right?
Gotta get to work.
How do we handle this?
Come up front,
Martin. I need you.
He's circling the boat.
This is
Amity Point Light Station to Orca.
Come in, Orca.
Orca. Come in.
I have Mrs. Martin Brody here.
Put her on.
Come on, Martin ! Move!
I'm not going out there!
Beyond the edge of the barrels.
Go to the end of the
barrels, further out.
Further out! Why?
Go further out! What for?
Will you go to the
end of the pulpit?
What?
Will you go to the
end of the pulpit?
I need something in the
foreground to give it some scale!
Foreground my ass!
Your husband's
okay. He's fishing.
He just caught some stripers.
We'll bring them for dinner. We
ain't seen anything yet. Over. Out.
I'm not staying here!
I'm begging you!
God damn it! Come here, darling.
Chief, I want you
up on the bridge,
just take her forward, steady.
I've never steered
a boat in my life.
Just watch my
hand, take her steady.
Mr. Hooper, attach the end
of this line to the first keg.
I've got to get a good
shot at that porker's head.
He's coming.
Hooper? Get clear of the bow.
Hurry up, will you?
Your turn, Quint.
Hooper, where are you?
Hurry it up now, tie it on.
He's coming straight for
us. Don't screw it up now.
Don't wait for me.
Come on, Hooper,
hurry it up! Tie it on!
Now.
Kill it!
Now!
Shoot!
Time.
What were you
doing? You knew I had
to get a clean shot
right in the head.
All right, let's see how long
that barrel takes to bring him up.
Bring another barrel !
I'm coming around again!
What do we do now?
We're quitting, right?
We got one barrel on him. We
stay out here until we find him again.
We could radio in
and get a bigger boat...
Don't you worry about it, Chief.
It won't be permanent. You
want to see something permanent?
You want to feel
something permanent?
Just put your hand underneath
my cap. You feel that little lump?
Knocko Nolans, St.
Patty's Day, Boston.
I got that beat.
It's a moray eel. It bit
right through my wet suit.
Well, Hoop, now, listen
I don't know about that, but I
entered an arm-wrestling contest
in a bar in San
Francisco. See this?
I can't extend that.
You know why?
'Cause in the semi-final
celebrating my
third wife's demise,
big Chinese fellow,
he pulled me right over.
Look at that.
That's a bull shark.
He scraped me when
I was taking samples.
I got something for you.
There's a thresher. You
see that? A thresher's tail.
Thresher? It's a shark.
You want a drink?
Drink to your leg?
I'll drink to your leg.
So we drink to our
legs.
I got the crme de la
crme. Right here. Hold on.
Here, you see that?
You're wearing a sweater.
Right there. Mary Ellen Moffit.
She broke my heart.
What's that one?
What?
That one, there. On your arm.
Oh.
A tattoo. I got that removed.
Don't tell me.
"Mother."
What is it?
Mr. Hooper, that's
the U.S.S. Indianapolis.
You were on the Indianapolis?
What happened?
Japanese submarine slammed
two torpedoes into her side, Chief.
I was coming back from
the island of Tinian to Leyte
just delivered the bomb,
the Hiroshima bomb.
1 , 100 men went into the water.
Vessel went down in 12 minutes.
Didn't see the first shark
for about half an hour.
Tiger, 13-footer.
You know how you know that
when you're in the water, Chief?
You tell by looking
from the dorsal to the tail.
Well, we didn't know.
Because our bomb
mission had been so secret
no distress signal
had been sent.
They didn't even list
us overdue for a week.
Very first light,
sharks come cruising
so we formed ourselves
into tight groups.
You know, kind
of like old squares
in a battle like you
see on a calendar
like the Battle of
Waterloo. The idea was...
the shark comes
to the nearest man
and he starts pounding,
hollering and screaming.
Sometimes the
shark would go away...
but sometimes he
wouldn't go away.
Sometimes that shark, he looks
right into you, right into your eyes.
You know, a thing
about a shark, he's got...
lifeless eyes. Black
eyes, like a doll's eyes.
When he comes at you,
he doesn't seem to be living
until he bites you. Those black
eyes roll over white and then...
Then you hear that terrible
high-pitched screaming.
The ocean turns red.
In spite of the pounding and
the hollering, they all come in.
They rip you to pieces.
You know, by the
end of that first dawn...
we lost 100 men.
I don't know how many
sharks. Maybe 1 ,000.
I don't know how many men,
they averaged six an hour.
On Thursday morning, I
bumped into a friend of mine...
Herbie Robinson, from Cleveland.
Baseball player, bosun's mate.
I thought he was asleep.
Reached over to wake him up.
He bobbed up and down in
the water just like a kind of top.
Upended.
He'd been bitten in
half, below the waist.
Noon the fifth day, a
Lockheed Ventura saw us.
He swung in low and he
saw us. He was a young pilot.
Younger than Mr. Hooper.
He saw us and he came in
low, and three hours later...
a big fat PBY comes down
and starts to pick us up.
That was the time I
was most frightened.
Waiting for my turn.
I'll never put on
a life jacket again.
So, 1 , 100 men
went into the water
316 men come out.
The sharks took the
rest, June 29, 1945.
Anyway, we delivered the bomb.
What's that?
It's a whale.
Farewell and
adieu to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
Show me the way to go home
I'm tired and I
want to go to bed
I had a
little drink about an hour ago
And it's gone right to my head
Wherever I may roam
By land, or sea or foam
You will always hear
me singing this song
Show me the way to go home
I'm tired and I
want to go to bed
I had a little drink
about an hour ago
And it's gone right to my head
Wherever I may roam
On land or sea or foam
You can always
hear me singing...
Start the engines.
Fire her up!
Right in the middle!
He's busting the shaft.
Put out the fire, will you?
Pump her out. Done.
Everybody on deck.
He ate the light.
- Terrific.
- Excuse me.
Quint, what are you doing?
Don't waste your time.
Quint, come on.
What's wrong with this?
Hooper, take the wheel.
Brody, follow that. Watch for him.
You okay?
Chief, more left rudder!
Pull your left hand down.
I can't. It'll only go
about three inches.
All of our
injectors got scored
from the salt water in the fuel.
Yeah, the housing's
bent, you can hear it.
Try the left rudder again. More
left. Good. Once again now.
Quint, there it is.
What do you say, Chief?
The barrel is up,
it's right in the stern.
I think he's right under the
keg. Grab the boat hook.
Quint, if we can
get close enough...
I've got things on
board that'll kill it.
Just want to goose
him up. Come on.
When he runs, you drop that
rope or you'll lose your hands.
I've seen fingers torn
out at the knuckles.
Whole sea's bones, full of them.
Give it to me a minute.
Haul in that line
or it'll foul us.
Start the engine.
Where are you going?
I'm going to make a phone call.
Hello, mayday,
Orca. Coast Guard?
Coast Guard, this is the
Orca. Do you read me?
Coast Guard, this
is the Orca. Do you...
Excuse me, Chief.
That's great! That's just great!
Now, where the hell are we, eh?
You're certifiable, Quint, you
know that? You're certifiable!
You're certifiable,
but I'll tell you this!
Boys,
I think he's come back
for his noon feeding.
Hook me up another barrel.
Bring her around after him.
Full throttle! Get me
right up alongside of him!
I can't rev it up that high,
it's not going to take it!
Five degrees port.
All right, hold your course.
Five degrees port now.
Hold your course.
Fast fish.
Watch my hand.
Be sure you watch
my hand ! Follow me.
Lad, you watch
him now! Starboard!
Run him down, Hooper.
Hard aport.
Watch him. Starboard.
I can't believe it. Two barrels
and he's going down again.
It's incredible.
They're up again ! Now what?
Why don't we lead
the shark into shore
instead of him
leading us out to sea?
Grab a couple of poles.
Hang on now, we're going around.
Into starboard. Easy.
I'm going to back her off now.
Watch those barrels,
boys. Watch them.
All right, gentlemen, snag them.
Now then, tie them
to the stern cleats.
Brody, bring your
end around the cleat.
That's right, it'll lock itself
off. Give him room, Brody.
Stay clear of the line!
Watch it. Stand clear.
Stand away from
those stern cleats!
Back home we got
a taxidermy man.
He's going to
have a heart attack
when he sees what I
brought him.
Throttle back.
You're losing a cleat.
My God, this one,
too. They're both going.
He's eating his way
through that line.
He's working his
way right up to us.
Quint! Come on, Quint. Hurry!
Out of my way.
Watch it.
Untie this. He'll
pull out the transom.
Make it fast! We got
another line in him!
I can't, it's trying to run!
We better
get another line!
Pull, you son of a bitch!
I hope your back breaks!
Go ahead. Pull
your bloody heart out.
Tie him off!
It's impossible!
Boys, it's too tight!
He's pulling us!
We're breaking up over here!
We're breaking up! Cut it!
Watch your hands!
Cut it
quick. I can't hold it!
He can't stay down
with three barrels on him.
Not with three
barrels, he can't.
What about us?
Hooper, get the pump out of
the locker in front of you, will you?
We're going to sink, aren't we?
Keep an eye on the
barrels. Pump it out, Chief.
Starting to go under.
He can't with three barrels
on him. Not with three he can't.
You ever have
one do this before?
No.
He's chasing
us. I don't believe it.
I'm going to draw
him into the shallows.
Draw him into the shallow water.
I'm going to draw
him in and drown him.
We're heading in, Brody.
Thank Christ!
You ever had a
great white do that?
No.
How far do we have to go?
Don't put that
much pressure on it.
God damn it.
Shut up. Get back there.
Hold on.
Farewell and
adieu to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
For we received order
for to sail back to Boston
You idiot, you
burned out the bearings.
All right,
stop the boat. Stop it.
What exactly can you do
with these things of yours?
I think I can pump 20 cc of
strychnine nitrate into him.
If I can get close enough.
Get this little needle
through his skin?
No, I can't do that.
If I can get him
close to the cage,
I can get him in the mouth.
That shark will rip
that cage to pieces.
You got any better suggestions?
Easy.
Up she goes.
Ease her up.
Ain't got no spit.
Try and keep him
off me until I'm lower.
Okay, I'm ready.
Bring him up, God
damn it. Bring him up now!
Pull it up. Pull it.
Pull him up. Come
on, Quint, bring him in.
It's giving way!
Rig something!
Got it?
It's coming.
Slow it down.
Slower.
All right, come on.
Show me the tank.
Blow up!
Smile, you son of a bitch!
Quint?
No.
Can we get in on those?
What day is this?
It's Wednesday.
It's Tuesday, I think.
I think the tide's with us.
Keep kicking.
I used to hate the water.
I can't imagine why.
Subs by KalEl82