[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
Hey, what the fuck?
Easy.
Don't move.
What?
He's good.
You're making big mistakes.
You know what I'm talking about, huh?
Let's go.
Fuck.
Shut the door.
Shut the fuck up.
What's your fucking jacket?
Stand up.
Move.
Listen to me.
You let your brother and I
shoot you in the back of the head.
You understand me?
OK.
Who's the boss?
Slow.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Yo, yo, yo.
You remember my pumpkin flap, huh?
Don't.
Touch it and he's fucking dead.
Hands up.
Jesus Christ, you dumb motherfucker.
Do you know who we are?
Yeah, I know you fucking are.
Last January, the two of you--
shot an innocent mother
and a kid, killed him in Newark.
Yeah, so who's the fucker, you are?
I brought something to give you.
Uh-huh.
But you have to watch what I'm doing.
You watching?
Oh!
[GUNSHOTS]
Ah!
Oh, shit.
[GROANING]
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Fuck!
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
No, no, don't touch.
Don't touch, don't touch, don't touch.
Fuck!
Look at me.
Look at me, you motherfucker.
You can't die!
He needs somebody to fucking pass you.
If you die, it won't fucking work.
Look at me!
Stay alive, you piece of shit!
[PANTING]
Fuck.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Ah!
Fuck.
Fuck!
Now I just know who to pass you.
No, no, no, no.
Who the fuck are you?
No one.
I'm losing.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Answer me.
I just buy from them, OK?
I fucking hate those guys.
I hate them too.
I fucking hate those actually.
And please, don't shoot me.
I didn't know anybody else was here.
I didn't fucking
know anybody else was here!
I fucked this whole thing up.
I'm sorry.
It's what meant for you.
What?
What was it meant for me?
I'm sorry.
What?
What are you talking about?
Fuck.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
What?
Yo!
What the fuck is that?
Shit.
Fuck.
Where's the--
Come on!
No, no, no, no, no, shoot!
Fuck! Fuck!
Get in the fucking--
Fuck!
Bring the fucking one down!
Bring it!
Fuck!
Suck up, motherfucker!
Fuck! Fuck!
Thank you, everybody.
Now, nearly one
year ago, singer-songwriter
and pop superstar
Sky Riley was fighting for
her life after being injured in a car
accident, an accident
that also tragically took the
life of actor Paul Hudson.
Today, for her
first public interview since
the accident,
ladies and gentlemen, the one
and only Sky Riley.
Oh, my gosh!
I'm so happy to be doing this with you.
I mean, I have got to say
that you look incredible in person.
As do you.
Your hair.
Oh, my God.
I was just trying something new.
I'm not sure if I'm pulling it off.
What do we think?
Oh, my God.
I think you have your answer.
Now you've announced new tour dates.
You're actually kicking off
right here in New York City next week.
Is this an emotional comeback?
Yes.
A lot of different
emotions, you know, with this one.
A year ago, you had just won a Grammy.
You were in the
middle of a big world tour.
And then you hit this rough patch.
Rough patch might be generous.
I was wondering if you could share
anything from that period of your life.
I was dealing with a lot of stress
and pressure from the demands of the tour.
And I should have asked for help, but
instead I drowned it
all out with drugs and alcohol
and a lot of bad decisions.
And I let myself get
completely out of control.
And actually, I want to take this
opportunity to
apologize to my fans, my loved ones,
my team, everyone who was
counting on me and supporting me.
I let you all down.
And I promise that
will never happen again.
You were in the
hospital when you got out.
What has the time
been like between then and now?
[screams]
I spent a lot of time looking inward,
relearning how to appreciate life sober.
And I'm just so grateful for the
second chance, and I don't want to waste it.
[music]
A car is waiting
right outside by the curb.
It's a bit of a crowd.
[screams]
[music]
That went really well.
You were perfectly graceful.
Yeah, Sky, you've got Instagram
and TikTok seriously blowing up right now.
You're turning number
23, I can't see you. [music]
Good.
Eyes up.
[music]
Are you okay?
What happened?
Are you hurt?
Yep, I'm fine.
I'm fine, I think
I just took a weird step.
Let's take a break, everyone.
Can we get some ice?
Anton, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Sky.
Can we please just go again?
I want to get it right, okay?
Okay, let's go.
Line up.
Music.
[music]
[music] [knocking]
One second.
Yeah, come in.
Hey.
You okay?
You ready to go?
Yeah, Mom, I just need a minute.
You should feel really good about today.
I know.
I do.
Good.
We're ready whenever you are.
Final rehearsal's
confirmed for Wednesday.
So we'll be at the
venue first thing in the morning.
You have a fitting photo shoot, then
stage walkthroughs, then a fan meet and greet.
Please go straight
to bed when you get home.
It's going to be a long day.
Oh, and a reminder,
Darius gets in tomorrow.
He's going to be here after opening.
I want him to feel the love, please.
The label is advancing
a lot of money on this tour.
Have I ever not been good with Darius?
Darius adores you, obviously.
I just want you to
remember who's paying the bill.
Hey, straight to bed, Skye.
Goodnight.
Riley.
[sirens]
Hey.
[sighs]
What the fuck, Louis?
What do you want from me?
I get in just-- I get in just
for-- I have pain same as last night.
Fuck that, Skye Riley.
It's just going to suddenly show up here.
You texted her to come over.
What?
I don't-- I don't remember texting her.
How come I don't remember texting her?
Oh, she's got the fuck off me.
Get the fuck off me!
Oh, oh, she-- Holy shit, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I am having the worst week.
The worst!
Louis, what was with the sword?
What?
What sword?
Oh, that's--
I'm so sorry about that.
I cannot be too careful right now, okay?
I am in the middle of
some genuinely fucking freaky shit.
Okay, I'm talking like fucking
scary, fucking haunted house shit, you know?
[buzzing]
Yo.
Do you believe in like weird stuff?
Yeah.
I'm going to go.
What?
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Please stay.
What am I doing?
Scott fucking Riley's here
and Louis is being fucking crazy.
I'm so stoked to see you.
I'm pumped.
Come on, come in.
I will chill.
Be my guest.
Please, take his feet.
Make yourself at home.
I'm sorry about the mess.
You said you wanted-- what was it?
It was-- you wanted Vicodin, right?
Yeah.
I got you.
I want anything else.
I got banger ketamine.
I got really good fucking molly.
I got some-- I don't know what--
No, dude, just the Vicodin for my back.
All right, you're back.
Ouch.
That sucks.
I hate that.
Okay, will you
chill and I'll be right back?
You'll chill and
I'll be right back, okay?
I'll be right back.
Oh, my God.
You smell good.
I missed you.
Scott fucking Riley, dude.
I-- I--
(sniffing)
(laughing)
It's some snow.
I mean, this is not a huge storm.
It's not, you know, a-- a--
a dangerous situation out there.
It's our first snow of the season.
And over in pop culture news,
singer-songwriter Sky Riley is back.
Nearly one year after she
was hospitalized in a car crash,
a tragically killed actor Paul Hudson.
Hudson had been
driving the vehicle after the
high-profile couple
had left the private party,
where both were
reportedly seen intoxicated.
The accident occurred while Riley
was in the middle of a blockbuster tour,
and at the time, there was
speculation surrounding Riley's substance abuse,
especially after candid photos of the
singer went viral just two weeks before the--
(door opens)
Hey, uh, Lewis, I kind of have
a really early morning tomorrow, so...
(footsteps)
Lewis!
(sighs)
This fucking guy.
Lewis, what the fuck, man?
(footsteps)
Lewis!
I swear to God, if
you're fucking with me, dude...
(screams)
Jesus!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What the fuck did you come from?
What?
(panting)
No! No!
What?
What is it?
Get the fuck away from me!
What the fuck is happening?
No! No!
(coughs)
(thud)
Lewis?
Fuck!
What do I do?
Do I call an ambulance?
Fuck.
Shit!
Lewis! Lewis!
Lewis!
What the fuck?
Lewis?
Fuck!
Shit!
You fucking ODE-ing, man?
Fuck!
(eerie music)
Lewis?
(sniffles)
(Clara Rememberful!! campsite in Paris)
(wall rattles)
(screaming)
(panting)
[SIRENS]
[GASPS]
[ROAR]
[SIRENS]
[GUNSHOT]
[SIRENS] [SIRENS]
[SIRENS]
[SOBBING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[PING]
[DOOR SLAMS] [SIRENS]
[SLEIGH BELLS RINGING]
[GROANS]
[SOBBING]
(crying)
(gasping)
Oh my god.
Oh, gee.
Oh, fuck.
God.
(gasping)
God, I'm like, I'm like.
(crying)
(gasping)
(ominous music)
(gasping) (ominous music)
(crunching)
(gasping)
(ominous music)
(muffled voices) (ominous music)
What?
Yeah.
This stuff is important.
I'm listening.
Are you okay?
You look exhausted.
Wow, thanks, Mom.
It's really important for you to stay
on top of your sleep schedule.
Joshua, grab her a water.
I'm fine.
I want you to have someone around
to help out with things again.
Have you talked to
Gemma about coming on tour?
Gemma is not gonna
wanna hear from you, Mom.
Have you reached out?
No.
Exactly.
She's your best friend.
I'm sure she'd be willing to forgive
whatever it was that
happened between the two of you.
You're a completely
different person than you were.
Can you please just leave it alone?
All I'm saying is real
friends are hard to come by.
And it was really good
for you when Gemma was around.
I'd be more than happy to help out
with any personal stuff Sky might need.
I don't want that.
You need to stay hydrated.
Will you just stop?
Okay.
No, sorry, not you.
Come in.
Hi Darius.
I wanted to say hi
to my favorite rock star.
I get up and hug you, but I'm trapped.
I'll come to you.
Look at you.
Hey Darius.
Hey man.
Starting to get exciting around here.
Oh my God, I am so excited.
I have a little favor to ask of you.
Sure.
Tomorrow night there's a fundraising
dinner for Music Aspires Hope.
It's the foundation
for underprivileged youth.
Interscope Records has done a lot
of work with the foundation.
I know this is super last minute,
but I was hoping you'd be willing
to be a special presenter.
I know you've got a lot on your plate,
but there's no arrival carpet, no press,
none of that annoying stuff.
It's purely about the kids.
Your remarks will be pre-written.
All you have to do is
smile and read from the teleprompter.
How could I say no?
Number three.
Let's start with the 70.
(muffled talking)
All right, Sky.
Loving this.
Can you give me more?
Even more.
More.
(dramatic music)
(gun fires)
(keyboard clacking)
(sighing)
(inhaling)
(exhaling)
(inhaling) (beeping)
(eerie music)
(keyboard clacking)
(gasping)
(eerie music)
(screaming)
(gasping)
(eerie music)
Hi, man.
Come on.
You're shitting, you're shitting.
(sighing)
(door slams)
Jesus!
Can you knock?
We were knocking, you weren't answering.
Why were you screaming?
I saw a spider.
Sorry, there's a spider in here.
Tanya says there's some wardrobe issue
that you needed me to look at.
Yeah, I'm not wearing this one.
I love it.
What's wrong with it?
Can you show her, please?
The lighting's gonna
show right through this on stage.
And?
I'm not trying to show
everyone how fucking disgusting.
I think you're overreacting a little bit.
Yeah, Scott, you know what?
I think your scar is badass.
It is badass. Seriously.
I mean, this is
honestly one of your best looks.
I'm not wearing it.
(eerie music)
(thunder rumbling)
(upbeat music)
There you go.
Thank you, thank you.
All right, let's grab that photo, yeah?
What?
Could we do matching poses?
Of course, what are you thinking?
Um, like, okay.
(upbeat music)
Twinsies, super cute, thank you.
Thanks for coming out.
Who's next?
Too much for one heart got me through
literally the worst breakup of my life.
I feel like you're my spirit animal and,
oh my gosh, can I give you a hug?
Oh my gosh, yes.
Scott, you gotta check out my SoundCloud.
Like, who does your production?
All right, dog,
let's grab that photo now.
Nice.
Oh, can we do one more vertical?
Doctor, I need a new brain
Oh my God, that was amazing.
Could you sign for Alfredo?
Love,
Skye.
Yeah.
(upbeat music)
Here we go.
All right, let's take that photo.
I'm a really big fan.
No, thanks for coming out.
I can see your sat on the inside.
Sorry, what?
I could make you happy.
We would be so happy to get there.
Okay, thank you, got it?
And you're so beautiful,
you have the most amazing skin.
Dude, get the fuck out.
I love you, I love
you, Skye, Skye, Skye, Skye,
I love you.
Hey folks, just
give us like one quick sec.
You okay?
(sighs)
Can you take a break?
You sure?
Let's just get through this.
Skye, everything great?
Yeah, fine.
All right, who's next?
(phone ringing)
Hi, what's your name?
It's a pretty cool shirt you got,
you want me to sign it?
(soft music)
Okay, how about a photo?
Yeah, that's so sweet.
All right, one, two, cheese.
All right, now that's a good one.
(soft music)
(ominous music)
(phone ringing)
It's Gemma, leave it.
Hi, hi, it's me.
I was just
thinking about you and how much,
how much I want to
apologize about everything.
Anyway, I don't know
if you want to talk to me.
Will you call me, please?
I miss you.
(phone ringing)
Hey.
How have you been?
Pretty good, I guess.
Surprised to hear from you.
I know, sorry I
just called out of the blue.
That's okay, it's cool.
Actually, I kind of feel
really overwhelmed at the moment.
I know it's not, I
know it's not your problem
and it's probably really
shitty of me to even be calling you
but I don't really have
anyone I can talk to right now.
What's going on?
Any chance you'd want to come over?
Well, like right now?
Yeah, unless you're busy or something.
No, I, yeah, no, I can
come over, yeah, give me like 45.
Perfect.
Okay, cool, see you soon.
See you then, bye.
(sighing)
(door slamming)
(water dripping)
(sighing)
(door opening)
(door closing)
(somber piano music)
I'm just scared
(sighing)
(somber piano music)
I got thick skin but I'm all
Made up of broken bars
Got a body but it's borrowed
With a shadow for a heart
Is this how my story's told
I get hurt and
(glass clattering)
(footsteps)
Hello?
(sighing)
(door opening)
(door closing)
(door creaking) (door knocking)
(door creaking)
(somber piano music)
(crying)
(eerie music)
And I
(crying)
(door clicking)
(dramatic music)
(panting)
(screaming)
Jesus, fuck!
What is happening right now?
Shh, shh.
Is someone else here?
(eerie music)
Skye, what's going on?
What the fuck?
Right, so I'm confused.
Oh, hi, choo choo.
How did you get here so fast?
Wait, why, what do you mean?
You called me like an hour ago.
An hour?
Whoa.
How you doing, Skye?
I, um, didn't sleep last night,
and I think I had some sort of crazy,
lucid nightmare fever dream,
and it scared the,
it scared the crap out of me.
Thirsty?
This therapist from my recovery program,
she suggested that
anytime I feel overwhelmed
by the urge to use or get drunk,
that I should stop whatever I'm doing
and drink a full glass of water.
It's supposed to be some
sort of form of acknowledgement
for what I can and can't control.
Well, it's good to see you.
Jesus, Gemma.
I'm so sorry.
I was a ginormous fucking asshole.
I know you such a huge apology.
You really do.
I don't know why it's taken
you like a year to tell me that.
I know, I'm sorry.
I, I did want to call sooner.
I just didn't know
if you would forgive me
or if you like hated me
and never wanted to hear from me again.
Apology accepted.
Oh, God.
Fucking love you.
You know that, right?
Seriously, am I right or die?
Okay, okay.
Before we start like
sucking each other's dicks,
what's going on?
Why are you being so weird?
I don't know.
Such a mess.
This time, Master, are we talking?
No.
Something really bad happened.
You remember Lewis Vergoli?
Lewis Vergoli from high school?
He died in front of me yesterday.
What?
I went to his
apartment to buy Vicodin from him.
Sky, what the fuck?
Just for pain, I swear.
Gemma, I haven't
touched alcohol or coke in a year.
I promise, but my back is still fucked
since I have a
history of substance abuse.
No one will prescribe me
anything stronger than Tylenol.
You think that maybe
there's like a reason for that?
Well, I don't know what else to do.
Everyone's counting on me.
Okay, just wait.
All right, go back.
What happened to Lewis?
When I showed up, there
was something off about him.
He was scared of something.
He started freaking out and screaming,
like screaming, screaming,
and then he grabbed this metal gym way
from a bench press.
He like just smashed
his whole face in with it.
What?
Ew, oh my God, what?
I don't know what to do.
I just freaking ran out
and Gemma, I just left him there.
Does anyone else know about this?
No.
Should I tell the police?
No, Sky, no, listen to me.
If anyone connects
you to a drug dealer's death,
the story will take over your entire life
and fuck up everything.
It's not your fault.
I keep seeing his face everywhere.
She feels fucked up.
Yeah, no wonder, I can't imagine.
How scary that must've been.
Oh God, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry I'm
laying all of this on you.
I just, no, I just don't
really have anyone to talk to.
You want me to spend the night?
Really, would you?
Me and Marty here.
Oh God, I missed you, but I didn't.
(ominous music)
(crying)
(gasping)
(sighing)
I hear you okay.
Yeah.
(sighing)
Gemma, I'm so sorry about everything.
I know, it's okay,
I heard he forgave you.
(somber music)
(gasping)
I don't know why I destroy everything.
I feel like my brain is...
This really fucked up place,
full of all this chaos and noise,
and I'm trapped there, all alone,
in this darkness, and
I just wanna quiet the noise,
but I don't know how.
So because you're a horrible person,
what did you say?
Gemma?
(gasping)
(crying)
(ominous music)
Oh hey, you're up.
What the fuck is happening?
What do you mean, I made matcha?
Matcha, wait.
Wait, it's morning?
What time is it?
Fuck, fuck, I'm so
late, why didn't you wake me?
I'm sorry, I didn't
know, I don't have your schedule.
My mom's gonna fucking kill me.
Shit.
Can I help you or something?
Will you come on tour?
What?
Come in a rehearsal with me today.
I can't, I have a
friend's thing later on.
What?
What friend, do you have to go?
Well yeah, I made a commitment.
Well then can you start tomorrow?
I mean, I don't know, I
sort of feel like this is like
a thing we should have
a conversation about first.
Are you kidding me?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
There are a hundred
people waiting for just you.
I know, I know.
Okay.
Hey Elizabeth.
Thought we said 830.
I'm so sorry, it's my
fault, but I'm ready, I'm ready.
Let's do this, I'm sorry everyone.
Here, don't start,
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
(humming)
(screaming)
I need some water for
my daughter, for my daughter.
I need some water, I need some water.
I need a waiter with some water,
I need a waiter with some water.
(sniffing)
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
I got a secret to tell you
I think you already know
(humming)
There's something wrong with me
Bet you can see it's starting to show
(humming)
I'm feeling different in my skin
I feel like something is changing
(humming)
Is it just me or are the colors melting
Nothing to paint
Might be a tragedy
Death stitch right in front of me
Am I a future disaster
This waiting, it happened
Light, blood and white
But the sea is shaking out of my way
I'm holding glass in
my head and it could break
Nothing so physical
Maybe a cynical disaster
Waiting, it happened
Light, blood and white
Sittin'
Oh
It's like the switch of an engine
I think I broke all the brakes
Am I defective
Cause I'm dying to make stupid mistakes
Oh, might be a tragedy
(gun fires)
(screams)
Fuck!
God.
Oh my God!
Fuck!
Oh, fuck, fuck!
(screams)
Fuck!
Oh God!
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
You okay?
My leg!
What happened?
What's wrong?
(beeping)
Who was that?
One of you was out of
place and knocked me over.
Who was it?
Sky, I don't think that's what happened.
Do not tell me what
I just experienced, Anton!
I'm not.
I'm just saying that
from where I was watching,
I didn't see anyone out of place.
(ominous music)
Sky!
(gun fires)
(ominous music)
Yeah.
(ominous music) (gun fires)
(sniffles)
(phone rings)
(ominous music)
(sniffles)
(gun fires)
(grunts)
What happened?
Where's Joshua?
Christ, what did you do?
Hey, everything okay?
Can I get you anything?
What the fuck is your problem, man?
Sorry, what?
Are you fucking with me?
I have no idea what
you're talking about, I swear.
He trashed my dressing room!
What?
No, I didn't!
I fucking saw you, Joshua!
Sky, I, Sky, I
would never, ever do something
like that to you, okay?
Come on, what reason would I have?
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
Fuck you, Joshua, fuck you!
All right, that's enough.
Mom, you need to believe me.
He did this!
He fucking did this!
To cool off.
You're not actually taking his side!
I am on your side, okay?
Always.
But Joshua has
been with me the entire day.
What?
What are you even talking about?
Look, I don't even
care what happened in here.
We'll get it fixed.
I just, I need you to tell me the truth.
I'm gonna ask you something,
and I want you to be honest with me.
Sky, are you using again?
What?
Nobody has to know.
You just have to tell me the truth.
Oh my God, no, I am not using again, Mom.
You want me to take a drug test?
Okay, I believe you.
What's going on?
I don't know, I don't know.
I just, fuck, I feel crazy all the time.
Everything's going wrong.
Nobody will fucking listen to me.
And everyone fucking hates me.
Come on, do you hear yourself?
Everybody loves you.
We're all here for you.
We're here because we believe in you.
We believe in this tour.
I think doing this
tour was a huge mistake.
It's too much.
I'm not ready for it.
Okay, you know what?
We're gonna look at the book tonight,
look at the dates, carve out some time
for you to decompress before opening.
But right now, you
need to pull it together
and get back out there, okay?
Because we need to be on time
for Darius's foundation event.
Fuck, no, Mom,
please don't make me do that.
No.
I can't get out on stage
in front of a bunch of people tonight.
Skye.
Mom, you're not, fuck,
you're not listening to me.
I am not in the head
space to put in a fucking dress
and play dancing monkey
in front of a room full of strangers.
Darius is counting
on you to be there, okay?
You gave him your word.
You are a woman who keeps her word.
You are not gonna cancel on a commitment
to underprivileged youth
right before launching a tour.
(sighing)
(dramatic music)
Music inspires
hope, was founded on the idea
that no dream could be true.
With the help we've
enforced, everyone in this group,
and from all of us across the country,
the foundation has been
able to reach more families this year
than ever before.
Thanks to you, more
and more children every day
are able to make
their wildest dreams a reality.
And now, without
further ado, it is my great pleasure
to introduce our
wonderful, strong artist,
ladies and gentlemen,
please put your hands together
for Skye Riley.
(audience applauding)
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I'm Skye Riley,
and I'm here tonight to...
I'm here tonight to...
(clears throat)
So, how's everyone doing tonight?
Hope you're all enjoying the party.
Don't worry though, I'm sober, so.
(audience chuckling)
What can I say
about how music inspires hope?
Well, music gave me
everything I ever wanted.
Then again, music did
almost kill me, so there's that.
I guess that's not fair.
Music didn't put all
those drugs up my nose, I did.
(audience chattering)
I think I'm supposed to be up here
offering words of inspiration and advice.
Well, when I think
about what I wish someone
would have told me when I was younger
and first getting
started, I suppose I'd say,
this business is really hard.
And you'll spend years
of your life chasing success,
thinking that when it
comes, it will magically fix
everything that's
bad and wrong about you.
And then you
achieve success and you realize
that it can't fix
the deeply broken person
that you have always been.
And now you can't
escape the miserable thing
that you've
become, and one day you realize
how badly you wish
you could just trade it all
just for one fucking moment of happiness.
Oh, sorry about that.
What I meant to say
is I hope the next generation
of young artists finds
themselves truly inspired tonight.
I know I sure am.
And without any
further ado, I'd like to introduce
our next guest, a very special person
who surely needs no
introduction, Paul Hudson.
(audience chattering)
Why does it say that?
That's not, this, no, why did,
that's, why did,
that's, that's.
(ominous music)
No, no, stay away from me.
Stay away from me.
Paul's dead, you're not.
Paul, stop smiling at me.
No, no.
I can't hold it.
(groaning)
(panting)
(gasping)
(screaming)
(audience chattering)
(ominous music)
(panting)
Okay, okay, okay.
Lucy.
It just stares at me, smiling.
(screaming)
(panting)
No.
(screaming)
(ominous music)
(audience chattering)
Thank you for agreeing to see me.
What are you doing?
Sending a photo of you to my friend
in case you're some kind of creep.
What, I'm not a creep.
Well, that's whatever a creep says.
(audience chattering)
Look, I realize you're super famous
and I invaded your privacy.
I apologize.
This is also very weird for me.
How do you know Louis?
I don't, I didn't.
I was trying to
contact Louis to warn him,
track down his
address and went to his apartment.
The front door was
unlocked and he was already dead inside.
I checked his phone
and you were the last person
he texted with.
What were you trying to warn him about?
Look, I'm aware
that what I'm about to say
is going to sound completely insane,
but Louis didn't kill himself.
He was
systematically infected, possessed,
and then murdered by
some kind of metaphysical being.
What the fuck are you talking about?
If it helps, you might
call it a spirit or a demon.
Maybe, I have no clue what this thing is,
but it disguises
itself to look like people,
like smiling people, but only the person
that's been infected by it can see it.
That's not real.
That's some supernatural bullshit.
But you've seen it, haven't you?
That's why you're still sitting here.
I don't know, I
don't know what's happening.
I feel like I'm losing my goddamn mind.
That's precisely
what this thing does to you.
It's what it did to Louis
while it was latched onto him.
It's like a parasite that
infects a host through their mind.
In less than a week,
it drives the host insane.
It's like it feeds off
all the bad shit in her head,
and then once it's done feeding,
it forces the host to kill themselves
in front of a witness,
and then that
witness becomes the new host.
That's how you got it from Louis.
Before that, it was
passed to Louis by a cop in Jersey.
That cop was the
first one I tried to contact,
but I guess he went off the grid.
The cop caught it from some
doctor who got it from a patient,
who got it from a college professor,
and the chain keeps going back.
I've documented all of this.
I can show you,
right? Why did you even know
all of this?
Because it killed my brother.
My brother was a host.
Eight people before you.
He tried to tell me
what was happening to him,
but he made it hard to trust him,
and the stuff he was
saying sounded certifiably crazy.
He begged me for
help, but I didn't listen.
And then a few days later,
I got a call informing
me that he tore his own jaw off
with a crowbar.
(gunshot) Have you gone to the police?
And say what?
My brother's suicide was actually caused
by some cosmic evil
beam that no one else can see.
The police can't stop this thing anyway.
Aren't you supposed to
wait until this thing kills me?
No, I want you to help me destroy it.
How?
From what I can tell, the chain stops
when an infected
host dies in some other way
outside of the beam's control.
My guess is that
just like other parasites,
without a living host,
it has no way to survive.
It ceases to exist.
So it only stops if
I die before it kills me?
Exactly. We need to kill you first.
What?
Only technically.
Look, there are ways that
we can very safely stop your heart.
That'll deprive it of a living host.
Once it goes, I can
resuscitate your heart and bring you back.
You're out of your fucking mind.
I know. It seems extreme.
Extreme? You're asking to kill me.
Whoa, hey, just keep it down.
I don't even know. I don't even know.
My name's Morris. I'm an ER nurse.
And if we don't do
this, it's gonna kill you
like you killed Lewis
and infect another victim.
Look, I've already
got everything prepared.
We should just go right now
and get rid of this thing tonight.
I can do this.
You're nearly out of time.
This thing's been feeding
on you for three days already.
It's already
taking control of your brain,
and pretty soon you won't even realise
the way this is manipulating you,
and then it'll be too late to stop it.
We have to go right now.
Skye, does that sky ryley?
Holy shit, dude. That sky?
Oh, that sky ryley!
Would you do a quick TikTok with us?
No, right? You should do this, Skye.
I watched that video.
We knocked down
that old lady like 50 times.
That shoe was so fucking funny.
(all cheering)
Skye!
(door creaking)
(ominous music)
(door slamming)
(heavy breathing)
(door creaking) (heavy breathing)
(dramatic music)
(door creaking) (door creaking)
(dramatic music) (dramatic music)
(dramatic music)
(door creaking)
(door creaking) (door creaking)
(footsteps)
(footsteps) (footsteps) (footsteps)
(footsteps) (footsteps)
(heavy breathing)
(screams)
Fuck!
(footsteps)
(screams)
(footsteps) (heavy breathing)
(heavy breathing)
Fuck! ( ideas falling )
( screams of pain )
(diabolic ampersands Itsome changes with slow, solemn, long pants)
(ropic breathe of a felled Composer)
(grunting)
(screaming)
(breathing heavily)
(beeping)
(screaming)
(breathing heavily)
(glass breaking)
(growling)
(screaming)
No!
(glass breaking)
(grunting)
No!
(glass breaking)
(grunting)
(screaming)
No!
(screaming) (grunting)
(screaming)
(eerie music)
(sniffling)
What?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Are you crying right now?
I'm crying.
Are you crying?
Hmm?
Huh?
Hey, hey, I'm fucking talking to you!
Are you fucking kidding me?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What the fuck is wrong with me?
What the fuck is wrong with you, huh?
I don't know, I
don't know, I don't know, Paul.
Why don't you tell me
since I can't do anything right?
Jesus Christ!
I swear, I swear,
fucking God, you are so--
What, what?
What, I'm so, I'm so fucking what?
Say it, say it, what am I?
Tell me, I am so fucking--
Huh?
You're fucking psycho!
Oh, yay!
Yeah!
Psycho!
It's out of the bag!
You're fucking crazy!
I'm so you crazy!
Oh, yeah!
You wanna fucking be crazy?
Yeah, yeah, stop it!
Fucking crazy!
Stop it, what are you doing?
Paul, that fucked you!
Stop, stop it!
Is it crazy?
Yes, that is crazy!
You fucking psycho!
Jesus fucking Christ.
Fucking drive.
Fucking hate you!
Good, good!
Because I fucking hate you too.
I fucking...
You crazy bitch.
(laughing)
You psycho bitch!
Are you gonna cry?
Are you gonna cry now?
Is that your name?
Oh, God!
Oh, you look so
fucking ugly when you cry.
It's horrible, I can't...
I can't fuck it.
(crying)
Oh, help me, God!
(screaming)
What the fuck are you doing?
What are you doing?
(screaming)
Oh, my God!
(crying)
It's okay, it's okay.
Everything's fine.
Hey, hey.
You're okay.
You have a mild concussion.
Where am I, where am I?
Harvest Moon, it's
a private wellness clinic.
You fainted and hit your head.
We found you lying on your living room,
floor unconscious.
The doctor said you were sleep deprived
and extremely dehydrated.
No, no, that's just not...
That's not what happened.
Sasha, could you go find Dr. Fowler
and let him know Sky's awake?
Of course, yeah.
I hope you're feeling better, Sky.
I brought a sweatshirt for you,
just in case you get cold.
(sighing)
We can cover that with makeup,
and the team's
already working on a fill piece
for your hair.
Don't worry, you won't
be able to tell the difference.
And I've cleared your schedule,
so today you can just have a whole day
of rest and recuperation.
Where's my phone?
I need my phone.
It's right here.
I got it.
I need it, give it to me.
Maybe later.
Right now we're
just gonna focus on relaxing.
Please, please.
Something really
crazy is happening to me.
I need to get out of here right now.
No, we are gonna stay here together
until we head to the
venue tomorrow for the pre-show.
That way we can make sure you're 100%
and ready to perform.
No, no, I can't, I--
Can't what?
I can't do the show.
If you cancel the show,
then you will be checking yourself
into a recovery program.
That's the only
explanation as to why Sky Riley
is canceling another
tour the night before it starts.
You will have to explain to the label
who've invested millions of dollars.
Mom, you're putting the work there.
Mom, you don't understand.
No, you don't understand, Sky.
There are no more second chances.
If you cancel, this is it.
The media will rake you over the calls.
We'll be sued by the label for millions.
It will be the end
of everything we've built.
Oh my God.
Why is that all you care about, Mom?
You treat me like
I'm some fucking wind-up toy.
You don't give a shit about me
other than the business.
I bring in--
You arrogant little asshole.
I have given up everything for you.
Every second of my time.
Years of my life, my career,
and here I am
sacrificing every fiber of my being
to support you.
You're too selfish to even see it.
You put everyone through absolute hell
and still we support you.
But you want to go and throw it away?
Fine.
Do it.
Throw it away.
I don't care.
That's what
everyone expects of you anyway.
I wish you could feel what it's like
having to live inside my head.
I've tasted what's inside your head.
No, no, please, no.
Please, no.
No.
No, no.
No!
(glass shattering)
(screaming)
No, no, no.
What are you doing to your poor mother?
No.
(glass shattering)
(crying)
(eerie music)
(glass shattering)
(gasping)
(gagging)
No, no, it's not real.
It's not real, it's not real.
It's not real.
No, no.
(glass shattering)
No!
(gasping)
(knocking)
It's Joshua.
(footsteps)
(gasping)
I need a second.
I'm changing.
Sorry.
You know what?
I'll wait out here.
Also, the doctor said
he's gonna come and see you
in a few minutes.
Actually, I feel kind of thirsty.
You think you should
go find me something to drink?
Oh, I brought some bottles of water,
put them in the little refrigerator.
I feel like soda.
Could you get me a soda, please?
Sure, yeah, no problem.
What kind?
Any kind, just surprise me.
You got it.
You know what?
I'll be right back
with one surprising soda.
(gasping)
(door slamming)
Fuck.
(gasping)
(crying)
(eerie music)
Sky?
Are you, oh my God, is that blood?
No.
Hey, we need a doctor over here.
Yeah, can we please get some help?
Somebody please come help us.
Fuck off, she had
an accident or something.
Are you hurt?
We need a doctor or something.
Oh my God, Sky.
Hey, this is Dr. Rosales,
I need to send somebody
down to the lobby immediately.
No, no, no, no,
easy, I got you, I got you.
Get away from me!
Oh, shit!
Hey, just take it easy.
(gunshot)
Oh my God, get the fuck away from me!
(crying)
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Sky?
Sky, what are you doing?
Think about the tour.
Fuck, the tour!
(gunshot)
Man, what the fuck?
Jeez.
That's guy riding.
Looks like a fucking wheel.
(eerie music)
(dramatic music)
(gunshot)
(screaming)
Stop!
Fuck!
Oh, God.
Sky?
What are you doing out here?
Jenna, what are you doing here?
Your mom told me, are you bleeding?
In your car, here.
Why is no of your mom driving from me?
Why? Where is she?
Why don't you just
drive me up over there?
What's going on?
What happened?
Sky.
Where are you, fuck?
Hey, get out, I need your car!
Miss Riley, what?
Shut the fuck up!
I'm fucking out of here!
She got a gun, she got a gun!
The fuck are you doing?
Jenna, I love you, but
if I don't leave right now,
I'm gonna fucking die!
Fuck it, I'm coming with you, move over!
No, Jenna, no!
You gotta drive, move over!
(screaming)
(dramatic music)
Dude, where are we going?
What am I doing, where am I going?
Where am I going, Sky?
I don't know, just keep driving.
No, I need you to
explain what the hell is going on.
I need to get to Staten Island.
What, gross, why?
Oh shit.
(screaming)
Jesus Christ, you
didn't go to a hospital!
No, I need to go to Staten Island!
What the fuck is going on?
Why are we going to Staten Island?
(grunting)
Sky?
Jenna, pull over.
What, you just told
me to go to Staten Island?
Jenna, just fucking pull over, please!
All I've ever done
is make your life hell.
I don't deserve
you, so please just pull over
and get away from me so
I don't fuck up your life too.
(breathing heavily)
Now fuck that noise.
Ride or die, bitch!
I need to tell you something.
What?
(phone ringing)
Sky.
Huh?
Hey, it's me.
I got your voicemail,
sorry, it's taking me a few days
to get back to you, but
honestly, I wasn't even sure
if I was gonna call you back.
Did you spend the night at my place?
What?
I haven't been to
your place in like a year.
Since you said I was a
stupid opportunistic cunt, remember?
Also, what's up with these
weird-ass fucking text messages
you've been sending me?
Hello?
No!
Jenna hates you, Sky.
No, please, please,
Jenna, no, please, Jenna, no.
I'm here, please.
Please.
No, no, no, no, no, fuck you!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, fuck you!
(crying)
Tell me to fuck up.
Let me go!
No one cares about you.
This is gonna happen to you.
You're not driving, you're not driving.
You're not driving, stop.
You're in my head, you're in my head.
You're in my head, you're in my head!
You're in my head!
You're not in control, I am!
I'm in control, I'm in control, I am...
I'm in control, I am
in control, I'm in control...
(screaming)
(dramatic music)
(breathing heavily)
I'm in control.
(screaming)
Fuck you!
Why'd you fucking cry?
(dramatic music)
(car horn honking)
Jesus Christ!
Christ, are you okay?
Where are your shoes?
Shut up, here, take this.
Why are you having--
Just take it!
Hey, if this
theory of yours doesn't work,
or you see me change and start smiling,
shoot me in the--
Whoa, hold on!
Hey, you need to stop it, no matter what.
We're going to.
Promise! All right!
All right, I promise I'll shoot you.
How do we stop my heart?
(door slamming) Sorry, I
haven't done anything about the lights.
Is this a pizza hut?
It's the only thing I
could find for lease on short notice
that had a large enough freezer.
Why do we need to freeze him?
For your brain.
Fuck.
Once we stop your heart,
your brain stops receiving oxygen.
Normally, necrosis sets in immediately.
You'd have two minutes, maybe,
before permanent brain damage occurs.
But if we bring your
body temperature down far enough,
we can delay the process,
giving us up to nine
minutes before permanent damage.
We need to make sure this
thing isn't able to hang around.
And I like our odds with
nine minutes better than two.
(door slamming)
(eerie music)
Freezer door latch is broken.
If it closes all the way,
it can't be opened from the inside.
(phone buzzing)
Here, change into this.
Jesus, that's a lot of blood.
Are the cops gonna be looking for you?
I don't know.
Let's just do this.
Once your body
temperature drops low enough,
I will inject you with a
drug that will cause your heart
to start slowing down until it stops.
How long will it take?
It's critical you reach
flatline as fast as possible.
So I'll need to inject it
directly into your internal jugular.
After 30 seconds, you'll be dead.
Wait, wait, wait.
Jacob, look at my neck.
I see the needle.
(door slamming)
What the fuck, man?
I know, sorry.
Lie down here.
(sniffing)
(breathing heavily)
Oh my God, I'm so fucking cold.
Oh, that's the idea.
I'll be monitoring your heart rate.
The moment you flatline,
I'll start a timer for eight minutes.
Once the timer's up,
I will inject a dose
of adrenaline into your heart
and start CPR resuscitation.
I can't believe I
might die in the freezer
with a fucking pizza.
I promise I'm gonna bring you back.
Morris, I'm sorry about your brother.
I know the story you're doing this.
Thank you for helping me.
Can I ask, what
made you change your mind?
Every good thing in my
life ends up broken because of me.
I hurt everything and everyone I touch.
It doesn't matter
what happens to me anymore.
But I've not let
this fucking thing use me
to hurt anyone else.
Put this in your mouth.
Don't move.
You just have to get something.
I'm hurt, where are you going?
(doorbell ringing) (dramatic music)
Morris?
(crying)
Hey, don't leave me alone here.
Morris.
(crying)
No!
(gun firing)
(crying)
I've been waiting
for you for such a long time.
Morris, Morris, what's that?
Morris, can't help you anymore.
It's just you and me.
I like wearing your skin.
(gun firing)
You can't get away from me, Skye.
(crying)
(screaming)
You'll never escape who
you truly are on the inside.
(crying)
You got me!
(screaming)
(crying)
(crowd cheering)
(crying) (crying)
Fuck you.
(crying)
(crying) (crying)
This isn't real, Skye.
(crying)
You're not in control, Skye.
I am.
(crying)
Break a leg out there.
No!
(crying)
Skye!
(crying) (crying)
I'm dead.
(crying)
What the?
(crying) (crying)
(crying)
(eerie music)
(screaming)
(gunshots)
Knocked out, love will be the death of me
I'm not scared to go on a good road
I'm not scared