I told you not to look for me.
Please, Father.
That's all I have.
The only proof of what they've done.
But she looks so...
Human.
But don't let yourself be fooled.
She wasn't conceived naturally.
They found a volunteer.
Someone devoted
But how did they...
No, please.
I can't uh...
I can't talk about that.
What I can tell you...
is that the pregnancy happened quickly.
She'll be in her teens now.
They're just waiting
until she's old enough.
Old enough for what?
Now, please.
I can't do this anymore.
I can't
But please don't let it touch me again.
Father?
Father Harris?
Hiding won't absolve your sins.
You think I want to be forgiven?
I don't want to be forgiven,
Father Brennan.
I just want it all to be over.
You'll understand...
soon enough.
Father, are you all right?
I'm fine.
Father.
Il volo sefte quattro due,
in arrivo da Milano Linate,
arrivera con quindici minuti dr ritardo.
- Margaret Daino?
- Yes.
- Hi.
- I'm Father Gabriel.
- Hello.
Cardinal Lawrence sent me to fetch you.
- Oh, sure. Thank you.
- Let me help you with that.
He's in the car outside.
I have heard so much about you.
I feel like I already know you.
Maggie!
- I'm so happy to see you.
- Oh, me too.
Oh, it's so beautiful here.
It's like a dream.
Well, wait till you see the actual city.
Look at you.
It hasn't been a year, and somehow,
you've found a way
to grow up even more.
Is that all you've got?
That's it.
Well, my word. Come on.
I'll show you to your new home.
So, what do you think?
It's wild.
Everything's so different.
Every street that we pass,
there's something to look at.
I just wanna explore.
Isn't it beautiful?
What better place
for you to be taking the veil?
It's wonderful to see you, Maggie.
Even when you were little,
I knew you were destined for great things.
See if you can get around them, Damiano.
These protests
have picked up recently, I'm afraid.
What are they protesting?
For the workers,
it's about conditions and wages.
But for the students, well,
it's a rejection of authority,
even the church.
The world is changing, Maggie, very fast.
The younger generation
no longer turn to us
- for guidance, I'm afraid.
- Ooh!
But it's a challenge we've embraced.
Perhaps you'll play your part
and help earn back their trust.
I'll try.
Come la treccia!
Tu devi essere la nostra bella Americana.
This is Sister Silva,
the Abbess.
And she'll take good care of you.
- Hello.
- Bellissima.
Welcome to our family.
Oh. Thank you.
Ooh.
Come. Come with me.
Let me give you a tour.
We're so happy to have you here.
This way.
We take care of girls.
Girls only.
A total of 62.
Babies to 18 years of age.
Come this way.
Buongiorno.
Buongiorno. Hello.
The state has contracted with us
to take in many unmarried women
who are about to give birth.
We have our birthing facilities
here in the hospital wing.
Come, come.
Our doctor will likely deliver
this baby within the week.
- Ciao, Lanoma.
- Salve.
- Come stai?
- Bene.
Tranquilla. Tutto va bene.
Pazienza, hmm?
Andiamo.
Sister Anjelica.
This is Margaret Daino from America.
She grew up here.
Abandoned on our front steps,
and very ill.
But she's very devoted
and she keeps all the children smiling.
And they all seem very happy.
Scusi.
I should see what the trouble is.
Of course.
Via dal cancello faccello.
La tua suora ・sempre gentilissima.
Amen.
Hail Mary.
Um...
Ave Maria is my favorite, too.
Il mo preferrito.
What's your name?
Come ti chiami?
I'm Margaret.
Mi chiami Margaret.
Hi.
Um...
What are you doing?
Get off of me!
Oh, there you are.
Have you been behaving yourself, Carlita?
Carlita.
Did you do that drawing outside, Carlita?
The one where the girl's floating
above the other girls?
I thought it was very nice.
Thank you.
Come.
Why is she kept alone like that
in the middle of the day?
It's safer.
She hurt another child just yesterday.
Luca will be your driver.
Rome has become a bit dangerous
with the protests.
Hello?
By Your divine mercy,
rein in the power of evil.
Build us into living stones
of a culture of life,
who demonstrates in both deed and word,
the truth that every life,
no matter its conditions,
is precious and unrepeatable.
Lord, speak to every human heart
and fill it with the conviction:
I am wanted.
I have a task in history.
I am accepted, and I am loved.
It is good that I exist.
Margaret's one of
our worst-behaved children...
What if she has another episode?
Then you must tie her to the bed.
Here. Let me show you.
Hi.
Mierda.
Ah, you must be Margaretta.
Yes.
- I'm Luz.
- Oh.
Did I wake you?
No, no. Um...
I was having a nightmare.
First night nerves?
Don't worry, same thing happened for me.
If we can't admit how we are feeling,
our dreams do it for us, right?
You're a novitiate?
Oh, yeah.
I just figured a little
exploration is healthy
before the big day.
I mean, I will be hiding this body
under a habit for the rest of my life.
So, why not let it breathe a little now?
Coffee?
So how does a girl from...
Uh, Pittsfield. Massachusetts.
So how does a girl from Pissfield
end up in Italy about to take the veil?
Well, Cardinal Lawrence was, um, a priest
at the orphanage that I grew up in.
And we got pretty close
because, uh,
well, I was somewhat of a problem child.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
You were a problem child?
Like how?
I don't know. I guess, uh...
I mean, I used to get punished a lot.
And how did they punish you?
And where did you get these?
Hey.
And you are a nosy girl.
Do you know that?
Well, would they beat you?
Would they beat me?
No, not really.
I used to have
a pretty active imagination.
I'd get so convinced sometimes
that what I was seeing was real
that the sisters would need to, um...
subdue me.
But then Cardinal Lawrence
came to the orphanage,
and, uh, he was really great, you know.
He really helped me to see
that all that stuff was just in my head.
Things got a lot better for me after that.
For me,
it was a voice.
I was 16.
Just kicked out of the house.
It was so cold that night,
and I didn't know what to do.
And then...
this warm wind came...
out of nowhere.
And suddenly it was as if
His voice was all around me.
Inside me even.
So clearly.
And He told me it didn't matter
if I had no earthly home
because my true home was with Him.
And for the first time in my life,
I felt like I belonged on this Earth.
Yes,
but even with the most handsome
milkman in town,
we still had a whole group of us
who took the veil together.
Yes.
Now, instead, girls go off to college
and poor Luz is taking the veil alone.
- Hmm. And Margaret...
- Mm.
Margaret will be alone in the chapel, too.
Don't worry.
I'll warm it up for you.
Warm up? What is this "warm it up"?
As if Mr. Milkman didn't teach you.
I'm sorry!
It's true!
Practice it again.
Sono una farfalla.
E devo volare.
No, no, no. Shy American.
Say it with passione.
With passione?
Okay. All right.
Sono una...
- Farfalla.
E devo volare.
Good?
Good.
- Yeah・
- Yeah.
What does it mean?
"I am a teacher and I love to teach."
Silenzio.
Silenzio, ragazze.
Padre nostro, che sei neri ciell,
sia santificato il fuo nome,
venga il tuo regno,
sia fatta la tua volonia,
come in cielo cosi in terra.
Dacci oggi
il nostro pane quotidiano,
e rimetti...
No! No!
Margaret.
There you are.
I'm sorry I scared you. Come on.
I have something to show you for tonight.
You're gonna love it.
Ah-ha!
There she is.
Oh, my God, you look hot.
- I look naked.
- Yes.
What do you mean, naked?
You look gorgeous.
Come on.
Up with your foot.
The other one.
Mother Mary.
Don't be nervous.
Can you stand?
No.
Yes, you can.
Hmm? Whoop.
Perfect.
Luz?
Yeah?
I can't do this.
Tell me.
Have you ever been to a bar?
No.
- A disco?
- No.
Anything at all?
Because your whole life, you've wanted
to give yourself only to Him, right?
Look, I know.
I know it's scary coming out
from under the habit,
but look at you!
You're a very beautiful girl, Margaretta.
And you have to understand
that about yourself.
If only to know
what it means to give it up.
So, let yourself feel it. Okay?
Be brave.
So...
To the bravest girl I know.
Go.
Do you still feel your feet?
Oh, my.
Yes.
Okay. Another, then.
Hello.
- Parlate italiano?
- What?
Parlate italiano?
Ah, no. Not when I'm drinking.
Too hard.
Inglese, per favore, no?
If you can.
I'm Alfonzo, and this is Paolo.
Hi.
Uh, we can buy you a drink if you want.
Excuse me.
Um...
Can I have a sip of that?
Ah, yeah, eat it.
- Eat it?
- Yes. Eat it.
I was watching this movie
with my mother yesterday.
- Yeah?
- And, um...
And was with Barbara Streisand,
and I just... I don't know.
I love her and...
- You do?
- I do.
- Barbra?
- I love Barbara.
- Yes, Barbara Streisand.
- Barbara?
Barbra, yeah.
I mean, it was the part with the "Hello,
gorgeous."
Hello, gorgeous.
Gorgeous.
Uh, what? Gorgeous.
- Gor... Gorgeous.
- Gorgeous.
You know, it's...
Sorry if I'm not a "professional..."
- It was good.
- Like Barbra.
But, um, what do you... what do you do?
Um...
Well, since you asked, um...
I am a butterfly...
And I must fly!
- Volare?
- Volare.
Okay.
A butterfly? Well then,
I must not keep you from flying!
- What?
- Dai... dai!
- Come on.
- Where are you going?
Come on.
Darkness all around me
This is the BBC World Service,
and it's the 3rd of June, 1971.
Riots have erupted in Rome,
with clashes between the far left
and far right groups escalating rapidly.
The unrest has caused
widespread damage to property
and has left several people injured.
Italian authorities are struggling
to contain the violence and restore order.
Public transportation, factories,
and schools are heavily affected...
Good morning.
Did you have fun last night?
Yeah.
I'm guessing you've never
drunk like that before.
I didn't, like,
embarrass myself or anything last night,
did 1?
No. No.
Okay.
You were well-behaved.
Mostly.
Okay. I found you before
anything got out of control.
And for the record,
I was a very nice friend.
You came home with me.
Thanks.
But it wasn't easy
pulling you away from him.
What do you mean? I didn't...
Let's just say
you took my advice to heart.
You were a very brave girl, Margaretta.
But, hey, don't worry.
It's our little secret. Okay?
I am loved. I am accepted.
It is good to be a human being.
It is good to be alive.
Excuse me.
May I sit?
No, please, please stay.
I'm sorry. Do I know you?
My name is Father Brennan.
I apologize for startling you.
Please sit with me.
This will only take a few minutes.
Your name is Margaret Daino.
You work at the orphanage.
You're new there.
I don't understand.
How do you know that?
It's about the girl. Scianna.
Carlita?
You must be very careful, Margaret.
Bad things will start
to happen around her.
Evil things.
No, I have to go now.
No, no. Please, please.
Come see me tonight.
Saint Rita cloister, room 42.
I'll tell you everything.
Good morning, farfalla.
Good morning.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Just a little tired, that's all.
Where's Carlita?
She's in the bad room.
The bad room?
Dirty.
Sister.
Sister, I need your help.
Carlita, she's locked in a room.
That's right.
She bit Sister Romano just this morning,
so she had to go to the bad room.
Sister, why is there a bad room?
Because some girls are bad.
This room is suffocating.
It's not meant to be pleasant.
The things we do aren't always pleasant,
but they are in the name of God.
Do you wanna talk about
why they put you in that room?
Sono cattiva.
I'm bad.
Oh. You're bad.
Well, guess who else was bad.
Who?
You?
Oh, yeah.
But you know what?
I realized that I'm not bad.
They just tell you that you are
because you're not doing
what they want you to do.
Back then, I used to think
that there was something
really, really wrong with me.
What did you do?
Well, I guess at first,
I tried to run away.
But, uh,
it didn't fix the feeling.
That's what I like about you, actually.
What?
What do you like about me?
I think that you feel
the same way that I felt.
But you're not scared, you don't run away.
You just...
You raise your little claws,
and you fight.
Carlita, go to your room, okay?
I'll be right there.
- Linfermiera, la ragga.
- Si, dottore.
Forcipe, per favore.
Forcipe.
Stia ferma.
No!
Stia buona!
Everything looks all right.
You did say you didn't
eat much in the morning.
May be low blood sugar.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry? Margaret, what for?
You wouldn't be the first to faint
witnessing the birth of a child.
Frankly, I'm surprised
it doesn't happen more often.
The miracle of life
can be a messy business.
You guys mind if I join?
Carlita, did you do this drawing?
This part is mine.
It's a boy.
Uh, I don't think
that that's very appropriate, Sister.
You all right?
Yes?
Andiamo!
Um...
Here. Let's... Let's go for a walk.
- Join the group.
- Oh, not today, girls.
- Come on!
- Okay.
Venite, venite!
No, no, no, not me.
It's all right. It's okay.
You ready?
It's all for you.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, don't. Don't!
Don't!
Psst. Psst, psst.
Margaret. Come in.
Something happened, didn't it?
Yes. Um...
One of the sisters took her own life.
You mentioned the name "Scianna."
That's right.
I assume you know these people.
The priest is named Spiletto.
He's a radical.
Yes, I've seen him.
Turn it over.
The baby in this photo is Carlita?
I believe so.
And this is why she's in danger?
I know these sisters.
They're women of God.
They belong to the Church.
Listen to me, Margaret.
The truth is there are two Churches.
The one that follows
the teachings of Christ,
the one that you and I are part of.
And the other.
The Church that will turn a blind eye
to torture, to rape.
To commit murder in the name of God.
All in the name of supreme power.
What do you think that Church
is most frightened of?
The Devil?
Secularism.
We are living in unprecedented times.
Look at what's been occurring
in your very own generation.
A culture that is outspoken, rebelling.
Sometimes violently.
People are turning away
from the church in droves.
And, Margaret, you know as well as I do
that belief is power.
Now, how do you control people
who no longer believe
in your stories of fire and brimstone?
People who do not seem to fear?
You create something to fear.
This Church has maintained
power for generations.
Thousands of years.
And they will stop at nothing
to keep it that way.
So,
a small, but very powerful group
of priests and bishops,
even higher,
they decided
something drastic had to be done.
These priests...
believe they can birth the Antichrist
and then control him.
Allow him to bring his dark forces
to bear on the world just enough
to drive people back to the Church.
That's insane.
Yes. Don't you see?
If no one believes such a thing can exist,
who will stand in their way?
What does any of this
have to do with Carlita?
I was excommunicated.
My contacts within the Church
are very limited.
That photo is all I have to go on.
But I believe the baby girl in the picture
is to be the mother.
The mother of what?
Of the Antichrist?
Yes.
Oh, my God. You're crazy.
Look, if I am right,
Carlita would have been born
on the sixth day
of the sixth month at 6 a.m.
666.
It's the mark of the Devil
which she will have on her body.
I don't understand
why you're telling me this.
They're keeping her files
at the orphanage.
Locked away.
I need you to get them to me.
I need to know how she was born.
What do you mean, how she was born?
Listen to me, Margaret.
There is a beast they're mating.
A jackal. That's the father.
- I have to go now.
- No, no, Margaret.
If Carlita is, in fact, the mother,
the evil inside her will do
whatever it takes to stop us.
We must destroy it at all costs.
- Do you understand?
- No.
Carlita is a little girl.
And she is not pregnant.
But we're not talking about a human child!
It's almost June 6th.
Look, we haven't a lot of time
and I need your help.
No, you need a doctor.
I'm sorry that I can't help you.
Will you let go of my arm?
Oh. Margaret.
- Hi.
- How are you feeling?
Um, I need to talk to you about Carlita.
Do you know anything about her history,
or how she came to the orphanage?
Um, not off the top of my head. Why?
Do you know where I could find
that kind of information?
I'm afraid this is not really my area,
you know?
What?
Why do you keep staring at me?
I'm not.
Will you come with me?
Come on.
I need to talk to you about something.
But before I do, I...
I just want you to know
that you can trust me, okay?
Okay.
Um...
Has anyone ever done anything to you
that might have scared you
or upset you?
I don't know.
What don't you know?
Sometimes I get this...
bad feelings.
I see...
I see things.
And I can't tell if they're real or not.
Listen to me.
When I was younger,
I... I used to have these
horrible visions.
They were so terrible that
convinced myself that they were real.
But I learned that those thoughts,
they were just lies.
Just tricks that my brain
was playing on me
because I was so unhappy.
This isn't a lie.
How can you know that for certain?
Carlita.
I'm sorry.
Carlita. I'm sorry.
There you are.
A riot's broken out.
We must go.
Deve andare adesso
Listen.
It's all right, girls.
It's okay. Stay close to me, okay?
Stay close to me, okay?
Carlita!
Silenzio.
Silenzio, ragazze.
Padre nostro, che ser nei ciell,
sia santificato il fuo nome,
venga il tuo regno...
Margaretta.
Sister Silva would like
to see you in her office.
Please take a seat.
Margaret...
Part of my job here is to look out
for the well-being of all those
who are under my care.
I'm sure this will come as no surprise,
but I've become concerned.
I'm fine.
Perhaps I should have put it this way.
We are concerned.
Myself and Cardinal Lawrence.
We think it might be time
for you to take a step back.
And perhaps we postpone your vows.
What? No. Why?
We're also concerned about
your attachment to Carlita.
Carlita?
- But...
- Cardinal Lawrence told me
about your troubles growing up.
Your hallucinations.
Perhaps being around Carlita
is not what's right for you.
Carlita is disturbed.
And her illness must not infect us
as her caretakers.
And clearly, it has.
Wait.
I'm not ill.
I understand how hard you had to work
to get to where you are.
It would be a shame to give it all up now.
I am the only one who cares about her.
You don't let her play
- with the other girls.
- I've told you...
- You keep her in the bad room.
- We're only doing
what's right for her.
The girl is sick in the head.
Because of you!
If there was any doubt in our decision,
you've all but confirmed it.
You're clearly unwell.
And, Margaret,
you will keep your distance from Carlita.
Or there will be consequences.
Stop the car, Luca.
I can just walk home from here, okay?
You don't have to wait.
Paolo.
Paolo!
No, no, no.
Lasciami stare, ti pego, ti prego.
Paolo?
Just leave me alone, please.
Hey!
Sorry. I'm sorry, I didn't know.
- Really, I didn't know.
- You didn't know what?
Just stop following me!
Paolo, talk to me.
Just look for the mark.
Oh, okay.
All right. Oh, God. Okay.
All right. Um...
Hey, call an... call an ambulance.
Call an ambulance.
- Help me.
- I'm gonna help you.
I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
I'm gonna help you.
- I can't move.
- I know.
- I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
- I know. Okay.
- I'm scared.
- Paolo,
you're gonna be fine, I promise.
I don't wanna die.
No, no, no.
You're not gonna die,
you're gonna be okay.
You ready?
Oh, no, no.
Oh, God.
Oh, no, God.
Shh.
In nomine Patris, et Fill,
et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Deus,
benedice hunc anulum.
Da ut soror quae induat altam fidem
in te habeat et remaneat
tibi fidelis in omni tempore.
Accipe hunc anulum,
nam aeterno Regi spondes.
Serva fidem cum sponso tuo
ut ad cenam nuptialem
aeternae gaudii venias.
Amen.
Oh, god.
Come on.
Farfalla! Farfalla!
Oh, God.
Carlita.
Come with me, Carlita.
Okay, you go to the bed.
I am so sorry that I didn't believe you.
But I believe you now.
Okay?
I'm gonna keep you safe.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Margaret.
Go, go, go. Over there.
- Margaret.
- You stay away.
I know what you're doing.
We don't want to hurt you.
Just put that down.
I know what you've done with the babies.
You stay away! No!
You stay away from me!
- Remain calm!
- No, no, no!
Please, please, I'm sorry.
No, no, no!
Not in there! Not in there!
Not in there!
No! No! No!
Let me out!
Please let me out!
Please!
Breathe. Breathe.
Crucifxus mortuu.
Sede da divinum.
Conviction:
I am wanted. I have a task in history.
I am accepted. It is good that I exist.
It is good to be a human being.
Let every human heart
experience your love.
It's not real.
It's not real. It's not real.
What's not real?
Who said that?
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
No!
Margaret. We have to go.
We have to go. I found the files.
We have to go now. It's just me.
It's just me.
Get me out of here.
Yes. I know. I know.
All right, all right.
Father Gabriel. Margaret.
I don't understand.
How?
Oh, well done, Margaret. Well done.
Were you followed?
What? No.
I don't think so.
Luca, Margaret's driver, brought us.
We can trust him.
He's keeping watch outside.
You two know each other?
- Yes.
- No.
Uh, he tried approaching me.
I thought he was crazy.
It is crazy.
Carlita.
We have to go get her.
No, it's not safe.
Not safe?
She's the one who's not safe right now,
Gabriel.
Margaret, after what just happened,
they're not gonna let us
anywhere near that orphanage.
Especially Carlita.
He's right.
It's only a matter of time
before they realize we've got these.
And when they do, they will come for us.
We have to help her.
The only path forward
is to prove what they've done.
Otherwise,
no one will believe a word we say.
There's so many of them.
Yes.
Too many.
I had no idea they'd gone to such lengths.
I don't understand.
They need a male.
They've only birthed females.
They've all died except for Carlita.
After all these years, so many failures...
They believe the only way
is for the beast to mate
with its own offspring.
What is this?
I told you,
it's the photo from Carlita's birth.
No.
This.
It's the mark.
Carlita doesn't have the mark on her head.
Hers is here.
What are you talking about?
I've seen it.
You see? Carlita.
No mark.
The baby in this photo is not Carlita.
What does that mean?
Brennan?
I don't know.
Well, if this is the child
that we're looking for,
then all we have to do
is find a baby with the mark on its scalp.
We must have missed something.
Right?
Where is it?
Why do they all look like this?
The father. He's not human.
It's her.
There was another survivor.
A sister?
Did you know about this?
No.
They must have kept it hidden away.
Look for the mark.
How did he know?
He knew where it was.
Margaret, Margaret. Hush.
Margaret. Margaret.
Margaret.
Just let me have a look.
Let me look.
Somebody say something.
How is that possible?
She's been a ward of the Church
her entire life.
They must have moved her around
to cover their tracks.
Carlita must be too young,
so they brought Margaret back
to Rome to...
To what?
I have to get out of here.
- You can't leave.
- Don't touch me.
- Margaret...
- Don't you touch me!
You can't just leave.
Touch me again, I'll fucking kill you!
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry this is happening to you,
my child.
But nothing will change
if you decide to leave.
It's June 6th.
Midnight.
They will be coming for you.
If this is true...
If I am pregnant...
then I need it out of me.
I need it out of me now.
Margaret,
you all right?
This doctor knows what he's doing?
He's experienced, yes.
Wait. Stop.
What are you doing?
Don't stop.
Make like you're heading for the main road
and then turn off before the arch.
Margaret.
What's happening to me?
Hello?
Can anyone hear me?
Yes.
I can hear.
I can't tell if this is real or not.
This is very real, Margaret.
Can you untie me?
Soon.
Soon it will be all over, I promise.
No.
- No, no.
- Oh. Oh...
You don't have to be afraid.
I won't let anything bad happen to you.
I've watched over you
since you were a little girl.
The very first moment we met,
do you remember what I said to you?
That you, Margaret,
were the bravest girl I'd ever known.
Now you know how special you are to me.
To us.
The baby you're about to bear
will redeem the Church.
Will bring the people back to God.
All because of you.
Don't you understand, Margaret?
Your whole life, you've been searching,
waiting for His voice.
But the truth is...
He was always there with you.
He brought you here.
He chose you.
I... No.
There.
You're ready now.
Please know that I love you.
I'll be right here.
Stay down.
No, no.
No, no. Please.
Please, please, please.
No.
No, no, no.
No, please.
Please.
Help me, please.
Please help me. Please.
Please untie me.
Please untie me, I'm in pain.
I'm in pain. Please.
Help.
Help me, please.
Please help me.
Help me.
Help. I'm in pain.
What is it? A boy or girl?
There are two.
A girl...
And the other?
A boy!
We have him.
In nomine Patris, et Fill,
et Spiritus Sancti.
Help.
- Help. Help.
- Of course.
Of course, my dear.
- I'm in pain.
- Of course.
Can I hold him?
You're sure?
I'm his mother. I'm his mother.
Bring him here.
She's right.
It is important for a child
to bond with its mother.
We all need the comfort of our mothers
in the beginning.
Don't we?
You did so well, my child.
You are doing God's work.
He would be so proud of you.
Can't you hear Him telling you?
Don't you hear His voice?
No.
No, I only hear my own.
No!
Margaret.
Stop this.
Margaret,
give me the baby.
Just give me the baby.
No!
Burn everything.
Leave them both to die.
It's okay.
The man you are looking for.
The US Ambassador to Rome.
He will be the new father.
He and his wife will suffer a tragic loss,
and be in need of a child.
The boy will inherit their privilege
and power.
Soon, his darkness will spread
and the world shall be saved.
Baby, you're supposed to eat them.
You're supposed to eat them like...
Like that.
What are you doing?
Come here.
No, no, no. Here.
This.
No, not this.
You want one?
You want it?
Give it to Mama. Give it to Mama.
Give it to Mama.
I'm so sorry, Margaret.
I tried just to leave you be.
You need to go.
Now.
I came to warn you.
They know you're alive.
You weren't supposed to survive.
None of you were.
Especially the girl.
She'll be important, Margaret.
I just want to be left alone.
I know.
But they will come for you.
They've even given it a name.
Your son.
Damien.