So, who is the woman
in the station wagon?
Beth.
Keenish.
Herr... Konish?
'Ö.' It's not an 'E.'
'Ö.' "Herr König."
Where's Gretchen?
Gretchen and the movers
are right behind us.
Okay, so, she's not your mother?
No, she's Beth.
Ah, okay.
And what is going on
with your sister?
She deaf or something?
No.
But she can't speak.
It's fucking annoying.
You okay, honey?
The nice man who owns this place
will take us to our new home.
Oh!
Ah, very good, Luis!
You've been practicing, huh?
How was your journey?
Oh, very pleasant, thank you.
We almost forgot
how beautiful it is here.
Ah, we almost forgot how
beautiful you are, Beth.
Oh, stop!
Keep going!
Gretchen, come say hi.
Gretchen.
- What's up?
- Oh, Jesus.
Nice to meet you.
Willkommen.
Thank you.
No, thank you, Beth.
We are so glad to have you back.
And please do not worry
about your late arrival.
I completely understand.
We have something for you.
It's...
The original sketch.
We drew that up the night
that you showed us
the land you acquired.
Beth, that is...
Well, we will display
this in the new guest lodge.
- Oh!
- You know, you two lovebirds
stumbled into my nest almost
eight years ago to the day.
And I believe there were more
than just architectural plans
that were conceived this day.
Hello, Alma.
Your German is already
better than your father's, huh?
Ja, ja.
Hey, Gretchen.
How are you holding up?
I wish we could have spent a little
more time together after the funeral,
but I get it.
You're all over Europe
with your dad's family, huh?
Don't forget you have a band
that needs your voice.
Anyway, I'm sending you
the new mix.
I knew your mom
would have loved it.
Beth? It's occupied.
Gretchen, let's go!
Herr König is taking us
to the new house.
Can you sit with Alma this time?
Car? What?
Car what?
What?
Hello there!
My name is Bonomo.
I'm your neighbor.
I have my hands full.
Oh, me too.
Are you the housekeeper?
No, I'm a daughter.
Oh, really?
Haven't heard about you.
Are you from England as well?
No, I'm not.
Why would you have heard
about me?
I told...
Jesus.
Forgive me, my dear.
Didn't mean to startle you.
I told Dr. Bonomo
about your family.
Dr. Bonomo is the medical
superintendent of the local hospital
and also the chronic disease
treatment facility,
which I am also funding.
This is Gretchen.
Gretchen.
Yeah.
Gretchen is from
the United States.
It has been decided that she
is moving in with her father.
What a pleasant surprise.
Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it.
Hi, mom.
I know this is weird, um...
But it's good to hear
your voice.
Going with dad was a bad idea,
and I miss our house.
I'm short on money, but I'm
gonna try to come home soon.
I know it's been tough.
But we are very happy
you're here.
Excuse me.
Gretchen, my dear.
I, uh...
I've been thinking,
for a young woman like you
there's... not so many things to do
here during the summer, and so...
I have a little idea.
A proposal. How would you like
to come work for me at the resort?
Oh, Herr König...
Well, it's an easy job,
and it will give you
something to do
while your parents build
the new resort for me.
I could use some more
English-speaking staff.
Herr König, I think Gretchen...
I would pay you an
appropriate salary, of course.
- I don't...
- Yeah, sure. I'll do it.
Oh.
Schön.
Wonderful.
Come by the reception tomorrow.
Here's your ID badge, sir.
Would you like to pay
with cash or credit card?
Cash, or credit?
Cash.
"That will be
45 euro for a single room."
Uh, that will be 45 euro
for a single room.
Oh, and this is Beatrice
and I am Gretchen.
You have to be polite and
friendly, even if the guest is rude.
And remember to put up the sign
if you go to the bathroom.
But if you have any real
trouble, just call the boss.
He lives up the resort street,
on the hill.
He lives in a vacation bungalow?
No, he has a villa way up there.
He bought the hotel,
and so the bungalows
are basically in the front yard
of his villa.
Weird, right?
Super.
This happens sometimes.
How's your first day, my dear?
Can't complain.
And how is your German
coming along?
Not good.
This is okay.
You know, there are
English-speaking schools
over the border, in Italy.
Well, I'll be along
to pick you up in one hour.
Oh, I have my bike.
Oh?
No.
No, no, no.
No, it will be too dark
on the country roads by then.
This is why you
will not work late.
You will help Beatrix
with the peak times.
What?
I thought we were going to split
the evening shifts.
You have a car.
I have a life, too.
Beatrix, I will not get drawn
into another debate with you.
I don't wanna have
a debate with you.
No. Every time I raise
an issue with you,
there is something
you have to say about it.
- I do everything you ask!
- No.
What? I work every day
late shifts!
You're blasting your
Scheisse music on the car radio
on your way to work.
I hear it across the forest.
This is a nature reserve
and you are disturbing
the wildlife
with your 'boom, boom...'
They can dance on the carpet...
Hey, Alma!
What the fuck are you doing?
Gretchen, turn it down!
Alma?
Shh, it's okay, it's okay.
What happened to your face?
My father's daughter
scratched me.
Your sister?
- She's not my sister.
- Oh.
Come on now.
I'm sure she really wants you
to be her sister.
She had a chance at getting one
but she ate her twin.
It's called vanishing twin
syndrome.
It's when one fetus dies in the
early stages of the pregnancy
and then the surviving fetus
absorbs the dead one.
I always thought
it was kind of badass.
But yeah, she's a bitch.
Okay.
Another reason to not have kids.
Thanks for finishing my shift.
Erik and I haven't been
on a date in ages.
Here's my master key.
There's only one. Don't lose it.
And at 10 p.m. sharp you lock
everything up like I showed you.
And boss doesn't need to know.
It's fine.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
Can I get a room?
May I see your ID or passport?
You can't just ask for my name?
Uhm...
Is it just you...
or are you here with a partner?
We have special rates
and amenities
for couples and newlyweds.
For now, just me.
Okay.
I'm Ed.
What's your name?
I'm Gretchen.
You look like
you don't belong here, Gretchen.
I won't be here
for long anyways.
You like music?
Sure.
Then you should come to Paris.
Okay.
Hey!
Is this normal?
It's only my second day.
Better go check on her.
Uh-huh.
Resort Alpschatten...
Gretchen?
- Yes.
- Where's Beatrix?
Uh, I stayed longer
and let her leave.
But I know how to lock up,
it's no trouble.
Gretchen.
I want you to lock the doors
and wait for me,
I will come pick you up
right now.
Uh...
Yeah, Herr König, it's fine.
There's a confused guest
and I need to go check on her.
But I have my bike here,
so you don't need to pick me up.
Gretchen, listen to me
carefully.
I need you to lock the doors...
Fuck no.
Gretchen?
Hello!
Please let me in!
Please let me in right now!
Please!
I started bleeding.
The woman stood there
until the police arrived.
I was chased.
Fuck!
It's really important that your
statement is as accurate as possible.
The receptionist, she stated that she
did not see any woman in the parking lot.
May I suggest...
we change the last part into...
"The woman stood there until
Mrs. So-and-so entered the room..."
"Then the police arrived."
That is so much better.
I think...
you are the victim of a prank.
Everybody
is very nice here, honey.
It's best we run some tests,
but this is actually
very common.
- Dad.
- Gretchen?
What happened?
Did you fall?
Yeah, that's not
the important part.
Your sister had
some kind of seizure.
We need to get her checked out.
Dad, I was attacked.
- By who?
- I don't know, the cops think it was a prank...
A prank? Did somebody hit you?
- No, I fell, but...
- Gretchen?
She fell, it's okay.
We are going to do an MRI...
It might be childhood epilepsy.
Epilepsy?
It might be?
It means it might be genetic
and not caused
by an injury or tumor.
The cause itself
isn't life-threatening.
- Well, that's good.
- Yeah.
The better news
is I'm the superintendent
of the chronic disease
treatment center up here.
What's causing the seizures?
There are many possible
triggers for a seizure in a child.
Fever. Certain lights.
Certain sounds.
A change in hormone levels.
But Alma is too young for that.
Has there been a stressful event
or disruption
in your family lately?
Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it!
Mom, this place
is completely fucked.
Alma keeps freaking out, and they
say she has epilepsy or something.
I think Dad is blaming me.
I'm coming back home.
I got the money.
- What happened to you?
- Jesus.
Uh, I don't wanna talk about it.
I'm police investigator
Henry Lando.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions about the...
incident last night.
Which one?
You told the police
that you were chased by a woman.
I don't wanna talk to you.
Excuse me?
Um... excuse me.
There's another guest waiting.
I think there's something wrong
with my air conditioning.
Could you come see me
when you're done?
Fine.
I'm checking out.
Oh.
Okay.
You didn't charge me.
Don't I have to pay
for the room?
Um...
No, you don't.
Do you smoke?
You coming?
Yeah, just give me a minute.
I have a house
back in the States.
I just need to get
to an airport.
Well, lucky you.
We have one of these in Paris.
And then the woman went
into that weird pink bungalow.
I wasn't going in there.
That pink bungalow
is called the "Lover's Nest."
and then the woman went
into that weird pink bungalow.
I wasn't going in there.
That pink bungalow
is called the "Lover's Nest."
and then the woman went
into that weird pink bungalow.
I wasn't going in there.
Watch out!
Do you smell this?
Yes.
Or are those molecules binding
to a receptor in your nasal cavity?
Got me.
And are you...
right now, in this moment...
are you putting your slashed
skin back together yourself?
And what makes you think
you can take charge of the rest?
Hm?
If I were you...
I would stay home
until my body was done
growing back those cells.
I wouldn't want
to get hurt even more.
As if I was stuck in a loop.
Can you... do this?
Good.
Apology accepted.
Luis.
What are you doing?
I'm getting my stuff.
What? You're not going
to sleep in the bed?
I mean, they said we can...
I can't sleep here again,
Gretchen. I've got work to do.
Beth has been watching Alma
while I've been here looking after you.
I have to go home
and give her a break.
- Please don't leave.
- You'll be fine.
There are people here
all the time.
No, there's not!
It's deserted all night!
It's fine. You'll be home soon.
What if she comes back?
Gretchen, stop it!
But why? I'm not making this up!
I don't want to hear
any more about this shit.
You're making it
very difficult for your sister.
I wasn't high.
Oh, you were!
You were tested.
You stole money from Herr König
and then you ran away
with a complete stranger.
I can't force you
to do anything.
You are almost eighteen
years old.
But you don't have a job anymore
and you will not
be getting an allowance.
If you wanna run away,
then take your fucking bicycle.
Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it!
Mom? Mom...
Mom, I really wanna come home.
It's really bad.
I just wanna come home.
Where's Gretchen?
Or what do you think?
What do you think, mom?
I told you to come see me.
I saved your life.
I saw the woman.
You saw her?
And you didn't tell anyone?
They think I'm crazy.
I need you to help me
find that woman.
She's wanted for murder.
And I expect her
to come for you again.
I can protect you.
If we find her...
I personally take you
wherever you want to go.
Does Alma listen to music often?
She loves music, especially
since Gretchen moved in with us.
Now...
And this is extremely important.
Nobody must know
about this investigation.
I don't know who to trust.
Loud music
has showN to trigger seizures
in people with Alma's condition.
Alma?
Dr. Bonomo says music, no more.
It's just music.
You going out?
A month ago,
a married couple on vacation
had rented this cabin.
A cabin not far from here.
The husband told the police
that in the evening
he'd lost consciousness.
When he woke up...
he found a strange,
blonde woman in his bedroom.
Along with his wife,
who he found unconscious.
The blonde woman's voice
had a hypnotic effect on the man.
He chased the woman into
the woods, but she got away.
When the husband returned
to the cabin,
his wife had choked
on her vomit.
Jesus.
Dude...
The other night, a half-naked
woman came into the reception,
and she wasn't responding
to anything.
Where was she staying?
The Lover's Nest.
You're right.
The next bungalow is not in use.
I didn't know stakeouts
were gonna be so boring.
When are we gonna see
some action?
Almost 11.
Be on the lookout and listen
for anything strange.
She'll choke.
Last time I was too late.
Gretchen?
Did we wake you?
All the owls
have individual calls
so that they can understand
each other over long distances.
And maybe we
can make a secret call
so that we
can understand each other.
Now, I brought you something.
I know that you will like this.
Gretchen, come sit with us.
Gretchen?
I'm so sorry, did we wake you?
No.
Okay, good. Please join us.
I went out last night.
Where did you go?
The resort.
What were you doing there?
I was with Trixie.
Hm.
I didn't know Beatrix
was working late last night.
She wasn't.
She was really confused.
Come to think of it,
a lot like the guest
we spoke about over the phone
the other night.
Hm. I will look into this.
Why is there nobody
working the reception after ten?
Seems like a lot of people
need assistance after ten.
It doesn't make sense
economically.
- That's stupid, it's a hotel.
- Gretchen!
I can show you the numbers
if you like.
It's not so interesting, but...
Maybe another time.
It's quite the place
you got here.
Gretchen, what's the matter?
Why did you bring us here?
Your parents are planning a...
A new resort, I know.
Why do we have to live here?
Gretchen!
Because it's pretty outside?
Calm down, right now.
You are here because your family
belongs here.
That's a fucking weird way
to put it!
- Gretchen, that's enough! What has gotten into you?
- I don't know dad!
I'm just reflecting on this very
fucking weird living situation
that everybody just seems
to be cool with.
Out!
Now!
- Great.
- No, no, Luis.
A gentleman knows
when it's time to leave.
You need some family time,
I understand.
No, no, no, Herr König,
we don't want you to leave.
It's alright, thank you
for the wonderful afternoon
- and I wish you a good evening.
- I'm very sorry.
No, Luis, we are
so very happy to have you here.
We've been desperately eager
for you to be here.
And Gretchen, if there
is anything that... bothers you,
don't be afraid to...
talk to me.
Oh, I leave your package
just here.
Oh... it was a surprise.
I was not supposed
to say anything.
I am so sorry.
What package?
- What package?
- It has your family name on it.
It was your mother's stuff.
The small stuff, at least.
I received it this morning.
I... your father should perhaps
change the address
on the counter...
What is it doing here, dad?
I sold the old house.
It was... still my house.
And I put the money
in an account for you.
I... I didn't want you
to get worked up again...
Hi, you have reached
the Vanderkurt residence.
Neither Gretchen nor Olivia
are here now,
but we are dying to hear
what you have to say,
so get ready to say it.
Mom, I really wanna come home.
It's really bad.
I really want to come home.
What do you think?
What do you think, mom?
What's your take on that, mom?
Next message.
Hello Ms. Vanderkurt,
my name is Alma.
I'm calling you
because of my sister, Gretchen.
Gretchen calls you
when she feels bad,
but you never answer.
I can hear her from my room.
I'm worried.
If you get my message,
I want you to call Gretchen
back on the phone.
You can tell her
that you love her.
It would mean a lot to her.
It would make her happy.
If you'd like to,
you can come visit us.
You are always welcome here.
Good, you're packed.
Do you even know how to drive?
Where is everybody?
They're at the hospital
with Dr. Bonomo.
Alma had a very strong seizure.
It's your fault, Gretchen.
You know that.
You terrified her.
I want you now
to write a farewell note.
Then we will pick up
some money for you at my house
and I'll drive you
to the station.
The last train leaves
in one hour.
Bring your bike.
You like it?
Sure.
You know it? A common cuckoo.
A magnificent creature.
Common.
Ah. But its behavior is not.
Its nature is quite remarkable.
A nature modern man
destroys by disregard.
Some species need our help
to survive and reproduce.
I'm a preservationist, you know?
Oh, come along now.
I want you to understand
who you got involved with.
Herr Lando here
was trespassing on my property
with an illegal firearm.
What are you doing?
He's a cop.
No, he's not.
Not anymore.
You see, Erik here...
is actually a policeman.
He has access to police files.
Herr Lando was recently
discharged
when they found out
he was investigating a case,
one that he is personally
involved with.
Okay, Erik. I think it is time to
take Herr Lando to the police station.
Gretchen, let's get your money.
This way, please.
Come along, now.
You are a liability, Gretchen.
I can't let you out.
What the fuck did you spray
me with?
Just pheromones.
I am giving you the chance
to be of great use
in our quest for preservation.
The adolescent
needs to be trained.
Consider yourself lucky.
It's a mild sedative.
What?
It'll make Alma sleep
through the night.
I'm staying here tonight.
These creatures can't speak
like you or I.
But when trained,
their song can be dizzyingly
persuasive.
Ah, ah, ah.
Something is not right.
Gretchen, your parents
need to hurry up
with those construction plans.
This one needs her own
mating grounds soon, no?
And you know what else
she needs, Erik?
What happened
to Herr Lando's wife
must not repeat itself.
I'm very sorry for what
happened to your wife, Herr Lando.
But this one's mother
wandered off my area of authority.
She got nervous
when this one left the nest
before we had another offspring
ready to replace her.
There were family matters
prolonging my endeavor.
Actually...
Are you aware that
you have had the good fortune
to witness three laying
ceremonies as of now?
Wow.
Most people don't get
to attend a single one.
And those that do
don't remember that they did.
A sacred process that keeps
an ancient creature alive and well.
A magnificent creature
whose approach to family
is beyond human comprehension.
Which brings me back to you,
Erik.
You will get Beatrix
ready to conceive.
Consider your mishap last night
a dry run.
Erik?
Shh...
Oh.
No, no, no, no.
You should be on your side.
You could choke, my dear.
Honey?
Honey, what's wrong?
I don't feel so good.
Take this.
I think they
impregnate women at the resort.
After my mom died,
I accidentally called
our house...
and I heard her voice
on the answering machine.
It kind of helped,
so I kept calling.
Maybe you can do that too.
Do you know what this bird
is famous for?
This bird lays its eggs in
the nests of other bird species
and then lets those birds
raise its offspring.
No! Not in here!
Your parents spent
their honeymoon here?
How old is your sister?
Gretchen?
Yes, I am fine.
We are in the treatment center
by the hospital.
If you come back in the morning,
Alma won't even know
you were gone.
Alma is going
to stay here for the evening.
Dr. Bonomo is going to monitor
her sleep.
Dad?
Beth and I are coming home.
Dad, I really need
to talk to you about...
What is it, Gretchen?
We can't trust them.
Gretchen, we can talk
when we're home.
I told you I will protect you.
Get ready.
What's wrong with Beth?
Dr. Bonomo, June 21st.
This is homo-cuculidae, Alma.
Astonishing resemblance
to her surrogate mother, Beth.
The surrogate mother's distress
grows in close proximity
to the biological mother.
Thus both host parents have
been removed from the premises.
Compared to animal brood
parasites,
homo-cuculidae developed
a unique evolutionary trait.
Instead of leaving their
offspring in the care of a host,
homo-cuculidae returns
to claim their young.
Contact with the biological
mother
speeds up the process of the
offspring's physical development
and its abilities significantly.
We are about to initiate the
first close-distance encounter
with the biological mother.
Brood parasites.
They don't impregnate.
They implant eggs.
My wife and I tried
to get pregnant.
I was supposed to fertilize
that egg.
Like your father...
on his honeymoon.
And then what do they do?
Release them into the wild.
When the mother shows up...
I end this experiment.
What about my sister?
That is not your sister.
Two.
Yeah, the sister
of the young one
and a rogue police detective.
Yeah, I am afraid we must commence
definitive measures immediately.
She's dead.
The feather
I wrote my name with.
The plumage of the apportioners.
Yeah.
No! No!
I'm not going to hurt you.
Alma. Alma?
Alma, we have to go.
We have to go now.
Just stay right here.
Cover your ears
and stay close to me.
Alma?
She's dead!
Mom is dead!
Where's your machine gun,
my dear?
Is it under your cast, huh?
Why me?
It's not about you,
you little brat.
This is nature.
She is supposed
to be focusing...
on reproduction and breeding.
And you are competing for
resources with her offspring.
Our process here ensures
that each new generation
we breed
is more powerful than the last.
And my dear,
when I am done with you
and reunite Alma with...
Stay away from her, Alma.
No.
S-She... can't.
But she says thank you.
Thank you, Alma.
I really need your help.
Henry!
You said you'll protect me.
I stand by it.
Did you ever tell your wife
you'd protect her?
What?
Did you tell her
you'd protect her?
Did you?
Yes!
Okay, we are coming out now.
Alma!
I need you to come
to me now, my angel.
What are you doing?
She's one of them!
Alma!
I don't think so.
Come to me.
She will be.
She will become!
- I don't think so.
- Alma!
We need to find out
how many there are.
I need to take my sister
away from this place.
- Stop!
- Let her go.
Let her go, she's destined
to become a mother.
She is not your sister!
They stopped reproducing before.
They will go extinct
without preservation.
Oh, they will go extinct.
Hundreds of years of research.
This is the will
of the apportioners.
Let her go.
You don't know
what you're doing!