Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Hmm.
[IN ENGLISH] Okay, cool.
Mmm.
Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
Uncle Malage.
Oh.
Wow. Okay.
Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh.
It's bullshit.
It's just bullshit.
They're just...
They're just
trying to scare me, all right?
They're trying to find
a religious explanation.
It's... It's nothing.
It's just bullshit.
Don't worry. It's nothing.
Huh?
Hmm?
Paco.
Yeah!
Yeah.
Uh...
Aye! Aye! Aye!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Um...
Hmm?
Oh...
Um...
Ah...
Mmm?
Uh-huh.
Mmm.
Ah.
Hmm?
Koffi...
Aye, aye, aye. Oh...
- Aye, ah, huh?
- Hmm.
Hey...
[IN ENGLISH] Damn!
My pussy hurts so bad.
What?
Is it that time of the month?
No, not even...
It's this burning feeling,
you know.
It's been two weeks now
but getting worse and worse.
How about you?
How's the roads?
I think I'm gonna sleep
at the next stop.
Dead, dead tired.
But I think I should be
there by tomorrow.
That's if I don't get
any problems
at the customs in Zambia.
You know how it is.
You'll be okay.
Okay, love.
You tell me
if there's any problem?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Take care.
- Love you, bye.
- Love you.
Wow.
Hmm?
[OVER PHONE] My love,
we must dissociate appearances
and the essence of the mind.
The mind is the creator
of happiness and suffering.
It is the creator of Nirvana
and negative emotions.
Ezra is an obstacle
to an infinite cycle.
I meditate
to control this emotion,
to transform my resentment
into karma of joy.
-
- We will be
the antidote
to this infection.
This mental poison
that lies within your organs,
within my organs,
results from our greed.
Mental poison
of our interrupted pleasure.
-
- I don't have the flu,
I get the flu,
and it will fade away
like white gel
in the light of healthy karma.
- My love,
call me when you arrive
-
so that we can
regenerate together.
What's the point
of getting tested
if you don't do all the STDs?
You slept again
with Malaika, didn't you?
She gave you something.
Ezra, you did.
I saw it. I know it.
I'm going to call her.
Hey, listen, you can go ahead
and fuck whoever you want.
But not with her.
Huh?
Hmm?
Hmm.
No way.
Fuckboy is here to take you
to live your best life
in Durban.
So what?
We couldn't wait
till we get to Durban
and see a real doctor?
So, now you're going to tell me
how your real doctors
treat this shit, huh?
I wouldn't be in this mess
if you hadn't
fucked with Malaika.
How could I have known?
You know she doesn't
protect herself.
All your fancy speeches...
of "Domination
should change first
in the bedroom", don't work.
What the fuck?
What does this all mean?
Palm oil doesn't cure shit.
I know. Sorry.
Okay.
♪ Falling to
your system again, I...
♪ Leave my dreams
in my bedsheets
♪ Looking out the window
again, I...
♪ I let you be the hero
♪ I'm losing
all my senses again
♪ Don't wanna be
a witness again
♪ I never get
as much as I give
♪ I wanna be
my reason to live
♪ I'm too old
to die young
♪ I'm too old to die
♪ I'm losing all
my senses again
♪ Don't wanna be
a witness again
♪ I never get
as much as I give
♪ I wanna be
my reason to live
♪ I'm too old
to die young
♪ I'm too old to die
♪ I'm too old
to die young ♪