Subtitle provided by[ME]💪
💪
That's them in there, just like that?
Just like that.
I wouldn't go in there for a day or two.
Heard the expression,
kick the hornet's nest?
I'll stay right here, thank you.
Those things scare me to death.
Yeah, they've been killing my honeybees.
A few days unchecked,
they'll wipe out out the whole colony.
What are you gonna do with them?
Well, that's between me and them,
if you don't mind.
That's okay.
I understand these things.
I just wanted to
thank you
for putting up with me
and all of my bees.
This place was crabgrass and weeds,
and you brought it back to life.
You're a blessing .
No one's ever taken care of me before.
I'll, uh...
Mr. Clay?
Come back at
supper time, let me feed you.
- Boss?
- Got something, yeah?
I got one.
I want it, I need it,
hey, clear my ear
Get this fucking hippie shit down, please.
Hi, United Data Group.
Good afternoon. This is Boyd.
How may I help you?
Boyd, uh... hello,
I just got a message saying that
there's a problem with my computer.
Don't you worry,
The message you received is from our
United Data Group Antivirus Software.
It's part of the software package
that pre-installed in your computer.
I'm sorry, I'm not a computer person.
What did you say the name
of your product is again?
Our record shows that you actually
have an older version on your account,
so what I'm going to need you
to do is uninstall that
and install the latest version.
I have no idea how to do that,
my daughter set up everything for me.
I would recommend you take
your computer to an IT specialist.
However, keep in mind that
you will lose all your data,
since they'll have to
replace the hard drive.
I'm pretty remote out here,
everything I have is on the computer.
Okay, there is actually a software
package that you can download
that would allow me to reinstall,
remotely.
Alright, tell me what to do.
Okay, can you type this,
friendlyfriend.net
Spelled just how it sounds.
Okay.
I'm there.
And there should be a button
on your screen that says install.
- Can you click on that button?
- I clicked the button.
So you're about to see some windows
open and close on your desktop
as I reinstall the virus shield for you.
Okay. I hope you fucking
clowns are paying attention.
You stick to the script.
But not so much that you sound like
a goddamn robot.
Alright?
She has got 10K checking.
Life insurance annuity,
Roth IRA, teacher's pension,
and holy fucking shit!
Alright, she is a signatory
on a $2 million account.
Some fucking charity.
Alright kids, let the script mining begin.
My computer's going crazy.
Totally normal.
Just do not touch
your keyboard.
This subtitle provide [byME]
Because of this inconvenience,
I'm gonna credit back
your subscription fees.
How about that?
I've gone ahead and deposited $500.
Into the account ending 020.
Oh, that's not my account.
That's an account that I manage.
Can you log into that account,
and verify the transfer,
please, Mrs. Parker.
Just hold on.
Yes, there's...
There's a transfer $50,000.
Set the hook!
With sympathy.
Mrs. Parker, I-I made a terrible mistake.
I was supposed to credit you $500,
but I don't know, I got a stuck key here.
I'm gonna lose my job here.
I got kids.
I ain't got fucking kids.
Oh, I don't want you to get in trouble,
but I could wire the amount back.
I will need a different
password.
One second.
This is the master password
for all of her accounts.
Okay, so the second we get it,
we zero out everything.
You know, I, um...
I think I should call the bank.
You know what? You're probably right,
but there goes my job.
And there goes all your data.
My kids' pictures are
on this computer.
Okay.
Boom... fucking yes!
That is what I am talking about!
Come on!
Let me fucking hear it,
I fucking love you! people!
I fucking love you!
Hello? Hello,
are you still there?
Oh!
Fraud Detection.
What did I do?
Mrs. Parker?
Don't move.
Don't you fucking move.
Drop the knife.
Hands behind your back.
Slowly, get on your knees
one knee at a time.
Now, who the fuck are you?
And what are you doing
in my mother's house?
Verona.
I'm so sorry.
How do you know my...
Mom...
Until we can clear him,
he's our best and only perp.
Clear him?
Agent Parker, I know that's
your mother. I understand.
But there's a word where
she commits suicide.
Suicide?
You can't be serious.
That woman loved life,
more than anybody, I know.
But by all means,
let's just completely ignore
the big white dude in
her house with a knife.
- Get him up.
- Come on.
It's Clay, right?
Adam Clay?
I don't have much to say.
Mr. Clay, we just got
a couple questions.
Like, What the fuck were you doing
in my mother's house?
I was bringing her a jar of honey.
A jar of honey?
Who the fuck are you,
Winnie-the-Pooh?
I keep bees.
How do you know my mother?
I rent some space in the barn from her.
I have a signed lease.
But what the fuck
were you doing in her house?
She didn't answer when I knocked.
I noted her car in the driveway.
I heard the smoke alarm
when I entered.
You "noted"?
You got a law enforcement background?
I told you, I'd take care of bees.
Oh, my God.
His hands test a negative
for gunshot residue,
but the prints on the gun
were your mother's.
It seems, sadly,
it was suicide.
Mr. Clay,
I need to apologize for last night.
I realize I may have been,
a little aggressive.
That's understandable.
Could I interest you
in something a bit stronger?
No.
But I'll sit with you if you like.
No, thank you.
I wanted to thank you
for taking care of my mom.
I tried to stay in her life
as much as I could.
Obviously I could have
done a better job.
Being old can be a lonely thing.
Turn a certain age,
you cease to exist.
Cease to matter.
Used to be a part of life,
of the family.
From the heart,
I guess you could say.
There's some British Isles
hiding in your accent.
I was born that.
I hated that she was
out here alone.
She wouldn't leave.
There's too many memories.
You know, I think I know
why she liked you.
You're just like my brother.
He was in MARSOC,
a Marine Raider.
He was killed
a few years ago kicking doors.
She loved him.
He'd mow the lawn and
you'd think he invented fire.
You know, while, I graduated
the FBI Academy and she said,
"Oh, that's nice."
She got scammed.
Somebody emptied out all her accounts.
Her savings, her retirement,
her every penny,
maxed out all her cards.
She was an educator,
director of a charity for kids.
They got two million
out of that account.
You know who did it?
I talked to an agent
in our cyber-crimes office.
This crew's been operating for two years
and we don't even have names.
And even if we did, good luck building
an indictment that would stand up in court.
Some defense attorney would just argue that
the elderly victim agreed
to wire a complete stranger
his entire life savings.
Taking from an elderly person
is as bad as stealing from a child.
Maybe worse.
If it was.
Someone hurts a child,
Parents, people who
care, ready to step in.
When someone hurts an older person,
Sometimes they are left
to face the hornets alone.
Because either
it goes unnoticed...
or no one cares.
I care...
And I'm stubborn.
And so help me God, I'm gonna get
these motherfuckers who did this.
I need to take care of the hive.
You've been up all night.
Hive is more important.
What are you doing?
I thought you retired.
I did.
I need a favor.
What kind of favor?
A name, an address.
Easy.
Not easy.
Even the FBI can't
find these people.
Well, we're not the FBI, are we?
Shoot me the deets
and stand by.
Yeah.
You weren't kidding.
This one kicked my butt.
They're routing all over the world.
But you found them?
Sure.
But who are these people?
I'm gonna find out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
The hell you think you're going, pal?
This United Data Group?
Don't know nothing about that.
This is private property
and you're trespassing.
I'm going inside.
I'm gonna burn it down.
Yeah, that's not happening, buddy.
You're not going any-fucking-where
except right the fuck back
the way you came.
Do you know what they do here?
Buddy, I'm counting to three.
One, two, three.
There, I did it for you.
You aware this is a criminal outfit?
Scamming the weakest in our society?
Stealing everything they have?
Do you know that's who you work for?
I'm looking for the call center?
Yeah, you're in the right place.
You just have to sign in here.
Tell any other companies
in the building to evacuate now.
- There's gonna be a fire.
- Okay, thanks.
Hang up the phone.
Nah, I'm good, buddy.
I'm just doing my thing here.
Hang up the phone.
Uh, Ms. Perkins?
So sorry,
I'll have to...
- call you right back.
- Everyone...
I Need your attention please.
Repeat after me.
I will never steal from the weak.
and the vulnerable again.
I sent you
a department download,
and we'll find out
what's going on...
Repeat after me.
I will never steal from the weak
and the vulnerable again.
To help you keep that promise,
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
Might be a good time to go home.
Hey!
Oh, my God!
It's gas!
You fucking psycho!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What the fuck, bro?
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
I'm the beekeeper.
To protect the hive.
Sometimes I use fire
to smoke out hornets.
This is a multi-million
dollar operation, asshole.
Okay, so you can't come up here
white-knighting shit.
Will you stomp his ass out, please?
I got it.
You fucking get him.
Bet you feel
really proud of yourself.
Mister...?
- Uh, uh, G-Garnett.
- Mr. Garnett.
I don't care if your friends here,
live or die.
The next call from your
little phishing scam.
To this call center
will make a spark
across these wires.
Given all of
the gasoline fumes in here.
I promise you...
anything alive in here won't be.
Uh guys, we might wanna dip out.
Hey, what's going on?
Uh, let me get
flat white, oat milk, of course,
and uh, extra shot of espresso.
- Of course, sir.
- Thank you.
Good morning.
Did we get the
otoro and the onion in?
- Yes, sure.
- We did?
Finally. Great.
Arigato gozaimasu.
- Hey, um, Mikaela.
- Yes
It came back.
The whole thing?
Yeah, and it's like,
I can barely fucking move.
It's all tweaked.
- Oh, those are nice.
- Mmm-hmm.
Those are the new bowls?
Yeah.
That's perfect.
Thank you.
What?
I'm in a meeting.
You said hit me on voice
if there's an emergency.
Okay. Right. Well, uh...
it seems we had
a disgruntled customer.
Uh, I just can't comprehend
why you're bothering me.
Just get in touch
with the attorney
and start shoving back.
Well, yeah, I don't think
that legal is...
gonna help much.
Okay, tell me what the fuck
is going on right now.
This dude just strolls in,
saying we're stealing from people,
and he just tears through
all my security guys, like fucking
tissue paper and um...
And what?
And he burns the place to the ground.
Yeah. The call center is gone.
I'm standing here staring
at a $30 million building,
it's now like a giant fucking
ashtray.
Four people didn't get out.
You're telling me that this asshole
burned the entire building down
and dropped four fucking bodies?
Yeah, that's not exactly
a disgruntled customer, is it?
Who did this?
Give me a name right now!
Sir, I don't have it.
All the cameras
and the, the drives
burned up in the fire.
He had a hat.
Oh, he had a hat.
Okay, I'm gonna hit you back, alright?
I got to go big-dog this shit
for a minute.
Hey, I need to talk to you.
About what?
What, what, no, nothing.
I mean, if I had a friend
who, like, had a call center and someone
burned it down,
maybe killed some people
you could get him, right?
Get him?
Yeah, like, disappear the problem.
Come on.
That's way above my pay grade.
You, you literally ran the CIA
and you're telling me
you can't just
find some guy in Massachusetts?
Listen, this sounds
like a job for the police.
I just need a name.
Well, you won't get it from me.
And you keep me
a million miles away
from your metaverse meth lab
or whatever it is.
Yup.
So, check it out.
Daddy can't
hold your hand on this one.
This is clearly
some kind of crime with
passion, spur of the moment.
Someone snapped, like,
whatever, but
what we're gonna do is
I'm going to send you some credentials,
You're gonna log into our cloud
and you're gonna look at
anyone connected to the last
few deals you closed, alright?
Just, I don't know,
start there.
And, like,
what if I find this guy?
Then what?
You get a wrecking crew together
and you "go Goodfellas" on him.
I mean, come on,
you're a connected guy, right?
Do you understand?
Yeah, No, I understand.
I, uh, I'll get it done.
It's called the day off.
V, you good?
Yeah, I'm great. Why?
I mean, you did lose your mother
yesterday.
Yeah.
- What do you want Wiley?
- Are you leaving? Please don't go.
I'm going to yoga.
Remember United Data Group?
Go on.
Are you sober enough to drive?
Yeah.
Give us a few seconds, thank you.
Where's mine?
It's an old cup from my car
with instant gas station's hot water.
Ew.
- You want a sip?
- No.
So the fire fried
all the CCTV footage,
Receptionist said she saw
some jacked dude,
in his 40's, manhandled security
and walked in with couple gas cans.
These clowns saw everything,
but no one's talking.
They're all frequent players
with perjury,
fraud, and cyber beefs.
Fucking scumbags.
I want IDs on all of them.
You know, this is just the tip
of like, 20 spears, right?
Can I just have this moment?
Eloise Parker.
Yeah, I took her for over
2 millions yesterday.
She's, uh, she's black.
Widow, just has a daughter in Boston.
I don't think this is it,
but, you know...
You said your boy
has an old-ass pickup truck.
That's him.
What the hell are those?
What?
Fucking beehives.
Yeah, Dickhead was talking about them.
I guess he's, like, Bee lover.
You know what?
He breaks my shit.
You break his shit.
Where you at, Bee Boy?
You fucking hiding, bitch?
Well, come out and fucking face us!
Bye, bitch, now!
Let's go.
No.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
Can someone like,
fucking help me?
Fuck.
No! I'm okay.
W-we can talk about this,
L-Lets work this out.
me and you. We can fix...
No, no!
Oh, no!
Oh, w-wait!
What the heck are you doing?
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
So help me understand
because I'm a little confused.
What's the nature of your business?
I don't know nothing
about no business.
So then why are people just wiring you
their entire life savings?
Must be your winning personality.
We've got some lawyers
and they want to talk to them.
You know, this is a really
nice shirt, by the way.
Did you steal it out of a casket,
you dog fucker?
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Verona, if you're done
shitting all over
this gentleman's civil rights,
can I speak to you for a moment?
That's a nice shirt.
- V.
- Yeah, I know. I know.
I'm an asshole.
Oh, so you like fires?
Yeah, today I do.
Good, 'cause, uh,
today's your lucky day.
'Cause apparently, your mother's
house is on fire too,
and some other shit.
- Let's go.
- Wait. What?
Yeah, shit's on fire, let's go.
You good?
V, you okay?
Yeah.
- That's a new one.
- Jesus Christ.
Where's Maggie?
Hey, Maggie,
ID?
United Data Group.
Well, he's handsome.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, Wiley, I'm good.
I'm good.
You think there's even
a remotest chance
that the dude who burned down
the United Data Group
is the same guy renting
this spot from your mother?
The beekeeper.
I lost my virginity in that barn.
Fucking shit.
The universe is gonna have to wait.
I gotta take this.
Yo. What's up, playa?
This is the part where you tell me
what a good job you did
and I put you on a G6
to Hawaii to chill for a week.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Danforth.
You fucked this up, are you?
Are you fucking crying right now?
I'm not crying.
I'm bleeding.
Bleeding?
Why are you bleeding?
What do you mean bleeding?
My fingers.
On my right hand.
He cut them off.
Okay, fuck off.
Go.
He, who the fuck is he?
Tell me who he is right now.
I-I don't know.
A fucking beekeeper.
Makes honey,
and fucks with bee hives.
He fucks with beehives?
What's he saying about bees?
I don't know.
He said he was, like, protecting
the hive or something.
Oh, fuck, man!
What the fuck is this?
Guys.
No, no, no, no!
whoa, whoa, whoa...
What do you want from me?
You want crypto? NFTs?
I got fucking NFTs.
What are you fucking... What?
What?
No! Dude,
What the fuck is this, man?
Don't move.
I fucking can't move!
You're fucking crazy, man.
What the fuck, bro?
No! No! No!
Fucking stop the fucking car!
No! No!
Who do I have the pleasure
of speaking with?
Fuck you.
That's who.
You burned my million-dollar
fucking call center.
Now I'm gonna burn you down.
You haven't told me your name.
I told you my name.
That's fuck you,
Mr. Fuck You,
and you better fucking remember it.
Because you don't burn me down,
I burn you down.
You understand me?
You're fucking with forces
that you cannot comprehend.
You sound young.
I bet you don't
have estate planning.
I'm fucking 28 years old.
Why would I need that?
I'm about to show you.
Breaking news in Springfield,
where three bodies
have been discovered
following an arson fire at a small farm.
There was an office building explosion.
And you say one guy did this?
Yup.
Killed seven armed men
without firing a shot?
Yup. And he said
he was gonna kill me.
And this is your data mining
consumer service business, right?
Yes, something like that.
Pulling in 9 million a month,
one office, I've got like 20.
Yeah.
The only thing you know about him
is he says he's a beekeeper.
Yeah, it's like his whole brand
or whatever.
Jesus.
What?
For someone who has elevated
fucking up into an art form.
This might well be your Mona Lisa.
How did I fuck up?
I don't know.
You've done something.
You've disturbed a beekeeper.
Oh. Oh, okay.
So fucking what?
What I care if the guy keeps bees?
If a beekeeper says you're gonna die,
you're gonna die.
There's nothing I can do
or anybody else to stop it.
So, like, what do you
even do here, then?
What good are you?
Yeah.
I did 35 years of loyal government service,
culminating as director of the world's
premier intelligence agency.
I could have done anything.
But I chose this job as
a favor to your mother,
I keep Danforth Enterprises safe.
Keep her reputation safe,
her name safe.
It's my fucking name too, alright?
Oh, sit down.
I put up with you.
I put up with your tantrums.
Kept you out of the tabloids.
Kept you out of jail.
The endless stream of sex workers.
You're a drowning man.
Do you know that?
Hmm, You're scared?
Dead right. I'm scared.
Terrified.
So should you be.
Wallace, just tell me
what the fuck this guy is.
He's probably the last pair of eyes
that you're gonna sneer at.
Okay, listen.
Remember our favorite burning building?
United Data Group.
The guys who work there are hackers,
con men, fraudsters, et cetera, et cetera.
Guy who ran it.
Garnet.
He's in the book.
He's a known mob associate.
He's missing, but I've got
PD chasing him down.
Okay, so I had some
analysts run some shit,
and I think I'm starting to get
the shape of the animal.
Dude, I think United Data Group
is one of several call centers,
so there's gotta be like a central office
that's controlling all of them,
and that's what we've gotta find.
Wiley, this could be like
a billion-dollar-a-year operation.
Hello. Hey! Did you hear
a single word I just said?
Yeah.
And?
I'm just thinking you come in here
hungover on your day off,
and gain more yardage on this thing
than the whole squad has in two years.
Yeah, well, they fucked with my family.
What'd you get on, Clay?
Your beekeeper?
Yeah.
He's a ghost.
What?
Yeah, all I have is a birth certificate
and a social.
The guy's never even had a bank account,
credit card, flown on a plane.
I ran his prints to every database
I could think of.
No hits.
That's bullshit. This dude is
former military all day.
No hits, I'm telling you.
Either he's never been printed
or Adam Clay doesn't exist,
which is terrifying to me because
he's probably in a classified program.
Special Agent Wiley.
Okay. Let's go.
What?
They found the guy, Garnet.
- What?
- They found him. Let's go.
Oh, shit.
Jessica.
I think you know why I'm calling.
You know I'd do anything for you.
Anything.
For you.
Derek's scared shitless.
I've never seen him this scared.
Well, he's made his bed.
I'll give you a board seat
on the holding company.
That's another million a year.
Plus you promised
you'd take care of him.
Look, I don't need that.
I have enough.
So you got this?
Yeah, you have my word.
Wallace, I still think of you.
Sometimes.
Why are you calling me
on a "never-call-this-line" line?
This is priority one, Janet.
Well, if it was priority one,
I would know about it.
Look, I'm heading downtown to
a POTUS brief.
Just hear me out. Now, you know
who I work for, don't you?
Oh, yeah.
God help you, Wallace.
Exactly.
Well, Director Harward.
My young friend seems to have caught
the unwanted attentions of...
I don't know how else
to say this, of a beekeeper.
Yeah.
A beekeeper, beekeeper?
As in.
Well, that's not good.
No, it's not.
What's the body count?
Seven today.
You busy making funeral
arrangements?
I need help, Janet,
not jokes.
Is that Garnett?
He was strapped to an old pick up.
Check this out.
Does this mean you've taken pity
on the old man?
So your problem...
He's retired from the program.
No longer active.
Well, that changes everything.
The current active beekeeper
is aware of the issue
and is going to be
taking things from here.
You can rest easy, old friend.
Oh, no, Janet, the current active
beekeeper is a fucking lunatic
who should have been removed
months ago.
God help us now.
Your services are required.
Forward it.
Eliminate Adam Clay.
what fun, hahaha.
Get out of here!
Shit!
- Excuse me.
- No problem.
You've been a busy bee.
You're supposed to be retired.
I'm assuming you're my replacement.
Shit!
Ah!
Fuck you!
This subtitle provide [by:ME]
I need your keys.
There's an issue.
Problem has not been solved.
Well, that is a surprise.
The beekeepers have studied the situation
and have decided to remain neutral.
How can they do that?
He was their man, for fuck's sake!
I'm sorry, Wallace.
You're on your own.
I thought you could
fucking handle this.
I can handle this!
Thank you.
What you got for us, Detective?
That's a vehicle registered
to Anisette Landress.
The ATF are en route in bound
to take care of it.
We're way cooler than the ATF.
I'll show you why I called them.
That's a minigun.
They use those on military
vehicles.
Do you know that puppy
shoots 6,000 rounds a minute?
I know.
Do you know that's
100 rounds a second?
Yep, I know.
Did you know that you know a lot?
Yes, I do.
It's because I minored in math.
I'm a pretty smart guy actually.
Okay, then do you know
who Anisette Landress is?
- Yes, I do.
- Go ahead and tell me.
Someone who doesn't exist in
any commercial or government database.
Someone who's a ghost,
like our good friend Adam Clay.
"Beekeeping for beekeepers."
Here's another reason that
Anisette Landress is like
our good friend Adam Clay.
Do you know what's that way?
Springfield.
Where the call center was torched.
And that way,
where Adam Clay's headed?
Boston.
Let's go.
How are you, my friend?
- Good to see you, sir.
- Good to see you.
Come on, leave them alone.
Leave them alone.
Don't play with those things.
They go off.
Sit down,
Make yourself comfortable.
When I was sworn in as director,
I was read into programs
I never imagined existed.
Well,
there are programs
even I wasn't privy to.
Like the beekeepers.
The honeybee...
has always had a special
relationship with humanity.
A sacred relationship.
Why?
No bees, no agriculture,
no agriculture, no civilization.
Our nation
is not unlike a beehive
with its complex systems of
workers, caretakers,
even royalty.
If any of the
beehive's complex mechanisms
are compromised,
the hive collapses.
Someone a long time ago decided that
a mechanism was needed
to keep our nation safe.
A mechanism outside the chain of command.
Outside the system.
It's one mission
to keep the system safe.
Beekeepers,
are given all resources,
empowered to act
on their own judgment.
For decades they have quietly
worked to keep the hive safe.
That is, until now.
It appears that
a retired beekeeper
has gone off program and is acting
in what he mistakenly believes
is the hive's best interest.
Can't somebody just pick up the phone
and tell this yahoo to stand the fuck down?
That's the one thing beekeepers don't do.
Stand down.
Not unlike bees themselves.
Beekeepers keep working
until they die.
So he's basically one of us.
No.
He's not like you.
You're Tier 1 operators.
Form a SEAL Team 6,
Delta group.
You are in other words,
pussies.
If you were in the same room,
he would kill you.
With enough of you, then maybe
you just might
in fact be able to kill him
before he accomplishes his goal.
What would that be?
To kill his way
to the top of the hive.
Mr. Pettis, you should get
your people moving.
Dude, bees are interesting
little shits. Did you know that?
I know, they pollinate
a bunch of shit
and we'd be fucked without them.
Listen.
Some bees are queen slayers,
which will rise up and kill their queen
if she fails to produce
the right kind of male offspring.
Fascinating.
No.
Nope.
- No.
- It's your turn!
- You can't.
Special Agent Parker.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
What?
The deputy director is flying
up from DC to see us.
This is your fault.
This subtitle provide by[ME]
Here's another interesting factoid.
Thank fuck.
You know, I was getting sick
of enjoying my peaceful thoughts.
Sir.
So this is Special Agent Parker,
Special Agent Wiley.
they'll be briefing you.
This is Deputy Director Prigg
and Amanda Munoz, Special Counsel.
Mr. Deputy Director.
My colleague and I believe,
that 3 major crime scenes in our area
are connected to a single subject,
Adam Clay.
He killed six people today
based on the extensive use
of tradecraft and
the nature of his alias.
We believe that Mr. Clay
is connected to
a classified program named
Beekeeper,
A program that none of
our partner agencies
seem willing to acknowledge.
Let's stick to what we know,
Special Agent Parker.
Yes, sir. In any event,
this individual is highly capable
and extremely motivated.
And we believe that
he's on his way to Boston,
if not already here.
And we believe that
this is his next target.
Nine Star United,
which appears to be the entity
operating the regional call centers
like the one that Mr. Clay burned down.
Why is Adam Clay on this rampage?
He's protecting the hive, sir.
It's what Beekeepers do.
I have enough to brief the director.
- What's your ask?
- My ask?
Well, a SWAT team for starters,
surveillance support,
additional agents, analysts.
That shouldn't be a problem.
Thank you.
- Did that just happen?
- Yeah.
Alright, everybody. Listen up.
It's roll call times.
I'm getting ready for
my dick to get hard
with some wonderful
beautiful numbers.
Let's start with Phoenix.
Where are we at?
Phoenix is up 101K.
200K I'm gonna suck your dick.
I love you.
New Orleans, show me,
Tell me. Where we at?
It's down 92K, boss.
Down? You're a fucking loser.
You give me a fucking headache.
You give me fucking cancer.
New York, make me happy.
I beg you.
New York City's up 64x K.
I love you, New York.
Gather round.
I want all weapons front on entry.
-Everybody give me an oos!
-Oos!
Let's go!
Power down, my federal friend.
Power down.
The Private security here
on the orders of the Governor.
State Department certified
to carry weapons in all 50 states.
Feel free to call
the highlighted numbers to verify.
You're not welcome here.
Get the fuck out.
Alright, boys. Let's go.
Set up a perimeter outside.
Your goals, they mean bonuses.
Money, money, money.
We fucking love it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What the fuck?
who the fuck are you?
You can't be in here.
We're the guys keeping you alive.
Shut it down now.
Everybody listen up.
Anyone who's not carrying a weapon,
Get the fuck out!
Shouldn't you be killing
bin Laden or something?
Listen to me, my friend.
This place prints money.
No one's shutting it down.
Anybody so much as puts
a phone down, they're fired!
I'm sorry to break it to you,
but bin Laden's been dead
for a while.
So I'm going to say this one last time.
- Shut it down.
- The fuck I am.
- Call your fucking boss.
- You want me to call my boss?
I'll do that.
And you'll be so fucked.
it's gonna be beautiful.
Don't be shy.
Come on.
What about the parking garage.
Closed and locked.
Steel gate.
I want a body on comms,
watching it.
-Delivery dock?
-Same deal.
-Station an agent there too.
-Yes, sir.
Sure there's no back
entrances into this place?
Hey, there's no other entrances.
Federal law enforcement
operation in progress.
Move along at minimum retreat
to a safe distance. Thank you.
Someone scout
the service tunnel.
The other option,
instead of going in,
is to smoke them out.
Excuse me?
I figured I'd give
the firefighters a break.
I've put them through
enough already.
What'd you say your name was?
Currently I'd go by Adam Clay.
Trust me.
If there was a back entrance,
I would've used it.
I don't wanna injure anyone
who's innocent or non-involved.
But it is what it is.
Somebody detain this guy!
Stop!
Ah!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Oh, wow. If it isn't the fucking
Golden Goose himself.
Sir, I got Captain Caveman here
telling me to send everyone off.
If we do that, we're walking
away from a lot of money.
Mm, put him on.
It's for you.
Why are you fucking with my business?
Because Mr. Westwyld hired me
to kick some fucking beekeeper ass.
Mr. Westwyld works for me,
which means that you work for me.
Now listen, that place is
the crown jewel of my kingdom.
I'm not going to let some crash test dummy
with a fucking gun fuck it up.
Is that clear, Mr. Pettis?
Didn't this character already burn
one of your centers to the ground?
Well, you know, they didn't
have you, and that's why.
So maybe you just do your fucking job
and don't tell me how to do mine, please.
- We got it?
- Copy that.
Fall out.
Set up a perimeter outside.
Let's go.
Move.
Round applause.
Let's say goodbye to our good friends.
Bye bye, Admiral.
Go join fucking Space Force.
You're a beautiful...
Now get the fuck out!
Keep walking.
Bye bye, dickhead.
What a bunch of jackoffs.
Yeah.
We love you.
One-time amnesty.
Whoever doesn't want to die this evening,
can in an orderly fashion.
Leave now.
Uh, uh, uh. No fucking way.
It's not happening.
Anybody moves, you're fired.
No bonus...
- Come on, boys! Move, move!
-  no vesting, no 2 weeks.
Nada.
Zero!
Are you fucking nuts?
Each one of these pricks.
it's worth 30 to 40
million a year in profit.
so no one is shooting no gun.
Not a good day to drag
innocent people into this.
These assholes?
They're not innocent.
For either one of us
to close that distance,
Some of them will get hurt.
Let's start with this prick right here.
On me!
Take right!
Pettis, we got a man down.
Oh!
Fire... Fire.
Fire.
You know who you're working for?
None of my fucking business.
I'm just the guy they call
when there's a problem.
And you are our problem.
Goddamn right,
I'm a problem.
Fire.
Damn, what the hell happened?
- Any dead?
- Not dead, but we got our asses kicked.
Our guy?
What do we know?
He's in the building.
I'm waiting for more men to roll in.
I don't know what this guy is,
but nobody can do what he's done.
He's just a beekeeper.
Bad idea.
I'm not waiting.
- V, wait!
- Move!
Come on, Wiley, keep up.
Fuck.
We got him!
-You done?
-Reload.
Everybody out!
You're done.
We should take the stairs.
Smart.
Subject is in the hallway.
Command, report back.
Anybody on comm?
Please, please don't kill me.
I'm just a middle manager.
I never hurt nobody.
I'd respect you more
if you look people
in their eyes when
you stole from them.
You're making a lot of money here.
Tell me where it's all going.
I don't know, man.
Ow!
I know you're the middle man.
Who's above you?
No. They'll kill me.
I'll torture you,
then kill you.
Come on, guys, you got it.
Wiley, get your ass up here.
Yeah, well,
I'm not an Olympian.
Make it stop.
You can make it stop.
You've stolen hundreds of millions
from people who've done nothing
but work hard all their lives.
She was an educator, a mom.
Dedicated her whole life
to helping people.
Yesterday she shot herself.
because you took two million
from a charity she ran.
She was the only person
who ever took care of me.
Who?
Where?
Mr. Anzalone.
Tell me who and where.
I can't.
Look, these people,
they're untouchable. I can't...
No, please, please, stop.
I will, I will.
Let me show you.
I told you they are untouchable.
Nobody's untouchable.
Sometimes when the hive's
out of balance,
you have to replace the queen.
Clay!
That man is directly responsible
for your mother's death.
I believe you.
But we have laws for these things.
You have laws for these things
until they fail.
Then you have me.
Arrest him!
On your feet before
I blow your fucking head off!
I just been thrown through
a plate-glass window!
Shut your fucking mouth!
Whoa.
I've four kids.
I know.
Three boys and a girl.
Wiley?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- He went that way.
- Have you been hit?
- My wife thinks I'm doing computer nerd shit.
Okay, well, I won't
tell her if you don't.
Have you been hit?
- No, I'm good, Mom.
- Yeah?
Did you get him?
Did you?
No, he's tricky, almost though...
You okay?
I guess that's just evidence.
Can I borrow your gun?
Yeah, let's go.
- On me. On me. On me. On me.
- Clear!
I want interviews with all of them.
We're gonna talk.
Get him out of here.
Wiley.
Holy shit.
Do you mind if I ask you
a really boring question?
Do you actually prefer
the money or the power?
Mm, that's deep...
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Excuse me.
Oh, God. Uh...
Would you excuse me for a moment?
Come upstairs.
You said these guys were
the fucking best.
Why are they all dead?
You kicked the beehive, and now
we have to reap the whirlwind.
- Unless...
- Unless?
Unless, unless,
unless fucking what?
Maybe now is the time
to call your mother.
I'm paying you
so much fucking money
and your advice is to call my mother?
He can't make his move on us,
if we're in her proximity, can he?
Her people.
You're a fuck.
- You're scared.
- I certainly am scared.
and you want to use my mother
as a human shield.
Just call her.
Come on.
- It's not a game.
- Oh, it's all a game.
Come on.
Yes, Derek.
What do you want?
Hey, Mom.
No, nothing.
I was, just you know,
thinking about you, I miss you.
I was hoping to maybe
see you this weekend.
I'm at the beach house.
You're welcome to join
if you behave.
I would love to.
And hey, I'm actually was gonna,
you know,
get together some of
my tech homies and stuff,
if that's, uh, if that's cool with you.
Fine,
No drugs.
Give Kelly the details.
Love you.
Have to go.
Derek's joining me this weekend.
Help me keep him sober.
Yes, ma'am.
I love babysitting.
Madame President.
Funmi Lawal.
Hello.
Good to meet you.
Sola Oyemade
Sola, thank you so much for coming.
Susan Aneno.
Thank you so much
for coming all this way.
Oli Ray-Imanuel.
Oli, how good to meet you.
Great to meet you, ma'am.
You don't have to do this, you know.
Why not let Clay do his thing?
Your mom is dead
because of these people.
Wherever it's headed,
I swore an oath.
I can't stand by
and watch it happen.
Even if he's right?
Even if he's right.
Apologies.
Damn plane was delayed.
What have you got?
We think we have a sense of
Mr. Clay's true intentions.
He seems to be following the money.
What money is that?
Usually it's from people
with no heirs, no family.
Nine Star United uses
data mining software
to identify these people
and then target their assets.
There's another company involved.
Sir, a company who is a vendor
to the intelligence community
and to the Justice Department.
In fact, we use this company's
software in this very office
to identify... financial fraud.
Are you going to tell me
the name of this company?
Danforth Enterprises, with an annual
revenue of $10 billion,
founded and operated
by Jessica Danforth,
who recently stepped down
because she was sworn in
as president of
the United States.
She self-financed her campaign.
Yeah, none of that money was clean.
Who else knows this?
- Us three.
- I have a really bad memory, sir.
Let's, uh, keep the circle small
until I can brief the director
and the attorney general.
Not a word of this to anyone,
understood?
Yes, sir.
and Mr. Clay,
I see his kill count is steadily rising.
In a beehive there is something
called a "queen slayer."
It's a bee that will rise
up and kill the queen
if she produces defective offspring.
I thought we were sticking
to the known, knowns.
Right, yes, not that
beekeepers exist,
But Mr. Clay does keep honeybees.
He admires their willingness
to sacrifice themselves
for the greater good.
Our concern is that
Clay believes that
Derek Danforth is the defective
offspring of a queen.
Thereby, Clay will strike
at the heart of the problem
and become a queen slayer.
Adam Clay's next victim is
Derek Danforth's mother?
President Danforth, sir.
You have a blank check.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
This is a private event.
I'm gonna need you to turn around,
go away.
Federal Bureau of something
or another.
We're good.
We have invites right here.
Alright, you'll need
to excuse my partner.
He's recently concussed
and hasn't slept in two days.
We're on the access list.
We're good boss.
Get the secret service
out of the house.
I don't want them here.
They're C-Team.
B-Team at best.
Uh, mom's detail
is not gonna like that.
Well, if mom's detail gets in
the way of what's coming for us,
they're dead men.
And so are we.
Tell them they can
stay in the kitchen.
Yes, sir.
He has a little talent, doesn't he?
It's absolutely fucking terrifying.
Good men, but clearly not good enough.
-Hm.
-Fuck, bruh!
How'd you piss this oak off, huh?
I...
-You're looking at me?
-Mm-hmm.
How is any of this my fault?
Wasn't your super secret CIA
data mining software supposed to,
I don't know, maybe filter out
un-fucking-stoppable killing machine?
Don't you fuck with me, young man.
Any other life you'd be in jail.
Hey, this is a fucking beekeeper!
Yeah, you know, I killed one once.
- Oh, you see?
- Yeah, only 'cause I was lucky.
- And un-fucking-lucky.
- Oh, jeez.
Yeah, don't piss your pants, Bru.
My team will be out shortly.
If anyone can knock
this guy's dick in the dirt, it's them.
Ain't that right,
Money man?
Yeah.
I'm supposed to be at a kid's
birthday party with my wife.
You are at a kid's birthday party.
And I'm your work wife.
Madam Presiden, you look spectacular.
When the fuck are you going to tell me
what's going on, Wallace?
Good. Go through.
Tell that guy to hurry up.
I want every manhole
on this street welded shut.
- We got this.
- Alright.
I'm going to watch your back.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on. Move it up.
Put your head
on a swivel, gentlemen.
Alright.
Hold on.
I'm in there now.
Alright, you're good.
Hey, when did you get in?
What a surprise.
You didn't hear the giant marine
helicopter land
on the front lawn.
I guess not.
Is this nicotine
or a carnival ride?
I wouldn't unless you want to
go talk with the machine elves.
Hey, you look fucking great,
by the way.
I mean, power, it just
looks so good on you.
Doing below on your father's desk.
God, how I wish
he was still alive,
so I can show him.
Stop picking your face.
Why does Wallace Westwyld
look nervous as a burning cat?
What have you done to the man?
I wouldn't know, mother.
Well, he's there to protect
you if you'll let him.
You're a good-looking kid.
You really are, you know that?
What does that mean?
It means that God doesn't
give with both hands.
Okay, I love you too, Mom.
Gotta go run the free world.
Don't burn it down.
Why are you up?
Fucking fantastic!
Wiley, look.
Oh, shit.
Danforth looks like
she wants to throw up.
Look at her body language.
Bad vibes.
She got caught riding dirty.
What have we done?
Are you, uh, fucking
with crypto at all, right now?
It's gonna pop.
They're minting next week,
so just hit me up on Insta.
- Okay.
- I'll connect your wallet.
- May I borrow my son?
- Of course.
Speak to you a moment
in private?
Who's this?
Jackson Prigg he's number two,
at The FBI.
- Have a seat.
- I'm cool. I'll stand.
What is this, like,
an ambush or something?
This feels weird.
I don't like it.
No, you'll sit.
I'll sit.
Kelly, would you give us a moment?
It's okay, ma'am.
I can take notes.
I need you to step outside.
The deputy director
has flagged his concerns
about some uncomfortable
things happening
inside the family company.
Like what?
Uncomfortable things about
the source of my campaign funds.
Sounds serious.
What's up?
Deputy director.
Mr. Danforth, are you familiar with
United Data Group?
Yeah.
I invested in that.
I invest everywhere.
I mean, it's everywhere.
It's very diverse.
How about a Nine-Star United?
Yeah, that's more of like a consulting
type of role.
It's the blockchain issues
and you probably...
I don't want to bore you
with all that.
What do you know
about a classified algorithmic
data mining software package
developed by the intelligence community?
He's here.
All stations, target's in the building.
East Wing.
East Wing, give me everything you got.
He's in the house.
Assault teams.
Saddle up!
Break, break. Package is in the house.
Level three, side four.
Blue over blue.
You see him.
You fucking get him.
Put your fucking hands up.
Now turn, the fuck around.
He's outside.
Target's outside.
Let's get this fucking guy.
Easy. You see him?
Negative.
Clay!
That's right.
Now, on your knees.
On your knees.
Place your fingers behind your head.
Down.
On your knees.
Now. Do it. Now.
Beekeeper, huh?
God's right hand?
You are unchecked.
You aren't shit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, take your step back.
I'm putting this asshole's
brains on the lawn.
What are you doing?
He's not even armed.
Armed?
As long as death motherfucker's breathing,
- He's armed.
- You're not fucking executing him.
Nice crowd
you're rolling with.
Watch me.
V, what the fuck is going on?
To "bee" or not to "bee"?
Isn't that the bloody question?
I think I'll take...
to "bee."
- Wiley?
- Yeah, you good?
- Yeah
- Go!
Get off me.
Huh?
He's fucking mine!
Talk to me, people.
I need news.
He's here.
Go! Go! All stations!
I'll take it.
Why are you waiting?
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Come on, come on.
Hold your hands, guys.
Come on.
Hold it so hard.
Hang tight.
On feet. On me.On me.On me.On me.On me.On me.On me.On me.
Get on the ground.
You understand.
You did this, right?
You broke the rules.
You corrupted an imperfect
but functioning system.
I was just trying to get you
in the office, mom.
How else do you think
you got elected?
I was going to win with
or without your help.
We were already rich.
Your father built an empire.
Yeah, and you were
going to fucking break it up
into pieces and sell it off.
In the name of public service,
because I care,
I want to leave a better world.
Okay, right.
Yeah, because you hate the fact that
being the president is just
like an endless cocktail party.
You realize that you were behind
in 15 of 20 counties you needed to win.
15 of 20 counties.
I taught CIA software
to hunt... money
and not terrorists.
You didn't hear that.
You got elected because of me,
and you know that.
And you know that. Yeah, I know it.And you know that. Yeah, I know it.
Everyone knows it.
Now I know where the money came from.
And all the people you hurt.
Okay, whatever.
It's computer data, Mom.
Somebody in this family has to have
their fucking feet on the ground
to actually get shit done.
You understand that?
Mom.
The wolves are
at the fucking door right now.
What are you gonna do to fix this?
Tell the truth.
The fucking...
What does that even mean?
Tell the fucking truth?
You have an entire building
full of PR people
that are going to choose
the right way forward.
That guy who's coming to kill us,
that beekeeper,
I'm telling him the truth
about what you did, Derek.
Then I'm telling the entire nation
and if it costs me everything,
well, so be it.
you fucking git!
You're just a man.
I know.
Thank you.
Jesus. Looks like a tornado
came through here.
What's your plan here, huh?
You're going to tell this guy
the fucking truth and hope that
he spares you
and kills me instead?
No, Derek, I'll tell him the truth
because it's the truth.
It's gone far enough,
you proved your point.
Beekeepers live
for the good of society.
I'm retired.
It's just personal.
For the more reason to stop.
Go back and live a quiet life.
Making honey for your neighbors.
That's all I wanted.
My neighbor's dead.
I know, I'm sorry.
But do you live in the real world
or just protect it?
What does it matter to you
how presidents come to be elected?
- Hm?
- It doesn't.
What does matter to you?
Right and wrong.
It's not fashionable.
I believe there's
good in the universe.
Yeah, well, we agree.
I mean, that's...
that's my view.
Until the Danforth family
bought you.
- Ah.
- You can stop pretending.
We wouldn't need beekeepers
if it wasn't for men like you.
Don't do that.
- Sir, you might want to step back.
- No
I don't want you to get hurt.
I'm sorry, I can't do that.
Now have a seat.
Nah, fuck the truth, man.
The truth...
- Wait. You put that down.
- No, Derek.
Jesus!
That's fucking real right there.
Wait!
- Clay, no!
- Drop your weapon.
Drop it! Drop it!
You decide who you work for.
For the law.
Or for justice.
Fuck this.
Bye, Mom.
Go! Go!
I want my...
Clay!
No!
Goodbye, Adam Clay.
Keep eyes on! Let's go!
No!
Thanks for watching!