Books. Okay. Uh, yeah.
Absolutely.
And...
I'm not gonna read it.
I'll get it.
Okay, Mom.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Lea dropped it off this morning.
She is so happy it's yours.
I know exactly
where I'm gonna put it.
- Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
- Thank you!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
So Daniel got her this, like, all-access
backstage pass and a VIP meet and greet
with that boy band she used to like,
August Moon.
Oh, yeah, they're cute.
- Mm-hmm.
- That sounds fun, Izz.
You get to meet August Moon?
I'm not really into them anymore.
Now it's more about, like, aggressively
talented female singer-songwriters.
- Which I think is great.
- Right, of course, of course.
Oh, they're here.
Hi.
- Hey. -What's up?
- Hi.
- Oh, my God, you guys took forever.
- Hey.
VIP meet and greet,
all-access backstage pass,
her friends are coming,
- and, oh, yeah, Eva's going, too.
- Ugh.
- Hi.
- Hi. You look so cute.
- Hi. -Thank you.
- So you're going camping alone?
- Yes.
- And why would you do that?
- Seriously? Why wouldn't I do that?
Bears? Serial killers?
Dirt?
I'm looking forward to it.
Have a little me time,
process the last 20 years.
And what if I could just be the sort of
person that goes camping by herself?
What if all I need is Izz
and my artists and my gallery
and my friends?
- Okay. Well, is that what you want?
- Maybe that's all I want.
But is it?
I'm going camping to find out, right?
Speaking of things you want,
your 40th birthday party.
I don't need a party.
Thank you. I love you. Don't need it.
Stop it. You're having a party.
It's nonnegotiable.
Mom, if you get lonely,
promise you'll text me, okay?
I'm gonna be fine, baby.
I just want you to be happy
and have the best time.
- Are you happy?
- Yes.
No, but, like...
but, like, really, though.
What is going on?
Are you guys in an alliance or something?
Just focus on being selfish teenagers,
all right?
Oh, my God, August Moon!
- Ugh, so... - Seventh grade!
- So seventh grade!
- Haters gonna hate, Izz.
- Are they?
Just let that shit fly by.
And... we made it.
- Let's go guys.
- Okay, trunk should be open.
Let me know if you need help.
Okay. We will.
There she is.
- Hey, Solène.
- Hi, Eva.
How are you?
- Oh, I'm well, thank you.
- You look really...
- I like your-your dress.
- Thank you.
Hello.
Hey, so, um, I'm gonna have
my phone on airplane mode,
but I'm gonna check it, like,
every three hours.
- You can make it four. Live a little.
- Okay.
Have so much fun and, you know,
good stupid, not stupid stupid.
- Yes, I know. Okay, I love you.
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
- Thanks, Solène.
- Mwah. Mwah. -I love you.
- Love you so much. Mwah.
- Bye, Solène. Thank you. Love you, too.
Bye. Have so much fun.
- Hey.
- Hey, Dad. -Hey.
- Hi! -
- Hey, baby.
- How are you? Ready for some fun?
- I'm... Yeah.
- Georgia, Zeke, what's up?
- Oh, hey, Eva.
Hey.
- Hey.
Thank you for dropping them off.
I mean, I had to, right?
So are these guys, like,
so stoked for this trip or what?
"Stoked"? Very.
- Cool.
- Mm.
Cool, cool, cool.
So I got to... get to...
Yeah, real quick, I just wanted to, uh,
you know, invite you over sometime.
Come let us make you dinner.
Eva's a great cook.
That's...
- Or pickleball, you know?
- Um...
Come play pickleball.
You've heard of pickleball, right?
- Yes.
- It's so much fun.
- You know...
- You don't even have to be athletic.
You can pick it up in, like...
Eva's really good. She can teach you.
Yeah, I don't... I'm pretty bu...
I just, I got to go.
- Okay. Good. Great.
- I got to go.
Uh, enjoy your camping trip.
- Enjoy Coachella.
- Will do.
No, I can't drive them
to your house.
Yeah, I have other things going on.
I got a life. I got plans.
I'm doing stuff this weekend
you can't even imagine.
I'm doing stuff
you could never do, Daniel.
You like my outfit? You do?
Oh, my God, that means the world to me.
That is... that makes me feel
so much better
about the fact that
you fucking destroyed my life.
Sol!
- Sol, wait up.
- Oh.
Did you not get my texts?
- I'm in airplane mode. What's going on?
- Hi.
- What... Are you okay?
- Yeah, no. It's all good. It's all good.
- What's happening? What's...
- I can't do the trip now.
- Daniel...
- My whole merger thing just blew up.
I... S-Sol, can you please
take them to Coachella?
- Everything's paid for, all the hotels, the meals.
- What?
- It's all set.
- Are you kidding me?
They're booking tickets to Houston.
I... It's happening right now.
- Let Eva take them.
- Eva's coming with me.
Of course she is.
Come on, we... we really got to go.
- We got to go.
- Please. Please, please, please, please.
Okay.
- Yes?
- Yes.
- Thank you, thank you, thank you.
- Okay, I'm going to get my sandals, Izz.
- Sol, I owe you. I do. I know.
- Yeah, you do. You do.
- Okay, have fun, guys.
- Mom. Mom.
- Hey, can you...
- Izzy, I love you.
I'm going to take 30 seconds,
and I'm going to get my sandals.
Okay, okay.
Stay hydrated.
O-Okay. Okay, okay.
Uh, VIP entrance is by Lodestar?
- Lodestar is...?
- Oh, wait, y'all.
- I got the stage lineup.
- St. Vincent is about to play. Let's go!
- Let's go. Come on.
- Guys, guys, guys, guys, w-wait.
- Really fast, really fast.
- Okay, sorry, sorry.
- Look after one another. And please check your texts.
- Yes.
- We're good. We're good.
- Come on, come on. Let's go!
- Okay. Bye.
- Come on. Bye. -Bye, Solène!
- Love you. - Whoo!
- Don't be stupid stupid!
We won't!
Okay.
- Hi.
- Do you mind if I...
- Uh, no, please.
Thank you.
This your first time?
- Sorry?
- Getting Mooned.
What?
Once a Moonhead, always a Moonhead.
I'm here with my daughter and...
So which one is your favorite?
Oh, sorry.
Which one is your "daughter's" favorite?
No, I...
Mine's Adrian.
I mean, just look at him.
He's such a hottie.
Uh, actually, do you know
where the bathroom is?
Uh, yeah. Right out there.
- The VIP ones are on the right.
- On the right?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, great. Thank you.
- Have a good one.
- See ya.
Oh, uh, just a second.
Okay.
- Hi.
Do you mind?
Oh, you... you want to use the bathroom.
Yeah. Um, thanks.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hi again.
Are you a part of that ASMR community
that gets off on listening to people pee?
No, I wasn't...
Because I don't think
you can just go around assuming...
- It's actually my trailer.
- What?
It's not literally mine.
You know, I don't own it.
- This is your trailer?
- Yeah.
I'm in a band. We're performing
on the main stage in an hour.
I'm Hayes Campbell.
August Moon?
Yeah.
I absolutely know who you are.
Um, anyway...
I'll...
Hey, you know, if you wanted to, um...
I don't know, hang out.
- Hang out?
- Yeah.
Do you want a drink?
- Uh...
- I mean, I've got all the, uh, the-the sodas,
the healthy ones, the not-so-healthy ones.
Um... there's kombucha.
Which, in case you never tried it,
it's like kind of a... a salad dressing.
Uh, but we also have beer,
we have wine, um, um, vodka...
Um, I'm actually with
my daughter for the...
August Moon meet and greet, and,
uh, I'm driving, so I don't think it's...
Your daughter,
she's, um, an August Moon fan?
Sh-She was.
- Ouch.
- Very sorry.
I-I do think she will be, um...
a future nostalgic fan,
but at this moment, today, right now,
you are so "seventh grade."
Damn.
Truth hurts, doesn't it?
My, uh, daughter's father bought
the tickets for the meet and greet,
and, um, he was
supposed to be here with her.
He...
Anyway, uh, canceled last minute.
Now I'm here...
So her father, not your husband?
Well, he was my husband,
but now he's just her father.
Mm.
Hayes, I think
they're almost ready for you.
Who are you?
It's okay, Desmond.
- She's, uh, a friend. -
- Knock, knock, Hayes.
- It's showtime.
- Okay.
- Um, okay, so do you need me to dress you?
- Ha.
No. I'm fine, Jodie.
- Okay. Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right.
- Thanks, Jodie.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
That was Jodie.
- Jodie.
- Yeah.
Do you need someone to help dress you?
- On special occasions, yeah, sometimes.
- Mm.
Ah.
- I'm gonna...
- Oh, excuse me.
I'll just...
We've got news.
We got the TAG Heuer campaign.
- Oh.
- And he wants you to wear a watch.
- Great.
- So let's take this off.
- Let's get a look at this. And you need...
- Okay, yeah.
- These off? Okay.
- Yes, let's take those off.
Uh, James?
This is gonna be the best option.
Okay.
Wow.
Christ, get ahold of yourself, Solène.
- Mom. I'm so sorry.
- Oh, hi.
But, hey, but you don't understand.
St. Vincent was killing it.
We couldn't leave.
- No, it truly was transcendent.
- Okay, great. Let's just do...
- Oh, can we go back, really quick?
- We got to do this first, baby.
Okay, I... Wh-Why?
Because your dad paid
a lot of money for this.
I'm-I'm so grateful for that,
but August Moon is just, like, so...
Seventh grade.
N... No.
Sorry, I... Thank you.
I...
Epic. Yeah.
She was gonna say, "August
Moon is so epic." -"Epic"? Okay.
Yeah. Hey there.
I'm Zeke Randall,
Campbell Hall High School class treasurer.
It's truly an honor to meet you.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- I love your shirt. There you go.
- Thank you.
Could you just, like, yeah,
could you just sign that for me?
Yeah, thanks.
- Can I take a picture?
- Yes, please.
Hey.
- Hi.
- I'm... uh, it-it's for, uh, it's for Izz... it's for Izzy.
- Izzy. All right.
- Yeah.
Two Z's?
- Uh, yeah, two Z's.
- Two Z's.
And, Rory, I just...
I have to say, you're...
Rory's my favorite, so it's like...
- Thank you.
- Really, yeah.
Thanks. Ah.
You know, I don't think
I ever got your name.
- Hey, what's up?
- Hey, I'm good. Nice to meet you.
- Uh, Zeke. Yeah.
- Zeke?
Thank you so much.
Hi. Wh-What's happening?
- Do you guys...
- Oh, we met earlier.
- Oh.
- In line for the bathroom.
Yes.
And you must be the daughter.
Uh, yeah, Izzy, yeah.
- And, uh, this is...
- I'm, um...
Well, it's on the tip of my tongue,
I swear.
I mean, I literally forgot my own name.
- It's Georgia. It's Georgia.
- My name is Georgia.
Nice to meet you, Georgia.
Uh, we've totally taken up
enough of your time.
- Thank you so much.
- Aren't you gonna introduce me?
Oliver Hoyt-Knight, this is Izzy,
this is Georgia, Zeke...
Hey.
And...
still don't know your name.
I'm Solène.
Oh, is that, uh, is that French?
Uh, just French grandparents.
Solène, the big sister, I'm guessing?
Okay. Solène the mom.
Yes, my mom.
Uh, you don't look like my mom.
- Okay.
- Hey, now, so...
- It's just a fact. She's Black.
- She is Black.
She actually owns
a contemporary art gallery in Silver Lake.
- You guys should, like, come visit sometime.
- I love art.
Yeah, in fact, wherever we go,
while everyone else is too hungover
to get out of bed,
Hayesy is out and about exploring.
- Right? He's got a special penchant for art museums.
- Guys, I'm sorry.
You need to go. I'm so sorry.
Uh, duty calls.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Thank you. -Good meeting you guys.
- Nice meeting you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Bye. -Bye.
Okay. Now we go.
Like that. Yeah.
What's up, Coachella?!
Thank you, guys!
Let's give it up for our band!
Are you having a good time?
Oh, we're so honored to be here
on this iconic stage.
Thank you so much for coming.
We appreciate all of you.
You guys ready?
Okay. Sorry, one second, guys. One second.
Cut it.
Right now?
- Right now?
- Yeah, definitely.
I'm sorry about that, guys.
Uh, slight change of plan.
I met someone tonight.
And I feel a little inspired.
Not planning on doing this, but...
this one's called "Closer."
So?
- So?
- How's it feel to be 40?
- Oh, there he goes.
- Honey, really? Okay. -
What? It's a milestone.
It is.
- It is.
- It's a good question.
Um, it feels very, very sweet.
I don't know.
I think I just feel really grateful.
I'm glad to be here.
I'm grateful to be here.
Maybe confusing.
You know?
Um, I had Izzy when I was so young,
so I feel like I, like, disconnected
from my age, uh, in my 20s.
I mean, I was just out of college, you know?
- Sure.
- Do you get it?
- I think
you're not even a person until you hit 30.
I mean, just think about it, right?
And then you spend
the next ten years after that
trying to figure out
the type of person you want to be.
- That is profound.
- That is drunk.
Well, let's drink
a little bit more. Hear, hear.
To life experience.
- Yeah, let's put that spin on it.
- Hear, hear.
Hey, hey!
Birthday girl. Hi.
- Whew, you startled me there.
- Yeah, I know.
Hi, Todd.
Hi. Um...
Listen, I just wanted to come over and say
that I-I really admire you.
- Oh.
- Uh, you've built a community
around art and inclusiveness.
It's just... that's so cool.
That's very sweet. Thank you.
So I teach high school science.
Oh, cool. What year are your students?
Oh, sophomores.
- My daughter's gonna be a senior.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
And divorce, I mean,
it's such an identify shift, right?
- Yeah.
- I totally get it.
I mean, who am I
if I'm not Jessica's husband?
Do you have any children?
I do.
That's my son Rosco.
Oh, he's so cute.
- Charlie.
- Uh-huh.
Copernicus.
Rupert.
How long ago did you guys split up?
"Split" is such a specific word.
I'm just gonna say it.
Uh, I would like you
to accompany me next week
to a restaurant for a meal of food.
It's been rocky for a while.
Let's put it that way.
Oh. Sorry.
It's her.
Hi, honey.
Yeah, I'll be home soon.
Solène. We need you up front.
Okay, okay. Just give me a second.
Really, Solène,
we need you up front, like, now.
Okay. Okay. Is everything all right?
Yeah, we just need you.
She really uses her inclusive space to...
Oh.
And there she is now.
Hey.
Hi.
I don't know if you remember me,
but we met in Coachella.
Yes, I remember you.
So you know each other.
Great. Um, can I get anyone anything?
Water? Coffee?
- Thank you. We're all right, Jeremy.
- Oh. Yeah.
Bye.
Wow.
Um...
This is a surprise.
I did some online sleuthing
for a Solène of Silver Lake,
and, uh, well, I have
this very large, empty flat in London
that, uh, desperately needs some artwork.
So I was thinking maybe you could, uh...
Okay. Um...
Why don't we start in the back
with the ceramics?
You know, I was hoping
you'd start with the ceramics.
Um...
So these pieces were thrown by a fantastic
potter we work with called Susan Hable.
- Mm. She threw them at the wall?
- Sh...
N-No. She...
That's what they call it when they do
the work on the, on the wheel.
It's called throwing.
- Right.
Who is he?
That's Hayes Campbell
from August Moon.
Where have you been?
Being in my 30s, obviously.
The silhouettes of these pieces
echo Susan's fascination with, uh...
gesture and movement.
Yeah, I can see that.
Yeah, her work's very popular.
I'm sure.
Great. Well, I will, um... just...
take all of... all of these ones.
Sorry, what do you mean?
Oh, just-just everything
in this general area would be great.
- Claire.
- What's up?
So, um...
This client would like to buy
all these pieces.
Okay.
Hi, Claire.
Hey.
Thank you.
I'll get that all dealt with.
- That's Claire.
- Mm. Seems nice.
She's very nice.
She's very hardworking, competent, single.
Sorry, what are these ones over here?
These took my fancy.
Hayes, I love you!
Um...
These pieces are by a local artist,
Amanda Friedman.
Uh, she lives in Eagle Rock.
She chose to feature,
um, a strong light source.
Mm-hmm.
As if aliens had just, uh, landed.
Hmm.
These are shot on
a medium and large format camera on film.
No digital manipulation.
So cool. I'll take them all.
- What?
- If you could Bubble Wrap them or whatever,
and then I'll send someone over later
just to pick them up.
These bowls, by the way, these are lovely.
- Thank you.
- And the spaghetti tiles?
I mean, the detail I-is beautiful.
And whatever this is,
I want it in my home.
Honestly, uh...
I think I'll take all of it.
This is real art,
and these are real artists.
They take their work very seriously,
as do I.
They made it with a great deal of care,
and you're coming in here like...
I don't know...
Like you're buying apples or something.
Honestly, I've been looking
for art like this for so long,
and-and I genuinely connect with it,
and so...
I-I would really like to buy it,
if it's okay with you.
Okay.
- Okay.
- And for the record,
you have never seen me buy apples before.
It's fucked up.
So?
Are you gonna show me something else?
Don't you have a football stadium
to get to or a photo shoot to attend?
Well, um, what's-what's the day today?
- It's Tuesday.
- Yeah, no, don't have any of those until Wednesday.
I actually would love to show you
some more art,
but you just bought
everything in the gallery.
Oh.
Well, that was incredibly rude of me.
Does that happen a lot?
Yeah.
Well, if you have nothing left to show me,
then I'm gonna have to go find
another art gallery
- owned by a different art dealer...
- Okay. Okay.
I have a friend.
She's an artist I like very much.
She has a warehouse in Glendale.
She's not there right now,
but I happen to have the key.
I have been dying to go to Glendale
for the longest time.
- You have no idea.
- Middle of nowhere Glendale?
The middle of nowhere is
my favorite place in the world.
Why don't you have your driver meet us
out back, and we'll go to Glendale.
I mean, we could just go in your car.
- Sorry about the clutter.
- Oh. Uh, yeah.
I'll get that out of your way. Okay, um...
- Okay, I'm in.
- Whoops.
- I can take that.
- Oh, thank you.
Yeah, sure. Where do you want me to...
- Just on the floor or...
- Floor?
- Oh, yeah, the back. Sure, okay.
- Okay.
Okay.
Sorry about all this.
Oh.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
And go.
- Okay.
- Um...
- I'm coming up to the, uh, light.
So it's usually best if you just don't
look them in the eye.
Okay, great.
Just staring straight ahead.
They are really not noticing anything.
I think we're good.
That's kind of amazing.
Wow. You're a natural.
Hello.
Thanks.
- I like these.
- Ah.
Natrice Miller. Fantastic.
Is this a painting?
Yes, it is.
- What does it mean?
- It's a calendar.
- No, don't do that.
- Don't what?
Do you really want the lecture
about how art is subjective?
What do you see?
It's a grid. It's grid-like.
It's-it's-it's numerical.
Which means that...
Please. I-I've got nothing.
So the artist calls this piece
a self-portrait.
Now, what's she's showing is that
she's not some, uh, untouchable genius
in a rarefied space.
This is her life as an artist.
I find its honesty incredibly moving.
This piece is from my friend Sarah.
Um, she's sending all of these
to a gallery show in New York,
but she never sends this one.
Hmm, why's that?
Um, I don't know. She doesn't want to.
Wow.
What's it called?
Unclose me.
What do you feel when you look at it?
Everything.
- How did you meet Sarah?
- Uh...
Uh, in college. Freshman year.
She was, uh, blasting a Fiona Apple song
from her dorm room,
and I knew instantly we'd be friends.
Should we go?
And-and, um, college?
What'd you study?
Um, I was an art history major.
- Although I started out as premed.
- A doctor?
Well, I was an 18-year-old people pleaser
from New Jersey,
and my parents really liked the idea.
But then I...
took an art history class for the credits,
and I fell in love.
Anyway.
What about you? What's your life story?
I'm sorry, was that your life story?
Partly.
Tell me, how does one find oneself
in a boy band?
Very random.
Uh, I auditioned.
Others did, too.
You know, we were just Polaroids
on a wall, really.
You know, you got Adrian,
million-dollar smile.
Rory, Aussie rebel.
Simon, brooding poet.
Ollie, you know,
Ollie's just got that swagger.
And what about Hayes?
Oh, I'm just English.
Just works a charm, really.
You know, the funny thing is, the same day
that I auditioned for the band,
I also auditioned to play Tiny Tim
in the Hackney Playhouse version
of A Christmas Carol.
And in the end,
I didn't end up getting it.
You know, not tiny enough, apparently.
But I did get the boy band.
Had I got the play,
I would've done it, and...
someone else would've been me
in the band.
And, uh, I would've been...
I don't know what I would've been.
God, I'm starving. Are you hungry?
We should go get a bite to eat.
I...
I'm not sure.
What... what do you mean?
I'm not sure what we're doing here
at a boiling hot warehouse in Glendale,
asking about my major.
Well, I told you. I-I love Glendale.
I feel like I don't meet people like you
very often.
And most people think
they already know me.
Hayes Campbell.
It's not me.
I don't know. You didn't seem to care.
And for what it's worth,
I think we met in a very interesting way.
I think you're smart and, you know,
y-you're also just-just...
y-you're hot, or whatever.
"Hot"?
Or whatever.
So I guess what I'm doing here is...
just trying to get to know you better.
Well...
I do appreciate your honesty.
So what should we eat?
Uh, we could go back to my hotel
in Beverly Hills,
order some room service.
Uh, that's... kind of a drive.
- Yeah, no, I was just throwing out some options.
- Mm.
- I-I don't really know L.A.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
How about, um, All Time on Hillhurst?
That is Hayes Campbell.
Is that a popular spot?
Um, it's pretty popular, I guess. It's...
Okay, uh...
Actually, let's go to my house.
I'm gonna make you a sandwich.
Sounds good.
Here we are.
Wow.
It's a little, uh, bit messy.
Izzy's packing for camp, so, uh...
It's perfect. It's, um... it's a home.
Thanks.
Daniel hated... uh, my ex,
hated it.
He called it a starter house.
But...
I always thought of it like a home, too.
- Oh, shit.
- Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine, sort of. It's...
Ah. Past the expiration date?
You know, I usually find those dates
to be more of a suggestion.
No, no, it's just... it's...
My fridge is broken again.
So, um, I was just seeing
how long it's been down.
- But if you just want to go, then I-I...
- Oh, no. Hell no.
- Give it to me. Let me have a taste, yeah.
- What?
Oh, no, I mean, this has definitely got,
like, a week left in it for sure.
Oh, my God!
No, it doesn't.
Why would you do that?
No, that's yours.
Okay, uh, yeah.
Um... put me to work.
What? No. I'm not gonna let you smell-test
the contents of my refrigerator.
Woman, time is a-wasting. Put me to work.
- It would be my honor.
- Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Uh, cooler from the garage,
we fill it with ice,
sort it into two categories:
salvageable and hazmat.
Okay, got it.
Oh, um, those sandwiches.
Do we still get those or...?
Let me get the cooler.
- Tomato?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Your daughter, you, uh, close?
Yeah, we are.
I mean, she is my daughter
and I am her mother,
so we do drive each other
up a wall sometimes, but, um...
but yeah.
She's my favorite person.
So what about you?
You and your parents, are you guys close?
Oh. No, not really.
I mean, they split up
when I was very young.
Mum remarried to, uh...
"Darren from Scunthorpe.
Good show, Hayes."
- You're not a fan?
- I mean, he's nice enough.
He's just a twerp.
And he's from Scunthorpe,
which is a bit of a shithole.
He's-he's, uh, he's not bad really.
What about your dad?
Dad's wanted a lot more of a relationship
in the last few years,
which is really funny timing
given that he wasn't really there
for the first 16 years of my life.
Now he wants to be best mates.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean, I want to be close to him, but...
It's hard to trust people, isn't it?
Yeah.
This is very good.
Thank you.
This Daniel guy, ex-husband,
what happened to him?
Really?
Not even a softball question
to warm us up a little bit like,
"Hey, Solène, what's your favorite color?"
Hey, Solène,
what's your favorite color?
That's actually a very personal question.
For context, um...
I had just moved to L.A.
Um, I wanted to be in the art scene
in Downtown New York,
- but I could afford to be in the art scene in Downtown L.A.
- Mm.
So I met Daniel, uh,
at a party in Echo Park.
Hate him already.
It's getting late.
I think that maybe we should...
- Solène.
- Mm-hmm. Hayes?
We're just talking.
We're two people with trust issues who
need to open up a little. -
I mean, what's the worst that can happen?
Oh, you want to know the worst thing that
can happen when you open up to someone?
Please tell me.
Okay.
I'll tell you.
Daniel, he was very intelligent,
outgoing, very driven...
and we really liked each other.
So we got together, fell in love,
got married, got pregnant...
Although not in that order.
And then we were just very young.
With a baby.
We, you know, put our heads down.
He was crushing it at work.
The gallery had finally opened,
Izzy was at school,
but there was, uh, distance.
It's... we had... there was a drift.
But I thought, you know,
"Okay, that's normal.
That's normal. You know?
So you didn't get a fairy tale. Grow up."
And then one night
about three years ago...
we were out at dinner
with his work friends,
and, um, I was repeating some stupid...
gossip about, uh, someone we all knew,
who cheated on someone else,
and the whole table went silent.
Like, you know that feeling
when you walk into a room
and you know everybody
was just talking about you?
And I look at Daniel,
and he won't look at me.
He wouldn't look at me.
So we got back to the house,
paid the sitter,
and I asked him.
He said her name was Eva.
She was a...
young lawyer at his firm.
The thing that I'm the most angry about
is I was so nice about it.
I offered to forget it.
I said that, for us, for our family,
for the good of our family, I would...
I mean, people make mistakes...
I'll forget... I'll...
I'll forgive it.
And then he said...
he didn't want to move past it.
He was in love.
And then he very quietly...
left.
So that, in my experience,
is the worst thing that can happen
when you open yourself up to someone.
Well...
we're still here.
Mm-hmm.
Eating great fucking sandwiches.
They are great, aren't they?
And maybe we're not all Daniel.
I'll take that under consideration,
Hayes Campbell.
Oh, please not the first and last name.
Do you not like that?
It just doesn't tell the whole story.
I see that.
Just... I'll be right back.
Hello.
Oh, hi, Izzy.
Hey... uh, no.
Why'd you stop?
No reason.
What is that song?
Uh, it's-it's nothing, really.
I like it.
Yeah?
Yeah.
- I'm too old for you.
- No, you're not.
Okay.
- I could be your mother.
- You're not.
- But I could be.
- But you're not.
No.
Can I take you back to your hotel?
Uh, no, it's fine. Desmond's outside.
So when can I see you again?
Hayes.
Solène.
- I can't do this.
- Why's that?
Because you're you and I'm me,
and we just don't fit.
- We'll see.
- Mm.
Glad you enjoyed the sandwich.
Legendary.
- Hi. Hey.
- Hey. Hey.
- I know. I know. I'm packing.
- Yes, good. Okay.
Sup?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Oh, my God, are you high?
No.
- Did Tracy give you a gummy again?
- No.
I'm fine.
All right. And I'm packing,
so don't come in, please.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ You got to pay ♪
♪ Your way in pain ♪
♪ You got to pray ♪
♪ Your way in shame...
being, like,
an older camper versus a JC
is that, as a JC, you get to, like,
hang out with different divisions and...
- Izzy!
- Hi!
- Oh, my God!
- Hi.
Oh, my God. How are you?
- So happy we're here. Okay, wait.
- Okay, girls, let's go. Come on.
Come on.
- Okay, okay. Wait, I'll see you in one second, okay?
- Bye, guys.
- Izz, I need you.
Okay, okay, I'll be right there.
- Um, I-I really... I got to go.
- Okay. I know, I know, I know.
- Okay, do you have your, uh, bug spray?
- Yes.
- Antihistamines?
- Yes, Mom.
- I have everything, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay, we'll talk on Sundays.
- Sundays, Sundays. Bye-bye-bye-bye-bye.
- Okay.
- I love you. And you have a good summer.
- Bye-bye-bye. I will.
Love you. Bye.
I need you.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. We do really... We got to go.
- What? No, no.
We've reached
our cruising altitude of 32,000 feet.
And we're expecting a smooth flight
all the way into LaGuardia.
- Hi.
How was the flight?
It was fine. Good.
Uneventful.
New dress?
No.
How was your show?
Fine.
Good.
Uneventful.
I brought you your watch.
Well, I think it looks
a lot better on you.
Okay. Okay.
- There's so many buttons.
- I know, but it looks so good.
Can I have the chicken fingers?
Cool. Uh, what do you want?
- A BLT.
- BLT.
Fries?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, we'll have some fries.
And a cookie plate.
Here are your chicken fingers.
Is that the same song you were playing
at my house on the piano?
Mm-hmm.
I like it. It's good.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Have you always played guitar?
No.
- I didn't know how to play an instrument before I started the band.
- Mm.
They told us it wasn't necessary.
Yeah.
You want to hear a story?
Mm-hmm.
A few years ago,
the head of my label calls me.
And he says that the lead singer
of my favorite band
wants to meet me.
I'm so excited.
Maybe we'll hit it off,
record a song.
And I get there,
and it's his ten-year-old daughter's
birthday party.
And he wants me to take pictures with her
and all her friends.
I think that's my greatest fear in life.
That I'm a joke.
You're not a joke.
Morning.
I hope you don't mind
that I borrowed your cardigan.
It's only temporary. I will give it back.
- Oh, no complaints here.
- Okay. Just checking.
I'm leaving this afternoon
to go on the European leg of my tour.
Don't worry. I'll be out of your hair
before you know it.
And I was really hoping
you'd come with me.
You know I can't do that.
Why not?
Izzy.
- And I don't think it's...
- She's at camp all summer.
The gallery, I-I have to,
you know, work...
I literally bought all of the art
in your gallery, so, I mean...
Don't your artists need
some more time to m-make some art?
I don't have any clothes.
- I have an army of stylists, an army.
- No, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
I did not bring enough underwear.
Well, we can go to Target.
And we'll get some Fruit of the Loom.
- That's what you wear, right? Fruit of the Looms?
- Thank you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, absolutely.
- Thank you. Only the best.
- So...
When was the last time
you took a real holiday?
What about what people will say?
I don't care what they say.
And worse comes to worst,
we'll just say that you are my...
extremely attractive art consultant.
Everyone has secrets.
Hi, Gene.
Hey, everyone, this is Solène.
- She's my art consultant.
- Hi.
Hi.
Art consultant?
- Okay.
- Hi.
- Come on. We got to go.
- Uh, break a leg. Oh.
- Okay, this is for you. Ears.
- Thank you.
- Hayes.
- And, uh, and down there...
Thank you. Okay.
What's up?
Pretty amazing, huh?
- Izzy?
- Hey, Mom.
How are you? What's up?
Oh, I'm, uh, I'm... I-I'm good.
Thank you.
Yeah, I'm, uh, I'm doing
some, uh, traveling.
Oh, where?
I'm, uh, I'm-I'm all over the place.
Come on. I, like, need to know.
What do you think, huh?
- Who's that?
- It-it-it's, uh, my new client.
- Oh, my God, what are you doing?
- He came into the gallery,
and he liked the stuff,
so now we're traveling around.
Anyway, tell me about the musical.
- What about Izzy?
- I haven't told her yet.
You embarrassed to be jet-setting around
the world with a 24-year-old pop star?
Because that's... it's fine.
I know how it is.
No, it's fine, it's fine.
I only get 15 minutes
to speak with her every week,
and there is so much camp drama.
You having a good time?
Oui.
That was reckless.
We're in Paris.
It's still reckless.
It's still Paris.
We have a long weekend coming up,
and Rory and Simon are going off to Ibiza,
but Ollie and I rented this spectacular
house in the south of France.
It's peaceful... quiet.
And I think we could have a lot of fun.
Okay, hold on.
Ah. Oh.
Wow.
Okay.
- Oh.
- Is this a funeral?
Hi.
- Hi.
Is this Hayes's chair?
- Yeah.
Family history of, uh, skin cancer.
Ah.
So, are you guys having fun on the tour?
- Mm-hmm. -Oh, yeah.
- Yeah. It's fun.
Charlotte, how long have
you and Ollie been dating?
Dating?
We've been hanging out for a while.
I'm getting popsicles. You guys want some?
- Oh, yeah.
- Yes. -Okay, one, two.
- Do you want one?
- No, I'm good, thank you.
Okay.
Wait, pass one to me.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God, look at this. -Hello.
Excuse me. So sorry.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Make some room?
- Make some room please.
Hello.
- Hi.
Please warm me.
- Okay.
- I'm done.
This place is incredible.
I plan to keep doing
absolutely nothing all weekend.
Not sign an autograph, write a tweet.
So, Ollie says you own an art gallery?
Yeah, in Silver Lake.
It's amazing.
- Solène's got a real eye for talent.
- No doubt.
I hear you're a mom, too.
Yes. Yes.
Uh, I have a daughter, Izzy.
She's, um, 16.
I love that. Where does she go to school?
Uh, she just finished her junior year
at Campbell Hall.
Oh, my God.
I have a friend who graduated
Campbell Hall two years ago.
That's crazy. I wonder if she knows her.
Now, that's hilarious.
Charlotte, wha... um, what do you do?
I'm in college.
I'm taking a year off
to, you know, travel.
Charlotte is being modest.
Okay, she's brilliant.
She speaks like ten different languages,
and plus she's an amazing dancer.
I wonder what Rory
and Simon are doing.
Simon, how many models
are with you right now?
We're gonna have to do
something a little naughty
to prove that we're having more fun.
Orgies are still a thing, right?
- Ollie, can you not, please?
- I know, I know.
Now that you're with Solène,
you're like a middle-aged man.
You know, before you showed up,
he behaved like an actual pop star.
Do you just say every fucking thing
that pops in your head?
Popsicles.
Come on, guys.
Solène, how did you guys meet?
We need to know the story.
Uh, we met at Coachella.
- Actually, it was at an August Moon meet and greet.
- Yeah.
Oh, my God. You're a Moonhead.
- No, no.
- That's so cute.
It's actually kind of a crazy story.
Uh, she wasn't supposed to be there.
And then she was,
and she was with her daughter.
Yeah, yeah.
No, we-we, uh, we met by accident.
By accident, yeah.
In my trailer.
And then Hayes, you know, really upped
the ante when he dedicated a song to me.
"Closer"?
- Yes.
- Of course that was the one.
We do that
when one of us finds a girl,
or in Hayes's case, a woman, cute.
We pretend to change the set list
at the last minute.
- It's a bit.
- It's a bit. Right.
Oh, my God, wait. Oh, wait.
Do you guys remember when he did it
for that Swedish actress
who was, like, in love with him?
- Hayes told you that, didn't he?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hanna. Wasn't it Hanna, Hayes?
- Oh, my God.
Poor Hanna. She was obsessed.
I mean,
can you imagine if he did it?
That would be so fucked up.
She just kept showing up.
We couldn't ditch her 'cause she was,
like, famous in Sweden or something.
She was like 33 and clueless.
It was, like, so awkward.
- Oh, shoot, I forgot my, um, thing.
- Just let me...
I just need it. So excuse me.
Sorry. Just got to grab it.
Enjoy the popsicles.
- Bye.
- Bye. -See you.
Why'd you do that?
Do what?
I'm sorry about Ollie.
- He can be a...
- It's fine.
He's a guy in his 20s.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means I think it's time I went home.
- Hey, Sol, can we just take a beat...
- It's not you.
It's me.
You are very, very beautiful,
and I fell for your fuck-boy move.
40 and clueless, I guess.
Can I explain myself? It was stupid.
- I was trying to impress you.
- And it worked.
And it worked for Hanna, too. Nice job.
I'm sorry, is it so shocking to you
that I've slept with other women?
Other older women? No.
- It's even fine that you have a type.
- I actually liked Hanna.
- You know what, Hayes?
- Not that that's any of your business.
I got swept up in the idea of you,
and it's been fun, it really has,
- but we both knew it had to end.
- Does it?
- Does it what? I...
- Does it have to end?
W-We have a few more weeks of the tour,
then I'm gonna be in L.A.
It would just be me,
and we could hang out like normal people.
Um, yeah, it's not gonna work for me.
This was fun, but now it's, uh, not.
Wh-What are you so afraid of, Solène?
The father of my child
lied to me for a year,
and all of his friends knew.
Everybody knew except for me.
Which is a gut punch similar to the one
I just felt by the pool with your friends.
- I'm not Daniel.
- Tell that to my stomach.
You know, I-I know what it is
that you're doing.
You're bailing. You're running away.
No, I'm not running away.
Oh, you're not running away?
You're literally packing a bag.
Hayes, this doesn't
have to be dramatic, okay?
- We both knew what this was. It's fine.
- What if I want more?
- Wh...
- For the first time in
I don't even fucking know how long,
I-I'm actually happy.
I mean, usually, I feel numb or...
you know, I-I feel like I'm supposed to be
feeling something when I'm not.
But with you,
laughing, just being with you,
holding you at night, I mean,
it's meant the world to me.
And I'm writing music.
God, the music I'm writing now,
I-I actually feel like I care about it,
so-so why on earth
would I want this to end?
This is where you say, "Of course, Hayes,
I... I feel some of this, too."
I can't say that.
God, you know
what the crazy thing is, Sol?
I don't think you ever
even gave us a chance.
I mean, does anyone in your life
even know about me?
Does your daughter? Do your friends?
If the roles were reversed, do you think
anyone else would give a shit?
Or judge?
I mean, did anyone with Daniel and Eva?
Izzy did. Tracy did. I did.
I do.
So, what, you're, um,
you're ashamed of me?
Is that it?
I... am...
ashamed.
Um...
Okay, well...
I'm going to go find
somewhere else to sleep tonight,
and I'll arrange a flight back to L.A.
Izzy's turning 17.
Can you believe it?
I got to say, I'm really surprised
you got her a new car, Daniel.
It's not new. It's used.
I got it at CarMax.
It's like new. Almost new.
Well, we had a price cap,
so I bought her watercolors and an easel.
Well, that's cool. I mean, you know?
She's got something cute
and something powerful.
Do you think she should,
like, just, like, come home to it?
- Um...
- Or, oh, no. I know.
Framed photograph of the car wrapped up.
You can give it to her
when you pick her up at camp.
- Okay.
- Great.
Okay, ready? Okay.
Oh, uh, do you remember
Kip Brooks from my old firm?
Maybe. Why?
Well, we had lunch
with him and his wife last week,
and they were telling us about
this amazing trip that they took to Rome,
and he said that he could've sworn
that he saw you there in a café
with the kid from August Moon.
- Were you in Italy?
- Yes, I was.
I was in Venice for the Biennale.
Oh, right on.
Finally stepping up to the plate.
Nice.
Uh, thing is, he said that
you guys were kissing and holding hands.
And, I mean, that would just be, like,
mind-blowing if that were true.
Yeah, that would be mind-blowing.
Um, he is a client.
He's been by the gallery.
Okay, well, I mean,
I'm sure we can all agree
that any relationship with
a 24-year-old world-famous pop star
would be crazy on, like, so many levels.
Well, I'm not really interested
in relationship advice from you, Daniel.
But in this case,
I do agree it would be crazy.
Okay, I'm gonna go
snap some pics of the car.
Please know I'm not unaware
of his, uh, stunning...
hypocrisy.
Cool.
I'm leaving him.
He obviously has no idea yet, but, um...
Yeah, it's over between us.
Um, why are you telling me this?
Because I wanted you to know the truth.
Would you want to get Thai food
with me sometime?
- No.
- Okay.
Thank you so much.
The food,
the people-watching, the art,
uh, it was...
- it was Europe.
- Mm-hmm.
Who's this guy you were with?
He's a pretty high-profile client,
so I probably shouldn't name names.
So it's strictly professional?
Well, this client...
he's very young.
How young are we talking?
20s.
Mid-20s.
Oh, okay. That's nothing.
I mean, if you were gonna tell me
something happened,
I'm just saying, that's nothing.
Okay, so hang on.
Um, when Daniel does it, it's gross,
but if I were to do it, it would be fine?
Yeah. Because I hate him and I love you.
You live there
and obviously enjoy living there,
but there must be things you miss.
I miss British humor.
I mean, you know.
Yeah.
Our humor is this...
Just doesn't always travel.
- Hi. Hi. Solène Marchand?
- Yes.
- Brenda McCall, Dana's mom.
- Oh.
- I think she's in a bunk with your daughter.
- Yes, yes.
Izzy has mentioned Dana. Hello.
How are you? -
Can I just tell you, you are my hero.
Also divorced.
You have inspired me not to lie about
my age on my Hinge profile, so...
Well...
Uh, you're even prettier in person.
- Um... Oh. No, no. It's... No, no.
- Can I get a selfie?
- Thanks so much.
- Neil, stop.
- What? Come on. What...
- Can we just trade places?
- Neil.
- What did I do?
- Hi. Hi.
- Hi.
I have to tell you, my daughter has had
a crush on Hayes since she was like ten,
and she is so heartbroken.
Yeah.
We talked like
a million times, Mom.
You never said anything.
I mean, I could tell something
was going on.
I didn't tell anyone.
I kept thinking,
"I'm just gonna have this experience,
and no one will ever know."
Mom, it's Hayes Campbell.
You're right.
We're not dating anymore.
I mean, I don't know if we... Anyway.
I ended it ten days ago.
Which is what's so crazy
about all of this.
- Wait, wait, you broke up with him?
- Yes.
Wow.
Okay.
You know, I could have handled
that you were dating him.
It pisses me off that you lied to me.
Like, Dad lied, and that sucked.
I thought I could count on you.
I am so, so sorry.
It will never happen again. I promise.
People on the Internet that are
picking you apart are disgusting.
It's 'cause you're a woman,
and it's 'cause you're older than him.
They hate you for it.
So that's just hypocritical and unfair.
And wrong.
You like him?
Yeah, I do.
Is he a feminist?
'Cause that's important here.
- I mean, he is still a guy...
- Right.
But, um...
but, yeah,
he's a feminist.
Mom.
Why would you break up
with a talented, kind feminist?
Because...
Where's he now?
He's in L.A., I think.
So?
What are you gonna do?
Hey, guys, you think you can
give me the room for a bit?
Hi.
You okay?
It was horrible...
But... seems to have died down.
What I am not okay with
is how I treated you.
I'm sorry.
When you said this is the part
where I was supposed to say
that I felt all those things, too...
I was afraid.
I do, very much...
feel all those things.
With you, I feel...
everything.
So...
maybe you're right.
Maybe it doesn't have to end.
I'm sorry, Solène. I, um...
I wasn't expecting this.
- Of course. I...
- I'm feeling a little overwhelmed right now
with everything that's going
on, you know? -
- I totally understand.
- I just need a moment.
You know.
All right, I've had a moment.
It's gonna be a lot.
We're ready.
There's gonna be
a firestorm of attention on us.
- We'll just delete all our social media.
- You sure?
Ignorance is bliss.
This feels good.
- So.
I don't think I can delete TikTok.
- Do I have to delete TikTok?
- No, you don't. No.
- Yes. Okay.
- All right.
A second.
- Hey.
You must be Daniel. I'm Hayes.
Mm.
I'm sorry to hear about Eva, mate.
- That, um, sucks.
- Yeah.
Wh-Where's Izzy? I'm taking her to school.
I will let her know.
I just put a pot of coffee on.
You want a cup?
No, thank you. I'm fine.
You know, there's a dozen photographers
out there across the street.
Yeah, we know.
Um, my head of security just installed
some pretty incredible cameras,
so we should be fine.
Security. Okay.
Um, what's your endgame here, bro?
"Bro"?
Didn't realize we were
on bro terms, Daniel.
I don't know what you want me
to say to you, man.
I mean, how long are you gonna keep up
this insanity with my wife?
Daniel?
What are you doing here?
I'm gonna go get Izzy.
Thanks.
It was really nice to have met you, bro.
- What's up?
I don't know... just thought I'd like to
check to make sure our daughter is safe
from crazy fans and paparazzi
while she's here at her mother's home.
- Of course we all want that.
- Oh.
Which is why we have security,
and Izzy understands
this is all gonna blow over,
and she says she's fine with it.
Well, then you got it all covered, huh?
Pretty much.
You know,
I think I'll drive her to school today.
That's great.
- I'll pick her up.
- Fine.
Is that all?
Is there something
you'd like to say, Daniel?
As a matter of fact, there is.
I mean, you're my w...
You're the mother of my child,
and you're screwing this kid
that she's had a poster of next to her bed
since she was ten.
I mean, it's a little fucking weird.
First of all, I'm not your wife.
I was your wife,
and you lied, cheated and left.
The only reason that I met Hayes
was because you thought a business trip
was more important than
a bonding experience with your daughter.
- I had to go to Houston.
- Yes, I know, Daniel! I know that!
It's work... I get it... but
it is also a choice! -
And that is the choice
that you repeatedly make for yourself,
so excuse me if this whole white knight
routine is falling a little flat.
Ooh, zing.
Also, she never had a poster of Hayes
in her bedroom.
It was Rory. It was always Rory.
Sol, c-can you hear yourself?
I mean, come back to reality
for just a moment here.
Do you have any idea
what they're saying about you?
No.
Wow, okay.
Um, I'll be outside.
- Hey.
- Bye, Mom.
You okay?
- Yeah, no, I'm just running late.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna pick you up, all right?
- Ready? Okay?
- Yeah.
Hey, sweetheart!
Over here, over here!
Come on, guys.
Take a break.
- You all right?
- Huh?
Uh...
What's the matter?
Um...
Charlotte just texted me from New York.
Ollie's, um... he's got himself
in a bit of trouble.
- Is he all right?
- Yeah.
I-I'm gonna pack a bag
and go and see him this afternoon.
- And I'm really sorry. This is so...
- Oh. Okay. Okay.
Last-minute and crazy.
I-I understand. Go.
- You sure?
- Yeah, of course.
Okay. It's-it's just gonna be
a few days, all right?
- All right.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry about this.
I can't do anything about the phone stuff,
but I'll put up a "by appointment only"
sign to keep out weirdos.
Okay, that's a good plan.
Would you, um...?
- Tracy, hi. Come in, come in, come in.
- Hi. Uh...
Hi.
- What's with the horde?
- Um, okay.
People are, uh, having feelings.
You're okay?
I mean, I didn't know my being happy
would piss so many people off.
Oh, right. Did I not warn you?
People hate happy women.
It's kind of a lot.
- Sol, it's almost 3:00.
- Oh, God. Okay.
- Uh, sorry, I got to pick up Izzy from school.
- No.
We're... it's a thing,
and she hates when I'm late.
Bye, Izz!
- Honey, what's going on?
- Drive, Mom.
- Well, who are those...
- Just drive please.
Honey, what happened back there?
Oh, those were just some seniors
asking if you could get a picture
of Hayes's penis for them.
So, you know, just a regular Tuesday.
- They said that?
- No, actually.
Uh, they said "dick."
Then there's that guy in band, Trevor,
you know, that I really like.
Well, we've been texting.
And I thought he liked me, too, but then
you know what he said to me today?
"Tell your mom I turn 18 in a month."
So, yeah, that's how my day was.
Oh, Izz.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Can you just drop me at Dad's?
- I just can't deal today.
- Okay.
Um...
Love you.
You have time for a comment?
What do you have to say
to the fans of August Moon?
What do you have to say to all the fans
in the world who are brokenhearted?
Hey, Sol, this is Jodie.
Do you want to comment
on these latest stories?
You know, given the tenor of them,
you might want to say something.
All right? Give me a call back.
- Hey, you. How you doing?
- Hey.
Oh, God.
I tell you, that flight, oy.
I am so tired.
Mwah.
- There you go.
- Oh, thank you very much.
Why'd you give me the watch?
And why aren't we moving?
Hey.
Sol, Sol, what's wrong?
I can't do this anymore.
Us, our relationship, I...
I can't do it anymore.
It's Izz.
- Okay, um...
- It's just...
It's too much for her.
I mean, it's... it's actually insane.
I mean, she didn't sign up for
any of this, and it's too much for her.
And I have to put her first.
Okay.
Okay, let me just, um...
Let me just think about this for a second.
Um...
I mean, look, I-I could quit.
- I could quit all of it.
- No, you can't.
I'm f...
I'm fine with doing that.
I could do that.
It would just get worse.
Please don't do this, Solène. Please.
Please just go.
You're not gonna fight for us?
I auditioned for the band when I was 14.
It shouldn't ruin a whole life.
It's not going to.
You're gonna have a big, beautiful life.
I'm so sorry.
I love you, Solène.
I love you, too.
Just promise me
you'll revisit this in five years.
Izzy will be out of school,
living her best life.
And I'll be some D-list celebrity
that nobody gives a shit about.
It's too long.
If you get a shot at happiness,
you take it.
And I will, too, okay?
- Hi.
- Hi, sweetie.
- How are you?
- Oh. I love your hair.
Oh, thank you. I just did it.
It's beautiful. You look really good!
- How's Chicago?
- Good.
I mean, like, freezing right now but good.
Are you staying warm?
Do you need anything,
a sweater or a-a vest or a-a scarf?
No, I have about 5,000
of your sweaters here.
Okay.
When it comes to the Ramona Coaster,
one minute you're soaring
through the air...
a little heat from the cayenne and a
little smokiness from the sweet paprika...
Put "milk steak." She'll know what it is.
No, she won't know what it is, Charlie.
Nobody knows what that is.
Thank you.
Hayes Campbell!
- You sit there. Okay.
- Okay.
That was amazing, Hayes.
Thank you so much.
Really special performance, wasn't it?
Gorgeous. Absolutely gorgeous.
Thank you.
It seems like you have been
touring nonstop.
- Yeah.
- Presumably, there is a break somewhere in your future.
- You need a break, Hayes.
- I-I need a break.
I-I'm-I'm on my last legs, I think,
at the moment, Graham.
But, um, no, I think, um, it-it's just
about, you know, getting through the tour.
And, um, I think after that,
I-I've scheduled myself a little break,
maybe a little holiday to L.A.
L.A.? Any particular reason why L.A.?
Uh, there's someone
I would like to see there.
Thank you.
-Bye.
How are you?
Really compelling collection.
You know, I think there's a Teddy Kelly
back there with your name on it.
Yeah.