LAWRENCE
You don't have to be afraid.
God has great plans for you.
This child is His way.
MARGARET
There's this girl...
...at the orphanage.
I think that she really needs
someone to look out for her.
SILVIA
Carlita...
...suffers from a touch of madness.
FATHER BRENNAN
You must be very careful, Margaret.
Bad things will start to happen
around her.
Evil things.
ANJELICA
It's all for you.
MARGARET
No, no, don't.
What does any of this have to do
with Carlita?
FATHER BRENNAN
This church has maintained power
for thousands of years.
They will stop at nothing
to keep it that way.
How do you control people
who no longer believe?
You create something to fear.
I believe the girl is to be the mother.
MARGARET
The mother of what?
FATHER BRENNAN
It's the mark of the Devil.
MARGARET
Hey!
It's not real. It's not real.
It's not real.
ANJELICA
What's not real?
MARGARET
Who said that?
LAWRENCE
This... is very real.