What's wrong?
There's someone on the roof.
Jules, maybe you're used to sleepwalking.
Listen.
I don't hear anything. Come on, baby.
It's three o'clock in the morning.
I know.
I don't know if she's
heard something on the roof.
There are footsteps.
Naturally. Channel Bose too, right?
Mark, stop.
But I heard him.
Can you take care of this, please? I've
got to be here for 20 hours.
Come on, Jules. Let's get back into bed.
I'm going to show you after dinner, okay?
Too many bed dreams and not enough sleep.
But mom, I didn't have a bed dream.
I really heard someone on the roof.
Shh. Keep your voice down, okay? Don't
wake up your brother.
Nobody believes me.
Jules, it was probably
just the house settling.
Or an animal, you know, sometimes a
raccoon or squirrel can get out there.
It was Santa. I'm positive.
You know who I really think it was?
Who?
One is Santa's house.
Can you help?
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes Santa sends a scout a few days
before Christmas Eve
to make sure our house meets all the
necessary safety requirements.
Like what?
Like making sure the roof is sturdy
enough to hold all the
reindeer, for one thing.
And I've been crashing through the
ceiling, running all through the house,
pooping on everything.
What else?
I have to measure the chimney to make
sure it's wide enough to
fit Santa's big fat belly.
Sometimes he's squirre just too much
during the holidays.
Just like Daddy?
Just like Daddy.
Can you move some milk
and cookies out for me else?
If you go to sleep right now, I'll go
downstairs and leave them alone.
Okay?
You forgot to lock the front door again.
Perhaps you got a little concerned
through your family's safety.
By the way, your daughter left a glass of
milk and cookies for
Santa's house in the kitchen.
We should get that for school.
Hello?
Can you take care of that
when you wake up, please?
When I wake up, I am up, Jen.
I win up because you keep talking to me.
I will do their best.
I'll do this.
I don't care yet.
No need to." Santa? Timmy! Timmy wake up!
Santa's downstairs!
Timmy, you were putting presents under
the tree! I saw him!
Away!
Julian, I told you to stay out of my way!
(water splashing)
Maybe, maybe.
(screaming)
Do it, do it, do it.
Do it.
(screaming)
(water splashing)
(screaming) (screaming)
(singing in foreign language) (singing in foreign language)
(singing in foreign language)
(wind blowing)
Once you are totally
be advised not to miss
a college-based possible assessment
on maybe one of your heart and fingers.
(wind blowing)
Do Spanish, I got a
decapitated body down here.
Do you think it appears to be male?
All available units go to mode.
Stand for it.
Dispatch, I'm on a low down here.
What's the easier way to back up?
Multiple units are having to sleep.
(wind blowing)
(screaming)
Get out of here,
Jeff, the ship's on fire.
(wind blowing)
Dean, I need you to get down here now.
So three, swing.
Let me get a situation.
What for us?
I can't get down here.
Broncho.
(wind blowing)
(screaming)
Are you helping?
Are you ready to do it?
Please help me.
(laughing)
Help me, help me, you fucker.
Help me.
Help me, help me.
(laughing)
(screaming)
(wind blowing)
Yo, yo, you guys, you look so good.
I mean, way better than mine.
I was gonna do the blood thing too,
but I was just worried about the cleanup.
But can I get a picture?
I'm gonna place this.
Seriously, you killed it.
(screaming)
(laughing)
Please, please help me.
What the fuck?
(screaming)
Free girl.
Free girl!
(screaming)
(screaming) Good afternoon.
I'm Ray.
Hi.
Good morning.
I'm Ray.
I'm here to pick up my niece.
She's a patient here.
What was her name?
Shaw.
See you in a shot.
Oh, great.
Nevermind.
Hey.
How are you?
Good, how are you?
Good.
It's good to see you.
You too.
Wow.
You look good.
No, I got it.
No, no, no.
I got it.
I insist.
Thanks.
Welcome.
So do we run or?
I gotta sign up first.
Yeah.
(screaming)
So,
has been a partner crime.
Oh, she's not so little anymore.
She's great.
Man.
Beautiful.
Sassy's, uh,
and talented like you.
Back to her all she ever talks about.
So,
a little warning.
Just get ready to have your hands full.
Cause she misses.
I miss her too.
(eerie music)
Hey,
we're home.
All right.
Hello?
Sienna!
Incoming.
Hey.
Hey, guys.
Oh my God, you've been so big.
What did that happen?
Never leave me for this long ever again.
I promise.
Oh, you got glitter all over your face.
I just said you were gonna make it.
Did you want to help?
Gabby, Sienna's not
even in here two minutes.
Why don't you let her get
set up first, all right?
Fine.
Yeah, I loved you.
I'm so happy to see you.
Me too.
I'm on the truck.
Fine, you wanna see her room?
Go ahead, catch up later.
Come on.
All right, I'll see you guys later.
Okay.
Don't pull her arm out.
Are you leaving?
Yes.
Oh my God.
It looks like a fairy
tale exploded in here.
You like it?
Me and Mommy were
decorated, but I get down most of it.
I know how much you
like dragons and wizards.
I love it.
Really?
Yes, really, this is
the coolest room ever.
Are you kidding?
I don't know what to say.
Is this beautiful?
I need this for you too.
Gabs.
Toussina, my big
sister from another mister.
I've missed you more than ever,
and getting into
trouble hasn't been nearly
as much fun without you.
Looking forward to
the best Christmas ever,
filled with fun, smiles, and laughter.
Love, Gabby.
P.S., we still
haven't made it to the moon.
To the moon.
Not our little cardboard rocket ship.
She remembered.
What was that thing?
The camera.
(eerie music)
Jesus.
She didn't stink, Sinaire.
She's a real beauty.
Oh, shit.
It's a rat kid, not the devil.
Yeah.
Are you all right?
Oh, you've been skittish all day.
There's just places like this.
It's like they got a
soul and they're pissed
that we're tearing apart.
Oh, shit, please don't tell me
you believe all the
stories about this place.
What stories?
Back in the early
90s, some maniac abducted
and killed over a
dozen kids in this town.
He buried all the bodies in the basement
here in this building.
Now everyone swears the place is haunted.
(eerie music)
You fuck with me?
Go motherfucker with you.
(laughing) Come on, I'll take the
first floor in the basement,
you upstairs.
Skittish all day.
The herald angels sing
Glory to the newborn king
He's son of Earth and mercy mild
God has sent his back inside
Joyful all ye nations rise
Joyful the triumph of the sky
With angelic host proclaim
Christ is haunted by the pain
(eerie music)
(children playing)
So, what do you think?
More blaster man.
What's the matter with blaster man?
Thought you liked him?
You only draw boys.
Boys, boys, boys.
That's not true.
I draw girls all the time.
There's a girl right there, look at that.
That was a girl.
But she's not a super hero.
Last time you said you
were gonna draw a girl
I couldn't be the last man.
Remember?
You pinky swore.
That's sacred.
I'm sorry sweetheart.
I will tell you what though.
As soon as I finish you with this comic
I'm gonna make you
something really special.
How's that?
Good?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Out of your bed.
Cece.
Wait a minute.
I do have something for you.
I woke up back in the clown cafe.
Encased in glass.
My lens filled with ice water.
This wasn't a dream or a hallucination.
Hey.
Give me that.
This isn't for public consumption, is he?
It's my diary, okay?
It's for my eyes only.
Got it?
Got it.
What's the clown cafe?
It's a bad place.
At least I don't wanna think about.
Happy thoughts from now on.
Okay?
(sniffing)
(laughing)
Jingle bells, jingle bells
This place is fucking smell
(eerie music)
What the hell is that?
Home.
(phone ringing)
What the fuck?
Hello?
(whistling)
That's not me.
That's not me, okay?
Andy Jackson!
(sighing)
(screaming)
Anybody home?
Yo.
What the fuck?
Shh.
Holy shit.
(crickets chirping)
It's Dennis!
Dennis!
(gasping)
Get your ass up here!
Now!
Are you real?
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
(crunching)
Come on.
(screaming)
(crunching)
(laughing)
(screaming)
(crunching)
(screaming) (screaming)
(panting)
(crunching)
(screaming)
I think we need to make some cookies.
Yeah, for dessert.
We need to, yeah.
Wow, man.
Chocolate and peanut
butter, you are right.
That's the combination.
Oh, those coconut peanut
butter ones are amazing.
This is gonna be Christmas extravaganza.
I'd like to go see those lights again.
I wanna see the lights.
I like the holiday market
that they have over there.
Yeah, stuff's there.
It's rude.
What, I like her scars.
Gabby, none of this, it's fine.
No, it's not, it's very inappropriate.
I just think they're cool.
You know what, why don't
you show her your new scar.
Look at this thing, bad boy.
Ooh, how'd she get that?
Fell off my neck during summer break.
And landed on a broken bottle.
Oh yeah, seven stitches too.
There was so many blood, I like this
piece of fat oozing.
All right, all right,
can we change the subject,
please, I don't wanna think about blood
and fat while we're eating.
Okay honey, you're disgusting.
Regardless, Christmas
hasn't really been the same
around here since
someone stopped believing
in Santa Claus.
When did that happen?
When I was like eight.
Oh stop, you were older than that?
No, I just went along
with it so you and daddy
wouldn't feel bad.
I've been finding
presents stuffed around the house
for years now.
Yeah, that's cause you're a little snoop.
Yeah, finding is a loose
term, more like investigating
and discovering, really.
Do you miss the rice?
It's not my fault that
they're really, really
bad at hiding presents.
Dude, it was under the
floorboard, under carpet.
Pass the rice please.
Oh, she's also
notorious for opening presents
and then re-wrapping them.
Not very well either.
If you don't pass the
rice, I'm not gonna leave.
Please, pass the rice.
Sienna, hello Sienna.
You know, I'm dead because of you, okay?
You led us to him, you
and that little shithead
brother of yours.
I'm dead.
And you killed me.
I figure out which one.
Just like you killed your mother.
That was bad.
But anyway, I'm in the dark here.
He's kinda cute.
Sienna?
You all right?
Yeah.
Sienna.
I mean, no amount of
medication is gonna stop me
from being here in front of you.
You killed me.
The least you can do is pass the rice.
Pass the rice.
Pass the rice, pass
the rice, pass the rice.
Pass the rice.
(screaming)
Excuse me.
(crowd chattering)
Finish eating sweeties so we
can have our forte cookies.
(crowd chattering)
Whoa, wow, thanks for knocking, Sienna.
Sorry.
Oh wait, aren't you gonna end this?
Wow, hey, Shaw, this is Mia.
Hi.
She's a really big fan of yours.
I'm not a fan, you asshole.
She's obsessed with
the Miles County clown,
like all that true crime shit.
She thinks you were
so mad at her to do it.
Don't listen to him, like literally ever.
Hi, it is so nice to meet you.
Hi.
I seriously know my
favorite thing about you,
everything online, at least one.
I've been following you for years,
and dude, you're a legend.
You survived Art the Clown.
Si, fucking fangirl.
Meet me.
I have to get his autograph.
Listen, I actually had
a little bit of a favor
that I wanted to ask you.
You see my roommate and I,
we have a true crime podcast,
it's called Grave and Image,
and our Miles County Massacre episodes,
they get our biggest hits by far.
So I was wondering if
maybe you'd be willing
to come on as a guest sometime.
I seriously would be so honored.
All right, I don't
really do things like that.
Jesus, do you really
think he wants to dredge
out the worst experience of his life?
I mean, the kid's just
trying to move on, right, Shaw?
Okay, well, I get that, but I just,
I think a lot of people
would really like to hear
from you after all this time.
Oh, God.
Come on.
(phone ringing)
I'll think about it.
He'll think about it.
First.
Shaw, you coming to
Beta Chris's best run?
I won't take this.
Oh, girl call me.
It's great you need me up.
You too.
God, my man needs to get laid so bad.
Hey, hey.
How are you?
I'm doing good, just got out of class.
Good.
I just got to head
justice a couple hours ago.
It's really good to hear your voice.
You know, I miss you.
I miss you too.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm calling because I'm really excited
we're gonna be
spending Christmas together.
It's been too long.
Yeah, it has.
I'm really looking forward to it.
Well, I guess I'll see
you in a couple days.
See you soon.
Love you all.
Love you more.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
It's just this new medication I'm on
that makes me queasy sometimes.
Oh.
I need to be creative.
I need my canvas.
inside conversation was quite Truman.
He goes around playing over the watch very quickly in one cartridge on the other. music)
music)
music) music)
I got into a fight. Did you win?
Yeah, I won. Should I?
Alright, can we go to the knees?
You're all done?
You wanna see this through
the mystical masterpiece?
Yeah.
Wow.
It looks amazing.
You've wasted all the work.
Take a picture!
This is called
"Shag Me My
Skin"
I got my chimney.
I got my
ring.
Oh shit!
The
Lord have 1 for Christmas.
Then send out.
That comes with some hurts.
music)
music and
connections
I like it.
The result.
(screaming)
Shit, get a load of this fucking guy.
How many years have you?
That was a fucking first.
When I hold on to listen,
I'm wearing the after brace,
which is like Elvis, he gets the full,
same experience as you once, all right?
Hello, hello.
Aye, aye.
Come on, come on over.
Yeah.
(laughing)
Aye, yes, yes, yes, that's me.
That's me, guilty as charged.
Oh, it looks like you got a fan.
This would be outfit, huh?
Yeah, did the circus come in town?
Oh, hey, buddy, watch it.
It's the real deal.
That's my fucking beard.
If Santa doesn't have a real beard,
he's not a real Santa Claus.
(laughing)
Hey, fella, what's in the bag?
Oh, it's yours, yours, hey.
This is like you're usually on the one
who's bringing the
best little sack of toys.
Hi.
(laughing)
Oh, that's good.
Okay, listen up.
All right, now look, I'm
starting to like this guy.
Really, I'm planning.
Put your little horn away, have a seat,
and stand on by and retreat.
(laughing)
Clowning, I'm starting to like you.
Here you go.
I hope I gave you this marshmallow.
It's perfect.
Thank you.
It's a decent quiet
around here, finally, huh?
You must be exhausted.
No, I feel...
What?
Thorel.
Look, then, they're gonna pretend
that I know what you're going through.
Because I don't, I can't
even begin to imagine it.
But I promise, it'll get better.
You remind me so much of Mom.
Before Dad died, she
was the sweetest person.
I talked about anything.
Yeah, she was.
Mouth like a truck driver, though.
She hurts so much.
She once called Sister Rosemary a C-U-N-T
in the sixth grade.
I don't know where she came from.
Nobody in our family talked like that.
I miss her.
I miss her so much.
I miss you.
I know.
I miss her too.
(laughing)
Hey, Santa, looks like
you got some competition.
It's clowny cars.
No, hey, you're a natural, you look good.
But I'll get him dirty,
and remember to give him back
if you don't want to get
on Santa's naughty list.
Why don't you tell Santa
what you want for Christmas,
little boy?
Better hygiene.
All right, come on, let's have a drink.
For everybody, okay, come on.
You got an ID?
Come on, he's obviously old enough.
All right, don't you think
I'm gonna lose my license
for this guy?
Don't bust the clown's balls.
This is normal to you?
Sorry about this, clowny.
There, see, he's got it.
Maurice Jackson?
And you're killing me,
can we just celebrate?
Come on.
Fuckin' it, it's Christmas.
All right, let's have a drink.
To my new friend, huh?
To Maurice Jackson.
These checks.
Cheers.
What the fuck is the matter with you?
What's your problem, pal?
That vice you were drinking,
he spit it back in his fucking face?
Hey man, that's wrong.
Look, you were just rude,
and he's in a bit of a room.
Let's go, clowny, get up.
No, I'm not,
I'm not.
Oh shit.
What the fuck are you doing?
I'm being honest.
Fuck you, children.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Hey, come here, get me out of here.
You fucking fucker.
Let me out of here.
I'll get you killed.
Hey, I'll come and kill you.
Fuck you.
Goddamn it.
Smoky did his best.
Son of a bitch.
This is my busy weekend.
I know.
Fuck if I hit you,
you're gonna be a fuck.
There's no fuck out of here.
What?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I got it.
Want me to call the cops?
I know what you call cops,
I want you to call a
fucking track leader.
Track leader?
Get a fucking--
I told you all along though.
You were fucking dead here.
You said fucking normal.
Sit down, sit down.
Fucking you told me.
Have a fucking drink.
Oh fuck.
(screaming)
Oh god, oh god no, oh god no no no no.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
sir, no, no, no, no, sir.
No, no, please, please, please.
Let me be the first to apologize
for whatever's happened here tonight.
I don't know what happened.
Take it, take it, take it, take it.
It's yours, you're the killing villain.
Here, take it all.
The only thing said,
nothing with the same business.
It's just me and you, brother.
It's just me and you,
with the same business.
We're making people happy.
(screaming)
Help me, help me, help me.
Thank you, thank you.
This isn't funny, it's not funny.
Come on, come on, come on.
I'm sorry, please.
Please help me, just please help me.
Help me, I'm sorry.
Let me come on.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Help, oh.
Oh, it looks good, Connie.
You look good.
Oh yeah, that's never looked better.
I'm not old now then.
You know, you're just here, boy, right?
So I can go.
Yeah.
Help, help me.
Help me.
Oh, Connie.
What the hell was that?
Oh God, Connie, Connie,
Connie, look at me.
I mean, I'm not really saying it, Connie.
Don't, don't, Connie.
I have a name.
I have a real, no, I have a real name.
My name is Charles Johnson Connie.
And I have a wife, I
have a wife and two kids.
I'm Connie, I'm Connie, I'm Connie.
Connie, I tell you, this and I have four
gorgeous grandchildren.
My name's, their names are fine.
Help me please.
(crowd cheering)
(groaning)
(screaming)
Oh my God.
(groaning)
(screaming)
So, how is she?
It's good as can be expected.
I think Gabby brought some
life back into her today, right?
It's nice to see her smile a little bit.
Oh my God, Gabby.
She follows Sienna
around like a brand new puppy.
It's concerning.
Now they're going
Christmas shopping tomorrow.
Just the tool?
Mm-hmm.
Sienna wants to pick
up a gift for Jonathan.
You really think that's a good idea?
Don't be fine.
Just, did you not see
what happened today?
What if that little
episode was just a microcosm
of what's to come?
What if that shit gets worse?
I'm not gonna abandon her.
She's healing, it's gonna take time.
She's taking her medication.
All I'm saying is let's
keep her calm, all right?
That's all I'm saying.
(crowd singing)
This way please, this way.
All right, as we look over here, ready?
Don't come past this
point, you're in trouble.
Thank you.
Next.
All right, buddy,
let's go for the camera.
You guys ready to meet Santa?
What are you gonna ask for?
Makeup? Yeah.
Are you holding up for makeup?
Okay, thank you.
Next.
Hey guys, you can call like this.
Hmm, not sure.
I don't think Jonathan is
really into black anymore.
Jonathan doesn't wear black?
Mr. Deathmetal?
I don't think he listens
to that anymore either.
Just face I guess.
All right, well then,
where's he right now?
I don't know.
All the clothes?
Really narrows it down.
Thanks, guys.
Okay, sweetie, you ready?
(laughing)
Okay, thank you.
Bye, Santa. Bye.
At least it's very little though.
Got a boy vibe.
Let's take a break.
Oh, sorry folks.
Santa's gotta go feed his reindeer.
You know, I'm not in charge here, so.
Are we gonna break too or?
Sure.
This one's nice.
Okay.
Is it your favorite?
Top three.
All right, well done.
You choose, you know
you're not better than me.
(upbeat music)
(crowd cheering)
What are you saying?
Nothing.
Come on, ready?
Let's get going.
You okay?
Yeah.
Look, you know my theory of
the subject hasn't changed.
You don't even know.
Because you know I'm right.
Santa's shaw is the prime suspect.
Stop, that is ludicrous.
We can just look at the facts.
Do you wanna just do that?
Facts, okay, she's
linked to every single victim.
She was at every crime scene,
a history of mental
illness in her family,
or a abusive father who
just so happened to be obsessed
with Art the Clown.
And there's nobody.
How about you show me
the dead clowns, Mom?
Dude, there's so many
holes in that story.
Like how do you not see that?
Jonathan Shaw hadn't
testified on a sister's behalf.
She'd probably be serving
a life sentence right now.
You shouldn't be saying that shit.
(dramatic music)
You look great.
Your scars are healed all next week.
Yeah, yours too.
Yeah, everything's so cool, apparently.
So why'd you wanna see me right now?
(audience laughing)
I missed you.
I mean, can't the sisters
see your little brother?
Actually, I was thinking,
why don't you come for
Aunt Justice tonight?
I mean, why wait till Christmas Eve?
You gotta be done with
classes by now, right?
I can't, I can't tonight.
Why not?
There's a party on
campus that was invited to.
Really?
That's good, not happy yet.
Jonathan Shaw spotted in public.
What is this, a Christmas miracle?
Dick, Santa, this is called my roommate.
Called--
Oh, wow, hey.
What's this?
I've heard a lot about you.
It's nice to finally meet you.
Well, you've gotta be cool.
Baby broke here and I
treat him like he's my own.
You treat him like shit?
What are you jokes?
Oh shit, let me get out of here.
Oh my God.
Oh.
Siena.
Hey, you're Siena Shaw.
I'm seriously so good at gambling.
I'm sitting here with you guys.
I was literally just
telling your little brother.
I'm sorry, I'm
probably being a little weird.
I'm just super stoked to see you.
Mia has been following
our story, very close.
I am a true crime enthusiast
and I've actually been
following your case in particular
for years on my podcast
and no rush or anything,
but I do know the five
year anniversary's coming up
and the fan base is rapid.
We would literally kill for anything.
I'm thinking, get ready, it's with me.
What I eat in a day, just
show us how you're coping.
What you do on a daily
basis, anything like that.
How I'm coping?
Yeah.
Well, I'm gonna now have a second
I've been in the
(mumbles)
for the past five years.
I see images of my
dead friends and relatives
on a daily basis, images
that wave me up screaming
in the middle of the night.
I have hideous scars all over my body
and every time I see
that, I might think of how
that sick fuck ruined our
lives is still out there
and you wanna know how I'm coping?
With everything?
You guys are all the same.
It reaches.
Siena.
Why can't you act like a
human being for one person?
Fucking check it!
Siena, what's wrong with you?
I saw him today.
Who?
When I met them all.
It's gotta be, how can you
be sure it was really him?
I'm not sure of anything anymore.
I don't know, it's
real, it's my fucking head.
What'd you see exactly?
He was dressed as Santa Claus.
Santa Claus.
Okay, I know, I know how that sounds.
Okay.
It was him, I can feel it.
I both know this isn't over.
You don't know that,
I mean, Jesus Christ,
he cut his fucking head off.
Come here.
Hey, what is this?
Jonathan, hey!
You weren't shutting me out!
I'm not shutting you out.
You don't believe me?
Why would he come back here?
Even if he was alive, which he isn't.
Wouldn't you want to
get as far away from here
as possible as far away from you?
Maybe it's me they wanted.
Is that what you said?
Boy genius.
Wait, Mr. Academic, now
you think you're too good
for your own...
I'm sorry.
At least I'm fucking trying.
I'm proud of you, Miss.
We need each other, okay?
I need you.
What we need to do is move on.
Let it go.
It's over.
We have to destroy the little girl
before it's too late, Sienna.
Destroy her because
she's inhuman and demon.
Still have her letters.
You wrote me almost every week
when I first went away, remember that?
I heard theories about
demonology, possession.
You became obsessed, but you went crazy.
You're right.
I'm not listening to this.
Don't listen to me.
Sometimes demons try to enter our world,
only they can't do it alone.
They have to choose a vessel.
Someone recently deceased who functions
as a bridge between
worlds, but not just anyone.
Someone sinister,
depraved, the worst kind of evil.
Like a serial killer.
If a demon enters
this world in the flesh,
a counterpart must be appointed
to stop it from becoming too powerful.
It's you, Sienna.
As long as you're
alive, you're vulnerable,
and they know it.
That's why daddy created the sword.
Whoever chose me was guiding him.
He was preparing me for this.
She's in Victoria Hayes
as a host now, isn't it?
That's why she disappeared that night.
What do you want to do?
Why don't we just up and leave town?
Call the cops?
Tell Aunt Jess and Uncle Craig?
No, they'll never
believe us, especially me.
I have to go back to the Terrifier.
Why?
It's still a bear there, isn't it?
And if I'm right,
it might be the only
thing that could stop them.
(eerie music)
He's not with you.
(singing in foreign language)
Sure, get back on your knees.
Wow, thanks, Aunt
(singing in foreign language)
What's going on here?
That's not Bill.
What?
That's not our Santa Claus.
(singing in foreign language)
Hey, stay out here.
Get down, let's go.
Let's go.
(singing in foreign language)
Who's this Santa?
He's scaring my kid.
Yeah, he's scaring me too.
What are you thinking of?
He can't be here.
I swear that's the goal.
Come on, let's do that.
Sir, what did I say?
I stole mine.
You must stay up for evil.
Get the fuck out of here.
Move him back.
Corey?
Corey, get back over here.
Back in line here, time for real Santa.
I don't know where to hide.
Corey.
so
um
[Music]
What's that? Jesus!
You scared me. What are you
doing? Stoop around like that.
Is it for me?
None of your business, nosy.
This isn't it?
No, it's not. Don't
even think about it, okay?
What happened to your hands?
Hands.
[Music]
I fell. Okay? I slipped onto my ice and
took a ridiculously nasty spill in front
of like 20 college students.
Is that what you want to hear?
I wish I saw that.
I think that's funny. Come here.
[Music]
Mmm, this thing smells amazing.
You're back late. How's your brother?
He's good. Yeah. He's going to a campus
Christmas party tonight.
Jonathan's going to a Christmas party?
Oh, nice to resocializing. Yeah.
God, these are so frigging cute, I guess.
Those are my favorite. Johnson?
Mmm. Thanks.
Oh, sorry. I forgot you
don't like cereal anymore.
Who does like cereal?
What?
S
I mean, I can understand tofu or lima
beans, but cereal's the best.
I know. Honey, chill. Yeah, I just try to
stay away from people with sugar.
I'm a little hotter than me.
Hops. Would you stay in the groceryers
and play some board games?
Mm-hmm. Let's go.
Yeah. I think we can do
Christmas tree trickles.
Eating Christmas tree trickles.
I'm going to move forward. I have a time.
Pictionary, guess who? Monopoly.
I like Monopoly. Thanks for everything.
I never told you I don't like cereal.
What?
How'd you know I don't like cereal?
Gabby?
Did you read my journal?
I'm sorry.
Please don't be mad at me.
Huh?
Where is it?
I put it back in your room.
How much of it did you read?
Tell me.
Olivette?
Jesus. Gabby, you...
You promised me.
I'm sorry. I want to
know what happened to you.
Is it true?
All that stuff about the
clown and Uncle Michael.
You saw him today, didn't you?
I told them all
that's why you freaked out.
Gabby, I'm sick.
I see things that aren't there,
and sometimes I write
about it in my journal
and talk about it with
people who can help me.
So you didn't really chop off the clown's
head with a magical sword?
Damn, that wasn't so cool.
Guys, you have to promise me
you're not going to tell anyone what you
read in my journal, okay?
Not your parents, not
your friends at school.
No one. Promise me?
I promise.
Mickey's over.
Let's play video games
so I can kick your ass.
Yo, shots, Cole.
You probably still passed out.
Look, I just want to call
and see if you're okay, man.
Yeah, give me a call
back whenever you get this,
but if you can't reach me,
I'll be at the beta bash, so...
Peace.
You don't think I was
that innocent before, do you?
Uh, yes. Yes, I do, actually.
Okay, I get it's like a
touchy subject, you know?
But come on, it didn't happen yesterday.
It happened five years ago.
Yeah, I don't think that's something you
ever really get over.
Well, she still didn't
even sound the way she did.
Besides, chalking it out
is good therapy, I suppose.
It's basically doing her a favor.
Wow. How so, what's that about?
Well, what about Jonathan?
You think he's still willing to do it?
I don't know, Mia.
Cole, I want that interview.
I mean, sitting across from someone who
actually encountered Mark the Clown,
the most famous serial police, Jack the
Ripper, it's a story.
I encountered that, um...
What, a good mile away? What did she say?
That Kim was on his butcher.
You know what I mean.
I want to know what it's like to be in a
prison that's that kind of evil.
What goes through your brain when he's
close enough to you that you feel his
breath on your body?
What does he smell like?
When you look into his eyes, what do you
see? Is there a soul or...
A place!
He sounds...
You sound like you want to fuck him.
I don't want to fuck him.
I mean, I don't know what you want with
him, but you said he
looks up to you, right?
Maybe you can give it some for me.
Mia.
Come on. Do it for me. Please.
I'll be nice. I promise.
I'll end in just 20 minutes. Tops.
I think it worked for your life.
Well, you were very persuasive.
I'll see you later.
Okay, so remind me how to play
this game. It's been a while.
Wait. We need more players.
Dad, come on.
Dad?
You're not supposed to be
close. Do calls for my mic.
You want to turn out my tears attack?
Oh, no.
Let me hear you,
please. Let me just get out.
He was dressed as Santa Claus and he was
handing out presents to kids.
Every little kid that was
there, I heard a commotion.
And I saw some caroling in the guy out.
And then bam! There was
an explosion right there.
Holy shit.
Oh, dear.
It's not safe. It's not safe.
It's not safe.
Santa, what are you talking about?
A mouse-crowding clown.
I saw him. I saw him today.
Listen to me. No, I saw him today.
Okay, I saw him.
And I was going to say the same thing
because I knew you
were going to believe me.
Okay.
And, um, I think he's
going to come for us.
No, no. He's going to come for us.
We have to get--as long as
we live here, we're in danger.
Okay, we're in danger. We're going to be
our way from here as possible.
It's a mouse-crowding clown, Santa.
No, it was him, okay? I saw him.
Listen to me.
Stop it. You're
scaring, dad. We stopped him.
Jonathan, Jonathan, we have to go.
You called Jonathan?
Jonathan, no, Jonathan.
We have to go. Jonathan, break down.
Yeah, we'll break.
Jonathan, dude, your sister
is freaking out over here, man.
She saw something on the news.
She's adamant about getting you over here
as soon as possible.
She thinks you're in danger.
I am. What did you see?
She saw the news,
man, about the explosion.
Look, I think a few
people killed him. Now she's--
Dude, it's bad. I need to--
Okay, Jonathan.
It's happening. It's happening.
Okay, tell it up. I'm
going to get you right now.
You're not safe. You're not safe.
Okay, I'll come over.
Did you get it?
You. I got it.
I gave her something to help her sleep.
Good.
You're right.
We'll talk about it when I get back.
Be careful.
Call me if anything.
Hey, sweetie.
You okay?
Where's Deanna?
She's sleeping.
She's going to go back to the hospital.
Is that she?
I don't know, baby.
I don't want her to.
But if she's not well, we got to do
what's best for her.
But if she's right, what if the Miles
County clown is back?
He's not. Gabs.
You're safe.
Deanna's just scared. Nothing's going to
happen to any of us.
Okay, just get some rest.
Jonathan and daddy will be back soon.
Okay.
I love you.
I do, Mom.
What's that?
[Crickets chirping]
[Screaming]
Go, Miles!
[Crickets chirping]
Go!
[Screaming]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Hey, Uncle Greg.
Jonathan, I'm here.
Where?
I don't see you.
I'm parked right where you
told me I'm in front of your door.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Jonathan, can you hear me?
I'll be right there.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I'm here.
Ta-da.
You're true.
I knew you would.
Yeah, I just, I didn't think it was
really ready, but you are.
I love her.
She's beautiful.
Is she an angel?
Not just an angel.
She's an angel warrior.
You see the fire sword?
It has special powers.
She can defeat any
bad guy with that sword.
And I can never hurt her.
Wow.
Can't you defeat Blastromant?
Oh, yeah.
Ten Blastromant.
So cool.
Well, I need to get the name of her.
I can name her?
Of course you can.
Is your character in it?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Thanks, Dad.
You are very welcome, sweetheart.
Okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS]
Dad?
Daddy?
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS]
What the?
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS] [BLASTROMANT SOUNDS] What's that?
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS]
See someone?
I need you to listen to me.
Don't forget to.
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS]
I am always with you.
We have to think about that.
Shh.
Just keep your voice down.
That one's the end of yours.
Oh, I don't give a
fucking she hears us or not.
As a matter of fact, you know what I
think we should do to Siena?
I think we should go upstairs
and smother her under sleep.
Then we'd be free.
Free from our bullshit.
Free.
Yes.
Free. Free. Free.
Free. Free. Free. Free.
Free.
[BLASTROMMANT SOUNDS]
[BLASTROMANT SOUNDS]
[screaming]
[screaming] [defeated noises]
Service
bitch Mavericks
[more Geez.
[ice clinking]
[vegetarian Ministry breathing]
[
investments [ sobs ]
[ fussing continues ]
[crying]
[crinkling]
Try it up on me.
Oh, it's very funny.
[crying]
If you sleep, I'm gonna
rip your fucking tongue out.
Where's my daughter?
Oh, what did you do to my daughter?
I thought I could get her out.
[crying]
Merry Christmas, Mommy.
Hi, Mommy.
[screaming]
We love you.
We miss you.
My daughter does not like your daughter.
She is.
I can't recognize her on fucking blood.
[screaming]
I gave you a present, Mommy.
And now I want you to give me one.
Fuck you!
[crying] [crying]
Mommy, Santa.
Kill the queen of summer.
You first.
No!
No! No!
[crying]
No!
[screaming] No!
[crying]
No, Santa.
I'm gonna take everything you have.
And then I'm gonna leave that pretty pink
flesh of yours and throw you from inside
out just like I did this, bitch.
But first, I have the best drink.
That's my cappy.
Oh, cappy!
[crying]
No, you don't!
[crying] [screaming] [crying]
[crying]
Where's my present?
Santa, come.
You can have me.
I'm very happy.
But, cappy, I'll fucking kill you!
Stop!
You cruel fuck!
You disobey me!
Leave her alone!
Stop!
[crying]
It's all your fault.
I told you I was a cappy.
Excuse me.
[crying]
Shut it down!
No! No! No!
You fucking thing!
No!
[crying]
Come on!
Everything you love is gone!
There is no hope!
Let's go!
So you can let me.
[crying]
Oh, you are strong, aren't you?
Now I know why they chose you.
You really love them, don't you?
She's right in the cappy.
You're all she's got left.
And you're the only
thing that's keeping her.
For letting me in.
[crying]
No! No! No!
You're a fucking dudger!
No!
I'm sorry you didn't open the present.
[crying]
That's not fair.
How much money is yours, sweetie?
[crying]
I said once more!
What is it about? With angels?
The angels, of course.
[crying]
[crying] You're after yourself.
You're getting done.
[crying]
Do you want to know the
cappy got me for Christmas?
Yes. Do you want to open yourself?
Yes.
I'm doing it.
[crying]
No! No! No!
Stop it!
You said you wanted to open it.
Stop it! Stop it!
Let her go!
[crying]
Open it!
Please!
[crying]
We're waiting!
I hope you like it.
[crying]
Best gift ever.
Let's have a taste.
[crying]
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Did you know I opened
it? I was new, remember?
Yeah.
[crying]
[crying] [crying] Oh, God!
C'mon fuckers!
(C
(screaming)
(panting)
Rachel, come in.
Come on.
(screaming)
Yes, you can't get me to tell you why.
Come on, baby, you're.
(screaming)
Gabby!
(crying)
(panting)
Don't get me.
(crying)
I'll find you.
Summer stars
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
I'm sorry, you're reading a book?
Just tell me to show up next night.
Oh, no, it's okay.
This book is actually a lot
creamier than I anticipated.
Are you?
Yeah.
How you doing?
I don't get into all that blood and more.
I'm more of a rom-com guy.
Frankenstein, that's
a good movie, classic.
(singing)
and h
uh
once
you