(MYSTICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(LENS CRANKS)
- (CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
- (UMBRELLA WHOOSHES)
Do you think we're close?
They're almost
impossible to find.
No one's ever
captured one alive.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
I agreed to provide security
for you
because I thought you were
close to finding the spider.
Well, it'll be worth the wait.
Dead specimens show that
the peptides
in the spider's venom, they...
Basically, they supercharge
their cellular structure.
That spider can give
superhuman strength and power,
like Las Arañas.
Las Arañas?
The, uh, mythical spider people
who run across the treetops
and punish evil men with
their black, poisoned touch?
I like to base my research
in science,
not legends, Mr. Sims.
- Those powers are wasted here.
- (RAIN PATTERING)
These little spiders
have the potential
to cure hundreds of diseases.
It could...
(GROANS)
- Are you okay?
- No.
She's trying her best
to keep me from working.
(SIGHS)
But I'm not gonna
let her do that.
Not when I'm this close.
(PANTING)
Perhaps you should rest.
(SIGHS) I don't have time.
Thank you.
For the umbrella.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
CONSTANCE: I found it.
I found the spider.
(MEN CHATTER EXCITEDLY)
CONSTANCE: (GASPING)
Oh, my God.
- Isn't she beautiful?
- MAN: Wow!
- Incredible, isn't it?
- (MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Something so small
yet have so much power.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (SHRIEKING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (MAN GROANS)
(GASPING)
What are you doing?
I don't...
I don't understand.
I've been searching
for that spider for years.
No, don't...
We could help so many people.
I'm not interested
in helping people.
No one helped me
when my family was starving.
My road was not
as clear as yours.
We didn't have the same choices.
You're making
the wrong decision.
- Give me the spider!
- No.
You're making
the wrong decision.
- Give it to me.
- No.
You can just walk away.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (EZEKIEL GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WEAKLY) No.
(RUSTLING)
(VOICES
WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (LOW HUMMING)
- (GROANING)
(GASPS)
(GASPING)
(LOW HUMMING)
(CONSTANCE GASPING)
(GASPS ECHOING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SIGHING)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
SANTIAGO: Her journey
will not be easy,
- but she is strong.
- (BABY COOING)
She will come back
when she needs answers.
And when she does...
(BABY CRYING)
I will be here for her.
(CONSTANCE STRAINING)
(BABY WAILING)
- (SIREN BLARING)
- Come on!
(HORN BLARING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- MAN: Whoa!
(HORN AND SIREN BLARING)
(MILES AWAY BY
YEAH YEAH YEAHS PLAYING)
- Move!
- All right! All right!
This is 2-10
with a 42-year-old female.
Code three.
Cassie, I lost the pulse.
I'm starting compressions now.
Ben, what are you even doing
back there?
Oh, you wanna come take over?
I can drive.
She's not going room temp
on my watch.
(SIREN BLARING)
- (HORNS HONKING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARING)
- CASSANDRA: Come on.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(MILES AWAY CONTINUES PLAYING)
How you doing back there?
You know, last time I was
in a vehicle driven like this,
I was being shot at.
I wouldn't want you
to be homesick for the Army.
Never thought I'd be this happy
to be back in Queens.
What, you've never
been shot at in Queens?
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(GASPS)
Shouldn't you be in school?
- (SIREN CHIRPS)
- (GIRLS LAUGH)
Who flips off an ambulance?
Jesus.
(SIREN BLARING)
Kids.
- (HORN BLARING)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- I'm gonna get roped in.
- You're not.
You're gonna be in
the backyard grilling with us.
Mm-mm. I know how
these things work, Ben.
Oh, do you? How do you know?
I bet you've never even been
to a baby shower.
Because, yeah, I'm careful
not to get roped in.
I'm glad I caught you
before you headed back out.
She's gonna be okay.
Who?
Your, uh, patient.
Her little boy
wanted to say thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
Um... You know what,
Mr. Ben Parker here
did all the work, so...
BEN: Just take it.
Take it.
- Just take it.
- (CHUCKLES)
- That's... I mean...
- (WHISPERING) Thank you.
- BEN: Thanks, buddy.
- Thank you.
NURSE:
I'll take you in to see her.
- Are you all immediate family?
- Oh, my God.
I'm her stepdaughter.
I think she might prefer...
Yeah, it's okay, Dad.
I'll see you guys
back at your apartment?
Okay.
Come on, buddy.
Let's go see Mommy.
BEN: Okay. This one is
for you. This is for me.
Thanks so much.
What am I supposed
to do with this?
Just put it in your pocket
and then throw it away
somewhere else.
Can't even fold it.
It's like cardboard.
Oh, come on.
We both hate family stuff.
I think I have plans
anyways, so...
BEN: Plans?
Since when do you have plans?
You're, like,
impossible to pin down.
Well, I like to keep
my options open.
You know, I might sleep in.
I might go to the museum.
I might walk the dog.
You don't have a dog.
I might adopt one.
Return the favor.
I suspect you were a bit more
of a handful than a puppy.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I was a model foster kid.
I peed outside and everything.
So I, um...
I kinda met someone.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
What's this one's name?
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Oh.
Serious.
She's a lucky lady, Ben.
Thank you.
(CASSANDRA CHUCKLES)
Oh.
"You have
a winning personality."
I guess I got yours by mistake.
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- You're an asshole.
Here.
Let's see what your future
holds for you.
What if I don't wanna know?
Well, it's just a cookie.
(COOKIE CRACKS)
CASSANDRA: "You will."
You will what?
- Apparently, I have no future.
- Cassie.
- Do you know what this means?
- What?
It means that their printer
is broken.
We can't eat here anymore.
(LAUGHS)
(SIREN CHIRPING IN DISTANCE)
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
ANYA: We'll have it
for you tomorrow.
My dad just needs
to pick up his paycheck.
(SIGHS) Well, let me come in
and talk to your dad.
I haven't seen him in a while.
- We can work something out.
- He's not home right now,
actually.
LANDLORD:
Look, I'll be back tomorrow.
But no more excuses.
I swear. We'll have it.
LANDLORD: (SIGHS) All right.
(PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DOOR OPENS)
(MEOWS)
Us strays
need to stick together.
Somebody's hungry.
(MEOWS)
(CLICKS)
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES)
Hope the spiders
were worth it, Mom.
(SIREN WAILING)
(SIRENS BLARING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You gotta get, like,
Jaws of Life for that.
MVA, three vehicles.
One vehicle flipped over
with entrapment.
DISPATCH: Copy that.
Sending backup to your location.
MAN: It won't open.
BEN: All right, sir.
We're gonna get you
out of there, okay?
Just don't move.
- Hi, sir.
- (MAN BREATHING HEAVILY)
Can you tell me your name?
(GROANING) Robert.
Robert, I'm Cassie.
I'm gonna
help you out today, okay?
You're gonna be all right.
All right,
I'm gonna cut your seatbelt.
And when I do, you're gonna fall
and my partner Ben
is gonna help you out
- on that side, okay?
- (CAR CREAKING)
- Three, two, one.
- (ROBERT GRUNTING)
- (ROBERT GRUNTS)
- BEN: All right, Robert.
We're gonna move on three.
- Okay? Here we go.
- ROBERT: Yeah.
- One, two, three.
- (GROANS IN PAIN)
BEN: Okay.
You're gonna be okay, sir.
Just try and lay still.
We're gonna get you checked...
- Hey! Cassie!
- Ben!
- Cassie!
- CASSANDRA: Ben!
(CRASHES, GLASS CRACKS)
(GASPS)
(TENSE AMBIENT MUSIC PLAYING)
(HEART THUMPING)
BEN: 79 over 55.
CASSANDRA:
Dial it back, I'm fine.
BEN: You need a real workup
at a real hospital.
No, you were right.
They're roping ya in.
LORNA: Games!
MARY: You guys are ice-cold.
- (BALLOON POPS)
- (WOMEN SHRIEK)
O'NEIL: (ECHOING) Cassie!
This place has always
been a death trap. (ECHOING)
SCROOGE: Are these the shadows
of things that must be
or are they only shadows
of things that might be?
EZEKIEL:
You can't save all three!
SANTIAGO: ...web to be
in more than one place
at the same time.
You are the only one
who can change the future.
EZEKIEL: (SHOUTS) No!
WOMAN: Cassie!
BEN: That's it, Cassie,
breathe!
Come on!
(COUGHING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
You're okay. You're okay.
Did I die?
Yeah. You were
down three minutes
- before I fished you out.
- (COUGHING)
- Three minutes?
- Yeah.
Welcome back
to the land of the living.
(CHUCKLES, COUGHING)
(SIGHS)
(SIREN BLARES, CHIRPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(PUMPING SPHYGMOMANOMETER)
79 over 55.
You need a real workup
at a real hospital
with a real doctor.
I don't need a doctor.
I trust you.
Ah, 80%. No, it's great.
Slightly above that
of a dead fish.
Ah.
All right. Well,
O2 is going up to 89.
Jump back in the water anytime.
(VELCRO RIPS OPEN)
(SIREN BLARES, CHIRPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
79 over 55.
You need a real workup
at a real hospital
with a real doctor.
(SCOFFS)
Seriously, Ben, dial it back.
I'm fine.
Wait, wait, wait. I need
to get your oxygen levels.
Again?
What are you talking about?
My O2 is 89.
No, it's...
Oh, you're right.
(CHUCKLES)
Are you okay?
What the hell happened
down there?
I'm fine.
I just wanna go home
and watch Idol.
(VELCRO RIPS OPEN)
(OPERA MUSIC PLAYING
IN DISTANCE)
(OPERA MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WOMAN SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(OPERA MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING
IN DISTANCE)
(CHUCKLES)
Wow.
- Great apartment.
- (CHUCKLES)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPING)
(GASPING INTENSIFIES)
EZEKIEL: Where's my spider?
They took my spider.
(GROANS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
EZEKIEL: Who are you?
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- (GROANS)
(SWISHES, THUDS)
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMING) No!
(SCREAM ECHOES)
(GASPING)
Mm, bad dream?
It's not a dream.
I'm gonna be murdered one day.
Oh, wow, that's a buzzkill.
The same three faces.
Every night, the same vision.
It's a curse.
But we all die someday.
Nothing we can
really do to stop that.
But if you saw
who was going to murder you...
you'd try to stop them.
Okay...
You have no idea
of the torment and torture
of dying over and over again.
And I can't escape it.
So I'm not gonna
sit back and let it happen.
I will find them
and kill them first.
So you know who did it...
I mean, will do it?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
It's always those three faces.
Can you imagine
how frustrating it's been?
Trying to identify someone
I've only seen in a vision?
Mm-hmm. (CHUCKLES)
But as the years pass,
there have been
technological advances.
New ways to find people,
if you know their faces.
The kind of technology
I've heard
the National Security Agency
has been pursuing.
(SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINISTER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WOMAN GROANING)
WOMAN: What are you doing?
(GROANS)
How are you poisoning me?
What's your password?
I can't tell you. Oh, please!
Is "please" your password?
Tell me quickly
before the paralysis
reaches your lips
and I'll stop the poison.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Q-9-2-0...
B-3-7-5.
(STAMMERING)
Oh, God.
(GROANING)
Believe me, it's a good thing
you had no idea
today was the day
you were going to die.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(LIVELY CHATTER)
- Hey, Cassie.
- Hey.
BEN: I'm serious. You should
open, like, a barbecue.
- Hey.
- Hey, man.
BEN: You know
what you're doing.
MAN 1: I saw him leave.
MAN 2: Yeah, I...
- Hey!
- Cassie!
- Hi.
Hey, the next time
you wanna go swimmin',
maybe you should stick
to Astoria Park.
Oh, that's really funny.
- You're such a funny guy.
- (CHUCKLING)
Are you pressing the burgers?
I'm releasin' the fat.
That's called flavor, man.
Plus, it's, like,
really flammable.
- Here you go.
- Oh, thanks.
You don't think that maybe
in light of recent events
I could use a beer?
Well, as you know,
the protocol is
no booze within 24 hours
of your death. So...
- Is that protocol?
- Yeah, it's protocol.
That's boring.
I feel like there's more
of a story there.
No, there's...
You guys, we've seen this
a hundred times.
It was cardiac arrest.
When your heart starts
back up again, you're fine.
Really?
Dead, huh?
Did you see a white light or...
(FLAME WHOOSHING)
Well, actually, I saw Jersey,
- so you tell me.
- Oh, come on, you saw Jer...
- Hey.
- CASSANDRA: Hey.
She hit me with a Jersey joke.
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHS) Has he been
pressin' the burgers again?
Yeah, they're ruined now.
For you, sir.
Oh, now they're really ruined.
- Oh, okay.
- (LAUGHTER)
- We're ready to start.
- CASSANDRA: What?
What?
They're starting,
so you should get in there.
No, you were right,
they're roping ya in.
- Yeah. Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
Have fun.
- (LIVELY CHATTER)
- MARY: ...for you, okay.
Oh, my God.
- Hi. (LAUGHING)
- Look at you. Hi. (LAUGHING)
Okay. This is crazy.
CHLOE: Well, I couldn't
decide, so I got two.
MARY: Yeah, that's like...
- Hey. Hi.
- Hi.
Um, Cassie Webb.
Um, thanks for having me.
You're Ben's partner.
I'm his sister-in-law, Mary.
- Nice to meet you.
- Mm-hmm.
Ben is so excited
about being an uncle.
I don't know
what we'd do without him.
- Especially with Richard away.
- SUSAN: Again.
Where is it this time?
He's in (HESITATES) Mumbai...
Shanghai...
I can't keep track. (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Never stops
leaping around in there.
And always hungry.
Um, does it have a name?
The...
(LAUGHS)
We're saving that
for one of the games.
- Games?
- Games!
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
(NERVOUSLY) Games!
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
MARY: Okay.
"My mother always cut
the crusts off my sandwiches."
ALL: Oh.
Chloe, is that you?
Yes.
(LAUGHTER)
My mom said the crusts
would make my hair go curly.
It was years
before I figured that one out.
(LAUGHTER)
Okay.
Whose is this?
BEN: Don't give him any money.
Oh, it's mine.
You must have at least
one fond memory of your mother.
Um, well, my mother actually
died, uh, in childbirth.
Well, but it wasn't that bad.
It wasn't like...
I mean, obviously,
it was bad, you know.
(LAUGHS) She died.
Um, but, um,
I grew up totally healthy.
Death in childbirth
is super rare.
I mean, she chose to be, like,
way deep in the Amazon
for the last month
of her pregnancy
hundreds of miles away
from any
medical facilities, so...
Okay, so let's, um,
let's move on to the next game.
(AWKWARD LAUGHTER)
SUSAN: Guess the name
of Mary's baby.
- (ALL EXCLAIM)
- LORNA: Oh, yes!
Okay, I'll kick things off.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(CLICKING TONGUE)
- Sam.
- Nope.
Steven.
- He's not named Steven.
- Shoot.
- WOMAN: Baby sausage?
- You guys are ice-cold.
- (BALLOON POPS)
- (WOMEN SHRIEK)
(LAUGHTER)
- (SIGHS)
- Richard Junior?
Richard wishes.
(LAUGHTER)
O'NEIL: Get your hamburger.
Get your hamburger.
Cassie,
what's your guess?
Um...
Mm. Hmm...
BEN: Do that thing
where you throw it up
and catch it on the...
(CELL PHONES BEEPING)
- Oh, my God.
- Ben?
- BEN: Look at that.
- The name is...
- (BALLOON POPS)
- (WOMEN SHRIEK)
(LAUGHTER)
WOMAN: Baby sausage?
Richard Junior?
- Richard wishes.
- (LAUGHTER)
O'NEIL: Get your hamburger.
Get your hamburger.
Cassie, what's your guess?
O'NEIL: Put five dollars down,
let's go.
Wait. We just did this.
BEN: Do that thing
where you throw it up
and catch it on the...
- (EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CELL PHONES BEEPING)
What, seriously,
is this part of the game?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Uh, sorry.
They're calling everyone in.
Fire down at the docks.
So...
You okay?
Yeah. I just got
a weird sense of déjà vu.
- FIREFIGHTER: I got you, man.
- (MAN COUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
FIREFIGHTER 2: Come on,
come on. This way.
Turn around, come on!
(SIREN BLARING)
FIREFIGHTER 3: Come on.
Go. Go. Go.
(BUSY CHATTER)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, looks like
a fractured left radius.
Otherwise stable.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Check his abdomen.
(SIREN BLARING)
Okay, and internal injuries.
Good catch.
Let's go. Come on.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
O'NEIL: Hey, I need
to get my guys in there.
FIREFIGHTER 4:
No, it's not safe.
The structure's unstable.
O'NEIL:
Hey, the people are trapped.
We need to treat 'em
before we move them.
The place is packed
with explosives.
Industrial grade fireworks.
(GASPS)
It could blow up any minute.
(HEART THUMPING)
O'NEIL: Cassie!
MAN: Blow up any minute.
(HEART THUMPING SLOWLY)
FIREFIGHTER 4: It's not safe.
O'NEIL: This place has
always been a death trap.
Come on, come on. This way.
Turn around, come on!
BEN: Otherwise stable.
CASSANDRA: Wait, wait, wait,
wait. Check his abdomen.
And internal injuries.
Good catch.
Let's go. Come on.
(SIREN BLARING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
I gotta get my guys in there.
FIREFIGHTER 4:
The structure's unstable.
Hey, the people are trapped.
FIREFIGHTER 4: Place is packed
with explosives.
Industrial grade fireworks.
O'NEIL: This place has
always been a death trap.
Cassie!
Cassie! Cassie.
I need you at the triage.
CASSANDRA: Sir, you're okay.
You're okay.
He's stable.
Ready to transport.
PARAMEDIC: Copy that.
You're gonna be okay.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Wait. O'Neil!
Hey, what is it? I gotta roll.
Will you let me drive?
What are you talking about?
(HESITATES) I don't know.
I just have a weird feeling.
Cassie, I need you over here.
CASSANDRA:
Will you just let me drive?
Look, you had
a bad experience on the job.
I don't think
that's what's happening.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Don't let it
mess with your head.
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- (GLASS BREAKING)
- (GASPS)
- BEN: Cassie, come on!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (SIREN BLARING)
- (SIGHS)
O'NEIL: (ON RADIO)
This is O'Neil.
Clear of dock side.
- Headed back...
- (CRASHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SLOW, DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
O'Neil, come on.
(GRUNTING)
Come on. O'Neil.
Come on!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Wake up!
O'Neil, come on.
O'NEIL: Did you see
a white light or...
CASSANDRA: O'Neil, come on.
O'NEIL: Cassie! Cassie!
(SOBBING)
Come on. Come back.
Come on, come on. (SOBBING)
- Ben, help me.
- Cassie, Cassie, it's okay.
It's all right. It's okay.
It's okay. Okay?
There's nothing you could
have done. Okay?
(GASPING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOBBING)
(MUSIC FADES)
So, was it worth the trouble?
AMARIA: The scale
of the NSA surveillance
is unprecedented.
They can access everything.
There's...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
OVER MONITORS)
There's nowhere to hide.
That's the idea.
The potential is infinite.
It's...
It's intoxicating.
But in the wrong hands, I mean,
people can be tracked
wherever they go.
It's gonna change everything.
As long as it has the ability
to find those women now
before they get their powers.
This is what they look like
in your visions
as well as you can recollect.
EZEKIEL: Their faces have been
taunting me for years.
AMARIA: We don't know exactly
when your vision takes place,
so I'm giving us a 10-year range
just to be safe.
Here's what they should
look like now.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
They're younger
than I thought. I...
I didn't know
we'd be targeting teenagers.
They're teenagers now,
but in the future
they have powers,
and they will try to destroy me.
I came from nothing,
less than nothing.
I will not give up
everything I've built
and have my life cut short.
Well, if they ride
public transportation,
go to a museum,
get money from an ATM,
wherever they are
in the world...
Find them.
I pay you a fortune.
Yeah, I'll find them.
DOCTOR: Still no blurriness.
No double vision.
No discoloration at all.
Your eyesight is good,
and all your other vitals
check out.
Um, but what about the visions?
(CHUCKLES) How am I
seeing that stuff?
Mm, sometimes when
we experience trauma,
it can have a lasting effect.
CASSANDRA: This isn't trauma.
I knew he was gonna die.
I saw it.
Cassie, I have
all your reports here
from your other consultations.
Your head CT was normal.
Your MRI was clear.
The scan showed
no abnormalities.
I know that it sounds crazy,
I know,
but I don't understand
what's happening.
I will be recommending
that you take a week off.
Get some rest.
Watch old movies.
If you still have concerns,
I can run some bloods
or refer you to psych.
But I'm sure everything
will be back to normal
before you know it.
(SIGHS)
SCROOGE: (OVER TV)
I am in the presence
of the Spirit of Christmas
Yet-to-Come.
(SLOW, DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
And you're going
to show me shadows of things
that have not yet happened
but will happen.
Spirit of the Future,
I fear you more
than any other specter
I've seen.
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
- But even in my fear,
I must tell you, I am too old.
I cannot change.
Whose funeral
were they talking about?
(TELEPHONE BEEPS)
BEN: Hey, Cass,
it's me again. Uh, Ben.
I know you're there.
Just pick up.
Okay, well, uh, O'Neil's funeral
starts at 2:00
in Poughkeepsie.
Everyone's going.
I know it's the last place
you wanna be,
but it would help Susan
if you came.
It might help you too.
Look, if you leave now,
you can still make it.
Cassie?
Cass?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(MICROWAVE BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
SCROOGE: (OVER TV) Before
I draw nearer to that stone,
answer me one question.
Are these the shadows
of things that must be
or are they only shadows
of things that might be?
I hate to break it
to you, Scrooge,
but you can't change anything.
(CLICKS)
- (GROANS)
- (BOWL SHATTERS)
- (THUDS)
- (GASPS)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MICROWAVE BEEPING)
SCROOGE: (OVER TV)
Are these the shadows
of things that must be?
Or are they only shadows
of things that might be?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
This isn't
gonna change anything.
(GASPING)
(COOING)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Guess you didn't die after all.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SLOW, DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: (OVER PA)
Please keep all personal
belongings with you
throughout your trip.
MATTIE:
Come on, guys. This way.
GIRL: Come on,
let's go down the rail.
MATTIE: Yeah, awesome.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
Can I have one
to Poughkeepsie, please?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON MONITORS)
Anya Corazón is now moving
onto the platform.
She's on her own.
Julia Cornwall is on
the concourse, also alone.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
And Martha Franklin.
Shit. Um...
What are the odds
of them all being
in the same place
at the same time?
EZEKIEL: (OVER RADIO)
It's not a coincidence.
AMARIA: There must be
something that connects them.
Or...
something that will.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER:
Please keep all belongings
with you at all times.
If you see something suspicious,
find a member of the MTA staff.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
MALE ANNOUNCER:
Train to New Haven
now ready to leave on Track 25.
All aboard.
(TRAIN SCREECHING)
(TRAIN CLATTERING)
New York City
is a whole new level
of crazy these days.
(TRAIN SCREECHING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER PA)
(GASPS, CHOKING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
MALE ANNOUNCER:
Train to New Haven
now ready to leave on Track 25.
All aboard.
(TRAIN SCREECHING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
- (SHRIEKS)
- (NECK SNAPS)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
MALE ANNOUNCER:
Train to New Haven
now ready to leave on Track 25.
All aboard.
This is the train
to Mount Vernon, right?
(SCREAMING ECHOES)
(GASPING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(WHISPERING) Oh, my God.
MALE ANNOUNCER:
Train to New Haven
now ready to leave on Track 25.
- All aboard.
- Is this real?
Are you okay, dear?
Oh, God,
I think I'm going crazy.
New York City
is a whole new level
of crazy these days.
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
This is the train
to Mount Vernon, right?
I hope not.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER:
The Mount Vernon train
will be leaving in
three minutes, Track 8.
POLICEMAN: Hey, get back here!
Yeah, they're coming your way.
(TRAIN SCREECHING)
- (TRAIN CLATTERING)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HEART THUMPING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER PA)
(TRAIN CLATTERS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Get... Get up!
Get off! Get off!
- Get up!
- Me?
Go! Get off! You're gonna die
if you stay here!
- Get up!
- JULIA: We are?
ANYA: Are you threatening us?
This is an emergency situation.
I need you
to follow my instructions.
Get off the train. Come on.
My mom told me never
to talk to strangers. So...
- (GRUNTS) Get up!
- Hey, give me that back!
Hey, give me that back!
I am so pressing charges.
(GRUNTS)
Okay, knock yourself out.
Give me
my freakin' skateboard back.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Let's go.
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
- CASSANDRA: What? No.
Okay, never mind. Um...
Give me
my freaking skateboard back.
CASSANDRA: Okay...
Um, what exactly
is this emergency?
This woman's
trying to abduct us!
What?
No, that's not... That's...
Shh. That's... (SIGHS)
That's your emergency. That.
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
MATTIE: Is anybody else
seeing this?
That man is trying to kill you.
- And how do you...
- Why?
I don't know. Come on.
JULIA: We don't have tickets
for this train.
That's your biggest concern?
MALE ANNOUNCER: Please stand
clear of closing doors.
This train is departing.
Please be kind
and remove your bags
from the empty seats
and place them
in the luggage rack above.
CASSANDRA: Come on.
(TRAIN CLATTERING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay.
Hey, am I on the right train?
I don't know, man.
MALE ANNOUNCER:
Please have all tickets ready.
This is Metro North to North...
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- Hey, what are you doing?
No! Help...
- (CRASHES)
- (GROANS)
(SCUTTLING)
(GASPING)
Holy shit.
Come on.
(DOOR BUZZES)
Go.
Run!
(ALL PANTING)
(TRAIN CLATTERING)
There's an emergency exit
to the street that way.
Go.
Hey, help. Over here.
I've never been
so happy to see cops.
You guys need
to call for backup.
That will not be necessary
as long as you cooperate.
Wait. What?
No, it's not me. Ow.
ANYA:
No. You don't understand.
- We're being attacked.
- Don't worry. Calm down.
You're safe. (GROANS)
- (SHRIEKING)
- (GROANS)
CASSANDRA: Run! Go!
Run!
- (GROANS)
- (GIRLS SHRIEKING)
(OFFICER YELPS)
Run! Run!
Go! Go! Go!
(INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
CHATTER)
(OFFICERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY)
(GROANS)
(HORNS BLARING)
Come on.
- Get in.
- ANYA: What?
Here you go.
- Thank you so much.
- CASSANDRA: Get in!
- Come on, come on, come on.
- ANYA: Move. Slide over.
I appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- Oh, wow, thank... Hey!
MATTIE: That guy was nuts.
Do you guys think
he killed those cops?
Uh, he could climb on walls
and dodge bullets.
- How is that even possible?
- It's not.
There's not enough
frictional force
in the bare human foot
to overcome gravity
and keep him stuck to the wall
much less the ceiling.
What the hell is going on?
(EXHALES)
Yeah, well, science
didn't seem to stop him,
so what good is it?
- What good is science?
- (SIGHS) Okay, enough.
- Please, don't fight.
- CASSANDRA: Enough.
No, I was just telling them...
Enough! Your voices
are, like, drilling
in the center of my skull
and I need to think.
(PANTING)
I'm Cassie. Okay?
What are your names?
I'm Julia Cornwall.
My dad lives here in New York,
and my mom
lives back in L.A., but...
We don't need
your whole life story.
I'm Anya Corazón.
Mattie Franklin.
- Thank you for protecting us.
- CASSANDRA: No, no, no.
(LAUGHS)
I'm not... That's not...
That's not
what's happening here.
I'm not protecting you.
I am, I am...
Your parents can handle this.
My parents
are on a business trip.
Uh, yeah. My parents
are out of town too.
JULIA: Uh, my dad is
busy working, so...
Oh, my God.
I was gonna
go stay with some friends.
Well,
where do your friends live?
I'll drop you off first.
REPORTER: (ON RADIO) ...in
finding a person of interest
seen in the attack
on multiple NYPD officers
at Grand Central Terminal
this afternoon.
That's great. Good. (CHUCKLES)
I hope they find his crazy ass.
That was insane.
They better lock him up.
Right? I mean... (LAUGHS)
REPORTER:
She is also the same person
police are seeking to question
in the possible abduction
- of the three teenage girls.
- She?
Eyewitnesses have identified
the woman in her early 30s.
The public has been asked for
any information and to keep
- an eye out for these girls.
- Uh... What?
(HESITATES) What? That's...
But you guys...
What about them?
And he was crawling
on the ceiling.
What about that guy?
I mean, you saw. I...
No one saw ceiling guy.
Everyone thinks
you're the kidnapper.
Yeah, because you told them
I was.
I didn't know
what was happening.
Okay, guys.
My uncle, Jonah,
can totally help us.
- I'm gonna call him.
- You have a phone?
You know they can
track those nowadays, right?
- Hey! You can't do that.
- She's right.
It's okay. Daddy will buy you
a new one.
What is your problem?
- What do you mean?
- Please.
- I'm just trying to help.
- Okay.
Anyone who wants to leave
can leave right now.
- Okay.
- Wait.
Sorry. No,
you can't actually leave
because you guys
are the only ones
that know
what actually happened.
(SIGHS)
Okay, well, this is what
we're gonna do, okay?
We're just gonna, like,
lay low for a little bit.
And, um...
I'll figure out
how to get out of this.
(SIGHS)
(MUTTERING)
This is still not a kidnapping.
Okay?
Feels like a kidnapping.
(SIRENS AND HORNS BLARING)
EZEKIEL: How'd they get away?
It's like they knew
I was coming.
AMARIA: (OVER RADIO)
No hits at the train station,
bus depot,
or any of the bridges.
Wherever they went,
there aren't any cameras.
EZEKIEL: The police don't have
this technology.
You have access
to every camera in the city.
We should be ahead of them.
I went to a lot of trouble
to steal you these tools.
Use them better.
I've always wanted
to be a Girl Scout.
ANYA: Of course you did.
Anybody else starving?
ANYA: All I have is gum.
Here. I found this
in the glove compartment.
Wait. That bag's
already been opened.
We don't know how long
it's been in there.
Okay, I hope you're good
at, um, catching squirrels.
Okay, so what's the deal
with ceiling guy?
I told you, I don't know.
I've never seen him before.
Then how did you know
he was coming?
Oh, my God.
I'm kind of more interested
in why he's trying to kill us.
I don't know.
Crazy shit's been happening,
and I don't know why.
Stop asking me. Okay?
Wait. You're the paramedic.
You saved my stepmother,
then you were
super awkward about it.
That does sound like me.
Wait. I recognize you too.
What?
Yeah. You live in my building.
You leave your junk mail
in the lobby
and then everybody else
has to clean it up for you.
Okay. Well, there should be
a recycling bin there.
You don't think this is weird?
That we both know you?
It's honestly, like,
the least weird thing
that's happened all day.
What?
Total stranger.
No.
You flipped me off.
That's not really
narrowing it down much.
JULIA: You guys,
this is so freaky.
Who are you? What is going on?
I can see the future.
Kind of.
(SNICKERING)
I mean...
- Oh.
- What the hell?
See?
She didn't see that coming.
- (SNICKERS)
- It doesn't work like that.
You guys, just give her
a chance, please.
ANYA: Wait. When you were
looking into the future
did you see us
in the middle of nowhere
eating glove-compartment jerky?
Okay, look. Believe me
or don't. I don't care.
I didn't ask
to be doing this with you.
And I didn't ask for this
to happen to me, either.
Also, I'm pretty sure
I saved all of your lives.
So, you're welcome.
How does it work?
(SIGHS)
It just happens.
Can you do it now?
I can't control it.
You know the other guy can
walk on the ceiling, right?
Uh, no, he can't.
He was using his hands.
Why are you like this?
I'm just saying
it was more of a crawl.
It was like a spider...
person.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm gonna be back
in a few hours.
(HESITATES)
Where are you going?
I need to check some things out
about all of this.
You can't just leave us here.
We'll be okay, Julia.
- We don't need a babysitter.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
Just three teenagers
alone in the woods.
Definitely not the opening
of a horror film.
You are way safer out here.
Just, you know, be, um,
like a Girl Scout girl.
Be that. Just be that.
Can you bring us
some sandwiches?
Cassie.
Can we trust you?
Three hours. Okay?
Just stay here.
And don't do anything dumb.
- (CAR DOOR OPENS)
- (CASSIE SIGHS)
Seriously.
Don't do dumb things.
- She was talking to you.
- (CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Okay, well,
you're just a bitch, so...
(ENGINE STARTS)
I know tae kwon do.
ANYA: You?
Yeah, I had
a few rough years in school
when my parents were divorcing.
So I wanted to feel like
I could fight back
if I needed to.
- (GRUNTS)
- Uh... (CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
That's what I thought.
(TRAIN CLATTERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLATTERS)
(CLICKS)
(MEOWS)
(SIGHS) One second, cat.
(SIGHS) Come on.
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
"Research on Amazonian spiders,
"peptides, more peptides."
Come on, where is it?
Ah. Spider people.
"Las Arañas."
Have you ever heard
of Las Arañas?
(MEOWS)
Me neither.
"According to local folklore,
"they possess powers
derived from spider venom
"and are incredibly fast,
incredibly strong
"and they can climb
like spiders."
Just like ceiling guy.
How would you know
if you could climb a wall
if you've never tried?
(MEOWS)
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
Okay, let's not mention that
to anybody.
(MEOWS)
(SIGHS)
"Las Arañas are said
to possess a sixth sense
"as if they had the ability
to glimpse the future."
(MUSIC BUILDS)
Oh, my God.
(MUSIC FADES)
Hey, who's got the jerky?
ANYA: You ate it all.
I had, like, three pieces.
- Out of five.
- You counted?
You also ate all mine.
- What's this?
- Stop.
Stop. Just...
Jeez.
Okay, forget jerky.
Did you guys see that diner
like a half-mile down the road?
Let's just go there
and get real food.
- Cassie told us to stay here.
- Come on, Julia.
She bailed on us.
We don't have any money, genius.
Well, I have money, so...
You have money
so we should do what you want?
You got something to say?
You know,
I bet your dad is a senator
and your mom
sits on the board at the Met.
And you summer in the Hamptons
next to Martha Stewart.
So sad about Martha Stewart.
My parents are in Beijing
where my dad is raking in
a ton of money
for making plastics
that pollute the ocean,
and my mom is spending it
all on hideous art.
So...
I talk to them on Mondays.
So who do you live with?
The housekeeper.
Well, on the upside,
no curfew. (CHUCKLES)
I bet you have
your own room at least.
I live with my dad
and his wife and their kid.
- What about your mom?
- Uh, she's...
not really around.
She bailed on you?
Right. So, diner?
We spend some of Mattie's
daddy's pollution money?
Yay.
I'm going to order
everything on the menu.
Julia, you in?
Hey.
We have to take care
of ourselves.
Yeah.
You're right.
Let's go do this.
She's kind of cute
when she's mad.
I heard that.
You are making
the right decision, Julia.
You will not like me
when I'm hangry.
Who says we like you now?
JULIA: God! I knew
we shouldn't have done this.
(SCANDALOUS
BY MIS-TEEQ PLAYING)
MATTIE: Shit.
Do you think there's ticks?
ANYA: Can we walk
- a little faster, please?
- MATTIE: Julia.
You said this was a shortcut.
JULIA: Are we lost?
ANYA: Do you know
where you're going?
MATTIE: You know
ANYA: Yeah. Actually, I do.
- (BRANCH WHIPS)
- Ow! Shit!
Okay. Don't talk to anybody
except to order.
We're in the middle of nowhere.
No one's gonna track us
down here.
Just don't make eye contact.
(GASPS)
I hope they have cherry pie.
(SCANDALOUS PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
(LIVELY CHATTER)
Let's sit at the bar.
There you go.
Here.
Should we make a game plan?
Eat first, strategize later.
WAITRESS: Okay. Here we go.
(BITCH BY MEREDITH BROOKS
PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS)
(MOUTHFUL) Mm. Keep it coming.
Let's just eat quickly
and then get out of here.
Absolutely, great idea.
Uh, right after cherry pie.
No. No cherry pie.
Julia, tell me you agree
that we should get dessert.
Yeah, whatever you guys
are arguing about... (LAUGHS)
I'm sure you're both
making really good points.
BOY: Yo, she's looking at you.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
We should go over there
and talk to them.
Really?
No. (HESITATES) We...
Should we? We can't.
Come on. You know you want to.
No.
MATTIE:
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
ANYA: This is not a good idea.
- JULIA: What're you doing?
- Yeah, what are you doing?
MATTIE: Just hold on a second.
JULIA: What is this?
MATTIE: It's just
a little confidence boost.
This...
This isn't really my style.
So what? You look cute.
Come on.
This is not a good idea.
Seriously, guys.
Okay.
MATTIE: Hi. Hey, guys.
- (BOYS GREETING)
- I'm Mattie. This is Julia.
- Can we sit?
- BOY 1: Yeah, of course.
We've been saving
the seats for you.
MATTIE: (GIGGLES) Awesome.
BOY 2: Hey, what's up?
How you doing?
Nice to meet you, too.
DISPATCH: (ON CALL) Thank you
for your information.
Can you just confirm
your location?
4 Star Diner.
Davis Road, Route 206.
- Hey.
- Church Hill.
Possible sighting
in Church Hill, New Jersey.
EZEKIEL: Connect me with
Church Hill police dispatch.
Yeah. Patching you in now.
(CLANKS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE DIALING)
2-2-3 dispatch.
On scene at 4 Star Diner.
Route 206 at Davis Road.
DISPATCH: Go ahead, 2-2-3.
No need to send backup.
(SIGHS)
These aren't
our missing persons.
(ENGINE STARTS, REVVING)
Code four. Repeat.
These are not
our missing persons.
- (ENGINE REVVING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
Girls!
(BIRD WAILS)
(OWL HOOTING)
Oh, God damn it.
(BIRD WAILING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Girls!
(TOXIC BY BRITNEY SPEARS
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(GROANS)
ANYA: Let's go. Let's go!
MATTIE: Don't even pretend
that you're cooler than Britney.
I know you know the words.
- JULIA: Come on, get up here.
- (BOYS CHEERING)
So much
for not attracting attention.
(TOXIC CONTINUES
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
ANYA: Can you...
JULIA: (LAUGHING)
What are you doing?
- What are you...
- ANYA: What is that?
(LAUGHS) We have to go.
(GASPING) I'm so sorry.
Get down!
ANYA:
This isn't what you think.
CASSANDRA: Get your stuff.
MATTIE: You left us.
I'm so sorry.
(GASPS) Julia!
- Julia!
- (JULIA GASPS)
(GROANS)
- CASSANDRA: Julia, get back!
- (SHRIEKS)
- (BONES BREAKING)
- (ALL GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
- (GIRLS SCREAMING)
- (OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Come on!
- ANYA: Stop! Mattie!
- (GASPS)
- ANYA: (CRYING) No.
- (CHOKING)
(SHRIEKS)
(CHOKING)
(TOXIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(SHRIEKS, GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(BIRD WAILING)
(INSECTS TRILLING)
(TOXIC BY BRITNEY SPEARS
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
MALE DJ: (ON RADIO) This track
is going to be huge.
Are you in the zone?
This is Britney Spears.
Let's try that again.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
- I love this song.
- (LAUGHTER)
(TOXIC CONTINUES
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
ANYA: Guys.
Okay, okay, I'm sorry.
I have to dance.
- Come on, Julia.
- (CHUCKLES) Mattie, no!
Great. Okay.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(RADIO STATIC)
All right, come on.
(TOXIC CONTINUES
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(BOYS EXCLAIMING)
ANYA: Guys.
JULIA: Seriously, dude.
- (HORN HONKING)
- Come on.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORN BLARING)
(BOYS LAUGHING)
ANYA: Come on. Let's go.
Don't even pretend that
you're cooler than Britney.
I know you know the words.
- Come on, get up here.
- (BOYS CHEERING)
Hey!
Come on.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORN BLARING)
BOYS: (SINGING) You're toxic
- I'm slippin' under
- Hey!
(ALL HUMMING)
(LAUGHTER)
Guys. Guys, guys.
We have to go, we have to...
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
- (GROANS)
- (GIRLS SCREAMING)
Girls, get in! Get in! Get in!
Leave everything. Run!
ANYA: Come on,
let's go. Let's go!
JULIA: Mattie, come on! Hurry!
- Get in!
- JULIA: I'm so sorry, Cassie.
(GROANING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (PANTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
God!
So much
for not needing a babysitter.
Do you guys think of anybody
but yourselves?
You're so impulsive
and entitled,
and you don't listen!
- We didn't mean to...
- Whatever!
Don't even say anything!
God! (SIGHS)
Your futures were almost...
so different. (SIGHS)
You're lucky I saw them.
- I'm so sorry.
- Yes.
You should be so sorry.
All of you should be sorry.
God!
(GASPS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Tsk.
(GROANS IN PAIN)
Amaria, where did they go?
AMARIA: (ON RADIO)
I'm running checks now.
I don't understand
how they're doing this.
I've got a match on the woman
who's with them.
I'm not interested in her.
Focus on finding those girls.
- Cassandra Webb.
- (SYSTEM TRILLS)
Daughter of Constance Webb, deceased.
Did you say, "Webb"?
Uh, yeah. Do you know her?
That's not possible.
(SIGHS)
Come on.
He's not gonna stop
until he kills us, is he?
I don't know what he wants.
I don't know anything.
But you can see the future.
Can't you stop him
with your visions?
I don't know
how to control them.
It's useless.
Well, we're alive.
Maybe that's a plus.
- (CASSANDRA INHALES SHARPLY)
- Is your hand okay?
It's fine.
(DOOR BEEPS)
(CASSANDRA SIGHS)
First thing in the morning,
I'm taking you all home.
Your parents can deal with this.
- No, they can't.
- (SIGHS)
My mom's in a psych ward.
She, um...
She didn't really cope well
after my dad left,
and so,
I got sent to live with him
and his new family
and I don't think
that they want me there.
I wondered
if they missed me if...
if I ran away.
Hmm. So you did.
MATTIE: My parents
aren't around either.
I think they resent how having
a kid messed up their lives.
I don't think they're gonna
fly back from China
to deal with this.
(LAUGHS) And I really
don't wanna find out, so...
I'm on my own.
Well, fine.
Then you guys can just...
- go to the police.
- ANYA: No.
My dad got deported
six months ago.
I came home from school,
and he was gone.
What about your mom?
My mom died when I was five.
It's just me and my dad.
Except he never told me
he didn't have his papers.
So, I've just
been living by myself
at our apartment since then.
You're on your own?
I don't need anyone else
to look out for me.
And I don't have
a curfew, either.
(CHUCKLES)
So, I can't go to the police.
Okay?
Until I'm 18, I can't exist.
And there's no way
I'm getting deported too.
Or going into the foster system.
(SIGHS) Well,
foster system isn't always
that terrible.
Things didn't turn out
so bad for me.
Right.
Cassie, please help us.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
(KEYS JINGLE)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
(WINCES)
(SIGHS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
No one survives once enough
poison enters their system.
You won't be so lucky next time.
(ECHOING)
Why are you doing this?
I need to stop them
from killing me.
They're not killers.
They're just teenagers.
(ECHOING) In the future,
they become much more.
They will destroy me
and everything I've built.
Those girls cannot exist.
(ECHOING)
How come you get to decide?
Because I'm the one
with the powers.
If you knew what I knew,
you'd do the same thing.
Would I?
If I knew the price to pay
was the lives of three girls?
The only thing I know
is that, in the future,
they also have powers.
(ECHOING)
The girls? The girls
have powers in the future?
Did you think you could
beat me with your mind?
Your mother underestimated me.
The power of the spider...
Don't make the same mistake.
Tell me where they are!
They don't mean anything to you.
You could just walk away.
(GASPING)
(TENSE AMBIENT MUSIC PLAYING)
(RADIO CLICKS)
(I THINK WE'RE ALONE NOW BY
TIFFANY PLAYING ON RADIO)
(MATTIE MOANS)
(JULIA GROANS)
(VOLUME INCREASES)
What is this?
(MUSIC STOPS)
Rise and shine.
Okay, so this guy's hands
somehow release
an acute neurotoxin,
and it is painful.
I was lucky.
The longer he holds on to you,
the more poison
gets into your system.
Then what happens?
Then your heart stops.
But you can offset
cardiac arrest with CPR.
So you interlock your hands
like this.
You lock your elbows,
and then you place
the heel of your hand
right on the sternum. Okay?
And then you pump.
And you wanna go,
like, two inches down.
And you wanna keep a rhythm
like a heartbeat. Okay?
You ready?
Okay, begin compressions.
Go. Good.
Okay. And when do I stop?
You don't stop.
If you stop, they die.
- Oh.
- And if you get tired,
then you need somebody
to take over.
- I'm getting kinda tired.
- Okay.
- Anya, get ready to take over.
- Mm-hmm.
But you have to pick up
the exact same rhythm.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- Ready?
- Yep.
And go.
Great. Nice, Mattie.
Not cool.
Julia, you wanna take over?
Okay.
Get ready.
Okay. One, two, three.
Perfect.
Nice job, Anya.
I've never said this before
in my entire life,
but you're a good teacher.
Well, I've been learning
some things, too.
About my mom.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
Wait, so you do know this guy.
(SIGHS) My mom did. I think.
That's her.
She's really pretty.
So, this is because of you?
All I know is that
she was researching spiders.
In her notebook,
there's some stuff
about a local tribe in Peru
that can do,
like, crazy stuff.
What kind of crazy stuff?
(SIGHS) Climb like spiders.
So, is he one of them?
I need more information.
You're leaving.
(SIGHS)
I have to go and figure out
what is going on.
How?
You have to go to Peru.
CASSANDRA:
I'll be gone a week.
I don't wanna leave them,
but he's out there
looking for them
and they're relying on me,
and I don't know
how else to protect them.
Okay, uh, look,
I'm staying with Mary
for a few weeks
while Richard's out of town.
He won't find them there.
But, Cassie, I...
I can't pretend to understand
what's going on here.
Just be careful, okay?
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Thank you, Ben.
You didn't ask for any of this.
- Okay, well, neither did you.
- (SIGHS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(INTRIGUING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ANIMALS CHITTERING)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MYSTICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(RUSTLING)
(THUDS)
You have come back
looking for answers.
Back?
I promised your mother
I would be here.
CASSANDRA: My mom thought
Las Arañas were a myth.
SANTIAGO: What do you think?
I think she was crazy
for coming here alone.
Mm, she came here
hoping to extract
healing properties
from the spiders.
She thought
she was being protected.
CASSANDRA: By Ezekiel Sims?
His motives were selfish.
He used your mom to find us.
But, because he stole the spider
he was cursed.
And he's been trying to outrun
his destiny ever since.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
This is where my mom died?
And where you were born.
(CASSANDRA SIGHS)
I don't understand
why she risked my life
to come here.
To see the future clearly,
you have to heal
the wounds of your past.
That sounds like literally
every therapy session
I've ever avoided.
You have to go back
to your beginning
and keep going past that.
There are powers
you don't even know
you're capable of.
Your thread did not start
when you were born.
Do you trust me?
Not really sure at this point
I have a choice.
(GASPS)
EZEKIEL: (ECHOING)
You could just walk away.
SANTIAGO: Your thread did not
start when you were born.
CONSTANCE: They're almost
impossible to find.
(GROANS)
She really is trying her best
to keep me from working.
Not when I'm this close.
But I'm not gonna
let her do that.
Why did you hate me so much?
CONSTANCE: Thank you.
For the umbrella.
- EZEKIEL: Give it to me.
- (CONSTANCE WHIMPERING)
CONSTANCE: I found it.
I found the spider.
Incredible, isn't it?
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GROANS)
- (CONSTANCE SHRIEKS)
Give it to me.
- No, please.
- Give it to me.
You're making
the wrong decision.
- You could just walk away.
- You're making the wrong...
- (GUNSHOT)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
- (CONSTANCE GROANING)
(RUSTLING)
(GROANS)
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm s...
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
SANTIAGO:
Las Arañas could not stand by.
We tried to save you both.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
SANTIAGO: Her journey
will not be easy,
but she is strong.
(BABY COOING)
(CONSTANCE BREATHING HEAVILY)
DOCTOR:
Your test results came back.
I'm sorry to tell you
that your baby
has myasthenia gravis.
It's a genetic
neuromuscular disorder.
But I don't have
a neuromuscular disorder.
Life expectancy varies.
- Do you need a tissue?
- (SIGHS)
No. No. I need a cure.
I'm afraid there is no cure.
Uh, single target
nucleotide intervention.
It's, um, it's experimental,
but there are some
promising leads in the Amazon.
That's why you went there?
For me?
I have to advise you against
traveling in your condition.
I'm sorry, what are you
offering besides tissues?
I know this is hard to accept.
No, no, I am...
I'm unwilling to accept
a diagnosis of helplessness.
And I'm not gonna
teach my daughter to either.
(SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOBBING)
You did it.
I never knew I was sick.
The spider venom
did have healing properties.
I'm so sorry I spent so long
being mad at you. (SOBBING)
(BOTH GASPING)
(MUSIC BUILDS)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(MUSIC STOPS)
I always thought my mom
didn't care about me.
Sometimes you must
sacrifice yourself
for those you love.
I was there.
I was in the room...
I was in the room with her.
How did you do that?
You did that.
Now you're starting to see
what you're capable of.
You came here to learn
the truth about your past.
But you will leave ready
to embrace your future.
(SIGHS)
Seeing into the future
is no match for Ezekiel.
I need to stop him
before he kills those girls.
But I can't do what he can do.
I can't do the leapy, crawly,
like, death poison.
You didn't get the gift
of the greater physical strength
or the ability
to release poison,
but seeing into the future
is only the start.
Your mind
has infinite potential.
If you master your power,
you can use the web
to be in more than one place
at the same time.
You are the only one
who can change the future.
And when you take on
the responsibility,
great power will come.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIRENS BLARING)
Every day that goes by,
my appointment with death
gets closer.
And you still
have found nothing?
How can she have kept
three teenagers
hidden for a week?
I'm running checks
every three minutes,
scanning CCTV camera.
I have hacked police
and emergency services
frequencies.
I have eyes
on all of their houses,
including friends and family.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Still nothing.
Do you understand?
Huh?
Those girls cannot exist.
They will try to destroy me,
as I will you
if you don't find them.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
She can't hide them forever.
(SHRIEKING)
Okay, it's still pretty quiet
out there. Uh...
- What'd I miss?
- ANYA: Ben said words.
- MATTIE: Oh, boring.
- Okay, let's try and remember
- to pick up after ourselves.
- Nice nails.
- Okay, guys?
- Thank you.
- Hey!
- I mean, this is really...
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Rude!
- MARY: Guys?
- All right, throwing popcorn
- is super fun.
- I cannot wait for that.
- But I also think...
- Guys, either I peed myself
or my water broke.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Ew!
Well, honestly,
you probably peed yourself
because that isn't
supposed to happen yet.
Richard's not here,
and the baby isn't due
for four weeks.
I don't think the baby
got the memo, Ben. (GROANS)
- Okay.
- Okay. Okay. Uh...
Looks like we may have to wait
a little while for the...
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
...ambulance.
The baby is not waiting.
(STRAINING) He's coming now.
Now. (CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, like, here?
In the dining room?
If Ben doesn't get me
to the hospital, then yes.
Okay. Uh...
(GROANS)
Uh, get in the car.
(DOG BARKS DISTANTLY)
Keep your head down.
(MARY GROANING IN PAIN)
JULIA: It's gonna be okay.
MARY: Okay. Um...
Okay, okay.
- (MARY GROANING)
- BEN: Everyone okay?
Okay, seat belts, everybody.
- Seriously?
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- JULIA: Yeah.
- Let's go.
Uh, never mind.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MARY GROANING)
MARY: (HESITATES)
All right, let's step on it.
(GRUNTS IN PAIN)
- (TRUCK HORN BLARING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(TRUCK BEEPING)
(SYSTEM TRILLING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
I might have something.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SYSTEM TRILLS)
I've intercepted a call
to the hospital.
St. Timothy's.
Track the route.
AMARIA: Tracking.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
MARY: The baby is not waiting.
...doesn't get me
to the hospital, then...
MATTIE: No!
Get out, get out, get out!
ANYA: Go, go, go!
JULIA: No, no!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Shit!
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(AMBULANCE SIREN BLARING)
CASSANDRA: Sorry, guys.
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
- (DOORBELL RINGS)
FEMALE PARAMEDIC: Hey!
Thank you.
(TIRES SCREECH)
So, the last one was
three minutes and 24 seconds
after the previous one.
Uh, uh...
So that means
the time between contractions
is reducing at a rate of...
21.6 seconds.
- Oh, that's pretty fast.
- (MARY GROANS IN PAIN)
You better hurry up
'cause I'm not sticking around
- if it gets gross.
- Okay.
AMARIA: (ON RADIO)
He's heading southwest
on Vernon Avenue.
EZEKIEL: I'll cut them off
at the Second Avenue
intersection.
- (HORN BLARING)
- MATTIE: Drive faster.
Let's go. Let's go, please.
(GRUNTS)
(SIREN BLARING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORNS BLARING)
EZEKIEL:
Hack into traffic control.
Turn the lights green.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Amaria, now.
AMARIA: Turning all
traffic lights to green.
(GROANS)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORNS BLARING)
MATTIE:
Why is no one stopping? Hey!
MARY: Ben, watch out!
- What's happening?
- ANYA: They're not stopping.
BEN: Whoa, whoa!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- MARY: Ben!
- (ALL EXCLAIM)
(HORNS HONKING)
Everyone okay?
JULIA: Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- MARY: Yeah.
I'm fine.
Um...
(HESITATES) What is that?
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, my God, it's him.
Guys.
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(THUDS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
ANYA: Ben, go, go!
BEN: Everybody,
get out right now!
- (BOMB WHINES)
- JULIA: Go, go, go!
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- (GROANING)
- (BOMB TICKING)
- (GROANS)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TICKING, BEEPS)
(GIRLS SHRIEK)
JULIA: Cassie!
Get out. Go on.
Get in the ambulance. Go.
It's not over. Go.
Ben, I need you to get Mary
as far away from us as possible.
Okay? Ezekiel,
he won't care about you now.
BEN: Well, what about you?
I liked it better
when you didn't make plans.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
You're showing off.
Not yet.
Uh, I think we lost him.
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (THUDS)
- (HORN BLARING)
Get in the back
and charge the AED.
- For what?
- Just do it. Go.
Okay, press "charge."
Am I having a heart attack?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I think I'm having
a heart attack.
MATTIE: You're not gonna have
MAN: Hey! Hey!
Okay, get ready.
Get it close to the ceiling.
Nobody touch the sides
or anything.
- Ready?
- Okay. Yep, yep.
- Wait. Wait.
- (DEVICE POWERING UP)
Now!
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- (GROANS)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (GIRLS GROAN)
Sorry.
JULIA: You okay?
ANYA: Yeah.
- JULIA: You okay?
- You okay?
- (GIRLS CHUCKLE NERVOUSLY)
- (PANTING)
- Okay.
- (ANYA LAUGHING)
Now you're showing off.
(SIGHS) Maybe a little.
(GIRLS LAUGH)
(SIREN BLARING)
(ENGINE SPLUTTERING)
(ENGINE HISSING)
(BEEPING)
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(SIGHS)
(ECHOING) Now what?
EZEKIEL:
Those girls cannot exist.
JULIA: ...doesn't look safe!
CASSANDRA: It's a deathtrap.
SANTIAGO: Infinite potential.
O'NEIL: This place has always
been a death trap.
FIREFIGHTER:
...packed with explosives.
CASSANDRA: Get down!
Go! Run!
- (JULIA SHOUTS)
- CASSANDRA: Jump!
Come on, get in the helicopter.
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
I have a code 30. PD-36-307.
Requesting airlift support.
Dockside, Queens.
- DISPATCH: Copy that.
- (CASSANDRA BREATHES DEEPLY)
Okay.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
It's gonna get a little crazy.
It's already crazy.
You didn't bail on us.
Whatever happens, I promise
I'm going to protect you guys.
We'll protect each other.
We're in this together.
Right?
Yeah. (PANTING)
Okay. We are still
not doing a high five.
I know. It's not cool.
Let's go. Out the back.
- What?
- CASSANDRA: Go, go, go.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
JULIA: This doesn't look safe.
Well, it's full of explosives
and it's structurally unsound.
That doesn't sound safe.
It's a death trap. (PANTING)
And that's a good thing?
As long as we're not the ones
who get trapped.
No matter what happens,
we need to work together, okay?
JULIA: We're listening
this time, Cassie.
Yeah, and we won't be impulsive.
Are we ready?
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
We have to get to the roof.
He's gonna be here any minute.
Here. Take these.
Put them in as many crates
as you can.
Okay?
- You two, go that way.
- (PIN CLATTERS)
We need to slow him down.
JULIA: Mattie, this way.
CASSANDRA: You come with me.
- Come on.
- (FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
MATTIE: (WHISPERING)
I got this one.
- Come on, Julia. Let's go.
- (GASPING)
(SIZZLING)
(GASPS)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
CASSANDRA: Anya, go.
Go.
(FIREWORKS WHISTLING,
EXPLODING)
- (EXPLOSION)
- (GROANS)
Go straight ahead.
When I say "now," get down.
ANYA: What do you mean?
It's a dead end.
Now!
(WHOOSHING)
ANYA: Whoa, whoa!
CASSANDRA: Go! Run!
ANYA:
Now you're really showing off.
Come on, upstairs.
(ALL PANTING)
(THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
JULIA: I knew it.
I knew she had a plan.
MATTIE: Hey!
ANYA: Hey!
JULIA: Hey!
ANYA: We're here!
CASSANDRA: Down here!
ANYA: Here!
MATTIE: Hey! Here!
PILOT: (OVER PA) Make your way
to the south side.
Come on.
(EXPLOSION)
- Wait. Get down!
- (MATTIE GRUNTS)
(GIRLS GASPING)
ANYA: Let's go.
He said south side.
We can go this way.
- (WHOOSHING)
- Anya, stop!
- (CLANKING)
- (GIRLS YELPING)
(PANTING)
- (CLANKING)
- (GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
MATTIE: Let's go!
ANYA: Mattie!
Whoa!
(WHOOSHING)
(CLANKING)
We need to go this way.
Come on, Anya. Get down!
Go to the ladder. Let's go.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Come on, come on!
(GRUNTING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
SANTIAGO: Use the web.
(CRACKLING)
JULIA: (SCREAMS) Cassie!
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
CASSANDRA:
Get to the helicopter.
- ANYA: Hey!
- Wait! Girls! Get down!
(EXPLOSION)
PILOT: It's not safe to land.
You'll have to get higher.
Guys, this way.
We can get to the chopper
from up there.
Anya, jump.
Jump now! Julia, get back!
(EXPLOSION)
(SCREAMS)
Julia, get down!
(EXPLOSIONS)
(SCREAMS)
Oh, God!
EZEKIEL:
You should have walked away!
(CASSANDRA GROANS)
You can't protect them.
Cassie!
(GROANING)
Over here, asshole.
(GRUNTS)
Mattie!
- (METAL CREAKING)
- (GROANS)
- (CRASHES)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
ANYA: Don't hurt her!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Anya!
(STRAINING)
JULIA: Cassie!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(ANYA AND JULIA SCREAMING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(STRAINING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You can't save all three.
SANTIAGO: And when you take on
the responsibility,
great power will come.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
CASSANDRA: (ECHOING)
Julia, I got you.
Come on.
Mattie. You're gonna be okay.
Anya. Anya, give me your hand.
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
(CRACKLING)
(METAL CREAKING)
You still can't beat me
with your mind.
(GROANS)
What makes you so sure?
(CLANKING)
Come on. Come on, come on.
You're just like your mother.
(CHUCKLES) Yes, I am.
(GRUNTS, PANTING)
- (CLANKS)
- (GROANS)
(CRACKLING)
- (CLANKING)
- (GROANING)
(METAL CREAKING)
You've been trying
to change your future.
But the girls
were never your future.
I was.
(SCREAMING, GROANS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING) No!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(CRACKLING)
(EXCLAIMING)
- (METAL CREAKING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(CLANKING)
No. (SCREAMS) Cassie!
- (GASPS)
- (SCREAMS)
(SLOW, DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(HEART THUMPING)
JULIA: She's not breathing.
- Her heart's not beating.
- ANYA: We know what to do.
Beginning compressions.
MATTIE:
Interlock your fingers.
Come back, Cassie.
Come on, Cassie, come on!
(ANYA GRUNTING)
Keep going. We don't stop.
ANYA: Come on, Cassie.
I'm getting a little tired.
Okay, okay. I'm right here.
ANYA: Cassie, wake up! Please.
- JULIA: Cassie!
- Come back, Cassie.
ANYA: We're here, Cassie.
We're not leaving you.
Cassie, you got this.
Please. I need you. Please.
(GASPS, COUGHING)
Oh, my God!
- (GIRLS GASPING)
- Cassie.
(COUGHING)
- It's okay.
- It's okay. It's okay, Cassie.
Oh, my God. We did it.
(GIRLS PANTING)
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLES) We did it.
(EXHILARATING MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WAILING)
Hey.
Hello.
Oh, he's perfect.
- He is.
- (COOING)
- He's perfect.
- BEN: Yeah.
(BEEPING)
We're still here, Cassie.
Yeah. We're not leaving you.
I wouldn't be here
if it weren't
for the three of you.
Right back at ya.
Ben said to tell you that
the baby is doing really well.
And he's loving being an uncle.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
All the fun and none
of the responsibility.
That's what he thinks.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Are you all immediate family?
CASSANDRA: Yes.
They're all mine.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
Can we get you anything?
No.
I have everything
I need right here.
(GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (GIRLS LAUGHING)
- ANYA: No.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
You left your junk mail
downstairs again.
And we got takeout.
But we didn't know...
CASSANDRA: Kung Pao chicken
is perfect.
How'd you know?
Bless you, Anya.
What?
(SNEEZES)
Thank you.
Mattie!
What? I told you I'm starving.
And I told you guys
that you wouldn't...
BOTH: ...wouldn't like you
if you were hangry.
Well, you wouldn't, so...
How's your eyesight?
I can see better
than I ever have.
Oh, yeah?
Can you see us in the future?
CASSANDRA: Yes.
I can see you.
(HEROIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Standing up
for what you believe.
(GRUNTING)
- (WOMAN SCREAMING)
- MAN: Let go!
Just give me the bag, lady!
- (SHOUTS, GRUNTS)
- CASSANDRA: Never giving up.
(GROANING)
Discovering you were always
more powerful than you thought.
Nothing I didn't already know.
I don't know about you two,
but that totally
makes sense to me.
What? I'm serious.
Wow.
(MATTIE LAUGHS)
What? I'm being serious.
(LIVELY CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
Oh, wow. Okay.
Wow. I was trying to have
a nice bonding moment.
JULIA: Hey! No, wait. I don't
want to miss the whole...
ANYA: And now
you're gonna get the...
- (LIVELY CHATTER CONTINUES)
- (HEROIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
CASSANDRA:
Whatever the future holds...
we'll be ready.
And you know the best thing
about the future?
It hasn't happened yet.
(MUSIC FADES)
(DREAMS BY
THE CRANBERRIES PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(FINAL CONFRONTATION PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES)