I got a dirty mind
I got filthy ways
I'm tryna bathe my ape in your milky way
I'm a legend
I'm irreverent
I'll be reverend
I'll be so faaaaa-ar up
We don't give a fuuuh-uh-uck
Welcome to the danger zone
Step into the fantasy
You are not invited to the other side of sanity
They callin' me an alien
A big headed astronaut
Maybe it's because
Your boy Yeezy get ass a lot
You're so hypnotizing
Could you be the devil?
Could you be an angel?
Your touch magnetizing
Feels like I'm floating
Leaves my body glowing
They say be afraid
You're not like the others
Futuristic lover
Different DNA
They don't understand you
Your from a whole 'nother world
A different dimension
You open my eyes
And I'm ready to go
Lead me into the light
Kiss me  Ki-ki-kiss me
Infect me with your love and
Fill me with your poison
Take me  Ta-ta-take me
Wanna be a victim
Ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien
Your touch so foreign
It's supernatural
Extraterrestrial
Your so supersonic
Wanna feel your powers
Stun me with your lasers
Your kiss is cosmic
Every move is magic
Your from a whole other world
A different dimension
You open my eyes
And I'm ready to go
Lead me into the light
Kiss me  Ki-ki-kiss me
Infect me with your love and
Fill me with your poison
Take me  Ta-ta-take me
Wanna be a victim
Ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien
Your touch so foreign
It's supernatural
Extraterrestrial
There is this transcendental
On another level
Boy, you're my lucky star
I wanna walk on your wave length
And be there when you vibrate
For you I risk it all ......... All
I know a bar out in Mars
Where they driving spaceships instead of cars
Cop a Prada spacesuit about the stars
Getting stupid ass straight out the jar
Pockets on Shrek
Rockets on deck
Tell me what's next, alien sex?
I'mma disrobe you
Than I'mma probe you
See I abducted you
So I tell ya what to do
Kiss me  Ki-ki-kiss me
Infect me with your love and
Fill me with your poison
Take me  Ta-ta-take me
Wanna be a victim
Ready for abduction
Boy, you're an alien
Your touch so foreign
It's supernatural
Extraterrestrial
Boy, you're an alien
Your touch so foreign
It's supernatural
Extraterrestrial
...........................santanu...........................