~ Rihanna ~
•• Cheers (Drink To That) ••
CROWD: Rihanna, Rihanna, Rihanna.....
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
- (FIREWORKS BLOWS)
- (CROWD WHOOPING)
(RIHANNA LAUGHING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SEA WATER SPLASHING)
Yeah yeah, yeah yeah, yeah yeah
Cheers to the freaking weekend
I drink to that, yeah yeah
Oh let the Jameson sink in
Don’t let the bastards get you down
Turn it around with another round
There’s a party at the bar everybody
put your glasses up and I drink to that
I drink to that
Life’s too short to be
sitting around miserable
People gonna talk whether
you doing bad or good
Yeah
Got a drink on my mind
and my mind on my money
Yeah
Looking so bomb,
gonna find me a honey
Got my Ray-Bans on and
I’m feeling hella cool tonight
Yeah
Everybody’s vibing so
don’t nobody start a fight
Yeah-ah-ah-ah
Cheers to the freaking weekend
I drink to that, yeah yeah
Oh let the Jameson sink in
Don’t let the bastards get you down
Turn it around with another round
There’s a party at the bar everybody
put your glasses up and I drink to that
I drink to that
Bout to hop on the bar,
put it all on my card tonight
Might be mad in the morning
but you know we goin' hard tonight
It's getting coyote ugly up in here, no tyra
It's only up from here,
no downward spiral
Got my Ray-Bans on and
I'm feelin' hella cool tonight
Everybody's vibin' so
don't nobody start a fight
Cheers to the freakin' weekend
I drink to that, yeah yeah
Oh let the jameson sink in
Don't let the bastards get ya down
Turn it around with another round
There's a party at the bar everybody
putcha glasses up and I drink to that
I drink to that
CROWD: Cheers to the freakin' weekend
I drink to that, yeah yeah
CROWD: Oh let the jameson sink in
RIHANNA: I drink to that, yeah yeah
Don't let the bastards get ya down
Turn it around with another round
There's a party at the bar everybody
putcha glasses up and I drink to that
I drink to that
And I drink to that
- (RIHANNA SHOUTING)
- MAN: Hi guys,...
- (RIHANNA TALKING)
- (MAN LAUGHING)
IMPROVED BY: Fidel33