There is a creature alive today,
who has survived millions
of years of evolution
without change, without passion,
and without logic.
It lives to kill.
A mindless eating machine.
It will attack and devour...
“anything-
It is as if God created the Devil
and gave him jaws.
This is Universal's
extraordinary motion picture version
of Peter Benchley's best-selling novel:
Jaws.
I just found out
that a girl got killed here last week.
And you knew it.
You knew there was a shark out there.
You knew it was dangerous.
But you let people go swimming anyway.
Did you see that?
Everybody out!
It's all psychological.
You yell, "Barracuda!" and
everybody says, "Huh? What?"
You yell, "Shark!"
We've got a panic on our
hands on the Fourth of July.
Is it true that most people get attacked
by sharks in three feet of water
about 10 feet from the beach?
Yeah.
What we are dealing with here
is a perfect engine, an eating machine.
We have to close the beach
and hire someone to kill the shark!
Bad fish.
But I'll catch him and kill him.
Did you hear your father?
Out of the water now!
This shark, swallow you whole.
You're going to need a bigger boat.
That's a 20-footer.
Twenty-five.
Three tons of him.
He's coming straight for
us. Don't screw it up now.
Don't wait for me.
Now!
Show.
Watch the keel!
Give him room.
I can't, it's trying to run!
Cut it quick.
I can't hold it!
Hurry!
We're breaking up!
Everybody out of the water.
None of man's fantasies of evil
can compare with the reality of Jaws.
See it before you go swimming.