(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(BALL THWACKS)
DON: Beautiful.
Focus more on the arm whip
than wrist snap, okay?
It'll give you more velocity.
I had a long talk
with Mom this morning.
She said your bad dreams
are getting worse.
She also said
there was something
you needed to tell me.
Remember... Remember that day
you let me ride my bike
to practice?
You rode through
the storm drain, didn't you?
By the old mine.
Why? Did something happen?
No. Nothing happened, Dad.
I just freaked myself out a bit.
That's all.
Is that why you
started carrying around
Bunny Bear again?
Before you say no,
Mom thinks
one way of tackling this
is for you to let go
of some of the things
you needed
when you were little.
I agree.
But we also agree
that when that happens,
it's entirely up to you.
Let me toss the gear
in the shed,
and then we can
go grab some pizza.
(CRACKLING)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Dad?
(SOFT HISSING)
(LOUD CLANGING)
Dad?
Dad, are you in there?
(MAN COUGHING)
(MAN COUGHS WEAKLY)
-(DON GROANING)
-Dad?
Dad, what's happening?
-(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-Dad!
-(WEAKLY) Run!
-(ZIPPER CLACKING)
-(SCREAMS)
-No!
(BONES CRACKING)
-(BAGMAN GROWLS)
-(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(SCREAMING)
-(ZIPPER CLACKING)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Deep in the green wood
Animals play ♪
♪ Hoppin' and jumpin'
The day away ♪
(FLUTE PLAYING)
♪ Follow the animals
In their game ♪
♪ Here we go now
Let's do the same ♪
♪ Hop, hop, hop like a bunny ♪
Five more minutes. Okay, dude?
KARINA: I thought we said
no more Bunny Hop.
(PATRICK CHUCKLES)
It's better than
Little Baby Bum.
(KISSES, CHUCKLES)
Hey.
Hey, babe. You look awful.
You look like a waffle.
(PATRICK CHUCKLES)
Yeah, well,
I didn't sleep for shit.
I thought you said you were
gonna stop working so late.
It wasn't that.
There were deer or something
-in the backyard again.
-Hmm.
What time is it?
10:17.
Why?
Oh, I don't know.
My sister?
Liam and the girls?
11:00 a.m. brunch?
-(PATRICK SIGHS)
-Family brunch.
Okay. I am going to shower.
-Come on. (GRUNTS)
-(JAKE EXCLAIMS)
-(PATRICK BLOWS RASPBERRY)
-(GIGGLING)
ANNA: You're a zombie.
You're a zombie.
I'm gonna... Come.
I'll get you!
You're gonna
give him nightmares.
You're a zombie!
Please, he loves it.
-Don't you, ti cheri?
-(GIGGLING)
Yes, let Auntie eat you!
(JAKE GIGGLING)
Was there a blackout
last night?
Uh, no,
not that I know of. Why?
Clocks are all out of whack,
and the fridge is defrosted.
ARLENE: Oh!
Oh, wow.
Yeah, the place
looks amazing, Karina.
Thank you, Arlene.
Yeah, it's getting there.
Yeah, it's great.
It's so not getting there.
LIAM: Mmm.
It was probably just a possum.
I caught one under my grill
the other night.
Almost shat myself.
It sounded like
a person to me.
Then it was kids
drinking forties
in the woods like
we used to do.
It sounded like one person.
LIAM: Got a gun in the house?
Are you nuts?
All Dad ever needed
was his Henry Aaron.
(LIAM CHUCKLES)
Different era, my friend.
Hey, check this out.
Finally got the mechanics
working perfect.
My loan agent might be willing
to give me an extension.
But only if I cut
production costs by half.
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
I, uh...
You know, I thought we agreed
you were gonna let that go.
That you were gonna
get those loans paid off.
-Whatever you say, boss.
-(LAPTOP SLAMS)
ANNA: So how's Pat doing with
the move back to New Jersey?
Stressed.
-Mmm.
-Barely sleeping.
It killed him
to come back here
and take the job with Liam,
but the reality
is he couldn't find anyone
to fund his designs.
Our medical benefits
are about to expire.
If his mom
hadn't moved to Arizona,
we would be
at the YMCA right now.
-(FLUTE BLOWING SHRILLY)
-Ahh!
KARINA: Hey, honey.
Please, please don't play
Fute so loud. Okay?
(SWITCHES FLICKING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(CRACKLING)
-(CLANGING NEARBY)
-(GASPS SOFTLY)
(LOUD CRACKING NEARBY)
(FOOTSTEPS SHUFFLING)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOFTLY) Screw this.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Hey, listen.
It's fine with me if you guys
are partying out here.
(RUSTLING NEARBY)
But don't blame me
if I bash someone's face in
'cause you don't
wanna get caught.
-(SCREECHES)
-(SCREAMS)
Shit.
(PANTING)
Oh, my God.
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-(ENGINE WHIRRING)
LIAM: Listen, Patty.
I know you're still down
about how things played out,
but you should be proud
that you had the balls
to go for it.
Be careful what you wish for.
Remember when I took over
the yard after Dad died?
Had nightmares
every goddamn night
about them
repossessing our car
or foreclosing on the house.
Those are my good dreams,
Liam.
Ever since we moved back home,
I've been having
these white-knucklers about
Jake getting snatched.
We're in the backyard.
Or maybe it's a park
or a playground.
I just get this bad feeling,
you know?
You know
who I blame for that shit?
Yeah, I could really
use him right now.
Yeah.
You and me both, brother.
Meet me over
at the kiln in 20.
Yeah.
YOUNG LIAM: Can you
please stop doing that
for three seconds?
YOUNG PATRICK:
This is Irish Walnut.
If I leave it for too long,
it'll get chalky.
YOUNG LIAM: I don't care
if it's Scottish scrotum.
We're on a mission here.
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
YOUNG PATRICK: Dad always says
to never come down here.
YOUNG LIAM: "Dad always said
never to come down here."
You're just scared of what
might be inside there.
(RATTLING)
Liam, have you ever thought...
What if the things
they say are true?
YOUNG LIAM:
Don't be a moron.
I hate to be the one
to tell you this, but...
Bingo!
Okay, we saw it.
Can we go home now?
I dare you to go over there.
I double dare you.
Or I'll tell everybody
what a pussy you were.
I triple dare you to do it.
I already did it,
like, 10 times.
Then you shouldn't
be afraid to do it again.
Should you?
(UNEASY MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
I wanna go home.
Yeah.
Yeah, me too.
Holy crap.
-That's a wild plum tree.
-Who cares?
Grandpa said
it's the softest wood
in the entire world.
Patty.
Pat.
Pat!
Get away from there, Patty.
YOUNG PATRICK: Help me
pull this tree down first.
YOUNG LIAM: No frickin' way.
YOUNG PATRICK: I'm not leaving
until I get a piece!
YOUNG LIAM:
If you don't let go right now,
I'm totally telling Dad
we came here.
-Dude. You're the pussy.
-Screw you.
I'm leaving
if you don't get away...
(THUDDING LOUDLY)
YOUNG PATRICK: Sweet.
You're too close.
Seriously, Patty.
(CLACKING NEARBY)
YOUNG PATRICK: Almost got it.
(SOFT, RASPY BREATHING)
(YOUNG PATRICK GASPS)
(CLACKING NEARBY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-Are you holding on?
-Yes, I am.
Okay, good.
How many more times
you wanna do it?
One thousand.
-I gotta stop, okay?
-Again.
No. I know you want
to go again, baby,
but I have to work, okay?
JAKE: Stop.
KARINA: All right. I know.
Come on, then.
Let's go over here.
So maybe we can go when Daddy
gets back from work, okay?
JAKE: Okay.
(JAKE PLAYING FLUTE)
(FLUTE CONTINUES PLAYING)
Jakie.
Jakie, stop.
-I said stop!
-(JAKE STOPS PLAYING FLUTE)
I'm sorry.
Mommy just needs
some quiet for a bit. Okay?
Can you do that for me,
please?
JAKE: Okay.
Thank you.
(CHILD'S LAUGHTER NEARBY)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SWING CREAKING)
KARINA: Jake?
Jake?
Jakie, where are you?
Jakie?
If you don't come out
in three seconds,
no dessert tonight, okay?
Jakie?
Jakie!
Jake?
Jakie! Where are you?
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(LAUGHTER NEARBY)
JAKE: I'll take the one.
That's the one.
Jakie! Come to Mommy, okay?
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
JAKE: Hello. We're here.
Ooh! Look at this!
KARINA: Jakie! Come out!
Jakie!
(FLUTE PLAYING)
Jakie?
Jakie? Jakie!
Jakie! Jakie!
Jake.
Oh, my God.
Don't you ever run away
from me like that again, okay?
Let's go home. Okay, baby?
Okay?
(SCRAPING NEARBY)
(JAKE WHIMPERS)
Let's go home, baby, okay?
We go home.
(SOFT, RASPY BREATHING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
PATRICK: Hey, buddy.
(PATRICK GRUNTS PLAYFULLY)
-(JAKE GIGGLING)
-PATRICK: How's your day been?
JAKE: Good, good.
PATRICK: "Good, good," good?
-(PLAYING FLUTE)
-Okay. All right.
-That's enough Fute now, okay?
-KARINA: Slow down, buddy.
-(EXCLAIMS PLAYFULLY)
-KARINA: Jakie!
Oh, poor Daddy.
Oh, my God.
Put him down.
(PARTICK AND KARINA
SINGING IN FRENCH)
♪ Ding, ding, dong ♪
(DOOR CREAKS)
PATRICK: Wanna watch that show
your sister
was telling us about?
It's too heavy.
Anything on the queue?
Mm-hmm.
250 movies
we'll never actually watch.
What's wrong?
I almost lost him today.
Lost him how?
I... I was trying to work,
and he was just playing
the stupid recorder
and I just lost it. I snapped.
I took my eye off him
for one second,
and he wandered
into the woods...
and I... I panicked, and all
I could think about was...
Are we gonna be okay?
(LAPTOP CHIMES)
(FOREBODING MUSIC SOARS)
-(THUDDING LOUDLY)
-(MUSIC FADES)
-(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
-(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
JAKE: Again.
(JAKE GIGGLES)
Again, again.
PATRICK: Hey, who you
talking to, buddy?
JAKE: Dolly.
To Dolly?
Dolly.
Is there a moth in here?
Mmm-mmm. Just Dolly.
Come on. Lie down, kiddo.
Let's get you tucked in.
(EXCLAIMS PLAYFULLY)
Where did you go?
Where'd you go?
Okay, buddy, go into the light.
There's peace and tranquility
in the light.
(IN PLAYFUL VOICE)
All are welcome.
(THUDDING, CLATTERING)
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
All are not welcome.
(CRACKLING)
(FURNITURE SCRAPING)
(DOOR RATTLES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(CLACKING NEARBY)
(WINDOW CREAKS)
(SOFTLY) Pat?
Pat?
(SHUSHING)
I'm here.
What are you doing?
I think there's somebody
out there.
Oh. What?
-(GRUNTS)
-PATRICK: Don't bother.
The power's out again.
Just come here and listen.
You're freaking me out, Pat.
Just...
Just listen.
What am I listening for?
This weird zipping sound.
I couldn't, for the life of me,
place it until just now.
Like a rucksack or duffel bag.
Somebody's opening
and closing it
just to mess with my head.
Come on, Pat. Seriously?
As soon as I figure out
where this asshole is hiding,
-I'm gonna kick his goddamn...
-(LOUD THUD)
Oh, shit, Jake.
(JAKE CRYING)
KARINA: Hello. Hi. Yeah.
Yeah, someone's breaking
into our house.
PATRICK: Jake?
KARINA: Yeah,
it's 109 Walter Ave.
Hey, buddy. Hey, buddy.
Daddy's here, all right?
-Yes. Yeah, please hurry.
-I got you.
Thank you. Please.
(CLATTERING DOWNSTAIRS)
PATRICK: Go ahead, take him.
KARINA: Where're you going?
-I'm going downstairs.
-Pat, no.
Just stay inside, okay?
Close the door.
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CREAKING)
(SWALLOWS FEARFULLY)
(SWING CREAKING)
(RUSTLING NEARBY)
PATRICK: You wanna
mess with me, man?
Yeah, I'm right here.
I'm right here!
(ZIPPER CLACKING)
(CLACKING CONTINUES)
(SOFT, RASPY BREATHING)
KARINA: Pat.
I said stay upstairs!
(SOFT GROWLING)
KARINA:
What the hell is going on?
Are you okay?
Are you okay, babe?
(SOFTLY) Come on. Go for it.
PATRICK: Hey.
Hey.
I'd say welcome home, Pat,
but somebody obviously
beat me to the punch.
-You must be Karina. Hey.
-Hi.
As far as the perp
gettin' inside...
there's not a lot to go on.
Well, I know for a fact
the doors were locked.
You guys have a hide-a-key?
Oh, yeah.
Yes. Yeah, we do.
Right here.
ISAACS: Ah. Okay.
Most likely scenario is,
somebody saw the length
of the grass in your yard,
thought you might be
outta town
and decided to make
an impulse buy.
So, why didn't
they steal anything?
ISAACS: You're positive
nothing's missing?
Yeah, not as far
as we can tell.
ISAACS: Do me a favor.
Go through the house again.
Make a list of anything
that's not where it should be.
No matter
how small or insignificant.
Yeah. I'll start
in the kitchen.
Yeah, it felt more like
he was trying to scare us.
Yeah, he did a good job too.
(RAWLS WHISTLES)
Hey, Chief, you're gonna
wanna take a look at this.
Pat...
Can you come upstairs?
Sure.
A lot of these break-ins
where it looks like
there was an ulterior motive
to robbery,
turns out somebody
is sendin' a message.
You sure
you didn't know this guy?
Well, I mean,
I never got a look at him.
You let me know
if you remember anything else.
Okay?
Okay.
What do we got, Rawls?
RAWLS: Well,
I'm not entirely sure, sir.
ISAACS: Don't suppose
you made these?
PATRICK: Yeah.
Uh, yeah,
all the time when I was a kid.
There're boxes of 'em
in the garage.
You know, it seems to me like
someone was squatting here
like this, and, you know,
-tossing them. Like so.
-(THUDDING, CLATTERING)
Maybe drawin'
your son's attention?
ISAACS: Look...
Tell 'em I sent you.
They'll rig your whole house
for a song.
And mow your lawn,
for chrissake.
(JAKE PLAYING FLUTE)
KARINA: Jakie.
(CLATTERING)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
Holy shit.
(TOY RATTLING)
Daddy, look at this.
Very cool, buddy.
Hey, so, pile on the right
goes back on the shelves.
Everything on the left,
we can bag and toss outside.
This asshole
really did rob us,
he needs a new line of work.
Where the hell
did you find this?
Uh, I've never seen that
before in my life.
So, what's it doing in
the bottom of the wastebasket
in my office?
No idea.
It's, uh...
It's one of the first things
I ever carved.
Lost it years ago.
Speaking of things
carved out of wood...
Can you...
ditch this for me somewhere?
What for?
It's literally
his favorite thing in the world.
Yeah, and you need to find him
a new favorite thing, my love.
A quieter thing,
'cause if he blows this shit
in my ear one more time,
you are never
getting laid again.
Okay.
I'll hide it out here
until he drives you nuts
asking for it.
Thank you.
Uh, garbage goes
out front tonight.
COMMENTATOR: The score is now
two-zero in favor of Texas.
Fute.
-Anderson is trying...
-Later, Jakie.
-You can play Fute later.
-Fute.
Fute.
Fute!
Okay. Okay, fine, I'll get it.
But you better play quietly,
or Mommy'll kill me.
Hey, what do you say
when I say,
"if you're okay in the tub?"
Fute.
(CHUCKLES)
No, no. What do you say?
"Okay."
Okay. All right.
Mommy and Auntie Anna
are across the hall
if you need 'em.
I'm going downstairs
for a sec.
KARINA: Okay.
ANNA: Sis, I'm, like, juggling
four different campaigns.
You know, you promised me rose
-and Real Housewives.
-Are you okay?
Okay!
(CRACKLING)
Is that Dolly?
You okay up there?
JAKE: Okay!
(SWITCH FLICKS)
PATRICK: Huh.
Dolly!
(THUDDING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
You okay, Jake?
-(WATER SPLASHING)
-(JAKE GROANS)
Jake?
What are you
supposed to say, Jake?
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
KARINA: Daddy asked you
a question, Jakie.
JAKE: Okay.
PATRICK: Did you
turn the lights off?
JAKE: Nope.
KARINA:
Who are you playing with?
(SHUSHES)
KARINA: Oh. There he is.
JAKE: Dolly.
PATRICK: (SOFTLY)
Where'd I put it?
KARINA: Who are you
playing with?
JAKE: Dolly.
(GARBAGE CLATTERING)
(SIGHS)
The hell are you?
KARINA: Have you been
able to stop thinking
about what happened?
No.
Have you?
JAKE SR.: Patrick.
Patrick.
Need to ask you a question.
Harvey says he spotted you
playing by the old
service steps.
Yeah, because...
I was just looking
for softer wood to carve
than all this stupid oak.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
All right.
Let's you and me take a walk.
Come on.
(PHONE VIBRATING)
(SOFTLY)
You gotta be shitting me.
(BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Your Promethian
Home Security System
is activated.
(BEEPING)
The alarm system
will reset in 30 seconds.
(RUSTLING)
(RATTLING)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
PATRICK: Jesus.
(SCOFFS)
-(DOLL LAUGHS)
-(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLING SHEEPISHLY)
Oh, my God.
Screw you.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
Come on,
you gotta be shitting me.
(SIGHS IN EXASPERATION)
(STRAINING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(OMINOUS GROWLING)
(PLAYING FLUTE)
PATRICK: Karina!
Karina, wake up!
KARINA: Pat!
Pat! What's going on?
PATRICK: Did you see him?
-Did you see him?
-KARINA: See who?
What?
-Just go back inside, okay?
-No, but what...
Just go back inside.
Lock the door.
-Pat, what... No! Pat!
-Just stay here.
Where are you?
Are you in here?
Come on.
-Come on.
-(KNOCK ON DOOR)
PATRICK: It's me.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
And nobody's here.
-I swear I saw something...
-(ALARM BLARING)
KARINA: Alarm.
PATRICK: One sec.
ISAACS: No fingerprints
or any of the doors
or windows,
and none of the molds
in the backyard
came up a match.
Power company did confirm
13 separate interruptions,
but insist the problem
is not on their end.
KARINA: Meaning what?
You haven't had a new face
show up, have you?
Different guy
checkin' the gas meter,
-or fixin' a cable?
-No.
And nothing missing
from the house?
(JAKE GIGGLING)
Uh, Jake has this...
musical instrument, um...
a recorder
that he loves to play,
which I might have
thrown out by mistake.
But even if I did,
it would still be
in one of the garbage cans,
which it's not.
And I...
I could have sworn
I heard it being played.
You know, last night.
Hey.
Thought I said,
"Take some time off."
I need to show you something.
So, what?
There's a thousand more
like it back at the house.
That's the only owl
I ever made.
Do you remember
where I lost it?
Don't tell me
you went back there?
No.
I found it in a trash bin
at home yesterday.
How is that possible?
It's not.
Look what else
I found in Mom's garage.
What are you saying, Patty?
You explain it. I...
Mom always had a knack
for finding lost stuff.
You know she did.
Keep digging
through that house
and I guarantee you'll find
all kinds'a crazy shit.
Maybe, in the meantime,
I think you should
give that shrink a call.
What was her name?
Mary?
Barbara.
Yeah, something's
been bubbling up in you
for a long time now,
and she always seemed to help
back in the day.
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: Yeah, let your
brother have a go, all right?
Not too high.
KID: Are you serious?
WOMAN 2: Gotta go.
JAKE: Push it back.
Push it back.
(GROANS)
-JAKE: Present.
-Jeez.
-Jakie, you scared me.
-Present.
It's from Dolly.
What is this?
It's a present.
Okay?
Okay.
What the hell?
(JAKE GIGGLING)
Shit. Jakie.
Jakie, come out of there!
Jakie!
(GIGGLING)
-(RASPY BREATHING)
-KARINA: Jakie.
(BAGMAN GROWLING)
Get away from him!
Get the hell away from my son!
Jakie!
(CLACKING)
Jakie. Come here.
Come here. Jakie.
Jakie!
-(CLACKING)
-(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
(EXHALING)
(JAKE COOING OVER MONITOR)
BARBARA: What's happening
to you both is very normal.
To have your home invaded
is a traumatic experience,
one that brings up
all kinds of issues.
KARINA: Such as?
BARBARA: Such as,
"How will I ever let my son
out of my sight again?"
Or...
"Did I fulfill my obligation
as a husband
"and a father, and a man,
"to protect
my wife and child?"
Karina, Pat's description.
It's quite evocative
of a persistent phobia
your husband
struggled with as a child.
Which, of course,
is how Pat and I
came to know each other.
KARINA: What phobia was that?
JAKE SR.: Patrick.
Patrick.
Let's you and me take a walk.
Come on.
You know, long before
we built this yard,
this whole forest
was basically
one big copper mine.
Kicked out half the product
for the entire state,
before they finally
dug the sucker dry.
This was how you got down
to the main entry shaft...
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
...back when it was owned
by the mining company.
YOUNG PATRICK:
Who owns it now?
Us?
(WHISPERS)
Now it belongs to Bagman.
-YOUNG PATRICK: Who's Bagman?
-Shh!
You never know
who might be listenin'.
I told your brother this story
last summer,
just like your granddad did me
when I was your age
and his granddad's
granddad before that.
And all of them
swore it was true.
Just like
I'm swearing to you now.
They say...
he wanders
the world each night,
searching for children
to stuff in that
awful bag a' his.
-Not just any children...
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Let me guess.
He wants the naughty children
that don't listen
to their parents or...
Wrong, Patty. (SCOFFS)
It's the good kids he wants.
The shiny ones
and the dreamers.
Once they catch his eye,
or grab his fancy,
he won't rest
until he has them
slung over his bony shoulder.
Screamin' for help
that's never gonna come.
No, you're just trying
to scare me...
Damn right,
I'm trying to scare you, boy.
And scared you better be!
Wander too close,
he'll drag you in
and make pencils
out of your fingers,
and gobble
the rest of you down!
Are you with me, boy?
Good.
KARINA: Bagman?
You drew these?
Yep.
BARBARA: That's what I meant
by a persistent phobia.
Pat's was so intense,
I felt it was crucial
to give him
as much context as possible
for the familial lore
that provoked it.
As you can see,
the so-called Bag or Sackman,
is a figure common
to almost every culture.
Curiously, his methodology,
even the phenomena
that accompany his presence,
are remarkably consistent.
He has the power to paralyze
and incapacitate
parents and adults
leaving their young ones
vulnerable.
And he feeds off
the child's fear and anxiety.
It sustains him, nourishes him.
He can lure children to his lair
with toys or candy...
And when the child
is at their most terrified,
he steals them away
in his sack or bag.
Are you trying
to make us feel stupid?
On the contrary.
I never told Karina
about the Bagman, Barbara,
and it wasn't a dream
that broke into our house.
No, but I'd suggest,
as a coping mechanism,
you're projecting
the supernatural
onto something...
-all too painfully real.
-(SIGHS)
And until you deal
with the real stuff
bubbling up for you,
the anger,
the feelings of vulnerability,
and violation,
your panic attacks
and nightmares
will only get worse.
KARINA: Okay, so,
what do you suggest we do?
I see her.
ANNA: I'm the zombie.
-Whoa! Hey, guys.
-KARINA: Okay.
So, he goes down 7:30
at the latest.
-We read two stories...
-Two stories, yeah.
...and then we sing
Frere Jacques when
he goes in the Pack 'n Play.
Guys, check your phone.
I just texted you
the confirmation number
for a room at the Hyatt.
Two blocks from here,
three from the restaurant.
Already paid for.
Dinner's one thing,
but there's no chance in hell
we're sleeping
in a different place
than Jakie right now.
Who said anything
about sleeping?
Who said sleeping?
Will you just get her
out of here, Pat?
JAKE: Who said...
PATRICK: Jakie,
listen to Auntie Anna, okay?
KARINA: Call any time!
We can be back,
five minutes tops, okay?
-ANNA: Gonna play zombie.
-(JAKE GIGGLING)
KARINA: I'm not sure
I'm up for this.
Yeah, me neither.
Worst case, we get dinner to go
and eat on Anna's couch.
KARINA: Yep.
Let's at least try to make it
as far as dessert,
so she can put Jakie down.
So, what's the verdict?
Is your husband nuts?
(KARINA SNICKERS)
Completely fricking crackers.
So, what actually happened
with you and Liam at the mine?
Well, I thought I felt someone
cut off a lock of my hair.
I, uh...
I lost my shit
and then
we ran home screaming.
A lock of your hair?
Yeah. Bagman supposedly
always snips
one off the kids
that catch his fancy.
That's how it starts.
What the hell for?
So he always knows
where to find you.
No matter where
you try to run or hide.
Your father was something else.
I think in his own way
he was just trying
to protect me.
A cautionary tale
to keep me safe.
All I remember
was Mom was furious
'cause every night
I was convinced
he was tapping on my window.
And then one night,
the old man came in
and he said,
"Your mum wants me to tell you
there's no such thing
as Bagman."
But I'm afraid
I can't do that.
What I can do...
is tell you a secret
he don't want you to know.
Truth is,
no matter how big, or fast,
or sneaky he is,
he has weaknesses as well.
Escape his grasp long enough,
he'll rot away.
And he cannot lay a single,
skinny finger on you.
Not as long...
as you have this.
You see,
every kid's got something
that means more to them
than anything else
in the world.
Something they love so much,
it literally becomes
a piece of who they are.
And believe you me,
a child's love...
can be a magical thing.
It can turn even
the humblest object...
into a totem...
of great power.
Now you keep this
close to your heart,
and he cannot touch you.
But lose it,
or even worse,
throw it away...
So, you keep ahold of it.
No matter what.
And now you're concerned...
that Fute has gone missing.
If the one thing that can
supposedly protect Jake...
from you-know-who...
is the thing
that he loves the most?
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Honestly?
Well, what I wanna
do right now is go back home
and dig through the trash again.
But if we go down
that thought track,
I'm not sure we'll make it
to the other side, so...
Did Barbara help
when you were eight?
Wouldn't have made it
to nine without her.
So, we have to trust her now.
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
ANNA: No,
I do not miss you at all.
WOMAN: (ON PHONE) What?
ANNA: Mmm-mmm.
I have a real hot date tonight.
-Oh, yeah?
-Three feet tall,
talks gibberish
and craps his own pants.
It is so, so sexy.
-Stop it.
-(CHUCKLES)
Okay, babe, um...
We'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
And why don't you
make me something sweet?
Something sweet?
What do you mean?
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know what you mean.
You know exactly
what I'm talking about.
Okay. Okay, babe.
Yeah. Bye.
(EXHALES)
(GARBLED COOING)
(SOFT, RASPY BREATHING)
(GARBLED GROWLING)
(MONITOR CLATTERS)
(UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING)
(BEEPING)
ANGELO: Hey.
-Angelo.
-Yeah?
Is there something weird
happening on this floor?
Uh, what do you mean, "weird"?
I don't know.
I'm hearing a voice
on a baby monitor.
Everything's clear
on my security cams.
You want me to come up?
No, no. Um...
I'm sure it's nothing.
Okay. Take it easy.
Yeah.
(CRACKLING)
Angelo, has there been
a power surge?
Angelo, are you there?
(SOFTLY) Come on.
Shit.
(SLOW KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(KNOCKING COTINUES)
-(GROWLS)
-(GASPS)
I don't know
what you want from me.
But the cops are on their way!
(KNOCKING RESUMES)
Did I mention I have a gun?
Don't play with me,
motherfucker!
(CREAKING)
(JINGLING)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Sarah!
Sarah, call the police!
(SQUEAKING)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
-(BREATH TREMBLING)
-(DOOR CREAKING)
(BAGMAN BREATHING RASPILY)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
-(GROWLS)
-(YELLING)
-(KNIFE CLATTERING)
-(GROWLS)
-(SIREN BLARING)
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
OFFICER: Stay back.
ANNA: Karina.
Anna? Anna, are you okay?
Are you okay?
What happened?
Where's Jakie?
ISAACS: We got him. He's okay.
Hey, buddy. Hey. Hey.
There you go.
It's okay. Thank you.
ISAACS: We've got nothing
on the CCTV camera.
It was knocked out
when the power went down.
Thank God for the doorman.
Once the camera
on Anna's floor went dark,
he headed straight up.
He must have
scared the guy off.
-Did Angelo get a look at him?
-No.
But, Pat,
apparently
there are similarities
to a case from four years ago.
A girl named
Emily Greenberg went missing.
Her dad suffered
similar symptoms to Anna's,
temporary paralysis
and loss of speech.
And these strange abrasions
on his face.
He said he couldn't move.
He had to lie there
and watch this lunatic
stuff his daughter
into a duffel bag
and run off with her.
(SIGHS)
Look, we're gonna
get you somewhere safe.
I'll post officers outside
who'll keep watch
around the clock.
Don't worry, Pat.
We're gonna catch
this sick bastard.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
PATRICK: Thanks.
OFFICER: No problem.
ARLENE: This way. Right here.
Come on.
Watch your step, okay?
PATRICK:
They're trying to figure out
what paralyzed Anna,
and the doctors
don't have a frickin' clue.
Who cares,
as long as Anna's okay.
She's far from okay.
All right, she refused to stay
in the hospital.
She wouldn't even let us
turn the lights off upstairs.
Karina had to give her
a sedative
and get in bed with her,
you know?
Well, she can stay here
as long as she needs to.
Thank you.
Please.
We'd be insulted
if you went anywhere else.
Come here.
(VOICE BREAKING) I'm sorry.
For what?
Protecting my son?
Get some sleep.
I'm not going anywhere.
(PATRICK KISSES)
KARINA: 'Bout time.
PATRICK:
What are you doing awake?
(BAT CLATTERS)
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
We'll get through this.
I promise.
(PATRICK SIGHS)
KARINA: I can't believe
this is happening.
What do we do
if he really does exist...
and we have lost the one thing
in the whole world...
that could keep our son safe?
I'll make him a new one.
No, that won't be the same.
Hey, get some sleep, honey.
All right?
(SOFT STATIC OVER MONITOR)
-(GROWLS)
-(CRACKLING)
Jake!
-Pat?
-Jake!
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHOKING)
(BAGMAN GROWLING)
JAKE: Daddy. Daddy, help me.
Help me.
Jake.
Jake!
He's got the boy!
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Pat? Pat?
PATRICK: Help!
Help!
Somebody stop him!
(GRUNTS)
Stop right there!
JAKE: Daddy, help me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
JAKE: Daddy! Help me!
Jake!
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-(DEBRIS CLATTERING)
-(PATRICK GROANS)
(GROANS)
Jake!
JAKE: Daddy!
Help.
Daddy! Help me!
Daddy, help me.
PATRICK: Jake?
Jake?
(STRAINING)
(YELLS)
(GROANING)
(COUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
Jake? Are you in here?
Jake?
(CREAKING NEARBY)
God, please. God.
No, no, no.
(CLACKING)
(GRUNTS)
What the heck?
JAKE: (DISTORTED VOICE) Daddy.
Daddy.
Daddy, help me!
Mommy!
-KARINA: Jakie?
-(JAKE CRYING)
Oh, my God, Jake.
Oh, my gosh. Jake!
ANNA: Karina!
(KARINA CRYING)
(ANNA SIGHS IN RELIEF)
Karina, what's happening?
It's not Jake that he came for.
Show yourself,
you sick bastard!
Show yourself!
(DEBRIS CLATTERS)
(BAGMAN BREATHES RASPILY)
-(GROWLING)
-(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLS)
JAKE SR.: First,
he steals a lock of your hair,
so he always knows
where to find you.
And then he taunts you
and feeds off your fear.
It's the good kids he wants.
The shiny ones
and the dreamers.
And once they catch his eye,
or grab his fancy,
he won't rest
until he has them
slung over his bony shoulder,
screamin' for help
that's never gonna come.
(WEAKLY) Why come
for me now, huh?
After all this time?
Now you keep this
close to your heart,
and he cannot touch you.
But lose it,
or even worse,
throw it away...
(THUDDING LOUDLY)
(GROANING)
The cold hard truth of it,
Patty,
is that there are monsters
in this world.
There is evil.
And bad things
do happen to good people.
Even little children.
(WHIMPERING)
(BAGMAN PLAYING FLUTE)
JAKE SR.: The only thing that
gives me comfort at night...
is a belief that there's
something good out there,
much more powerful
than all the bad stuff.
Something that loves
and watches over us.
No matter what.
(PATRICK STRAINING)
(CLACKING)
And you really believe that?
-(BAGMAN GROWLS)
-(PATRICK STRAINING)
I'm lookin' at the proof.
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
(STRAINING)
(YELLING)
(SIREN BLARING IN DISTANCE)
(BAGMAN GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
(BAGMAN GROANING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on! It's me you want!
Come on.
(GROWLING)
-(SCREAMING)
-(BONES CRACKING)
(ZIPPER CLACKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SIREN BLARING IN DISTANCE)
OFFICER 1: Yeah, this way.
Down here! On me! Keep going.
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
I don't know who's on foot.
OFFICER 3: Down by the yard,
keep a guard here.
KARINA: What is it? What is it?
This is as far as she goes.
Pat must have
taken a different route.
Yo, boss, we got something.
It's got blood on it.
OFFICER 4: Let's fan out!
What is that?
KARINA: That's Jake's flute.
Pat. Pat!
Pat!
ISAACS: You need
to step away from...
KARINA: Pat! Can you hear me?
(CRYING) Pat!
Pat!
(TIRES RATTLING)
Mom said we could stay
as long as we need to.
I just can't be
in this house anymore.
Not without Pat.
There's still hope, 'Rina.
I mean, they haven't
even found anything yet.
They're not going to.
And it's not over yet, either.
What do you mean?
He's gonna come back for Jake.
I can just feel it.
What are you gonna do?
Whatever it takes.
Okay. Come here.
Just call me
when you get there. Okay?
Yep. Yep.
Yep.
Yeah.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC COTINUES)
Hey, so I got some
good news for you, pal.
Look what Daddy found.
Fute.
(JAKE PLAYING FLUTE)
You know, he gave everything
to get that back for you.
And, um... And Daddy...
He also told me a secret
that he really,
really wants you to know.
Okay, so how much
do you love Fute, Jakie?
Yeah. So a child's love
is a magical thing.
Keep it close to your heart.
And it will always
protect you.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Okay.
Always.
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)