Come here, little tractor,
come here.
Yeah, that's a good tractor.
No, no, no, no, come here.
What are you doing?
You're not supposed to go
wandering off all...
...alone.
What are you doin'
with those old racin' tires?
[Sighing heavily]
Come on, Doc, drive.
[Revs engine]
Ah... Yeah.
- Wow.
- Huh?
You're amazing!
[Coughing] What are you doin'?
Doc, wait!
[Trucks mooing]
Giddup right in there!
Come on, Rusty.
Doc, hold it!
Seriously, your driving's incredible!
- Wonderful. Now, go away.
- Hey, I mean it. You've still got it!
- I'm askin' you to leave.
- Come on.
I'm a racecar,
you're a much older racecar,
but under the hood
you and I are the same.
We are not the same!
Understand? Now, get out.
How could a car like you quit
at the top of your game?
You think I quit?
[Lightning] Right.
Your big wreck in '54.
They quit on me.
When I finally got put together,
I went back expecting a big welcome.
You know what they said?
"You're history."
Moved right on to
the next rookie standing in line.
There was a lot left in me.
I never got a chance to show 'em.
I keep that to remind me
never to go back.
I just never expected that
that world would...
...would find me here.
- Hey, look, Doc, I'm not them.
- Oh, yeah?
No, I'm not.
When is the last time you cared about
something except yourself, hot rod?
You name me one time
and I will take it all back.
Uh-huh. I didn't think so.
These are good folk around here,
who care about one another.
I don't want 'em depending
on someone they can't count on.
Oh, like you?
You've been here how long
and your friends
don't even know who you are?
Who's caring about only himself?
Just finish that road
and get outta here!
[Reveille plays]
[~ Jimi Hendrix: Star Spangled Banner]
[Sarge] Will you turn that
disrespectful junk off?
[Fillmore] Respect the classics, man.
[Snoring]
[Snorts, putters]
[Grunting]
[Smacking] Ah...
[Mater] He's done.
He must've finished it
while we was all sleepin'.
Good riddance.
He's gone?
Well, we wouldn't want him
to miss that race of his.
[Sniffing]
- Oh, dude, are you crying?
- No! I'm happy!
I don't have to watch him
every second of the day anymore!
I'm glad he's gone!
[Blubbering, sobbing]
What's wrong with Red?
Oh, he's just sad
'cause you left town
and went to your big race to win
the Piston Cup
that you've always dreamed about
your whole life
and get that big ol' sponsor and that
fancy helicopter you was talkin' about.
[Gasping] Wait a minute!
[All laugh]
I knowed you wouldn't leave
without saying goodbye.
What are you doin' here?
You're gonna miss your race.
Don't worry. I'll give you
a police escort, and we'll make up time.
Thank you, Sheriff.
But you know I can't go just yet.
Well, why not?
- I'm not sure these tires...
- [Luigi gasps excitedly]
...can get me to California.
- Peet stop?
Yeah, does anybody know
what time Luigi's opens?
[Laughing] I can't-a believe it!
Four new tires!
Grazie, Mr. Lightning. Grazie!
- Would you look at that!
- [Luigi] Our first customer in years!
I am filled with tears of ecstasy,
for this is the most glorious day
of my life!
All right, Luigi, give me
the best set of blackwalls you've got.
No! No, no, no.
You don't-a know what you want.
Luigi know what you want.
Blackwall tires.
They blend into the pavement.
But-a this...
Whitewall tires!
They say, "Look at me!
Here I am! Love me."
All right, you're the expert.
- [Snarling]
- [Lightning] Don't forget the spare.
- Perfetto. Guido!
- Peet stop!
[~ Chuck Berry: Route 66]
[Laughing] What did Luigi tell you, eh?
Wow, you were right.
Better than a Ferrari, huh?
Eh... No.
Wow! This organic fuel is great!
Why haven't I heard about it before?
It's a conspiracy, man!
The oil companies got a grip
on the government!
They're feedin' us a bunch of lies, man.
OK, I'll take a case.
Ow! Eh!
[Lightning yelps]
- [Chuckles]
- [Breathes in deeply]
[Ramone] Ah... Yeah.
[Lightning] Ka-chow.
- Here she comes!
- [Lightning] Places, everybody. Hurry!
- Act natural.
- [Whistling]
- Hi, Sally.
- Buon giorno!
All right, what's goin' on?
Ladies and gentlecars,
please welcome
the new Lightning McQueen!
Pow! What do you think?
Radiator Springs
looks pretty good on me.
[Chuckling] I'll say.
[Purring] Ka-chow.
You're gonna fit right in
in California.
My goodness. It looks like
you've helped everybody in town.
Yeah, everybody except one.
- Hey, is it getting dark out?
- What? What'd he say?
Let me say that again.
Is it getting dark out?
Now, what was I
supposed to do after that?
[~ The Chords: Sh-Boom]
[Gasping] They fixed their neon!
- Low and slow?
- Oh, yeah, baby! [chuckling]
[Flo laughs and shrieks]
Just like in its heyday, right?
It's even better than I pictured it.
Thank you.
[Chuckling]
Shall we cruise?
Oh, thank you, dear. I'd love to!
- No, no, no.
- Lizzie!
I remember when Stanley
first asked me to take a drive with him.
Hey, Miss Sally.
May I have this cruise?
- Of course, Mater.
- Uh-uh-uh!
[Mooing]
...and again and I said, "No."
He asked me again, and I said, "No."
But, oh, he was a persistent
little bugger for a two-cylinder.
Finally I said,
"All right, one little drive."
- Oh!
- [Mater chuckling]
- Hey!
- Thanks, Mater.
Good evenin', you two.
Oh, Stanley,
I wish you could see this.
- Is that what I think it is?
- Oh, I don't know, Flo.
I haven't had a chance to find out.
But I am going to find out. Hello.
Not that. That.
[Sally gasps] Customers?
Customers, everybody!
And a lot of 'em!
You know what to do.
Just like we rehearsed.
[All gasp]
It's the ghostlight!
We have found McQueen.
We have found McQueen!
McQueen, over here!
- Wait, excuse me.
- Is it true you've been in rehab?
- Did you have a nervous breakdown?
- What?
- McQueen's wearing whitewalls!
- Your tires balding?
[Sally] Stickers!
- Was McQueen your prisoner?
- Shoot, no!
We're best buds!
I ain't braggin' or nothin',
but I was in charge of huntin' him down
if he tried to escape.
Sally! Sally!
Will you still race for the Piston Cup?
- Stickers?
- Sally!
- Come on, give us some bolt!
- [Horn honking]
You're here!
Thank the manufacturer! You're alive!
- Mack?
- You're here! I can't believe it!
[Chuckling] You are a sight
for sore headlights!
I'm so sorry I lost you, boss.
I'll make it up to you!
Mack, I, I can't believe you're here.
[Harv] Is that the world's
fastest racing machine?
- Is that Harv?
- Yeah. He's in the back.
- Show us the bolt!
- Get back, you oil-thirsty parasites!
- Where's the old McQueen?
- Actually, this is my good side here.
- Harv! Harv!
- Give us the bolt!
- Harv?
- Come on!
- Kid, I'm over here!
- How you doin', buddy?
My star client disappears
off the face of the earth!
- How do you think I'm doing?
- I can explain.
I'm doing great! You're everywhere!
Radio, TV, the papers!
You can't buy this kind of publicity!
What do you need me for?
That's just a figure of speech,
by the way. You signed a contract.
Where are you?
I can't even find you on my GPS.
I'm in this little town
called Radiator Springs.
- You know Route 66? It's still here!
- Yeah, that's great, kid.
Playtime is over, pal.
While the world's been trying to
find you Dinoco has had no one to woo.
- Who are they gonna woo?
- Chick!
Bingo. In fact, check out
what's on the plasma right now.
- Show us the thunder!
- You want thunder?
You want thunder?
Ka-chicka, ka-chicka!
- Hey, that's my bit!
- You've gotta get to Cali, pronto!
Just get out of Radiation Stinks now,
or Dinoco is history, you hear me?
Just give me a second here, Harv.
No, wait. Where are you goin'?
Get in the trailer, baby. Kid!
You want a bigger trailer?
Sally, I... I want you to...
Look, I wish... [sighs]
Thank you. Thanks for everything.
[Groans, chuckles]
- It was just a road.
- No. It was much more than that.
Hey, kid! We gotta go.
Harv's goin' crazy!
He's gonna have me fired if
I don't get you in the truck right now!
- Mack, just... hold it for...
- You should go.
- I know, but...
- Good luck in California.
I hope you find
what you're looking for.
- McQueen, come on!
- Sally...
- Sally!
- Show us the bolt, McQueen! The bolt!
Hey, Lightning, show us the bolt!
- Come on, get in the trailer.
- Where's the old McQueen?
- The bolt!
- That's it. That's right, let's go!
You're a big shining star.
You're a superstar.
You don't belong there, anyway.
Whoa... Wait...
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait!
[Engine starts]
Hey, guys!
McQueen's leavin' in the truck!
Hey, are you Doc Hudson?
- Yeah.
- Thanks for the call.
- You called them?
- It's best for everyone, Sally.
Best for everyone or best for you?
I didn't get to say goodbye to him.
[Light buzzing]
[Bob] Hello, race fans. Welcome
to what has become, quite simply,
the biggest event
in the history of racing.
A three-way battle for the Piston Cup!
[Darrell] There's a crowd
of nearly 200,000 cars
here at the Los Angeles
International Speedway.
Tickets to this race are hotter than a
black leather seat on a hot summer day!
[Bob] The King, Chick Hicks
and Lightning McQueen
in a 200 lap, winner-takes-all,
tiebreaker race.
[Darrell] I got a lotta miles on me,
but let me tell you somethin'.
I never thought I'd see anything
like this. This is exciting!
[Bob] In fact, the country
has almost shut down
to watch what many experts
are calling "the race of the century."
Hey, King!
Good luck in your last race.
- You've sure been an inspiration to me.
- Thanks, Junior. Appreciate it.
- Hey, be careful out there, OK?
- Yeah, man.
[Mia] He's hot!
Wanna know the forecast?
I'll give you the forecast.
A 100 percent chance of thunder!
Ka-chicka! Ka-chicka!
Say it with me!
Hey, you! No admittance
without a garage pass.
Oh, it's OK.
Lightning McQueen knows me!
Hey, Marco, it's a beautiful day
for a race, isn't it?
- Absolutely, Mr. Andretti.
- And good morning to you, Fred.
Mario Andretti knows my name!
You gotta let me in now!
[Guard] Sorry, pal.
[Lightning] OK, here we go.
Focus. Speed.
I am speed.
[Cars whizzing]
Victory.
One winner, two losers.
[Engine revving]
Speed. Speed. Speed. Speed...
[birds singing]
[Knock on door]
[Mack] Lightnin'! You ready?
[Gasping] Yeah, yeah, yeah! I'm ready.
[Indistinct chatter]
Mack, thanks for being
my pit crew today.
Don't worry about it, kid.
It's the least I could do.
After all, "Gas Can"
is my middle name.
- It is?
- Ah... Not really.
[All shouting]
[Gulping]
Uh-oh
- [cheering, laughing]
- [Giggling]
Nelson! Zoom in.
Ready, 16? Take 16.
[Bob] And there he is,
Lightning McQueen!
Missing all week, and then he turns up
in the middle of nowhere!
In a little town
called Radiator Springs.
[Darrell] Wearin' whitewall tires,
of all things.
- Oh!
- Ka-chicka! Ka-chicka! Ka-chicka!
[Chuckling]
Hey, where you been?
I've been kinda lonely.
Nobody to hang out with.
I mean, except the Dinoco folks.
And the twins. Of course.
The ones that used to be your fans,
but now they're my fans.
Listen to what the twins think...
Agh! Shoot!
[Darrell] Boogity, boogity, boogity,
boys! Let's go racin'!
[Crowd cheering]
Come on, you can do it!
Come on, King, make us proud, boy!
[Bob] Fifty laps down, and The King
is still holding a slim lead.
[Darrell] McQueen's got a run on him!
He's lookin' to the inside!
Oh! Chick slammed the door on him!
[Bob] Chick's not
making it easy on him today.
[Darrell] He lost momentum,
and now he's gonna have to
chase him back down!
- [Soft music]
- [Birds singing]
[Breaks squealing]
[Bob] McQueen spins out in the infield!
[All gasp]
[Chuckling] Just me
and the old man, fellas.
- McQueen just doesn't have it today.
- [All laugh]
[Groans]
- Hey, kid, are you all right?
- I don't know, Mack.
I don't think I...
[Doc] I didn't come all this way
to see you quit.
Doc?
Guys, you're here!
I can't believe this!
I knew you needed a crew chief,
but I didn't know it was this bad.
You said you'd never come back.
Well, I really didn't have a choice.
Mater didn't get to say goodbye.
Goodbye! OK, I'm good.
[Chuckles]
All right, if you can drive as good
as you can fix a road
then you can win this race
with your eyes shut.
Now, get back out there!
Hot snot, we are back in business!
Guido! Luigi!
You're goin' up
against professional pit crews.
- You're gonna have to be fast.
- They will not know what bit them!
Kid, you can beat these guys.
Find a groove that works for you
and get that lap back.
[Murmuring]
- Is it?
- Oh, wow. That's him!
Is that? That's the Hudson Hornet!
The Hudson Hornet's back!
[Bob] It appears McQueen
has got himself a pit crew.
And look who he has for a crew chief!
- Look, man. It's the Hudson Hornet!
- Whoa!
Well, dip me in axle grease
and call me Slick! It surely is.
[Crowd cheering]
[Bob] Wow, this is history
in the making.
Nobody has seen the racing legend
in over 50 years!
Hey, Doc!
Come look at this fellow on the radio.
He looks just like you.
- [Bob] McQueen passes on the inside!
- [Darrell] He's nearly a lap down.
[Bob] Can he catch up to them
with only 60 laps to go?
You're goin' great, kid.
Just keep your head on.
Vai! Vai, vai!
Hey, shrimpie,
where did McQueen find you, huh?
Those round things are called tires,
and they go under the car!
[All laugh]
Con chi credi di parlare?
Ma, con chi stai parlando?
No! No, no! You'll have your chance.
You will have your chance.
Oh, kid's just tryin'
to be a hero, huh?
What do you think of this?
- [Tires squealing]
- Yeah, that's it, kid.
What?
Whoa! Git-R-done!
- [Laughing] I taught him that. Ka-chow!
- Ah!
[Bob] What a move by McQueen!
He's caught up to the leaders.
Yeah. This is what it's all about.
A three-way battle for the lead,
with ten to go!
[Chortling]
Look at that boy go out there!
[Chick] Oh! [grunting]
No, you don't.
[Tire blows]
Doc, I'm flat! I'm flat!
- Can you get back to the pits?
- Yeah, yeah. I think so.
Hey, got a yellow. Bring it in.
Don't tear yourself up, kid.
[Mack] We gotta get him
back out there fast
or we're gonna be a lap down,
and we'll never win this race!
Guido! It's time.
Hey, tiny,
you gonna clean his windshield?
[Air wrench whirring]
[Darrell] I don't believe it!
[Bob] That was
the fastest pit stop I've ever seen!
[Darrell] It was a great stop,
but he's still gotta beat that pace car!
[Bob] It's gonna be close.
- Yeah, baby!
- [All hollering]
[Darrell] He's back in!
Peet stop.
- Guido, you did it!
- Way to go, Guido!
[Bob] This is it. We're heading into
the final lap and McQueen
is right behind the leaders.
What a comeback!
[Darrell] A hundred and ninety-nine
laps! It all comes down to this!
This is it, kiddo.
You've got four turns left.
One at a time.
Drive it in deep and hope it sticks.
- Go!
- [Revving]
We'll see about that!
[Bob] McQueen's going inside!
- Chick and King are loose!
- [Darrell] I think McQueen's out!
- McQueen saved it!
- [Bob] He's back on the track!
- Float like a Cadillac...
- Sting like a Beemer!
- Ka-chow! Ka-chow! Ka...
- [all cheer]
[Darrell] Lightning McQueen
is gonna win the Piston Cup!
Come on! You got it!
You got it, Stickers!
[Grunts] I am not comin' in
behind you again, old man.
- Oh, no!
- [Crowd gasps]
[Breaks screeching]
[Engine idling]
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
I won, baby! Yeah! Oh, yeah!
[Flo] What's he up to, Doc?
[Grunting, moaning]
What are you doin', kid?
I think The King
should finish his last race.
You just gave up the Piston Cup,
you know that?
This grumpy old racecar I know
once told me somethin'.
It's just an empty cup.
[Bob] Darrell, is pushing
on the last lap legal?
He's not really pushin' him. He's
just givin' him a little bump draft.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Hey. What? What's goin' on?
- That's what I call racin'.
- [Sobbing]
[Laughing]
[Crowd cheers wildly]
- Bravo il mio amico!
- Way to go, buddy!
There's a lotta love out there,
you know, man?
- Don't embarrass me, Fillmore.
- That's my hot rod.
Come on, baby, bring it out!
Bring out the Piston Cup!
Ka-chicka! Ka-chicka!
Yeah!
Now, that's what I'm talkin' about!
Hey, how come the only one celebrating
is me, huh?
Where are the girls?
Bring on the confetti!
Ow! Ow! Easy with the confetti.
What's goin' on?
Come on, snap some pictures.
I gotta go sign my deal with Dinoco!
Say it with me. Ka-chicka!
- Boo!
What's wrong with everybody?
Where's the happiness?
Hey! This is the start of the Chick era!
- Thanks, Lightnin'.
- You're welcome.
- Way to go, King!
- You're still the car!
You're The King! Yeah!
[Crowd cheers]
[Laughing and cheering]
- You made us proud, kid!
- Congrats on the loss, me bucko!
You got a lotta stuff, kid.
Thanks, Doc.
Hey, Lightnin'.
How 'bout comin' over here
and talk to me a minute?
Son, that was some
real racin' out there.
How'd you like to become
the new face of Dinoco?
But I didn't win.
Lightnin', there's a whole lot
more to racin' than just winnin'.
[Clank] He was so rusty,
when he drove down the street
- buzzards used to circle the car!
- [All laugh]
Thank you, Mr. Tex, but...
...but these Rust-eze guys over there
gave me my big break.
I'm gonna stick with them.
Well, I sure can respect that.
Still, you know,
if there's ever anything
I can do for you, just let me know.
I sure appreciate that.
Thank you.
Actually, there is one thing.
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, look at me!
I'm flyin', by golly!
I'm happier than a tornado
in a trailer park!
I think it's about-a time
we redecorate.
Hi. Lightning McQueen told me
this was the best place in the world
to get tires.
How 'bout setting me and my friends up
with three or four sets each?
Guido! There is a real
Michael Schumacher Ferrari in my store.
A real Ferrari!
Punch me, Guido.
Punch me in the face.
This is the most glorious day
of my life.
Wow. [Italian]
Spero che il tuo amico si riprenda.
Mi dicono che siete fantastici.
- [Sighing]
- [Engine revving]
[Both chuckle]
Just passin' through?
Actually, I thought I'd stop
and stay awhile.
- I hear this place is back on the map.
- It is?
There's some rumor floating around
that some hotshot Piston Cup racecar
is setting up his big
racing headquarters here.
Really? Ah, well, there goes the town.
You know, I really missed you, Sally.
Well, I create feelings in others
they themselves don't understand and,
- blah, blah, blah.
- [Lightning chuckles]
McQueen and Sally
parked beneath the tree,
K-i-s-s...uh... i-n-t!
Great timing, Mater!
Hep-non, hip-hep, hi-li-lilly! Whee!
He's my best friend.
What're you gonna do?
So, Stickers, last one to Flo's buys?
I don't know.
Why don't we just take a drive?
Hmm... Nah.
Yeah! Ka-chow!
[~ John Mayer: Route 66]
[Yelling]
[Sirens blaring]
[Sniffing] Ah-choo!
[Mater] All right, everybody
please keep together now.
We is now entering the Doc Hudson
wing of the museum.
Wow. Unbelievable.
That many wins in a single season.
He's the real deal, Junior.
The Hudson Hornet was my inspiration.
Excuse me, son.
Is Doc Hudson here today?
Sorry, Mrs. The King, I think Doc
went out for a drive or somethin'.
- [Lightning] Whoo! Whoo!
- [Doc] Yeah!
Well, you sure ain't no dirt boy.
Not today, old man.
I know all your tricks.
[Growls]
Doc! Doc!
Whoo-ah!
[Doc] Not all my tricks, rookie!
[All grumble]
[Cheering]
Attention!
Kiss the pavement goodbye.
When I'm finished, you'll have mud
in places you didn't know you had!
- Yo, I've never been off-road!
- Well, that's gonna change right now!
About face!
Drop and give me 20 miles!
Go! Go!
Go, go, go, go, go! Go!
Man, now I got dirt in my rims!
- [Pole hits metal]
- Huh? Look at this!
It's my hood! It's my hood!
I ain't seen this thing in 20 years!
Well, it fits perfectly.
How do I look? Ah-choo!
Oh, dang.
You are a toy car!
You are a sad, strange little wagon
and you have my pity. Farewell.
[Woody Car] Oh, yeah?
Well, good riddance, you loony!
Hey, I hate to break up the road rally,
guys, but they're here!
Birthday guests at three o'clock!
[Chuckling] Oh, man! Whoever does
the voice of that piggy truck,
I'm tellin' ya, he's one great actor!
We're banished, genius! Stuck here
in this wasteland without chains!
But, Mike, the Boomobile's in trouble!
She needs our help!
- You're still not listening! [gasping]
- Ah!
Welcome to the Himalayas!
Snow cone?
Oh, that Abominable Snowplow
is quite the comic thespian!
Just get in there.
Go! Go, go, go!
Circus cars?
How can you be circus cars?
These are the lousiest
circus cars in the world,
and they're gonna make me rich!
Wait a minute here.
They're just usin' the same actor
over and over.
What kind of a cut-rate production
is this?
[~ Brad Paisley: Find Yourself]
[Minny moaning]
Oh, for the love of Chrysler, can we
please ask someone for directions?
No! There's an on-ramp close!
I know it! I can feel it!