[church bell tolling]
[metal creaking]
[♪ slow suspenseful
music playing]
[pulley creaking]
[indistinct conversation
in Italian]
[man] I told you
not to look for me.
[man 2] Please, Father.
[object rustling]
[man] That's all I have.
The only proof
of what they've done.
But she looks so...
[man] Human.
But don't let
yourself be fooled.
She wasn't
conceived naturally.
[♪ solemn choral
music playing]
They found a volunteer.
Someone devoted.
[man 2] But how did they...
[man] No, please.
I can't, uh...
I can't talk about that.
[breath shuddering]
[breathing quickening]
[gasping in fear]
[♪ sinister music playing]
What I can tell you...
is that the pregnancy
happened quickly.
[♪ sinister music continues]
She'll be in her teens now.
They're just waiting
until she's old enough.
Old enough for what?
[man] Now, please. [sighs]
[inhales]
I can't do this anymore.
[woman sobbing]
I can't.
But please
don't let it touch me again.
-[woman shuddering]
-[raspy breathing]
-[raspy breathing intensifies]
-[♪ tense music building]
[music stops]
Father?
[breathing heavily]
[♪ foreboding music playing]
Father Harris?
Father?
Hiding won't
absolve your sins.
[pulley creaking]
You think I want
to be forgiven? [scoffs]
-[creaking continues]
-[worker speaking Italian]
I don't want to be forgiven,
Father Brennan.
I just want it all to be over.
You'll understand...
-soon enough.
-[rope creaks]
-[worker shouts in panic]
-[metal clatters]
[eerie raspy breathing]
[soft clinking]
[raspy breathing continues]
[♪ eerie music playing]
[♪ music swells]
[music stops]
[grunting]
Father, are you all right?
I'm fine.
[glass shards crunching]
Father.
[♪ soft suspenseful
music playing]
[breath trembling]
[♪ pleasant classical
music playing]
[♪ pleasant classical music
continues playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[music fades out]
[announcer on PA]
Il volo sette quattro due,
in arrivo da Milano Linate,
arrivera con quindici minuti
di ritardo.
-Margaret Daino?
-Yes.
-Hi.
-I'm Father Gabriel.
-Hello. [chuckles]
Cardinal Lawrence sent me
to fetch you.
-Oh, sure. Thank you.
-Let me help you with that.
He's in the car outside.
I have heard
so much about you.
I feel like
I already know you.
Oh. [chuckles]
[Lawrence] Maggie!
-I'm so happy to see you.
-Oh, me too. [gasps]
Oh, it's so beautiful here.
It's like a dream.
Well, wait till you see
the actual city.
-[laughing]
-Look at you.
It hasn't been a year,
and somehow,
you've found a way
-to grow up even more.
-[chuckles]
Is that
all you've got?
That's it.
-Well, my word. Come on.
-[laughing]
I'll show you
to your new home.
[♪ Some Velvet Morning
by Nancy Sinatra
& Lee Hazlewood plays]
[horns honking]
So, what do you think?
It's wild.
Everything's so different.
Every street that we pass,
there's something to look at.
I just wanna explore.
[Lawrence]
Isn't it beautiful?
What better place
for you to be taking the veil?
It's wonderful
to see you, Maggie.
Even when you were little,
I knew you were destined
for great things.
-[window thuds]
-[gasps]
[Lawrence] See if you can get
around them, Damiano.
[car roof thuds]
[Lawrence] These protests
have picked up recently,
I'm afraid.
[Margaret]
What are they protesting?
[Lawrence] For the workers,
it's about conditions
and wages.
But for the students, well,
it's a rejection
of authority,
even the church.
The world is changing,
Maggie, very fast.
The younger generation
no longer turn to us
-for guidance, I'm afraid.
-[man] Ooh!
[Lawrence] But it's
a challenge we've embraced.
Perhaps you'll play your part
and help
earn back their trust.
I'll try.
Come la treccia!
[♪ choral music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[door opens]
[footsteps approaching]
Tu devi essere
la nostra bella Americana.
[Lawrence]
This is Sister Silva,
the Abbess.
And she'll take
good care of you.
-Hello.
-[Silva] Bellissima.
Welcome to our family.
Oh. [chuckles] Thank you.
Ooh. [chuckles]
Come. Come with me.
Let me give you a tour.
We're so happy
to have you here.
This way.
We take care of girls.
Girls only.
A total of 62.
Babies to 18 years of age.
Come this way.
Buongiorno.
[girls] Buongiorno. Hello.
[Margaret laughs] Buongiorno.
[babies crying]
The state has
contracted with us
to take in
many unmarried women
who are about to give birth.
We have
our birthing facilities
here in the hospital wing.
Come, come.
Our doctor will likely deliver
this baby within the week.
-Ciao, Lanoma.
-Salve.
-Come stai?
-Bene.
[Silva] Tranquilla.
Tutto va bene.
-Pazienza, hmm?
-[woman crying]
Andiamo.
[humming softly]
Sister Anjelica.
This is Margaret Daino
from America.
[♪ cryptic music plays]
She grew up here.
Abandoned on our front steps,
and very ill.
But she's very devoted
and she keeps
all the children smiling.
-And they all seem very happy.
-[girls shouting]
[girl screaming]
Scusi.
I should see
what the trouble is.
Of course.
[nun] Via dal
cancello faccello.
[girl whispering] La tua
suora e sempre gentilissima.
[♪ girls singing in classroom]
[girl continues whispering]
[♪ girl in room singing]
♪ Ave Maria ♪
♪ Gratia plena ♪
[door creaking]
[soft scratching]
♪ Dominus tecum ♪
♪ Sancta Maria ♪
♪ Mater Dei♪
Amen.
Hail Mary.
Um...
Ave Maria is my favorite, too.
Il mio preferito.
[chuckles] What's your name?
Come ti chiami?
I'm Margaret.
Mi chiami Margaret.
[chuckles]
Hi.
[metal clinking]
[♪ soft suspenseful
music playing]
Um... [gasps]
What are you doing?
Get off of me!
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[footsteps approaching]
[Silva] Oh, there you are.
Have you been
behaving yourself, Carlita?
Carlita.
Did you do that drawing
outside, Carlita?
The one where
the girl's floating
above the other girls?
I thought it was very nice.
[paper rustling]
Thank you.
Come.
Why is she kept alone
like that
in the middle of the day?
It's safer.
She hurt another child
just yesterday.
Luca will be your driver.
Rome has become
a bit dangerous
with the protests.
[♪ Our Love by Percy Faith
playing on record player]
[door opens]
[suitcase thuds]
[door closes]
Hello?
[♪ slow suspenseful
music playing]
[music fades out]
[exhales]
By Your divine mercy,
rein in the power of evil.
Build us into living stones
of a culture of life,
who demonstrates
in both deed and word,
the truth that every life,
no matter its conditions,
-is precious and unrepeatable.
-[wind blowing]
Lord, speak
to every human heart
and fill it
with the conviction:
I am wanted.
I have a task in history.
I am accepted, and I am loved.
-It is good that I exist.
-[doorknob clicks]
[♪ choral music
playing distantly]
[woman sighs]
Margaret's one of
our worst-behaved children...
[rattling]
[woman 2 whispers] What if
she has another episode?
[woman] Then you must
tie her to the bed.
Here. Let me show you.
[wind blowing]
-[voice cries out]
-[gasps]
[door shuts]
[footsteps]
[keys clatter]
[breath shudders]
-Hi.
-[gasps]
Mierda.
Ah, you must be Margaretta.
-Yes.
-[chuckles softly]
-I'm Luz. [smooches]
-Oh. [chuckles]
Did I wake you?
No, no. Um...
-I was having a nightmare.
-Oh.
First night nerves?
Don't worry,
same thing happened for me.
If we can't admit
how we are feeling,
our dreams do it for us,
right?
You're a novitiate?
[Luz] Oh, yeah.
I just figured a little
exploration is healthy
before the big day.
I mean, I will be hiding
this body [chuckles]
under a habit
for the rest of my life.
So, why not let it breathe
a little now?
Coffee?
[chuckles softly]
[♪ sentimental music playing]
So how does a girl from...
Uh, Pittsfield.
Massachusetts.
So how does a girl
from Pissfield
end up in Italy
about to take the veil?
Well, Cardinal Lawrence
was, um, a priest
at the orphanage
that I grew up in.
-Mm-hmm.
-And we got pretty close
because, uh,
well, I was somewhat
of a problem child.
[chuckles]
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
You were a problem child?
[chuckles]
Like how?
[Margaret] I don't know.
I guess, uh...
I mean,
I used to get punished a lot.
And how did they punish you?
[chuckling]
And where did you get these?
Hey.
And you are a nosy girl.
Do you know that?
[both chuckling]
Well, would they beat you?
Would they beat me?
No, not really.
I used to have
a pretty active imagination.
I'd get so convinced sometimes
that what I was seeing
was real
that the sisters
would need to, um...
subdue me.
But then Cardinal Lawrence
came to the orphanage,
and, uh,
he was really great, you know.
He really helped me to see
that all that stuff
was just in my head.
Things got a lot better
for me after that.
For me,
it was a voice.
[sighs] I was 16.
Just kicked out of the house.
It was so cold that night,
and I didn't know what to do.
And then...
this warm wind came...
out of nowhere.
And suddenly it was as if
His voice was all around me.
[♪ ethereal music playing]
Inside me even.
So clearly.
And He told me
it didn't matter
if I had no earthly home
because my true home
was with Him.
And for the first time
in my life,
I felt like I belonged
on this Earth.
[laughter]
[indistinct chatter]
[nun] Yes, but
even with the most handsome
milkman in town,
we still had
a whole group of us
who took the veil together.
Yes. Now, instead,
girls go off to college
and poor Luz
is taking the veil alone. Hmm.
-Hmm. And Margaret...
-[Margaret] Mm.
Margaret will be alone
in the chapel, too.
[chuckles] Don't worry.
I'll warm it up for you.
[both chuckling]
Warm up?
What is this "warm it up"?
As if Mr. Milkman
didn't teach you.
-[gasps]
-[nuns exclaiming]
-[laughs] I'm sorry!
-[nuns laughing]
-[nun 2] It's true!
Practice it again.
[clears throat]
Sono una farfalla.
[Margaret laughs]
E devo volare.
[girls laughing]
No, no, no. Shy American.
Say it with passione.
[Margaret] With passione?
[laughs]
-Okay. All right.
-[girls laugh]
Sono una...
-[girls] Farfalla.
-Farfalla.
E devo volare.
Good?
-[girl] Good.
-[girls applauding]
-Yeah?
-[girl] Yeah.
What does it mean?
"I am a teacher
and I love to teach."
-[Margaret chuckles]
-[girls laughing]
Oh.
-Hmm. [chuckles]
-[girls continue laughing]
[Silva on PA] Silenzio.
Silenzio, ragazze.
[quiet chattering
and laughing]
Padre nostro,
che sei nei cieli,
sia santificato il tuo nome,
venga il tuo regno,
sia fatta la tua volonta,
come in cielo cosi in terra.
-[♪ suspenseful music playing]
-Dacci oggi
il nostro pane quotidiano,
e rimetti...
[girl whimpering]
[woman whispering in Italian]
[girl sobbing]
[woman continues whispering
in Italian]
-[girl gasping]
-[bed rattling]
[nun] No! No!
[shackle fastens]
-[nun speaks Italian]
-[girl crying]
-[door shuts]
-[gasps]
[woman giggling]
[breath shuddering]
[continues giggling]
[gasps]
[giggles]
[Margaret shudders]
-[whispers] Margaret.
-[gasps]
There you are. [laughs]
I'm sorry I scared you.
Come on.
I have something
to show you for tonight.
You're gonna love it.
[chuckles]
[romantic Italian song
playing]
[sighs]
[Luz] Ah-ha!
There she is.
Oh, my God, you look hot.
-I look naked.
-Yes.
What do you mean, naked?
You look gorgeous.
Come on.
Up with your foot.
-The other one.
-Oh!
[sighs] Mother Mary.
[chuckles] Don't be nervous.
Can you stand?
No. [chuckles]
Yes, you can.
-[grunts]
-Hmm? Whoop.
Perfect.
Luz?
Yeah?
I can't do this.
Tell me.
Have you ever been to a bar?
[chuckles] No.
-A disco?
-No.
Anything at all?
Because your whole life,
you've wanted
to give yourself
only to Him, right?
Look, I know.
I know it's scary coming out
from under the habit,
but look at you!
You're a very beautiful girl,
Margaretta.
And you have to understand
that about yourself.
If only to know
what it means to give it up.
So, let yourself feel it.
Okay?
Be brave.
[♪ Rumore by Raffaella Carra
playing on speakers]
[indistinct chatter]
So...
To the bravest girl I know.
Go.
[grunts, coughs]
-Do you still feel your feet?
-[clears throat]
-[exhales sharply]
-Oh, my.
Hmm?
Do you still feel your feet?
-Yes.
-[chuckles]
Okay. Another, then.
[man] Hello.
-Parlate italiano?
-What?
Parlate italiano?
Ah, no.
Not when I'm drinking.
Too hard.
Inglese, per favore, no?
If you can.
I'm Alfonzo,
and this is Paolo.
Hi.
Uh, we can buy you a drink
if you want.
[♪ Domani by Raffaella Carra
playing on speakers]
[Luz laughing]
Excuse me.
Um...
Can I have a sip of that?
Ah, yeah, eat it.
Eh... [chuckles awkwardly]
-Eat it?
-Yes. Eat it.
I was watching this movie
with my mother yesterday.
-Yeah?
-And, um...
And was
with Barbara Streisand,
and I just... I don't know.
I love her and...
-You do?
-I do.
-Barbra?
-I love Barbara.
-Yes, Barbara Streisand.
-[imitates Paolo] Barbara?
-Barbra, yeah.
-[laughs]
I mean, it was the part
with the "Hello, gorgeous."
[imitating Barbra]
Hello, gorgeous.
Gorgeous.
[both laughing]
Uh, what? Gorgeous.
-Gor... Gorgeous.
-[imitates Barbra] Gorgeous.
You know, it's... Sorry
if I'm not a "professional..."
-[chuckles] It was good.
-...like Barbra.
But, um, what do you...
what do you do?
Um...
[clears throat]
Well, since you asked, um...
[in Italian]
-Volare?
-Volare. [chuckles]
[chuckles]
[in English] Okay.
[in Italian]
-[in English] What?
-Dai... dai!
-Come on.
-Where are you going?
[Paolo] Come on.
[♪ I've Got to Use
My Imagination playing]
♪ I've really got to use ♪
♪ My imagination ♪
♪ To think of good reasons ♪
♪ To keep on keepin' on ♪
♪ Keep on keepin' on ♪
♪ Got to make the best of ♪
♪ Best of, best of ♪
♪ A bad situation ♪
♪ Bad situation ♪
♪ Ever since that day ♪
-♪ Ever since that day ♪
-♪ I woke up and found ♪
♪ That you were gone ♪
♪ Gone, gone ♪
-♪ Darkness all around me ♪
-[breathing heavily]
♪ Blockin' out the sun ♪
♪ Old friends call me ♪
[Margaret laughing]
♪ But I just don't feel
like talkin' to anyone ♪
♪ Emptiness has found me ♪
♪ And it just won't
let me go ♪
♪ I go right on livin' ♪
♪ But why...♪
[♪ Need Your Loving
by the Flirtations playing]
♪ Need your loving, baby,
stand by me ♪
♪ Who could I turn to
if you leave me? ♪
♪ Without you,
where would I be? ♪
♪ There'll be a change in me ♪
♪ You'll see
Believe me, baby, yeah ♪
-♪ Need your loving ♪
-♪ Don't you hear me? ♪
-♪ Want your loving ♪
-♪ So bad ♪
♪ Didn't you hear me? ♪
♪ Baby, don't you know
that I need ♪
-♪ Need your loving ♪
-♪ Your loving ♪
-♪ Got to have your love♪
-♪ Oh♪
[music stops abruptly]
[heavy breathing]
[grunts softly]
[groans softly]
[man on radio]
This is the BBC World Service,
and it's the 3rd of June,
1971.
Riots have erupted in Rome,
with clashes between
the far left
and far right groups
escalating rapidly.
The unrest has caused
widespread damage to property
and has left
several people injured.
Italian authorities
are struggling
to contain the violence
and restore order.
Public transportation,
factories,
and schools
are heavily affected...
Good morning.
Did you have fun last night?
Yeah.
[chuckles]
I'm guessing you've never
drunk like that before.
[chuckles]
I didn't, like,
embarrass myself
or anything last night,
did I?
No. No.
Okay. [chuckles]
You were well-behaved.
Mostly.
Okay. I found you before
anything got out of control.
And for the record,
I was a very nice friend.
You came home with me.
Thanks.
But it wasn't easy
pulling you away from him.
What do you mean?
I didn't...
Uh...
[chuckles]
Let's just say
you took my advice to heart.
You were a very brave girl,
Margaretta.
-[chuckles lightly]
-[Luz] But, hey, don't worry.
It's our little secret. Okay?
-[♪ eerie music playing]
-[breathing shakily]
[indistinct whispering]
[whispering prayer]
I am loved. I am accepted.
It is good
to be a human being.
It is good to be alive.
[whispering indistinctly]
[voices whispering
indistinctly]
[♪ eerie music building]
[♪ solemn choral
music playing]
-[music fades out]
-[people chattering]
[Brennan] Excuse me.
May I sit?
No, please, please stay.
[Margaret] I'm sorry.
Do I know you?
My name is Father Brennan.
I apologize for startling you.
Please sit with me.
This will only take
a few minutes.
Your name is Margaret Daino.
You work at the orphanage.
You're new there.
I don't understand.
How do you know that?
It's about the girl. Scianna.
Carlita?
You must be very careful,
Margaret.
Bad things will start
to happen around her.
Evil things.
No, I have to go now.
No, no. Please, please.
Come see me tonight.
Saint Rita cloister, room 42.
I'll tell you everything.
[gasps softly]
[♪ suspenseful music building]
-[music stops]
-[all] Good morning, farfalla.
[girls laughing]
Good morning.
[girl] What's wrong?
Nothing.
Just a little tired,
that's all.
[girls laughing
and chattering]
Where's Carlita?
She's in the bad room.
The bad room?
[Silva] Dirty.
Dirty.
[girls] Dirty.
[Margaret] Sister.
[panting]
Sister, I need your help.
Uh...
Carlita, she's locked
in a room.
[Silva] That's right.
She bit Sister Romano
just this morning,
so she had to go
to the bad room.
Sister,
why is there a bad room?
Because some girls are bad.
[sketching]
[♪ low eerie music playing]
[doorknob rattles]
This room is suffocating.
It's not meant to be pleasant.
The things we do
aren't always pleasant,
but they are
in the name of God.
[♪ soft choral music playing]
[Margaret]
Do you wanna talk about
why they put you in that room?
Sono cattiva.
I'm bad.
[Margaret]
Oh. You're bad.
[sighs]
Well, guess who else was bad.
Who?
-You?
-[chuckles softly]
Mm-hmm.
Oh, yeah.
But you know what?
I realized that I'm not bad.
They just tell you
that you are
because you're not doing
what they want you to do.
Back then, I used to think
that there was something
really, really wrong with me.
What did you do?
[inhales]
Well, I guess at first,
I tried to run away.
But, uh,
it didn't fix the feeling.
That's what I like
about you, actually.
What?
What do you like about me?
I think that you feel
the same way that I felt.
But you're not scared,
you don't run away.
You just...
You raise your little claws,
and you fight.
-[growls]
-[woman screams]
Carlita, go to
your room, okay?
-I'll be right there.
-[woman screams]
[panting]
-[woman whimpering]
-[tools clacking]
[woman screams,
breathing heavily]
-[doctor] Infermiera,
la regga.
-[nurse] Si, dottore.
-[breathing shallowly]
-[doctor] Forcipe, per favore.
[nurse] Forcipe.
[woman whimpering]
[woman panting]
[indistinct conversation]
-[whimpering]
-[nurse] Stia ferma.
-No! [screaming]
-[forceps snip]
-[gas hissing]
-[nurse] Stia buona!
[muffled screaming]
[screaming slows down, stops]
[♪ choral music playing]
[chuckling softly]
[laughing]
[woman continues laughing]
[laughing heartily]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[breath trembling]
[continues laughing]
[grunting]
[gasps]
-[screaming]
-[shackles clanking]
[indistinct conversation]
[screaming continues]
[breathing heavily]
-[girls screaming distantly]
-[woman continues screaming]
[gasping violently]
[woman and indistinct
voices screaming]
[continues screaming]
-[screaming stops]
-[♪ eerie operatic
music plays]
[gasps]
[♪ music swells]
[music stops]
[eerie voices whispering]
[nurse]
Everything looks all right.
You did say you didn't
eat much in the morning.
-Mm.
-May be low blood sugar.
[Margaret] I'm so sorry.
Sorry? Margaret, what for?
You wouldn't be
the first to faint
witnessing the birth
of a child.
Frankly, I'm surprised
it doesn't happen more often.
The miracle of life
can be a messy business.
[chattering in Italian]
[laughing]
[♪ girls singing]
♪ Tutti giu per terra ♪
♪ Giro girotondo ♪
♪ L'angelo e biondo
Biondo e il grano ♪
♪ Tutti ci sediamo ♪
♪ Giro girotondo
Il mare e fondo ♪
♪ Tonda e la terra
Tutti giu per terra! ♪
♪ Giro girotondo
L'angelo e biondo ♪
♪ Biondo e il grano
Tutti ci sediamo!♪
[♪ cryptic music playing]
[whispering indistinctly]
You guys mind if I join?
Carlita, did you do
this drawing?
[Anjelica] This part is mine.
[in Italian]
[smacks lips]
[in English]
Uh, I don't think
that that's very
appropriate, Sister.
[♪ unsettling music playing]
[girls]
♪ Casca il mondo
Casca la terra ♪
♪ Tutti giu per terra ♪
♪ Giro girotondo
Il mare e fondo ♪
♪ Tonda e la terra
Tutti giu per terra ♪
♪ Giro girotondo
L'angelo e biondo ♪
♪ Biondo e il grano
Tutti ci sediamo!♪
You all right?
Yes?
[Margaret gasps]
[girls laughing]
[gasps]
[girl] Andiamo!
Um...
Here. Let's...
Let's go for a walk.
♪ Tonda e la terra
Tutti giu per terra! ♪
-Join the group.
-Oh, not today, girls.
-[girl] Come on!
-[Margaret chuckles] Okay.
-[girls] Venite, venite!
-[Margaret laughing]
No, no, no, not me.
It's all right. It's okay.
You ready?
[♪ girls and Margaret singing]
♪ Giro girotondo ♪
[girls]
♪ Casca il mondo
Casca la terra♪
♪ Tutti giu per terra!♪
♪ Giro girotondo
Il mare e fondo ♪
♪ Tonda e la terra
Tutti giu per terra!♪
[♪ slow suspenseful
music playing]
♪ Giro girotondo
Il pane e cotto in forno ♪
♪ Buona e la ciambella
Tutti giu per terra!♪
-[singing ends]
-[girls laughing]
[Anjelica giggling]
[nuns murmuring]
[continues giggling]
It's all for you.
[Margaret] Oh, no.
No, no, no, don't. Don't!
Don't!
-[Margaret gasps]
-[girls screaming]
[screaming]
[both gasp]
[shrieks]
[screaming]
[nun shouting in Italian]
[girls screaming]
-[panicked chatter]
-[♪ eerie operatic
music plays]
[breathing shakily]
[music fades out]
[♪ slow suspenseful
music playing]
-[voice 1] Psst. Psst, psst.
-[voice 2 speaks indistinctly]
-[knock at door]
-[door unlocking]
Margaret. Come in.
[wind howling]
Something happened, didn't it?
Yes. Um...
One of the sisters
took her own life.
You mentioned
the name "Scianna."
That's right.
[breathes heavily]
I assume you know
these people.
The priest is named Spiletto.
He's a radical.
Yes, I've seen him.
Turn it over.
[Margaret] The baby
in this photo is Carlita?
[Brennan] I believe so.
[Margaret] And this is why
she's in danger?
I know these sisters.
They're women of God.
They belong to the Church.
Listen to me, Margaret.
The truth is
there are two Churches.
The one that follows
the teachings of Christ,
the one that you and I
are part of.
And the other.
The Church
that will turn a blind eye
to torture, to rape.
To commit murder
in the name of God.
All in the name
of supreme power.
What do you think that Church
is most frightened of?
The Devil?
Secularism.
We are living
in unprecedented times.
Look at what's been occurring
in your very own generation.
A culture that is outspoken,
rebelling.
Sometimes violently.
People are turning away
from the church in droves.
And, Margaret,
you know as well as I do
that belief is power.
Now, how do you control people
who no longer believe
in your stories
of fire and brimstone?
People who do not
seem to fear?
You create something to fear.
This Church has maintained
power for generations.
Thousands of years.
And they will stop at nothing
to keep it that way.
[breathing shakily]
So,
a small,
but very powerful group
of priests and bishops,
even higher,
they decided
something drastic
had to be done.
These priests... [shuddering]
...believe they can birth
the Antichrist
and then control him.
Allow him to bring
his dark forces
to bear on the world
just enough
to drive people
back to the Church.
That's insane.
Yes. Don't you see?
If no one believes
such a thing can exist,
who will stand in their way?
[sighs] Uh...
What does any of this
have to do with Carlita?
I was excommunicated.
My contacts within the Church
are very limited.
That photo is all I have
to go on.
But I believe the baby girl
in the picture
is to be the mother.
The mother of what?
Of the Antichrist?
Yes.
Oh, my God. You're crazy.
Look, if I am right,
Carlita would have been born
on the sixth day
of the sixth month at 6 a.m.
666.
It's the mark of the Devil
which she will have
on her body.
I don't understand
why you're telling me this.
They're keeping her files
at the orphanage.
Locked away.
I need you to get them to me.
I need to know
how she was born.
What do you mean,
how she was born?
Listen to me, Margaret.
There is a beast
they're mating.
-A jackal. That's the father.
-[gasping]
-I have to go now.
-No, no, Margaret.
If Carlita is, in fact,
the mother,
the evil inside her will do
whatever it takes to stop us.
We must destroy it
at all costs.
-Do you understand?
-No.
Carlita is a little girl.
And she is not pregnant.
But we're not talking
about a human child!
It's almost June 6th.
Look, we haven't a lot of time
and I need your help.
No, you need a doctor.
I'm sorry
that I can't help you.
Will you let go of my arm?
[latches unlocking]
-[♪ suspenseful music playing]
-[indistinct chatter]
Oh. Margaret.
-Hi.
-How are you feeling?
Um, I need to talk to you
about Carlita.
Do you know anything
about her history,
or how she came
to the orphanage?
Um, not off the top
of my head. Why?
Do you know where I could find
that kind of information?
I'm afraid this is not really
my area, you know?
[man on radio
speaking Italian]
[indistinct chatter]
[radio chatter in Italian
continues]
[♪ suspenseful music
continues playing]
What?
Why do you keep
staring at me?
[margaret chuckles]
I'm not.
Will you come with me?
Come on.
I need to talk to you
about something.
But before I do, I...
I just want you to know
that you can trust me, okay?
Okay.
Um...
Has anyone ever
done anything to you
that might have scared you
or upset you?
Uh...
I don't know.
What don't you know?
[inhales]
Sometimes I get this...
bad feelings.
I see...
I see things.
[breath trembling]
And I can't tell
if they're real or not.
Listen to me.
When I was younger,
I... I used to have these
horrible visions.
They were so terrible that I
convinced myself
that they were real.
But I learned
that those thoughts,
they were just lies.
Just tricks that my brain
was playing on me
because I was so unhappy.
This isn't a lie.
How can you know that
for certain?
Carlita.
I'm sorry.
[sighs] Carlita. I'm sorry.
[woman giggling]
[♪ cryptic music plays]
[gasps]
There you are.
A riot's broken out.
We must go.
[guard] Deve andare adesso!
Deve andare adesso!
[people clamoring]
[protestors yelling]
[Margaret] Listen.
It's all right, girls.
It's okay.
Stay close to me, okay?
Oh.
[protestors chanting
indistinctly]
Stay close to me, okay?
[gasping]
[protestors clamoring]
Carlita!
[molotov shatters]
[explosion]
[gasps]
[Margaret grunting]
[continues grunting]
[Margaret gasps]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[screaming]
-[shout echoes]
-[ambient noises fade]
[♪ surreal choral
music playing]
[♪ surreal music intensifies]
[Silva] Silenzio.
Silenzio.
[music fades out]
Silenzio, ragazze.
[on PA] Padre nostro,
che sei nei cieli,
sia santificato
il tuo nome,
venga il tuo regno...
[voice fading out]
[nun whispering] Margaretta.
Sister Silva would like
to see you in her office.
Please take a seat.
[clears throat]
Margaret...
Part of my job here
is to look out
for the well-being
of all those
who are under my care.
I'm sure this will come
as no surprise,
but I've become concerned.
I'm fine. [chuckles]
Perhaps I should have
put it this way.
We are concerned.
Myself and Cardinal Lawrence.
We think it might be time
for you to take a step back.
And perhaps
we postpone your vows.
What? No. Why?
We're also concerned about
your attachment to Carlita.
Carlita?
-But...
-Cardinal Lawrence told me
about your troubles
growing up.
Your hallucinations.
Perhaps being around Carlita
is not what's right for you.
[voices whispering]
[Silva] Carlita is disturbed.
And her illness
must not infect us
as her caretakers.
And clearly, it has.
[whispering stops]
Wait.
I'm not ill.
I understand
how hard you had to work
to get to where you are.
It would be a shame
to give it all up now.
I am the only one
who cares about her.
You don't let her play
-with the other girls.
-I've told you...
-You keep her in the bad room.
-...we're only doing
what's right for her.
The girl is sick in the head.
-Because of you!
-[nuns gasp, whisper]
[breathes shakily]
If there was any doubt
in our decision,
you've all but confirmed it.
You're clearly unwell.
And, Margaret,
you will keep your distance
from Carlita.
Or there will be consequences.
[♪ discordant music playing]
Stop the car, Luca.
I can just walk home
from here, okay?
You don't have to wait.
Paolo.
Paolo!
[Paolo] No, no, no.
Lasciami stare,
ti pego, ti prego.
Paolo?
Just leave me alone, please.
Hey!
Sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
-Really, I didn't know.
-You didn't know what?
Just stop following me!
[breathing heavily]
Paolo, talk to me.
-Just look for the mark.
-[tires screeching]
-[gasps]
-[car crashes]
-[breathing shakily]
-[concerned chatter]
[metal creaks]
[engine stalling]
[Paolo grunts]
[gasps]
-[strained grunting]
-Oh, okay.
-All right. Oh, God. Okay.
-[grunts]
-All right. Um...
-[engine stalling]
Hey, call an...
call an ambulance.
[sobbing] Call an ambulance.
-Help me.
-[Margaret] I'm gonna
help you.
I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
[Margaret]
I'm gonna help you.
-I can't move.
-[Margaret] I know.
-I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
-I know. Okay.
[Paolo sobs]
-I'm scared.
-[Margaret] Paolo,
you're gonna be fine,
I promise.
I don't wanna die.
[sobbing] No, no, no.
You're not gonna die,
-you're gonna be okay.
-[Paolo speaks indistinctly]
[sobs]
[Margaret] You ready?
-[Margaret grunts]
-[Paolo groans]
-[woman screams]
-[crowd gasps]
[whispering] Oh, no, no.
Oh, God.
[crying] Oh, no, God.
[♪ ominous music playing]
[gasps]
[screams]
[whispering prayer]
[voices whispering]
[♪ ominous music
continues playing]
[♪ maniacal operatic
music playing]
[voices whispering]
[voices continue whispering]
[girls whispering]
[chattering in Italian]
[girls continue whispering]
[♪ solemn choral
music playing]
Shh.
[♪ solemn choral music
continues playing]
In nomine Patris, et Filii,
et Spiritus Sancti.
[all] Amen.
[♪ solemn choral music
continues playing]
Deus,
benedice hunc anulum.
Da ut soror
quae induat altam fidem
in te habeat et remaneat
tibi fidelis in omni tempore.
Accipe hunc anulum,
nam aeterno Regi spondes.
Serva fidem cum sponso tuo
ut ad cenam nuptialem
aeternae gaudii venias.
Amen.
[girls and nuns] Amen.
-[♪ tense music playing]
-[panting]
[exhales]
[nuns laughing outside]
[metal clinking]
[panting]
[voices whispering]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[voices continue whispering]
[exhales]
[whispering stops]
[door creaking]
[voices chanting indistinctly]
[breathing heavily]
[voices continue chanting]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[grunts quietly]
-[Luz grunts]
-[breathing heavily]
[♪ ethereal music
continues playing]
[exhales sharply]
[light crackles]
[♪ tense music playing]
[crackling]
[gasps]
[♪ tense music
continues playing]
[whispering prayer in Latin]
[all whispering in Latin]
[all continue
whispering in Latin]
[light crackling]
[♪ tense music intensifies]
[music stops]
[panting]
[softly] Oh, god.
[girls chattering]
Come on.
[girls]
Farfalla! Farfalla!
[Margaret] Oh, God.
Carlita.
Come with me, Carlita.
[gasps]
[panting]
Okay, you go to the bed.
I am so sorry
that I didn't believe you.
But I believe you now.
-Okay?
-[muffled chattering]
I'm gonna keep you safe.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
-[banging on door]
-[Silva] Margaret.
Go, go, go. Over there.
[insistent banging on door]
[muffled clamoring]
-[Gabriel] Margaret.
-You stay away. [gasping]
I know what you're doing.
We don't want to hurt you.
Just put that down.
I know what you've done
with the babies.
You stay away! No!
You stay away from me!
-[Margaret sobbing]
-[Carlita screaming]
-[Romano] Remain calm!
-[Margaret] No, no, no!
-[whimpering]
-[Carlita screaming]
[breath shuddering]
[gasping]
Please, please, I'm sorry.
No, no, no!
Not in there! Not in there!
Not in there!
No! No! No!
-[door locks]
-[panting]
Let me out!
Please let me out! [sobbing]
Please!
[hyperventilating]
[gasping for air]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[softly] Breathe. Breathe.
[breathing slowing down]
[quiet raspy breathing]
[♪ ethereal music
continues playing]
[female voice chanting
in Latin]
[music fades out]
[chanting stops]
[girl whispering in Latin]
[girl] Crucifxus mortuu.
Sede da divinum.
[woman whispering]
...conviction:
I am wanted.
I have a task in history.
[voices overlapping]
I am accepted.
It is good that I exist.
It is good
to be a human being.
[voices continue whispering]
Let every human heart
experience your love.
[gasps]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[breath shuddering]
[screaming]
[shackles rattling]
[growling]
[screaming]
[gasps]
[shudders]
It's not real.
[breathing heavily]
It's not real. It's not real.
[woman whispers]
What's not real?
Who said that?
[woman giggles]
-[breath shuddering]
-[quiet footsteps]
[soft squelching]
[faint laugh]
[heavy breathing]
[soft squelching]
[giggling]
[shuddering]
[snorts]
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
-[giggling]
-[squelching]
[screams]
[screaming]
No!
-Margaret. We have to go.
-[gasping]
We have to go.
I found the files.
We have to go now.
It's just me.
[panting]
Get me out of here.
Yes. I know. I know.
[knocking at door]
All right, all right.
Father Gabriel. Margaret.
I don't understand.
How?
Oh, well done, Margaret.
Well done.
Were you followed?
[Gabriel] What? No.
I don't think so.
Luca, Margaret's driver,
brought us.
We can trust him.
He's keeping watch outside.
You two know each other?
-Yes.
-[Gabriel] No.
Uh, he tried approaching me.
I thought he was crazy.
[hesitantly] It is crazy.
Carlita.
We have to go get her.
[Gabriel] No, it's not safe.
Not safe?
She's the one who's not safe
right now, Gabriel.
Margaret,
after what just happened,
they're not gonna let us
anywhere near that orphanage.
Especially Carlita.
[Brennan] He's right.
It's only a matter of time
before they realize
we've got these.
And when they do,
they will come for us.
We have to help her.
The only path forward
is to prove what they've done.
Otherwise, no one will believe
a word we say.
[thunder rumbling]
There's so many of them.
Yes.
Too many.
I had no idea
they'd gone to such lengths.
I don't understand.
They need a male.
They've only birthed females.
They've all died
except for Carlita.
After all these years,
so many failures...
They believe the only way
is for the beast to mate
with its own offspring.
What is this?
I told you, it's the photo
from Carlita's birth.
No.
This.
[Brennan] It's the mark.
Carlita doesn't have the mark
on her head.
Hers is here.
[Brennan]
What are you talking about?
I've seen it.
You see? Carlita.
No mark.
The baby in this photo
is not Carlita.
What does that mean?
Brennan?
I don't know.
Well, if this is the child
that we're looking for,
then all we have to do
is find a baby
with the mark on its scalp.
We must have
missed something.
Right?
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[gasps]
Where is it?
Why do they all
look like this?
[Brennan] The father.
He's not human.
[♪ suspenseful music
continues playing]
[music fades out]
It's her.
There was another survivor.
[Gabriel] A sister?
Did you know about this?
No.
They must have kept it
hidden away.
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[breath shuddering]
[muted] Look for the mark.
How did he know?
He knew where it was.
[♪ eerie surreal
music playing]
[♪ surreal music intensifying]
[♪ dramatic music building]
-[music fades out]
-[soft clinking]
[soft creaking]
[♪ unsettling music building]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[music stops]
[♪ mystical music playing]
[female voices chanting
in Latin]
[♪ mystical music continues]
[female voices continue
chanting in Latin]
[chanting intensifying]
[chanting stops]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[Margaret gasping]
[gasping in fear]
[shuddering]
[Margaret hyperventilating]
-[jackal growls]
-[screams]
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[screaming and sobbing]
Margaret, Margaret. Hush.
[shushes]
-Margaret. Margaret.
-[continues screaming]
Margaret. [shushes]
Just let me have a look.
Let me look.
[Brennan breathing shakily]
Uh...
[breath trembling]
[breathing heavily]
Somebody say something.
[Gabriel]
How is that possible?
[Brennan] She's been
a ward of the Church
her entire life.
They must have
moved her around
to cover their tracks.
Carlita must be too young,
so they brought Margaret back
to Rome to...
[Margaret] To what?
To what?
[shudders]
I have to get out of here.
-You can't leave.
-Don't touch me.
-Margaret...
-Don't you touch me!
...you can't just leave.
Touch me again,
I'll fucking kill you!
[Margaret sobbing]
[Brennan] I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry this is happening
to you, my child.
But nothing will change
if you decide to leave.
It's June 6th.
Midnight.
They will be coming for you.
[Margaret] If this is true...
[sighs]
If I am pregnant...
then I need it out of me.
I need it out of me now.
[♪ somber choral
music playing]
[Brennan] Margaret,
you all right?
This doctor knows
what he's doing?
He's experienced, yes.
[engine accelerating]
[grunts softly]
-[groans]
-[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[car accelerating]
[engine accelerating]
[Gabriel] Wait. Stop.
What are you doing?
-[groans]
-Don't stop.
Make like you're heading
for the main road
and then turn off
before the arch.
[groans]
[breathing shakily]
[sighs in relief]
[Margaret retching]
[Margaret coughs]
Margaret.
-[coughing]
-[♪ suspenseful music plays]
[heavy breathing]
What's happening to me?
[breath trembling]
[tires skid]
[glass shards clattering]
-[church bell tolling]
-[crickets chirping]
[moans, inhales deeply]
[exhales]
[inhales deeply]
[groaning]
[shuddering]
[grunting convulsively]
[moaning shakily]
[grunts]
[gasping convulsively]
[grunting and gasping]
[♪ eerie music playing]
[grunting intensifying]
[screams]
[laughs]
[gasping convulsively]
[grunting aggressively]
[grunting in deep voice]
[straining]
[grunting and panting]
[panting tiredly]
[♪ eerie music
continues playing]
[screaming in cracked voice]
[screaming stops]
[♪ sinister music playing]
-[soft creaking]
-[soft clinking]
-[gasps]
-[♪ music swells]
[shuddering]
[shackles rattling]
[whimpering]
[Margaret] Hello?
[shouts] hello?
Can anyone hear me?
-[Lawrence] Yes.
-[gasps]
I can hear.
[breath trembling]
I can't tell
if this is real or not.
This is very real, Margaret.
Can you untie me?
[Lawrence] Soon.
Soon it will be all over,
I promise.
[crying] No.
-No, no.
-Oh. Oh...
You don't have to be afraid.
I won't let anything bad
happen to you.
[♪ solemn choral
music playing]
I've watched over you
since you were a little girl.
The very first moment we met,
do you remember
what I said to you?
That you, Margaret,
were the bravest girl
I'd ever known.
Now you know how special
you are to me.
To us.
[shackles rattle]
The baby you're about to bear
will redeem the Church.
Will bring the people
back to God.
All because of you.
Don't you understand,
Margaret?
Your whole life,
you've been searching,
waiting for His voice.
But the truth is...
He was always there with you.
He brought you here.
He chose you.
I... No.
[soft creaking]
[groans softly]
[Lawrence] There.
You're ready now.
-Please know that I love you.
-[Margaret whimpering]
I'll be right here.
[♪ pensive music playing]
[shackles rattle]
[Margaret breathing heavily]
[♪ pensive choral
music playing]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[gasping]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
-[nurse] Stay down.
-[music stops]
[music fades out]
-[panting]
-[tools clacking]
[whimpers]
[sobbing]
[♪ eerie music playing]
No, no. [hyperventilating]
No, no. Please.
[whimpering]
[shackles rattling]
Please, please, please.
No.
No, no, no.
No, please.
[Margaret gasping]
Please.
[gasps sharply]
[hyperventilating]
[groans, sobbing]
[Margaret panting]
[Margaret continues sobbing]
Help me, please.
Please help me. Please.
Please untie me.
Please untie me, I'm in pain.
[Margaret sobbing]
I'm in pain. Please.
Help. [continues sobbing]
Help me, please.
-Please help me.
-[shackles rattling]
Help me.
Help. I'm in pain.
-[Margaret hyperventilating]
-[shackles rattling]
-[bed rattling]
-[breathing heavily]
[♪ disquieting music playing]
What is it? A boy or girl?
-[breathing heavily]
-[baby crying]
[baby continues crying]
[nurse in Italian]
-[babies crying]
-[gasping]
[in English] And the other?
-A boy!
-[sobbing]
[♪ sinister choral
music playing]
[chattering excitedly]
[priest] We have him.
[♪ sinister choral music
continues playing]
[baby crying]
[continues crying]
[nuns and priests
speaking indistinctly]
[crying]
[breath shuddering]
In nomine Patris, et Filii,
et Spiritus Sancti.
-[♪ ethereal choral
music plays]
-[breathing heavily]
[weakly] Help.
-Help. Help.
-Of course.
Of course, my dear.
-I'm in pain.
-[Lawrence] Of course.
[panting]
Can I hold him?
You're sure?
-[Margaret sobbing]
-[chuckles]
I'm his mother.
[Lawrence] Bring him here.
[breath shudders]
[Silva] She's right.
It is important for a child
to bond with its mother.
-[baby gurgling]
-[crying]
We all need the comfort
of our mothers
in the beginning.
Don't we?
[breathes heavily]
You did so well, my child.
[breathing heavily]
[Lawrence] You are doing
God's work.
He would be so proud of you.
Can't you hear Him
telling you?
Don't you hear His voice?
No.
No, I only hear my own.
-[Margaret grunts]
-[nuns screaming]
No!
[groaning]
[screaming]
[panicked chatter]
[baby crying]
[crying]
[Silva] Margaret.
Stop this.
[sobbing]
[Silva] Margaret,
give me the baby.
Just give me the baby.
[gasping]
[crying]
-[sobbing]
-[Silva screaming]
[Margaret] No!
[nun screams]
-[knife stabs]
-[gasps]
[chokes]
[Margaret whimpers]
[Margaret gasps]
[shuddering]
Burn everything.
Leave them both to die.
[♪ somber choral
music playing]
[baby crying distantly]
[breath shuddering]
[♪ sinister choral
music playing]
[cooing]
[softly] It's okay.
[sniffles, grunts]
[heavy breathing]
[eerie voice whispering]
[♪ demonic music playing]
[screaming]
[♪ wistful choral
music playing]
[eerie screeching]
[screeching]
[music fades out]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[Spiletto] The man
you are looking for.
The US Ambassador to Rome.
He will be the new father.
He and his wife will suffer
a tragic loss,
-and be in need of a child.
-[baby crying]
The boy will inherit
their privilege
and power.
Soon, his darkness will spread
and the world shall be saved.
[♪ sinister music
continues playing]
[music ends]
[wind howling]
[object clatters]
Baby, you're supposed
to eat them.
You're supposed to
eat them like... [chomps]
Like that.
What are you doing?
Come here.
No, no, no. Here.
This.
No, not this.
You want one?
[Carlita chuckles]
[Margaret] You want it?
[all laugh]
Give it to Mama.
[cattle crying in distance]
[cattle lowing]
-[gun cocks]
-[gasps]
[Brennan] I'm so sorry,
Margaret.
I tried just to leave you be.
You need to go.
Now. [breathing shakily]
I came to warn you.
They know you're alive.
You weren't supposed
to survive.
None of you were.
Especially the girl.
[girl laughing]
[Brennan] She'll be important,
Margaret.
I just want to be left alone.
I know.
-But they will come for you.
-[gun cocks]
They've even
given it a name.
Your son.
[wind whistling]
[Brennan] Damien.
[♪ dramatic sinister
music playing]
[♪ eerie music playing]