Ellen, you burned another pot.
You're a fire hazard.
I never hear the whistle.
Feed the dogs, will you?
Don't be a grouch. I'm a wonderful
person. Enjoy what you've got.
Whose clothes are those?
Yours.
If you were a dog bowl,
where would you be?
I'm taking them to the thrift shop.
It's Mrs. Vaughn's
pet charity.
That's not gonna help you in this town.
Look through that, see what you
want. It's mostly your city clothes.
Okay, guys, come on.
Here you go.
Hey, I wear this to the Garden.
Locked doors.
Garbage strikes.
Dog dirt and muggers.
Ship it.
Christine what?
Um...
You don't remember her name?
What's that name for people
who come over from the mainland?
Uh, tourists?
Summer dinks?
That's it.
So you picked her up at the
ferry. How many were in the group?
Urn, about 20 of us.
Spent the night on the beach?
Most of it.
Nobody saw her go into the water?
Somebody could've.
I was sort of passed out.
You mean, she ran out on you?
No, sir.
She must've drowned.
Look, I reported it to you, didn't I?
You live here?
No. Hartford.
I go to Trinity.
My folks live in Greenwich.
Your parents were born here?
Yeah, but they moved off
when my father retired.
You an Islander?
No. New York City.
You here for the summer?
Yeah, me and some friends got a house.
What are you paying?
Oh, um, $1,000 each.
There's five of us.
Uh, $100 a week for food, booze.
That's pretty expensive.
It's not bad.
Come on.
Action.
You're gonna have to take a look at this.
No.
I don't want to.
Please.
You're going to have to take a look at it.
Is it her?
That's what you're going to tell me.
I don't want to look.
Please, just take a look
and tell me if that's her.
Cut!
What have you got there?
Listen, we had a shark attack at
South Beach this morning, Mayor.
Fatal. I have to
batten down the beach.
Who have you told this to, Lenny?
I just found out about it.
There are some Boy Scouts in the water
a couple of miles down the coast
from where we found the girl.
Chief went to dry them off.
We'll take my car.
Come with us.
But I gotta do these signs...
Come, it'll give us time to
think of what the signs will say.
Action!
Okay. You can
take us back now.
I tell you, I can't do my job in a vacuum.
If this is what you want, you
should have hired Hendricks.
He's got relatives all over the island.
We hired the right man, Martin.
We didn't need someone
with old feuds, family ties.
We need someone to referee this thing.
All right.
Let me tell you about
some of the vandalism
that's been going on, on this island.
You know the white picket
fence around my office?
Apparently the little cookers are
coming with karate chops or something
I don't know what...
Kids are breaking my whole fence.
You're such a...
Where's the... Daddy! Uh...
Right this way.
Okay.
I put in a number three.
That should be softer than the number two.
Try it now.
Hello, Mr. Quint.
How are you, Katie?
Looking well.
Thank you.
Four spools of piano wire, number 12.
Sure.
What do those fish do?
Eat that stuff?
No, they choke on it.
So then Denherder and Charlie
sat there trying to catch their breath
and figure out how to tell Charlie's wife
what happened to her freezer full of meat.
That's not funny.
That's not funny at all.
Mrs. Kintner must've put
her ad in Field & Stream.
Looks more like The National Enquirer.
All right, hold on a minute.
Hold everything. I said, hold it!
The price is $100.
As a unit.
That's $35.
Why don't you wait
till you get out a little farther, huh?
Grab that...
Wait a minute.
You have a permit for that?
Yes, sir.
Okay. Keep the safety on.
Marker.
Action.
Holy Jesus H. Christ,
look at this bunch of nuts.
Fit for trout fishing, clam digging,
rabbit hunting,
bass fishing,
everything...
Get that guy, Chief.
Wait a minute.
You got a permit for that?
Yes, sir.
All right.
Just keep the safety on.
And the more they come,
the worse they look.
You're not going out, too, are you?
Yeah. $3,000 is a lot of
money, and I'd like to have it.
I can certainly use it.
Look out, Chief.
You aren't going out with that
bunch of crazy nuts, are you?
I don't know yet.
Come on! Go get him!
Come on!
I think Harry's got it.
Let's go!
Get him up!
I got him!
Come on.
Would you give me a hand?
Get them out of here.
Get it over here.
Get away from the shark.
Marker.
Take a deep breath, Lorraine.
Did you see the television special,
the Cousteau special on sea otters
where the mother was killed
in front of the baby?
The baby saw it. You could see
the tears coming down its face.
It was the most incredible
thing I've ever seen, but terrible.
Mikey wanted us to adopt the sea otter.
I've never been this moved by
anything on television. It was really...
It was special.
So, you're going on the Aurora.
You're gonna live there 18 months.
So she would go,
Like that. I mean, she
was a whacko. She was really smooth.
All this was happening during finals week.
She had my long-distance
telephone credit card.
And my father called up one day
and said, "What is
this $1,200 phone bill?"
What was I going to tell him? That
I knew some bozo
Into erotic phone calls?
She was driving me nuts.
She was great.
What was that?
I didn't hear anything.
Try breathing through your mouth.
I quit, Mr. Quint.
You don't go, you don't get paid.
I don't care.
Cut.
I'm not going on that old
slab after that crazy old shark.
I'm not crazy.
You miserable little son of a bitch.
You get that black fish on my boat.
Pump out the bilges, top up the fuel tanks
then get your ass out of here
because you're on the beach.
Beautiful. Cut it.
Marker.
Ready, Roy?
Yeah.
Action.
Gun jammed.
Okay, once again. Cut it.
Set it.
Marker.
Action.
Gun doesn't fire.
Cut.
Set it.
Step out. Marker.
And action.
Gun doesn't work!
Cut!
Marker.
Action.
Ah, fuck.
Step back.
Action.
Once again. Action.
Mr. Quint, I quit.
I ain't going.