Slave in the Magic Mirror,
come from the farthest space.
Through wind and darkness,
I summon thee.
Speak!
Let me see thy face.
What wouldst thou know,
my Queen?
Magic Mirror on the wall,
who is the fairest
one of all?
Famed is thy beauty, Majesty.
But hold,
a lovely maid I see.
Rags cannot hide
her gentle grace.
Alas, she is more
fair than thee.
Alas for her!
Reveal her name.
Lips red as the rose.
Hair black as ebony.
Skin white as snow.
Snow White!
Want to know a secret?
Promise not to tell?
♪ We are standing
by a wishing well
♪ Make a wish
into the well
♪ That's all
you have to do
♪ And if you hear it echoing
♪ Your wish
will soon come true
♪ I'm wishing
♪ For the one I love
♪ To find me
♪ Today
♪ I'm hoping
♪ And I'm dreaming of
♪ The nice things
♪ He'll say
♪ I'm wishing
♪ For the one I love
♪ To find me
♪ Today
♪ Today ♪
Oh!
Hello.
Oh.
Did I frighten you?
Wait! Wait, please.
Don't run away.
♪ Now that I've found you
♪ Hear what I have to say
♪ One song
♪ I have but one song
♪ One song only for you
♪ One heart
tenderly beating
♪ Ever entreating
♪ Constant and true
♪ One love
♪ That has possessed me
♪ Thrilling me through
♪ One song
♪ My heart keeps singing
♪ Of one love
♪ Only for you ♪
Take her far
into the forest.
Find some secluded glade
where she can
pick wildflowers.
Yes, Your Majesty.
And there,
my faithful Huntsman,
you will kill her!
But, Your Majesty,
the little Princess!
Silence!
You know the penalty
if you fail.
Yes, Your Majesty.
But to make doubly sure
you do not fail,
bring back her heart in this.
♪ One song,
I have but one song ♪
Hello there.
What's the matter?
Where's your mama and papa?
Why, I believe
you're lost.
Oh, please don't cry.
Come on, perk up.
Won't you smile for me?
That's better.
Your mama and papa
can't be far.
There they are!
Can you fly?
Good-bye. Good-bye!
I can't, I can't do it.
Forgive me.
I beg of Your Highness,
forgive me.
I don't understand!
She's mad,
jealous of you!
She'll stop at nothing!
But, but who?
The Queen.
The Queen?
Now, quick, child, run.
Run away, hide!
In the woods! Anywhere!
Never come back!
Now, go. Go! Go!
Run! Run! Hide!
Oh!
Please don't run away.
I won't hurt you.
I'm awfully sorry.
I didn't mean
to frighten you.
But you don't know
what I've been through.
And all because I was afraid.
I'm so ashamed of
the fuss I've made.
What do you do
when things go wrong?
Oh! You sing a song!
♪ With a smile and a song
♪ Life is just like
a bright, sunny day
♪ Your cares fade away
♪ And your heart is young
♪ With a smile and a song
♪ All the world
seems to waken anew
♪ Rejoicing with you
♪ As the song is sung
♪ There's no use in grumbling
♪ When raindrops
come tumbling
♪ Remember you're the one
♪ Who can fill
the world with sunshine
♪ When you smile and you sing
♪ Everything is in
tune and it's spring
♪ And life flows along
♪ With a smile and a song ♪
I really feel
quite happy now.
I'm sure I'll get
along somehow.
Everything's going
to be all right.
But I do need a place
to sleep at night.
I can't sleep
in the ground like you
or in a tree
the way you do.
And I'm sure no nest would possibly be big enough for me.
Maybe you know
where I can stay.
In the woods somewhere?
You do?
Will you take me there?
Oh, it's adorable!
Just like a doll's house.
I like it here.
Ooh, it's dark inside.
Guess there's no one home.
Hello?
May I come in?
Shh!
Oh!
What a cute little chair!
Why, there's seven
little chairs!
Must be seven
little children.
And from the look
of this table,
seven untidy little children.
A pickaxe.
A stocking, too!
And a shoe!
And just look at
that fireplace.
It's covered with dust.
And look,
cobwebs everywhere!
My, my, my!
What a pile of dirty dishes!
And just look
at that broom!
Why, they've never
swept this room.
You'd think
their mother would...
Maybe they have no mother.
Then they're orphans.
That's too bad.
I know!
We'll clean the house
and surprise them.
Then maybe
they'll let me stay.
Now, you wash the dishes.
You tidy up the room.
You clean the fireplace.
And I will use the broom.
♪ Just whistle while you work
♪ And cheerfully together
we can tidy up the place
♪ So hum a merry tune
♪ It won't take long when there's a song to help you set the pace
♪ And as you sweep the room
♪ Imagine that the broom
♪ Is someone that you love and soon
you'll find you're dancing to the tune
Oh, no, no, no, no!
Put them in the tub.
♪ When hearts are high
the time will fly
♪ So whistle while you work
Uh-uh, uh-uh!
Not under the rug.
♪ So whistle while you work ♪
♪ We dig, dig, dig,
dig, dig, dig, dig
♪ In our mine
the whole day through
♪ To dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig,
dig is what we like to do
♪ It ain't no trick
to get rich quick
♪ If ya dig, dig, dig
with a shovel or a pick
♪ In a mine
♪ Where a million diamonds
♪ Shine
♪ We dig, dig, dig,
dig, dig, dig, dig
♪ From early morn 'til night
♪ We dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig,
dig up everything in sight
♪ We dig up diamonds
by the score
♪ A thousand rubies
Sometimes more
♪ Though we don't know
what we dig 'em for
♪ We dig, dig,
dig-a-dig, dig
♪ Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho, hum
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho,
heigh-ho... ♪
Let's see what's upstairs.
Oh, what adorable
little beds!
And look,
they have their names carved on them.
Doc, Happy,
Sneezy, Dopey...
What funny names
for children!
Grumpy, Bashful and Sleepy.
I'm a little
sleepy myself.
Oh! Oh!
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Heigh-ho
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho,
heigh-ho, heigh... ♪
Look!
Our house!
The lit's light...
Uh, the light's lit.
Jiminy Crickets!
- The door is open.
- The chimney's smoking.
Something's in there.
Maybe a ghost.
Or a goblin.
A demon.
Or a dragon.
Mark my words,
there's trouble a-brewin'.
Felt it coming all day.
My corns hurt.
Gosh!
That's a bad sign.
What'll we do?
Let's sneak up on it.
Yes. We'll, uh,
squeak up... Sneak up.
Come on, hen...
Uh, men. Follow me.
Psst!
Shh!
Careful, men.
Search every
cook and nanny...
Hook and granny...
Crooked fan...
Search everywhere.
Shh!
Quiet.
Look! The floor,
it's been swept!
Hah!
Chair's been dusted!
Our window's been washed.
Gosh,
our cobwebs are missing.
Why, why, why, why,
the whole place is clean!
There's dirty work afoot.
Sink's empty.
Hey, someone
stole our dishes!
They ain't stole.
They're hid in the cupboard.
My cup's been washed.
Sugar's gone.
Something's cooking.
Smells good!
Don't touch it, you fools!
Might be poison.
See? It's witches' brew.
Look what's happened
to our stable... Uh, table.
Flowers!
Huh?
Look, goldenrod.
Don't do it.
Take them away.
My nose! My hay fever!
You know I can't stand it.
I can't...
I can't... I... Oh.
Ah...
Ahhh...
Thanks!
Hey!
Shh!
Ya crazy fool!
Fine time you picked
to sneeze!
I couldn't help it.
I can't tell.
When you gotta, you gotta.
I... I... I gotta.
It's coming.
Don't let him.
Stop him.
Oh! Ah... Ah... Ah!
No, tie it tight.
Don't let go.
Hold him tight.
I'll tie it.
Make a hard knot.
There, that will hold him.
Thanks!
Shh!
Quiet, you fool!
You want to get
us all killed?
What's that?
That's it.
Sounded close.
It's in this room
right now.
It's up there.
Yeah. In the bedroom.
One of us has gotta go down and chase it up.
Up. Down.
Here, take it.
Don't be nervous.
Don't be afraid.
We're right behind you.
Yes! Right behind ya.
Here it comes!
It's after us.
Don't let it out.
Hold it shut.
Here it comes.
Now's our chance.
Get it now!
Quick!
Give it to it!
Don't let it get away!
Hold on there.
It's only Dopey.
Did you see it?
How big is it?
Was it a dragon?
Has it got horns?
Was it breathing fire?
Was it droolin'?
What was it doin'?
He says it's a,
a monster asleep in our beds!
Let's attack.
While it's sleeping.
Yeah, while it's sleeping.
Hurry, men. It's now or never!
Off with its head.
Break its bones.
Chop it to pieces.
We'll kill it dead.
Jiminy Crickets!
Gosh!
Gee!
What a monster!
It covers three beds.
Let's kill it
before it wakes up.
Which end do we kill?
Shh!
Well, eh, ah...
What is it?
Why, it... It's a girl!
She's mighty purdy.
She's beautiful,
just like a angel.
Angel, hah!
She's a female!
And all females is poison!
They're full of
wicked wiles.
What are wicked wiles?
I don't know.
But I'm agin 'em.
Shh!
Not so loud.
You'll wake her up.
Aw, let her wake up!
She don't belong
here nohow.
Look out.
She's movin'.
She's wakin' up.
What'll we do?
Hide.
Oh, dear.
I wonder if
the children are...
Oh!
Why, why, you're little men!
How do you do?
I said, how do you do?
How do you do what?
Oh, you can talk!
I'm so glad!
Now, don't tell me
who you are.
Let me guess.
I know, you're Doc.
Why, why, why, yes.
Yes! That's true.
And you're, you're Bashful.
Oh, gosh!
And you, you're Sleepy.
How'd you guess?
And you?
And you're Sneezy.
Yes, and you must be...
Happy, ma'am. That's me.
And this is Dopey.
He don't talk none.
You mean he can't talk?
He don't know.
He never tried.
Oh, that's too bad.
Oh!
You must be Grumpy.
Oh, yes! Yes!
Hah! We know who we are.
Ask her who she is
and what she's a-doin' here.
Hmph! Yeah!
What are you and
who are you doin'?
What are you...
Who are you, my dear?
Oh, how silly of me.
I'm Snow White.
- Snow White?
- The Princess?
Yes.
Well... Well, my,
my dear Quincess... Uh, Princess.
We're, uh, we're honored.
Yes, we're, uh, we're...
Mad as hornets!
No, no, we're not.
We're bad as cornets...
No, no, as bad as...
What was I sayin'?
Nothing! Just standin' there
sputterin' like a doodlebug!
Who, who, who,
who's butterin' like a spoodledug?
Who's... Uh, gutter...
Aw, shut up and
tell her to get out!
Please don't send me away!
If you do, she'll kill me.
- Kill you?
- Who will?
- Yes, who?
My stepmother, the Queen.
- The Queen?
She's wicked!
She's bad!
She's mighty mean!
She's an old witch!
I'm warnin' ya.
If the Queen
finds her here,
she'll swoop down and wreak her vengeance on us!
But she doesn't
know where I am!
She don't, eh?
She knows everything.
She's full of black magic.
She can even make
herself invisible.
Pfft!
Might be in this
room right now.
Oh, she'll never
find me here.
And if you let me stay,
I'll keep house for you.
I'll wash and sew
and sweep and cook and...
Cook?
Can you make dapple lumpkins... Uh,
lumple dapplins?
Apple dumplings!
Eh, yes!
Crapple dumpkins.
Yes, and plum pudding
and gooseberry pie...
Gooseberry pie?
Hooray! She stays!
Ah!
Soup!
Hooray!
Uh-uh, uh-uh!
Just a minute.
Supper's not quite ready.
You'll just have
time to wash.
Wash? Wash?
Wash? Wash? Wash?
Hah! Knew there
was a catch to it.
Why wash?
What for?
We ain't goin' nowhere.
'Tain't New Year's.
Oh, perhaps you have washed.
Perhaps we...
Yes! Perhaps we have.
But when?
When? When.
Uh, you said whe...
Why, last week.
Why, recently!
Yes, recently!
Oh, recently!
Let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands!
Why, Doc, I'm surprised!
Come on, let's see them.
Oh, Bashful, my, my, my!
And you?
Worse than I thought!
Oh!
How shocking!
Goodness me,
this will never do.
March straight
outside and wash,
or you'll not get
a bite to eat.
Hah!
Well, aren't you
going to wash?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Oh! Did you hurt yourself?
Hah, women!
Courage, men, courage.
Don't be nervous.
Gosh, it's wet!
It's cold, too!
We ain't gonna
do it, are we?
Well, it'll please
the Princess.
I'll take
a chance for her!
Me, too!
Hah! Her wiles are
beginnin' to work.
But I'm warnin' ya,
you give 'em an inch,
and they'll walk
all over ya!
Don't listen to
that old warthog.
Come on now, men.
How hard do ya scrub?
Will our whiskers shrink?
Do ya get in the tub?
Do ya have to wash
where it doesn't show?
Now, now, now,
don't get excited. Here we go.
♪ Step up to the tub
'Tain't no disgrace
♪ Just pull up your sleeves
and get 'em in place
♪ Then scoop up the water and rub it on your face and go...
♪ Pick up the soap
Now don't try to bluff
♪ Work up a lather
And when you got enough
♪ Get your hands full of water and you snort and you snuff and go...
♪ You douse and you souse
Rub and you scrub
♪ You sputter and splash
all over the tub
♪ You may be cold
and wet when you're done
♪ But you gotta admit
it's good and clean fun
♪ So splash all you like
'Tain't any trick
♪ As soon as you're through
You'll feel mighty slick
Bunch of old nanny goats.
Ya make me sick going...
Hah! Next thing ya know
she'll be tyin' your beards up in pink ribbons
and smellin' ya up with
that stuff called "perfoom."
Hah!
A fine bunch of water lilies
you turned out to be.
I'd like to see anybody make me wash if I didn't wanna.
Get him!
Hey, let go of me!
Get him over to the tub.
Let me loose, you fools!
Let me loose!
Get him up on the tub.
Get him up!
Hang on to him!
Bang him! Pound him!
Get him up on the tub! On the tub.
That's the tub. That's the tub.
Don't, don't, don't,
don't get excited!
Don't get...
Don't get up... Don't get...
Get the soap!
Hey, steady, men.
We'll get him there. We'll get him.
Never say die.
You don't...
♪ Now,
scrub good and hard It can't be denied
♪ That he'll look mighty cute
as soon as he's dried
♪ Well,
it's good for the soul
♪ And it's good for
the hide to go... ♪
Ain't he sweet?
Smells like a petunia.
He sure is cute!
You'll pay dearly for this!
Supper!
- Food. Hooray!
Hah!
Magic Mirror on the wall,
who now is
the fairest one of all?
Over the seven jeweled hills
beyond the seventh fall,
in the cottage of
the seven dwarfs
dwells Snow White,
fairest one of all.
Snow White lies dead
in the forest.
The Huntsman has
brought me proof.
Behold her heart.
Snow White still lives,
the fairest in the land.
'Tis the heart of a pig
you hold in your hand.
The heart of a pig!
Then I've been tricked!
The blundering fool!
I'll go myself to
the dwarfs' cottage
in a disguise so complete
no one will ever suspect.
Now, a formula to transform
my beauty into ugliness,
change my queenly raiment
to a peddler's cloak.
Mummy Dust to make me old.
To shroud my clothes,
the black of night.
To age my voice,
an old hag's cackle.
To whiten my hair,
a scream of fright.
A blast of wind
to fan my hate!
A thunderbolt
to mix it well.
Now,
begin thy magic spell.
Look!
My hands!
My voice!
My voice.
A perfect disguise.
And now...
A special sort of death
for one so fair.
What shall it be?
Ah!
A poisoned apple!
Sleeping Death.
♪ I'd like to dance
and tap my feet
♪ But they won't
keep in rhythm
♪ You see,
I washed 'em both today
♪ And I can't do
nothin' with 'em
♪ Ho-hum,
the tune is dumb
♪ The words
don't mean a thing
♪ Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing?
♪ I...
Oh, gosh!
♪ I chased a polecat up a tree
Way out upon a limb
♪ And when he got the best of me I got the worst of him
♪ Ho-hum,
the tune is dumb
♪ The words
don't mean a thing
♪ Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing? ♪
Watch out. Be ca...
Watch... Watch...
Thanks.
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hooray!
That was fun!
Now you do something.
Well, what shall I do?
Tell us a story.
Yes, tell us a story.
A true story.
A love story.
Well, once there
was a princess.
Was the princess you?
And she fell in love.
Was it hard to do?
Oh,
it was very easy.
Anyone could see that the Prince was charming.
The only one for me.
Was he strong
and handsome?
Was he big and tall?
There's nobody like him
anywhere at all.
Did he say he loved ya?
Did he steal a kiss?
♪ He was so romantic
♪ I could not resist
♪ Some day
my prince will come
♪ Some day we'll meet again
♪ And away to
his castle we'll go
♪ To be happy forever
♪ I know ♪
Hah! Mush!
♪ Some day when spring is here
♪ We'll find our love anew
♪ And the birds will sing
♪ And wedding bells will ring
♪ Some day when my dreams
♪ Come true ♪
Oh, my goodness!
It's past bedtime.
Go right upstairs to bed.
Wait! Hold on there, men!
The, uh, Princess will sleep
in our beds upstairs.
But where will you sleep?
Oh, we'll be quite comfortable
down here in... in...
In a pig's eye!
In a pig's eye...
Sty. No, no! I mean...
We'll be comfortable,
won't we, men?
Oh, yes.
Mighty comfortable.
Now don't you
worry about us.
We'll be
all right, ma'am.
Go right on
up now, my dear.
Well, if you insist.
Good night.
Good night, Princess.
You're sure
you'll be comfortable?
Oh, yes. Very comfortable.
Well, pleasant dreams.
Pleasant dreams.
Let go!
I saw it first! Now, men,
don't get excited.
Remember, share.
It's share and share alike.
Look out, it'll rip.
It'll rip!
Bless the seven little men
who have been so kind to me.
And... And may
my dreams come true.
Amen.
Oh, yes!
And please make Grumpy like me.
Hah! Women!
A fine kettle of fish!
Dip the apple in the brew.
Let the Sleeping
Death seep through!
Look! On the skin!
The symbol of
what lies within.
Now, turn red
to tempt Snow White.
To make her hunger
for a bite.
Have a bite?
It's not for you.
It's for Snow White.
When she breaks
the tender peel
to taste the apple
in my hand,
her breath will still,
her blood congeal.
Then I'll be
fairest in the land!
But wait!
There may be an antidote.
Nothing must be overlooked.
Oh, here it is!
"Love's First Kiss."
Bah!
No fear of that.
The dwarfs will
think she's dead.
She'll be buried alive!
Buried alive!
Thirsty?
Have a drink!
Now, don't forget, my dear.
The... The old Queen's a sly one,
full of witchcraft.
So beware of strangers.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
See you tonight.
Uh, yes.
We... Well, c'mon, men.
Be awful careful
'cause if anything'd
happen to you, I, I...
Good-bye.
Oh, gosh!
Hah! Disgustin'!
And be sure to watch out...
To wa... To wa...
To wa...
Watch out.
Thanks.
Well... All right.
But that's the last...
Wha...
Oh, go on. Run along.
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
♪ It's off to work we go
♪ Heigh-ho ♪
Good-bye! Good-bye!
Now I'm warnin' ya.
Don't let nobody or
nothin' in the house.
Why, Grumpy, you do care.
Hah!
Good-bye, Grumpy!
The little men will be away
and she'll be all alone
with a harmless
old peddler woman.
A harmless old peddler woman!
♪ Some day
my prince will come
we'll meet again
♪ And away to
his castle we'll go
♪ To be happy forever
I know
♪ Some day
when spring is here
♪ We'll find
our love anew
♪ And the birds will sing
♪ And wedding bells will ring
♪ Some day when my dreams
♪ Come true ♪
All alone, my pet?
Why, why, yes, I am. But...
The, the little men
are not here?
No, they're not, but...
Mmm-hmm.
Making pies?
Yes, gooseberry pies.
It's apple pies
that make the menfolks'
mouths water.
Pies made from
apples like these.
Oh, they do
look delicious.
Yes!
But wait 'til you
taste one, dearie.
Like to try one?
Hmm?
Go on. Go on,
have a bite.
Stop it! Stop it!
Go away! Go away!
Shame on you,
frightening a poor old lady.
Oh, I thought I'd lost it.
There, there.
I'm sorry.
Oh! My heart!
Oh, my... My poor heart.
Take me into the house
and let me rest.
A drink of water,
please.
♪ Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
Hey, look!
Stop that! Get away, boy.
Get away! Go on, shoo!
Go on! Get outta here!
What ails these
crazy birds?
They've gone plumb daffy.
Yeah, they've...
And because you've been so good to poor old Granny,
I'll share
a secret with you.
This is no ordinary apple.
It's a magic wishing apple.
A wishing apple?
Yes!
One bite and all your dreams will come true.
Really?
Yes, girlie.
Now, make a wish
and take a bite.
Go on, get!
These pesky critters
won't stop.
- 'Tain't natural.
- There's something wrong.
They ain't actin'
this way for nothin'.
Maybe the old Queen's
got Snow White.
The Queen!
- Snow White!
The Queen'll kill her!
We gotta save her!
Yes! Yes!
We, we, we gotta save her!
She'll kill her!
What'll we do?
Yes,
yes, what'll we do?
Come on! Giddap!
Wait for me! Wait for...
There must be something
your little heart desires.
Perhaps there's
someone you love.
Well, there is someone.
I thought so. I thought so!
Old Granny knows
a young girl's heart.
Now, take
the apple, dearie,
and make a wish.
I wish... I wish...
That's it, go on! Go on.
And that he will carry me away to his castle
where we will live
happily ever after.
Fine! Fine!
Now take a bite.
Don't let
the wish grow cold!
Oh, I feel strange.
Her breath will still.
Oh. Oh.
Her blood congeal.
Oh.
Now I'll be
fairest in the land!
Hurry, hurry.
There she goes!
After her!
I'm trapped! What will I do?
The meddling little fools!
I'll fix ya. I'll fix ya.
I'll fix ya!
I'll crush your bones!
Look out!
♪ One song
♪ I have but one song
♪ Only for you
♪ For you
♪ One heart
♪ Tenderly beating
♪ Ever entreating
♪ Constant and true
♪ So true
♪ One love
♪ That has possessed me
♪ Thrilling me through
♪ So true
♪ One song
♪ My heart keeps singing
♪ Keeps singing
♪ Of one love
♪ One love
♪ Only for you...
♪ And away
to his castle you'll go
♪ To be happy
forever we know
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Grumpy.
Oh, Dopey.
Good-bye!
♪ Some day
when spring is here
♪ We'll find our love anew
♪ And the birds will sing
♪ And wedding bells will ring
♪ Some day when my dreams
♪ Come true! ♪