CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
[LA MARSEILLAISE PLAYING]
Narrator: WITH THE COMING
OF THE SECOND WORLD WAR,
MANY EYES
IN IMPRISONED EUROPE
TURNED HOPEFULLY
OR DESPERATELY
TOWARD THE FREEDOM
OF THE AMERICAS.
LISBON BECAME
THE GREAT EMBARKATION POINT,
BUT NOT EVERYBODY COULD GET
TO LISBON DIRECTLY.
AND SO A TORTUOUS ROUNDABOUT
REFUGEE TRAIL
SPRANG UP--
PARIS TO MARSEILLES...
ACROSS THE MEDITERRANEAN
TO ORAN...
THEN BY TRAIN
OR AUTO OR FOOT
ACROSS THE RIM OF AFRICA
TO CASABLANCA
IN FRENCH MOROCCO.
HERE THE FORTUNATE ONES,
THROUGH MONEY
OR INFLUENCE OR LUCK,
MIGHT OBTAIN EXIT VISAS
AND SCURRY TO LISBON
AND FROM LISBON
TO THE NEW WORLD.
BUT THE OTHERS WAIT
IN CASABLANCA...
AND WAIT...
AND WAIT.
"TO ALL OFFICERS--
"TWO GERMAN COURIERS
"CARRYING IMPORTANT
OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
"MURDERED ON TRAIN
FROM ORAN.
"MURDERER AND POSSIBLE
ACCOMPLICES
"HEADED FOR CASABLANCA.
"ROUND UP ALL
SUSPICIOUS CHARACTERS
AND SEARCH THEM
FOR STOLEN DOCUMENT. IMPORTANT."
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
[SHOUTING
IN FRENCH]
[SIREN]
MAY WE SEE
YOUR PAPERS?
I DON'T THINK
I HAVE THEM ON ME.
IN THAT CASE WE'LL HAVE
TO ASK YOU COME ALONG.
WAIT. IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT I...
YES, HERE THEY ARE.
THESE PAPERS EXPIRED
3 WEEKS AGO.
YOU'LL HAVE
TO COME ALONG.
HALT!
[GUNSHOT]
WHAT ON EARTH'S
GOING ON THERE?
I DON'T KNOW,
MY DEAR.
PARDON, MONSIEUR.
PARDON, MADAME.
HAVE YOU NOT HEARD?
WE HEAR VERY LITTLE.
WE UNDERSTAND EVEN LESS.
TWO GERMAN COURIERS
WERE FOUND MURDERED
IN THE UNOCCUPIED
DESERT.
THIS IS THE CUSTOMARY
ROUNDUP OF REFUGEES, LIBERALS,
AND, OF COURSE,
BEAUTIFUL YOUNG GIRLS
FOR MONSIEUR RENAULT,
THE PREFECT OF POLICE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
ALONG WITH THESE
UNHAPPY REFUGEES,
THE SCUM OF EUROPE
HAS GRAVITATED
TO CASABLANCA.
SOME HAVE BEEN WAITING
YEARS FOR A VISA.
I BEG OF YOU, MONSIEUR,
WATCH YOURSELF.
BE ON GUARD. THIS PLACE
IS FULL OF VULTURES,
VULTURES EVERYWHERE.
EVERYWHERE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOT AT ALL. AU REVOIR,
MONSIEUR, MADAME.
AU REVOIR.
AMUSING LITTLE FELLOW.
WAITER!
OH, HOW SILLY OF ME.
WHAT, DEAR?
I'VE LEFT MY WALLET
IN THE HOTEL. I...
[AIRPLANE ENGINES]
PERHAPS TOMORROW
WE'LL BE ON THE PLANE.
GARDE-A-VOUS!
HEIL HITLER.
IT'S VERY GOOD TO SEE YOU
AGAIN, MAJOR STRASSER.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
MAY I PRESENT
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
POLICE PREFECT
OF CASABLANCA?
MAJOR STRASSER.
UNOCCUPIED FRANCE
WELCOMES YOU
TO CASABLANCA.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
IT'S VERY GOOD TO BE HERE.
MAJOR STRASSER, MY AIDE
LIEUTENANT CASSELLE.
CAPTAIN TONELLI,
ITALIAN SERVICE,
AT YOUR COMMAND.
THAT IS KIND OF YOU.
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
YOU MAY FIND
THE CLIMATE
OF CASABLANCA
A TRIFLE WARM.
WE GERMANS MUST GET USED
TO ALL CLIMATES,
FROM RUSSIA TO THE SAHARA,
BUT PERHAPS YOU WERE NOT
REFERRING TO THE WEATHER.
WHAT ELSE,
MY DEAR MAJOR?
THE MURDER OF THE COURIERS--
WHAT HAS BEEN DONE?
REALIZING THE IMPORTANCE
OF THE CASE,
WE'RE ROUNDING UP TWICE THE
USUAL NUMBER OF SUSPECTS.
WE KNOW WHO
THE MURDERER IS.
GOOD.
IS HE IN CUSTODY?
OH, THERE'S NO HURRY.
TONIGHT HE'LL BE AT RICK'S.
EVERYBODY COMES TO RICK'S.
I'VE ALREADY HEARD ABOUT THIS
CAFE, AND ALSO ABOUT MR. RICK.
♫ IT HAD TO BE YOU ♫
♫ I WANDERED AROUND ♫
♫ AND FINALLY FOUND
THE SOMEBODY WHO ♫
♫ COULD MAKE ME BE TRUE ♫
♫ COULD MAKE ME BE BLUE ♫
♫ AND EVEN BE GLAD ♫
♫ JUST TO BE SAD
THINKING OF YOU ♫
♫ SOME OTHERS I'VE SEEN ♫
♫ MIGHT NEVER BE MEAN ♫
♫ MIGHT NEVER BE CROSS ♫
♫ OR TRY TO BE BOSS ♫
♫ BUT THEY WOULDN'T DO ♫
♫ FOR NOBODY ELSE
GAVE ME A THRILL ♫
♫ HONEY,
WITH ALL YOUR FAULTS ♫
♫ I LOVE YOU STILL ♫
♫ IT HAD TO BE YOU ♫
♫ WONDERFUL YOU ♫
♫ HAD TO BE YOU ♫
♫ 'CAUSE ♫
♫ MY HAIR IS CURLY ♫
♫ MY TEETH ARE PEARLY... ♫
WAITING,
WAITING, WAITING.
I'LL NEVER
GET OUT OF HERE.
I'LL DIE
IN CASABLANCA.
CAN'T YOU MAKE IT JUST
A LITTLE MORE? PLEASE?
SORRY, MADAME, BUT DIAMONDS
ARE A DRAG ON THE MARKET.
EVERYBODY SELLS DIAMONDS.
THERE ARE DIAMONDS
EVERYWHERE. 2,400.
ALL RIGHT.
THE TRUCKS ARE READY.
THE MEN ARE WAITING.
EVERYTHING IS--
[MEN SPEAKING GERMAN]
IT'S THE FISHING SMACK
SANTIAGO.
IT LEAVES AT 1:00
TOMORROW NIGHT
HERE FROM THE END OF
LA MEDINA. THIRD BOAT.
THANK YOU.
BRING 15,000 FRANCS
IN CASH.
REMEMBER, IN CASH.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
CHEERIO.
OPEN UP, ABDUL.
YES, HERR PROFESSOR.
GRAZIE, SIGNORE.
RED FOR MADAME.
BLACK FOR MONSIEUR.
UM...WAITER.
YES, MADAME?
WILL YOU ASK RICK IF HE'LL
HAVE A DRINK WITH US?
MADAME, HE NEVER DRINKS
WITH CUSTOMERS. NEVER.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN IT.
WHAT MAKES SALOON KEEPERS
SO SNOBBISH?
PERHAPS
IF YOU TOLD HIM
I RAN THE SECOND LARGEST
BANKING HOUSE IN AMSTERDAM.
SECOND LARGEST?
THAT WOULDN'T
IMPRESS RICK.
THE LEADING BANKER
IN AMSTERDAM
IS NOW THE PASTRY
CHEF IN OUR KITCHEN.
WE HAVE SOMETHING
TO LOOK FORWARD TO.
AND HIS FATHER
IS THE BELLBOY.
Waiter:
FOR MADAME.
MONSIEUR.
Waiter:
FOR MONSIEUR.
EXCUSE ME.
SORRY, SIR.
THIS IS A PRIVATE ROOM.
OF ALL THE NERVE!
WHO DO YOU--
I KNOW THERE'S
GAMBLING IN THERE.
THERE IS NO SECRET.
YOU DARE NOT
KEEP ME OUT OF HERE.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE?
I'VE BEEN IN EVERY
GAMBLING ROOM
BETWEEN HONOLULU
AND BERLIN.
IF YOU THINK I'LL BE
KEPT OUT OF A SALOON
LIKE THIS, YOU ARE
VERY MUCH MISTAKEN.
EXCUSE ME.
HELLO, RICK.
YOUR CASH IS GOOD
AT THE BAR.
WHAT? DO YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
I DO. YOU'RE LUCKY
THE BAR'S OPEN TO YOU.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS! I SHALL
REPORT IT TO THE ANGRIFF.
RICK, WATCHING YOU
WITH THE DEUTSCHE BANK,
ONE WOULD THINK YOU'VE BEEN
DOING THIS ALL YOUR LIFE.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I HAVEN'T?
NOTHING, BUT WHEN
YOU FIRST CAME
TO CASABLANCA,
I THOUGHT--
YOU THOUGHT WHAT?
WHAT RIGHT DO I
HAVE TO THINK?
MAY I?
TOO BAD ABOUT THOSE
2 GERMAN COURIERS.
THEY GOT A LUCKY BREAK.
YESTERDAY THEY WERE
JUST TWO GERMAN CLERKS.
TODAY THEY'RE
THE HONORED DEAD.
YOU ARE A VERY
CYNICAL PERSON.
FORGIVE ME
FOR SAYING SO.
I FORGIVE YOU.
WILL YOU HAVE
A DRINK WITH ME?
NO.
I FORGOT. YOU NEVER
DRINK WITH ANYONE.
I'LL HAVE ANOTHER,
PLEASE.
YOU DESPISE ME,
DON'T YOU?
IF I GAVE YOU ANY THOUGHT,
I PROBABLY WOULD.
WHY? YOU OBJECT
TO THE KIND OF
BUSINESS I DO, HUH?
THINK OF ALL THOSE
POOR REFUGEES
WHO'D ROT HERE IF I
DIDN'T HELP THEM.
THAT'S NOT SO BAD.
THROUGH WAYS
OF MY OWN,
I PROVIDE THEM
WITH EXIT VISAS.
FOR A PRICE, UGARTE,
FOR A PRICE.
BUT THINK OF
ALL THE POOR DEVILS
WHO CAN'T MEET
RENAULT'S PRICE.
I GET IT
FOR THEM FOR HALF.
IS THAT SO PARASITIC?
I DON'T MIND A PARASITE.
I OBJECT TO A CUT-RATE ONE.
WELL, AFTER TONIGHT,
I'LL BE THROUGH WITH
THE WHOLE BUSINESS.
I'M LEAVING, FINALLY,
THIS CASABLANCA.
WHO'D YOU BRIBE
FOR YOUR VISA,
RENAULT OR YOURSELF?
MYSELF. I FOUND MYSELF
MUCH MORE REASONABLE.
LOOK, RICK.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS?
SOMETHING THAT EVEN YOU
HAVE NEVER SEEN.
LETTERS OF TRANSIT
SIGNED BY GENERAL DE GAULLE.
CANNOT BE RESCINDED,
NOT EVEN QUESTIONED.
ONE MOMENT.
TONIGHT I'LL BE
SELLING THOSE
FOR MORE MONEY THAN EVEN
I'VE EVER DREAMED OF,
AND THEN ADDIO,
CASABLANCA.
YOU KNOW, RICK,
I HAVE MANY FRIENDS,
BUT SOMEHOW, BECAUSE
YOU DESPISE ME,
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
I TRUST.
WILL YOU KEEP THESE
FOR ME?
FOR HOW LONG?
PERHAPS AN HOUR. PERHAPS
A LITTLE LONGER.
I DON'T WANT THEM HERE
OVERNIGHT.
DON'T BE AFRAID
OF THAT.
PLEASE KEEP THEM
FOR ME.
THANK YOU. I KNEW
I COULD TRUST YOU.
OH, WAITER. I'M
EXPECTING SOME PEOPLE.
IF ANYBODY ASKS FOR ME,
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
YES, MONSIEUR.
RICK, I HOPE YOU'RE MORE
IMPRESSED WITH ME NOW.
IF YOU'LL FORGIVE ME,
I'LL SHARE MY GOOD LUCK
WITH YOUR
ROULETTE WHEEL.
JUST A MOMENT.
I HEARD A RUMOR
THOSE 2 GERMAN COURIERS
WERE CARRYING
LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
HUH?
OH. I'VE HEARD
THAT RUMOR, TOO.
POOR DEVILS.
YOU'RE RIGHT, UGARTE.
I AM A LITTLE MORE
IMPRESSED WITH YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
♫ SAY, WHO'S
GOT TROUBLE? ♫
♫ WE GOT TROUBLE ♫
♫ HOW MUCH TROUBLE? ♫
♫ TOO MUCH TROUBLE ♫
♫ WELL, NOW,
DON'T YOU FROWN ♫
♫ JUST KNUCKLE DOWN
AND KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♫ WHO'S UNHAPPY? ♫
♫ WE'RE UNHAPPY ♫
♫ HOW UNHAPPY? ♫
♫ TOO UNHAPPY ♫
♫ UH-OH,
THAT WON'T DO ♫
♫ WHEN YOU ARE BLUE,
JUST KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♫ WHO'S UNLUCKY? ♫
♫ WE'RE UNLUCKY ♫
♫ HOW UNLUCKY? ♫
♫ TOO UNLUCKY ♫
♫ BUT YOUR LUCK'LL
CHANGE ♫
♫ IF YOU'LL ARRANGE
TO KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♫ WHO'S GOT NOTHIN'? ♫
♫ WE GOT NOTHIN' ♫
♫ HOW MUCH NOTHIN'? ♫
♫ TOO MUCH NOTHIN' ♫
♫ SAY, NOTHIN'S NOT
AN AWFUL LOT ♫
♫ BUT KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♫ NOW WHO'S HAPPY? ♫
♫ WE'RE HAPPY ♫
♫ JUST HOW HAPPY? ♫
♫ VERY HAPPY ♫
♫ THAT'S THE WAY
WE'RE GONNA STAY ♫
♫ SO KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♫ NOW WHO'S LUCKY? ♫
♫ WE'RE ALL LUCKY ♫
♫ JUST HOW LUCKY? ♫
♫ VERY LUCKY ♫
♫ WELL, SMILE UP, THEN ♫
♫ AND ONCE AGAIN ♫
♫ LET'S KNOCK ON WOOD ♫
HELLO, RICK.
HELLO, FERRARI.
HOW'S BUSINESS
AT THE BLUE PARROT?
FINE, BUT I'D LIKE
TO BUY YOUR CAFE.
IT'S NOT FOR SALE.
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
MY OFFER.
IT'S NOT FOR SALE
AT ANY PRICE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FOR SAM?
I DON'T BUY OR SELL
HUMAN BEINGS.
TOO BAD. THAT'S CASABLANCA'S
LEADING COMMODITY.
IN REFUGEES ALONE,
WE COULD MAKE A FORTUNE.
YOU COULD WORK WITH ME
THROUGH THE BLACK MARKET.
SUPPOSE YOU RUN
YOUR BUSINESS,
AND LET ME RUN MINE.
SUPPOSE WE ASK SAM.
MAYBE HE'D LIKE A CHANGE.
SUPPOSE WE DO.
WHEN WILL YOU REALIZE
THAT IN THIS WORLD TODAY,
ISOLATIONISM IS NO LONGER
A PRACTICAL POLICY?
SAM, FERRARI WANTS YOU
TO WORK FOR HIM.
I LIKE IT FINE HERE.
HE'LL DOUBLE
WHAT I PAY YOU.
YEAH,
BUT I AIN'T GOT TIME
TO SPEND THE MONEY
I MAKE HERE.
SORRY.
BOSS' PRIVATE STOCK...
BECAUSE, YVONNE,
I LOVE YOU.
OH, SHUT UP.
ALL RIGHT. FOR YOU,
I SHUT UP...
BECAUSE, YVONNE,
I LOVE YOU.
UH-OH.
SOME GERMANS
GAVE THIS CHECK.
IS IT ALL RIGHT?
WHERE WERE YOU
LAST NIGHT?
THAT'S SO LONG AGO,
I DON'T REMEMBER.
WILL I SEE YOU
TONIGHT?
I NEVER MAKE PLANS
THAT FAR AHEAD.
GIVE ME ANOTHER.
SACHA,
SHE'S HAD ENOUGH.
DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
FILL IT UP.
YVONNE, I LOVE YOU,
BUT HE PAYS ME.
RICK, I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF HAVING YOU--
SACHA, CALL A CAB.
LET'S GET YOUR COAT.
YOU'RE GOING HOME.
YOU'VE HAD A LITTLE
TOO MUCH TO DRINK.
HEY, TAXI.
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU
ARE, PUSHING ME AROUND?
I WAS A FOOL TO FALL
FOR A MAN LIKE YOU.
MAKE SURE SHE GETS HOME...
AND COME RIGHT BACK.
YES, BOSS.
HELLO, RICK.
HELLO, LOUIS.
HOW EXTRAVAGANT YOU ARE,
THROWING AWAY WOMEN LIKE THAT.
SOMEDAY THEY MAY
BE SCARCE.
I THINK I'LL CALL ON YVONNE,
MAYBE GET HER ON THE REBOUND.
WHEN IT COMES TO WOMEN,
YOU'RE A TRUE DEMOCRAT.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
IF HE GETS A WORD IN,
IT'LL BE A MAJOR
ITALIAN VICTORY.
THE PLANE TO LISBON.
YOU WOULD LIKE
TO BE ON IT.
WHY?
WHAT'S IN LISBON?
THE CLIPPER TO AMERICA.
I'VE OFTEN SPECULATED
ON WHY YOU DON'T RETURN.
DID YOU ABSCOND
WITH THE CHURCH FUNDS?
DID YOU RUN OFF WITH
A SENATOR'S WIFE?
I'D LIKE TO THINK
THAT YOU KILLED A MAN.
IT'S THE ROMANTIC
IN ME.
IT'S A COMBINATION
OF ALL 3.
WHAT IN HEAVEN'S NAME
BROUGHT YOU TO CASABLANCA?
MY HEALTH.
I CAME TO CASABLANCA
FOR THE WATERS.
THE WATERS? WHAT WATERS?
WE'RE IN THE DESERT.
I WAS MISINFORMED.
EXCUSE ME,
MONSIEUR RICK.
A GENTLEMAN INSIDE
HAS WON 20,000 FRANCS,
AND THE CASHIER
WOULD LIKE SOME MONEY.
I'LL GET IT
FROM THE SAFE.
I'M SO UPSET, MONSIEUR RICK.
FORGET IT, EMIL.
THINGS LIKE THAT
HAPPEN ALL THE TIME.
I'M AWFULLY SORRY.
[PLAYING BABY FACE]
THERE'S GOING TO BE
SOME EXCITEMENT TONIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
AN ARREST IN YOUR CAFE.
WHAT, AGAIN?
THIS IS
NO ORDINARY ARREST.
A MURDERER, NO LESS.
IF YOU'RE THINKING
OF WARNING HIM,
DON'T
PUT YOURSELF OUT.
HE CANNOT POSSIBLY
ESCAPE.
I STICK MY NECK OUT
FOR NOBODY.
A WISE FOREIGN POLICY.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
WE COULD'VE
MADE THIS ARREST
EARLIER THIS EVENING
AT THE BLUE PARROT.
OUT OF MY REGARD FOR YOU,
WE'RE STAGING IT HERE.
IT WILL AMUSE
YOUR CUSTOMERS.
OUR ENTERTAINMENT'S
ENOUGH.
WE'LL HAVE AN IMPORTANT
GUEST HERE TONIGHT,
MAJOR STRASSER
OF THE THIRD REICH, NO LESS.
WE WANT HIM TO BE HERE
WHEN WE MAKE THE ARREST.
A LITTLE DEMONSTRATION
OF THE EFFICIENCY
OF MY ADMINISTRATION.
WHAT'S STRASSER
DOING HERE?
HE CERTAINLY DIDN'T
COME TO CASABLANCA
TO WITNESS
A DEMONSTRATION
OF YOUR EFFICIENCY.
PERHAPS NOT.
IT SHALL NOT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LOUIS, SOMETHING'S
ON YOUR MIND.
WHY DON'T YOU
SPILL IT?
HOW OBSERVANT YOU ARE.
I WANTED TO GIVE YOU
A WORD OF ADVICE.
YEAH?
HAVE A BRANDY?
THANK YOU.
THERE ARE MANY EXIT VISAS
SOLD IN THIS CAFE,
BUT WE KNOW
YOU'VE NEVER SOLD ONE.
THAT IS THE REASON
WE PERMIT YOU TO REMAIN OPEN.
I THOUGHT IT WAS BECAUSE
I LET YOU WIN AT ROULETTE.
THAT IS ANOTHER REASON.
A MAN ARRIVED IN CASABLANCA
ON HIS WAY TO AMERICA.
HE'LL OFFER A FORTUNE
TO ANYONE
WHO WILL FURNISH HIM
WITH AN EXIT VISA.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
VICTOR LASZLO.
VICTOR LASZLO?
THAT IS THE FIRST TIME I'VE
EVER SEEN YOU SO IMPRESSED.
WELL, HE'S IMPRESSED
HALF THE WORLD.
IT'S MY DUTY TO SEE HE DOESN'T
IMPRESS THE OTHER HALF.
RICK, LASZLO MUST NEVER
REACH AMERICA.
HE STAYS IN CASABLANCA.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING
TO SEE HOW HE MANAGES.
MANAGES WHAT?
HIS ESCAPE.
BUT I TOLD YOU--
STOP IT. SINCE HIS ESCAPE
FROM A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
THE NAZIS HAVE CHASED HIM
ALL OVER EUROPE.
THIS IS THE END
OF THE CHASE.
20,000 FRANCS
SAYS IT ISN'T.
IS THAT
A SERIOUS OFFER?
I JUST PAID OUT 20.
I'D LIKE IT BACK.
MAKE IT 10.
I'M ONLY A POOR,
CORRUPT OFFICIAL.
OK.
DONE. NO MATTER
HOW CLEVER HE IS,
HE STILL NEEDS
AN EXIT VISA.
I SHOULD SAY 2.
WHY 2?
HE'S TRAVELING
WITH A LADY.
HE'LL TAKE ONE.
I THINK NOT.
I'VE SEEN THE LADY.
IF HE DIDN'T LEAVE
HER IN MARSEILLES,
HE CERTAINLY WON'T
LEAVE HER IN CASABLANCA.
MAYBE HE'S NOT QUITE
AS ROMANTIC AS YOU ARE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THERE'S NO EXIT VISA
FOR HIM.
WHATEVER GAVE YOU
THE IMPRESSION
THAT I'D BE INTERESTED
IN HELPING LASZLO ESCAPE?
BECAUSE I SUSPECT THAT
UNDER THAT CYNICAL SHELL,
YOU'RE AT HEART
A SENTIMENTALIST.
LAUGH IF YOU WILL,
BUT I'M FAMILIAR
WITH YOUR RECORD.
LET ME POINT OUT
JUST 2 ITEMS.
IN 1935, YOU RAN GUNS
TO ETHIOPIA.
IN 1936,
YOU FOUGHT IN SPAIN
ON THE LOYALIST SIDE.
I GOT WELL PAID FOR IT
ON BOTH OCCASIONS.
THE WINNING SIDE
WOULD HAVE PAID YOU
MUCH BETTER.
MAYBE.
IT SEEMS YOU'RE DETERMINED
TO KEEP LASZLO HERE.
I HAVE MY ORDERS.
I SEE. GESTAPO SPANK.
YOU OVERESTIMATE
THE INFLUENCE
OF THE GESTAPO.
I DON'T INTERFERE
WITH THEM.
THEY DON'T
INTERFERE WITH ME.
IN CASABLANCA, I'M
MASTER OF MY FATE.
MAJOR STRASSER'S
HERE, SIR.
YOU WERE SAYING.
EXCUSE ME.
CARL, SEE THAT MAJOR STRASSER
GETS A GOOD TABLE.
ONE CLOSE TO THE LADIES.
I'VE ALREADY
GIVEN HIM THE BEST,
KNOWING HE'S GERMAN
AND WOULD TAKE IT
ANYWAY.
TAKE HIM QUIETLY.
2 GUARDS AT EVERY DOOR.
YES, SIR.
EVERYTHING
IS READY, SIR.
GO AHEAD.
GOOD EVENING,
GENTLEMEN.
GOOD EVENING, CAPTAIN.
WON'T YOU JOIN US?
THANK YOU.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO HAVE YOU HERE, MAJOR.
CHAMPAGNE
AND CAVIAR.
MAY I RECOMMEND
VEUVE CLIQUOT '26?
A GOOD FRENCH WINE.
VERY WELL, SIR.
VERY INTERESTING CLUB.
ESPECIALLY SO
TONIGHT, MAJOR.
IN A FEW MINUTES
YOU'LL SEE THE ARREST
OF THE MAN WHO MURDERED
YOUR COURIERS.
I EXPECTED NO LESS,
CAPTAIN.
MONSIEUR UGARTE.
OH.
YES?
WILL YOU PLEASE
COME WITH US?
CERTAINLY.
MAY I FIRST PLEASE
CASH MY CHIPS?
[SPEAKING
FRENCH]
PRETTY LUCKY, HUH?
2,000, PLEASE.
2,000.
THANK YOU.
[GUNSHOTS]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
RICK! RICK, HELP ME.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
YOU CAN'T GET AWAY.
HIDE ME. DO SOMETHING.
YOU MUST HELP ME!
DO SOMETHING!
RICK!
EXCELLENT, CAPTAIN.
WHEN THEY COME
TO GET ME, RICK,
I HOPE YOU'RE
MORE OF A HELP.
I STICK MY NECK OUT
FOR NOBODY.
I'M SORRY THERE WAS
A DISTURBANCE, FOLKS,
BUT IT'S ALL OVER NOW.
EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST SIT DOWN
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
ENJOY YOURSELVES.
ALL RIGHT, SAM.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
RICK.
RICK, THIS IS MAJOR
HEINRICH STRASSER
OF THE THIRD REICH.
HOW DO YOU DO?
YOU ALREADY KNOW
HERR HEINZE.
PLEASE JOIN US,
MR. RICK.
WE ARE HONORED
TONIGHT, RICK.
MAJOR STRASSER
IS ONE REASON
THE THIRD REICH
ENJOYS
THE REPUTATION
IT HAS TODAY.
YOU REPEAT
THIRD REICH
AS THOUGH YOU EXPECTED
THERE TO BE OTHERS.
PERSONALLY, MAJOR
I'LL TAKE WHAT COMES.
MAY I ASK A FEW QUESTIONS--
UNOFFICIALLY, OF COURSE?
MAKE IT OFFICIAL
IF YOU LIKE.
WHAT IS YOUR
NATIONALITY?
I'M A DRUNKARD.
THAT MAKES RICK
A CITIZEN OF THE WORLD.
I WAS BORN IN NEW YORK CITY
IF THAT'LL HELP YOU ANY.
YOU CAME HERE FROM PARIS
DURING THE OCCUPATION?
THERE'S NO SECRET
ABOUT THAT.
ARE YOU ONE
OF THOSE PEOPLE
WHO CANNOT
IMAGINE GERMANS
IN THEIR BELOVED PARIS?
IT'S NOT PARTICULARLY
MY BELOVED PARIS.
CAN YOU IMAGINE US
IN LONDON?
WHEN YOU GET THERE,
ASK ME.
DIPLOMATIST.
HOW ABOUT NEW YORK?
THERE ARE CERTAIN SECTIONS
OF NEW YORK, MAJOR,
THAT I WOULDN'T ADVISE YOU
TO TRY TO INVADE.
WHO DO YOU THINK
WILL WIN THE WAR?
I HAVEN'T
THE SLIGHTEST IDEA.
RICK IS NEUTRAL
ABOUT EVERYTHING.
THAT INCLUDES
WOMEN, TOO.
YOU WERE NOT ALWAYS
SO NEUTRAL.
WE HAVE A COMPLETE
DOSSIER ON YOU.
"RICHARD BLAINE,
AMERICAN, 37.
CANNOT RETURN
TO HIS COUNTRY."
THE REASON
IS A LITTLE VAGUE.
WE ALSO KNOW WHAT
YOU DID IN PARIS
AND WHY YOU LEFT PARIS.
DON'T WORRY. WE AREN'T
GOING TO BROADCAST IT.
ARE MY EYES
REALLY BROWN?
FORGIVE MY CURIOSITY.
THE POINT IS,
AN ENEMY OF THE REICH
HAS COME TO CASABLANCA,
AND WE ARE CHECKING UP
ON ANYBODY WHO CAN HELP.
MY INTEREST IN WHETHER
VICTOR LASZLO STAYS OR GOES
IS PURELY A SPORTING ONE.
IN THIS CASE, YOU HAVE
NO SYMPATHY FOR THE FOX?
NOT PARTICULARLY.
I UNDERSTAND THE HOUND'S
POINT OF VIEW, TOO.
VICTOR LASZLO PUBLISHED
THE FOULEST LIES
IN THE PRAGUE NEWSPAPERS
UNTIL WE MARCHED IN.
EVEN AFTER THAT,
HE PRINTED SCANDAL
SHEETS IN A CELLAR.
ONE MUST ADMIT
HE HAS GREAT
COURAGE.
I ADMIT
HE'S VERY CLEVER.
3 TIMES HE SLIPPED
THROUGH OUR FINGERS.
IN PARIS HE CONTINUED
HIS ACTIVITIES.
WE INTEND NOT
TO LET IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
EXCUSE ME, GENTLEMEN.
YOUR BUSINESS IS POLITICS,
MINE IS RUNNING
A SALOON.
GOOD EVENING,
MR. BLAINE.
YOU SEE, MAJOR,
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT RICK.
PERHAPS.
YES, MONSIEUR?
I RESERVED A TABLE.
VICTOR LASZLO.
YES, MONSIEUR LASZLO.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
TWO COINTREAUS, PLEASE.
OUI, MONSIEUR.
I SAW NO ONE OF UGARTE'S
DESCRIPTION.
VICTOR, I FEEL SOMEHOW
WE SHOULDN'T STAY HERE.
IF WE WOULD
WALK OUT SO SOON,
IT WOULD ONLY CALL
ATTENTION TO US.
PERHAPS UGARTE'S IN SOME
OTHER PART OF THE CAFE.
EXCUSE ME, BUT YOU
LOOK LIKE A COUPLE
WHO ARE ON THEIR WAY
TO AMERICA.
YOU'LL FIND A MARKET
THERE FOR THIS RING.
I'M FORCED
TO SELL IT.
THANK YOU, BUT I--
PERHAPS FOR THE LADY.
THE RING'S QUITE UNIQUE.
OH, YES, I'M
VERY INTERESTED.
GOOD.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
BERGER. NORWEGIAN.
AT YOUR SERVICE.
VICTOR.
I'LL MEET YOU IN A FEW
MINUTES AT THE BAR.
NO, WE DON'T WANT
TO BUY THE RING,
BUT THANK YOU FOR
SHOWING IT TO US.
THAT'S
YOUR DECISION?
I'M SORRY. IT IS.
MONSIEUR LASZLO,
IS IT NOT?
YES.
I AM CAPTAIN RENAULT,
PREFECT OF POLICE.
YES. WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT?
MERELY TO WELCOME YOU
TO CASABLANCA
AND TO WISH YOU
A PLEASANT STAY.
IT ISN'T OFTEN WE HAVE
SO DISTINGUISHED A VISITOR.
THANK YOU.
FORGIVE ME, CAPTAIN.
THE PRESENT FRENCH
ADMINISTRATION
HASN'T ALWAYS BEEN
SO CORDIAL.
MAY I PRESENT
MISS ILSA LUND?
I WAS INFORMED YOU WERE
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
EVER TO VISIT CASABLANCA.
THAT WAS A GROSS
UNDERSTATEMENT.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
WON'T YOU JOIN US?
IF YOU WILL PERMIT ME.
NO, EMIL, PLEASE,
A BOTTLE OF CHAMPAGNE.
PUT IT ON MY BILL.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE.
PLEASE. IT'S A LITTLE
GAME WE PLAY.
THEY PUT IT ON THE BILL,
I TEAR UP THE BILL.
IT IS VERY CONVENIENT.
CAPTAIN, THE BOY WHO'S
PLAYING THE PIANO--
SOMEWHERE I'VE SEEN HIM.
SAM? HE CAME FROM PARIS
WITH RICK.
RICK? WHO'S HE?
MADEMOISELLE, YOU'RE IN
RICK'S, AND RICK IS, UH...
WELL, HE'S THE KIND OF MAN
THAT IF I WERE A WOMAN,
AND I WERE NOT AROUND,
I SHOULD BE IN LOVE WITH RICK.
WHAT A FOOL I AM,
TALKING TO A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
ABOUT ANOTHER MAN.
EXCUSE ME.
AH, MAJOR.
MADEMOISELLE LUND
AND MONSIEUR LASZLO,
MAY I PRESENT
MAJOR HEINRICH STRASSER.
THIS IS A PLEASURE
I'VE LONG LOOKED FORWARD TO.
EXCUSE ME
IF I'M NOT GRACIOUS,
BUT, YOU SEE,
I'M A CZECHOSLOVAKIAN.
YOU WERE
A CZECHOSLOVAKIAN.
NOW YOU'RE A SUBJECT
OF THE GERMAN REICH.
I'VE NEVER ACCEPTED
THAT PRIVILEGE,
AND I'M NOW
ON FRENCH SOIL.
I SHOULD LIKE TO DISCUSS
SOME MATTERS ARISING
FROM YOUR PRESENCE
ON FRENCH SOIL.
THIS IS HARDLY
THE TIME OR PLACE.
THEN WE'LL STATE
ANOTHER TIME AND PLACE.
TOMORROW AT 10:00
IN THE PREFECT'S OFFICE...
WITH MADEMOISELLE.
CAPTAIN, I'M UNDER
YOUR AUTHORITY.
IS IT YOUR ORDER
THAT WE COME
TO YOUR OFFICE?
LET'S SAY
IT IS MY REQUEST--
THAT'S A MORE
PLEASANT WORD.
VERY WELL.
MADEMOISELLE.
A VERY CLEVER
TACTICAL RETREAT, MAJOR.
THIS TIME THEY REALLY
MEAN TO STOP ME.
VICTOR, I'M
AFRAID FOR YOU.
WE'VE BEEN IN DIFFICULT PLACES
BEFORE, HAVEN'T WE?
[APPLAUSE]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
I MUST FIND OUT
WHAT BERGER KNOWS.
BE CAREFUL.
I WILL.
DON'T WORRY.
MONSIEUR BERGER, THE RING,
COULD I SEE IT AGAIN?
YES.
CHAMPAGNE COCKTAIL,
PLEASE.
I RECOGNIZE YOU FROM
THE NEWS PHOTOGRAPHS.
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
ONE IS APT TO LOSE WEIGHT.
WE READ 5 TIMES
YOU WERE KILLED
IN 5 DIFFERENT
PLACES.
AS YOU SEE, IT WAS TRUE
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
THANK HEAVEN
I FOUND YOU, BERGER.
I'M LOOKING FOR
A MAN NAMED UGARTE.
HE'S SUPPOSED
TO HELP ME.
UGARTE CANNOT EVEN
HELP HIMSELF.
HE'S UNDER ARREST
FOR MURDER.
HE WAS ARRESTED
HERE TONIGHT.
I SEE.
BUT WE
WHO ARE STILL FREE
WILL DO WHAT WE CAN.
WE ARE ORGANIZED,
MONSIEUR...
UNDERGROUND LIKE
EVERYWHERE ELSE.
TOMORROW NIGHT
THERE'S A MEETING.
IF YOU'LL COME--
Bartender: MONSIEUR.
BRAVO!
WILL YOU ASK
THE PIANO PLAYER
TO COME OVER HERE,
PLEASE?
VERY WELL,
MADEMOISELLE.
HOW'S THE JEWELRY
BUSINESS, BERGER?
NOT SO GOOD.
CHECK, PLEASE.
TOO BAD YOU WEREN'T HERE
EARLIER, MONSIEUR LASZLO.
WE HAD QUITE A BIT
OF EXCITEMENT,
DIDN'T WE, BERGER?
YES.
EXCUSE ME.
MY BILL.
NO. TWO CHAMPAGNE
COCKTAILS. PLEASE.
HELLO, SAM.
HELLO, MISS ILSA.
I NEVER EXPECTED
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME.
YES, MA'AM.
A LOT OF WATER
UNDER THE BRIDGE.
SOME OF THE OLD
SONGS, SAM.
YES, MA'AM.
[PLAYS PIANO]
WHERE IS RICK?
I DON'T KNOW.
I AIN'T SEEN HIM ALL NIGHT.
WHEN WILL HE
BE BACK?
NOT TONIGHT.
HE AIN'T COMIN'.
HE WENT HOME.
DOES HE ALWAYS
LEAVE SO EARLY?
OH, HE NEVER--
HE'S GOT A GIRL
UP TO THE BLUE PARROT.
GOES UP THERE
ALL THE TIME.
YOU USED TO BE
A MUCH BETTER LIAR.
LEAVE HIM ALONE,
MISS ILSA.
YOU'RE BAD LUCK
TO HIM.
PLAY IT ONCE, SAM,
FOR OLD TIMES' SAKE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN, MISS ILSA.
PLAY IT, SAM.
PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY.
I CAN'T REMEMBER IT.
I'M A LITTLE RUSTY ON IT.
I'LL HUM IT FOR YOU.
♫ DA DI DA DI DA DUM ♫
♫ DA DI DEE DEE DEE DUM ♫
SING IT, SAM.
♫ YOU MUST REMEMBER THIS ♫
♫ A KISS IS JUST A KISS ♫
♫ A SIGH IS JUST A SIGH ♫
♫ THE FUNDAMENTAL
THINGS APPLY ♫
♫ AS TIME GOES BY ♫
♫ AND WHEN
TWO LOVERS WOO ♫
♫ THEY STILL SAY
I LOVE YOU ♫
♫ ON THAT YOU CAN RELY ♫
♫ NO MATTER
WHAT THE FUTURE BRINGS ♫
♫ AS TIME GOES BY ♫
SAM, I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
NEVER TO PLAY--
YOU WERE ASKING
ABOUT RICK. HERE HE IS.
MADEMOISELLE,
MAY I PRESENT--
HELLO, ILSA.
HELLO, RICK.
YOU'VE ALREADY MET RICK,
MADEMOISELLE.
THEN PERHAPS YOU ALSO--
THIS IS
MR. LASZLO.
HOW DO YOU DO?
ONE HEARS A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT RICK IN CASABLANCA.
AND ABOUT VICTOR LASZLO
EVERYWHERE.
WON'T YOU JOIN US
FOR A DRINK?
OH, NO. RICK NEVER--
THANKS. I WILL.
WELL...A PRECEDENT
IS BEING BROKEN. EMIL.
THIS IS A VERY
INTERESTING CAFE.
I CONGRATULATE YOU.
I CONGRATULATE YOU
FOR YOUR WORK.
THANK YOU. I TRY.
WE ALL TRY.
YOU SUCCEED.
I CAN'T GET OVER
YOU TWO.
SHE WAS ASKING
ABOUT YOU EARLIER
IN A WAY THAT MADE ME
EXTREMELY JEALOUS.
I WASN'T SURE
YOU WERE THE SAME.
THE LAST TIME WE MET--
IT WAS LA BELLE AURORE.
HOW NICE. YOU REMEMBERED.
THAT WAS THE DAY THE GERMANS
MARCHED INTO PARIS.
NOT AN EASY DAY
TO FORGET.
I REMEMBER
EVERY DETAIL.
THE GERMANS WORE GRAY.
YOU WORE BLUE.
YES. I PUT
THAT DRESS AWAY.
WHEN THE GERMANS MARCH
OUT, I'LL WEAR IT AGAIN.
RICKY, YOU'RE BECOMING
QUITE HUMAN.
I SUPPOSE WE HAVE
TO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
ILSA,
IT'S LATE.
SO IT IS, AND WE HAVE
A CURFEW HERE IN CASABLANCA.
IT WOULD NEVER DO
FOR THE CHIEF OF POLICE
TO BE FOUND
DRINKING AFTER HOURS
AND HAVE TO FINE HIMSELF.
I HOPE WE DIDN'T
OVERSTAY OUR WELCOME.
YOUR CHECK, SIR.
OH, IT'S MY PARTY.
ANOTHER PRECEDENT
GONE.
THIS HAS BEEN
A VERY INTERESTING EVENING.
I'LL CALL YOU A CAB.
GASOLINE RATIONING.
WE'LL
COME AGAIN.
ANY TIME.
SAY GOOD NIGHT
TO SAM FOR ME.
I WILL.
THERE'S STILL
NOBODY IN THE WORLD
WHO CAN PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY LIKE SAM.
HE HASN'T PLAYED IT
IN A LONG TIME.
GOOD NIGHT.
PUZZLING FELLOW, THIS RICK.
WHAT SORT IS HE?
I REALLY CAN'T SAY,
THOUGH I SAW HIM
QUITE OFTEN IN PARIS.
TOMORROW AT 10:00
AT THE PREFECT'S OFFICE.
WE'LL BE THERE.
GOOD NIGHT.
BOSS?
BOSS.
YEAH?
AIN'T YOU
GOING TO BED?
NOT RIGHT NOW.
AIN'T YOU PLANNING ON GOING
TO BED IN THE NEAR FUTURE?
NO!
YOU EVER GOING
TO BED? NO!
WELL, I AIN'T SLEEPY
EITHER.
GOOD.
THEN HAVE A DRINK.
NO, NOT ME, BOSS.
THEN DON'T
HAVE A DRINK.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
NO, SAM.
I'M WAITING FOR A LADY.
PLEASE, LET'S GO.
AIN'T NOTHING BUT TROUBLE
FOR YOU HERE.
SHE'S COMING BACK.
I KNOW SHE'S COMING BACK.
WE'LL DRIVE ALL NIGHT.
WE'LL GET DRUNK.
WE'LL GO FISHING AND STAY
AWAY TILL SHE'S GONE.
SHUT UP AND GO HOME.
NO, SIR.
I'M STAYING RIGHT HERE.
THEY GRAB UGARTE,
THEN SHE WALKS IN.
WELL, THAT'S
THE WAY IT GOES.
ONE IN, ONE OUT.
SAM.
YES, BOSS.
IF IT'S DECEMBER 1941
IN CASABLANCA,
WHAT TIME IS IT
IN NEW YORK?
WHAT?
MY WATCH STOPPED.
I BET THEY'RE ASLEEP
IN NEW YORK.
ALL OVER AMERICA.
OF ALL THE GIN JOINTS
IN ALL THE TOWNS
IN ALL THE WORLD,
SHE WALKS INTO MINE.
WHAT'S THAT
YOU'RE PLAYING?
JUST A LITTLE
SOMETHING OF MY OWN.
WELL, STOP IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I WANT TO HEAR.
NO, I DON'T.
YOU PLAYED IT FOR HER,
YOU CAN PLAY IT FOR ME.
I DON'T THINK
I CAN REMEMBER--
IF SHE CAN STAND IT,
I CAN!
PLAY IT.
YES, BOSS.
[PLAYS AS TIME GOES BY]
OH.
[POP]
WHO ARE YOU REALLY?
WHAT WERE YOU BEFORE?
WHAT DID YOU DO,
AND WHAT DID YOU THINK?
WE SAID NO QUESTIONS.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
A FRANC
FOR YOUR THOUGHTS.
IN AMERICA,
THEY'D BRING ONLY A PENNY.
I GUESS THAT'S ABOUT ALL
THEY'RE WORTH.
WELL, I'M WILLING
TO BE OVERCHARGED.
TELL ME.
WELL, I WAS WONDERING.
YES?
WHY I'M SO LUCKY.
WHY I SHOULD FIND YOU
WAITING FOR ME TO COME ALONG.
WHY THERE IS NO OTHER
MAN IN MY LIFE?
UH-HUH.
THAT'S EASY.
THERE WAS.
HE'S DEAD.
I'M SORRY
FOR ASKING.
I FORGOT.
WE SAID NO QUESTIONS.
WELL,
ONLY ONE ANSWER
CAN TAKE CARE OF
ALL OUR QUESTIONS.
[SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
Man on loudspeaker:
ICI, STUTTGART, ALLEMAGNE,
FRANCAIS, PARISIENS,
LES TROUPES FRANCAISES
ONT ABANDONNE LEURS POSITIONS.
LES ALLEMANDS SERONT DEMAIN
DANS LA CAPITALE.
NOTHING
CAN STOP THEM NOW.
THURSDAY AT THE LATEST,
THEY'LL BE IN PARIS.
IF THEY FIND OUT
YOUR RECORD,
IT WON'T BE SAFE
FOR YOU HERE.
I'M ON THEIR
BLACKLIST ALREADY.
THEIR ROLL OF HONOR.
♫ MOONLIGHT AND LOVE SONGS ♫
♫ NEVER OUT OF DATE ♫
♫ HEARTS FULL OF PASSION ♫
♫ JEALOUSY AND HATE ♫
♫ WOMAN NEEDS MAN ♫
♫ AND MAN
MUST HAVE HIS MATE ♫
♫ THAT NO ONE CAN DENY ♫
♫ IT'S STILL
THE SAME OLD STORY ♫
♫ A FIGHT
FOR LOVE AND GLORY ♫
♫ A CASE OF DO OR DIE ♫
♫ THE WORLD WILL
ALWAYS WELCOME LOVERS ♫
♫ AS TIME GOES BY ♫
HENRI WANTS US TO FINISH
THIS BOTTLE AND THEN 3 MORE.
SAYS HE'LL WATER
HIS GARDEN WITH CHAMPAGNE
BEFORE HE'LL LET
THE GERMANS DRINK IT.
THIS OUGHT TO TAKE THE STING
OUT OF BEING OCCUPIED.
YOU SAID IT.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
[MAN SPEAKING GERMAN
OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
MY GERMAN'S
A LITTLE RUSTY.
IT'S THE GESTAPO.
THEY SAY THEY EXPECT
TO BE IN PARIS TOMORROW.
THEY'RE TELLING US
HOW TO ACT
WHEN THEY COME MARCHING IN.
WITH THE WHOLE
WORLD CRUMBLING,
WE PICK THIS TIME
TO FALL IN LOVE.
YEAH, IT'S PRETTY
BAD TIMING.
WHERE WERE YOU, SAY,
10 YEARS AGO?
10 YEARS AGO.
LET'S SEE. I WAS HAVING
A BRACE PUT ON MY TEETH.
WHERE WERE YOU?
LOOKING FOR A JOB.
[DISTANT ARTILLERY]
WAS THAT CANNON FIRE,
OR IS IT
MY HEART POUNDING?
IT'S THE NEW
GERMAN 77.
JUDGING
BY THE SOUND,
ONLY ABOUT
35 MILES AWAY.
[ARTILLERY FIRE]
AND GETTING CLOSER
EVERY MINUTE.
HERE, HERE,
DRINK UP.
OR WE'LL NEVER FINISH
THE OTHER 3.
GERMANS WILL BE HERE
PRETTY SOON NOW.
THEY'LL COME
LOOKING FOR YOU.
REMEMBER THERE'S A PRICE
ON YOUR HEAD.
I LEFT A NOTE
IN MY APARTMENT.
THEY'LL KNOW WHERE
TO FIND ME.
STRANGE.
I KNOW SO VERY
LITTLE ABOUT YOU.
AND I KNOW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT YOU--
JUST THE FACT THAT YOU HAD
YOUR TEETH STRAIGHTENED.
BE SERIOUS,
YOU ARE IN DANGER.
YOU MUST
LEAVE PARIS.
NO, NO.
WE MUST LEAVE.
YES, OF COURSE, WE.
THE TRAIN FOR MARSEILLES
LEAVES AT 5:00.
I'LL PICK YOU UP
AT YOUR HOTEL AT 4:30.
NO. NOT AT MY HOTEL.
I HAVE THINGS
TO DO IN THE CITY
BEFORE I LEAVE.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT THE STATION.
ALL RIGHT, AT 4:45.
WHY DON'T WE GET MARRIED
IN MARSEILLES?
HA HA HA!
TH-THAT'S TOO FAR
AHEAD TO PLAN.
YES. IT IS A LITTLE
TOO FAR AHEAD.
WHAT ABOUT THE ENGINEER?
WHY CAN'T HE MARRY US
ON THE TRAIN?
OH, DARLING...
WHY NOT?
THE CAPTAIN ON A SHIP CAN.
IT DOESN'T SEEM FAIR--
HEY. HEY,
WHAT'S WRONG, KID?
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH...
AND I HATE THIS WAR
SO MUCH.
OH, IT'S
A CRAZY WORLD.
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN.
IF YOU
SHOULDN'T GET AWAY,
I MEAN, IF SOMETHING
SHOULD KEEP US APART,
WHEREVER THEY PUT YOU
AND WHEREVER I'LL BE,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I--
[ARTILLERY FIRE]
KISS ME.
KISS ME AS IF
IT WERE THE LAST TIME.
EN VOITURE!
ALLONS, ATTENTION!
ALL ABOARD! THE LAST TRAIN
LEAVING IN 20 MINUTES!
ALLEZ-EN!
EN VOITURE!
LE DERNIER TRAIN!
THE LAST TRAIN!
WHERE IS SHE?
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
NO, I CAN'T FIND HER.
SHE CHECKED OUT OF THE HOTEL.
BUT THIS NOTE CAME
AFTER YOU LEFT.
[WHISTLE]
THAT'S THE LAST CALL,
MR. RICHARD.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
COME ON. LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
COME ON.
[WHISTLE]
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
RICK, I HAVE TO
TALK TO YOU.
I SAVED MY FIRST DRINK
TO HAVE WITH YOU.
HERE.
NO. NO, RICK,
NOT TONIGHT.
ESPECIALLY TONIGHT.
WHY DID YOU HAVE TO
COME TO CASABLANCA?
THERE ARE OTHER PLACES.
I WOULDN'T HAVE COME
IF I'D KNOWN
THAT YOU WERE HERE.
BELIEVE ME. IT'S
TRUE. I DIDN'T KNOW.
YOUR VOICE HASN'T CHANGED.
I CAN STILL HEAR IT.
"RICHARD, DEAR,
I'LL GO WITH YOU ANYPLACE."
PLEASE, DON'T.
DON'T, RICK!
I CAN UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU'RE FEELING.
YOU UNDERSTAND
HOW I FEEL.
HOW LONG WAS IT
WE HAD, HONEY?
I DIDN'T
COUNT THE DAYS.
WELL, I DID.
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
MOSTLY I REMEMBER THE LAST ONE,
THE WOW FINISH,
A GUY STANDING ON A STATION
PLATFORM IN THE RAIN
WITH A COMICAL LOOK
ON HIS FACE
BECAUSE HIS INSIDES
HAD BEEN KICKED OUT.
CAN I TELL YOU
A STORY, RICK?
HAS IT GOT
A WOW FINISH?
I DON'T KNOW
THE FINISH YET.
GO ON, TELL IT.
MAYBE ONE'LL COME TO YOU
AS YOU GO ALONG.
IT'S ABOUT A GIRL
WHO HAD JUST
COME TO PARIS
FROM HER HOME IN OSLO.
AT THE HOUSE OF SOME
FRIENDS, SHE MET A MAN
ABOUT WHOM SHE HAD HEARD
HER WHOLE LIFE,
A VERY GREAT
AND COURAGEOUS MAN.
HE OPENED UP FOR HER
A WHOLE BEAUTIFUL WORLD
FULL OF KNOWLEDGE
AND THOUGHTS AND IDEALS.
EVERYTHING SHE KNEW
OR EVER BECAME
WAS BECAUSE OF HIM.
SHE LOOKED UP TO HIM
AND WORSHIPPED HIM
WITH A FEELING
SHE SUPPOSED WAS LOVE.
YES. IT'S VERY PRETTY.
I HEARD A STORY ONCE.
I'VE HEARD A LOT OF STORIES
IN MY TIME.
THEY WENT ALONG WITH THE SOUND
OF A TINNY PIANO
PLAYING IN THE PARLOR
DOWNSTAIRS.
"MISTER, I MET A MAN ONCE
WHEN I WAS A KID,"
IT ALWAYS BEGINS.
OH, I GUESS NEITHER ONE
OF OUR STORIES IS VERY FUNNY.
TELL ME, WHO WAS IT
YOU LEFT ME FOR?
WAS IT LASZLO, OR WERE THERE
OTHERS IN BETWEEN--
OR AREN'T YOU
THE KIND THAT TELLS?
[DOOR CLOSES]
I STRONGLY SUSPECT
THAT UGARTE LEFT THE LETTERS
OF TRANSIT WITH MR. BLAINE.
I SUGGEST YOU SEARCH THE CAFE
IMMEDIATELY AND THOROUGHLY.
IF RICK HAS THE LETTERS,
HE'S MUCH TOO SMART TO
LET YOU FIND THEM THERE.
YOU GIVE HIM CREDIT
FOR TOO MUCH CLEVERNESS.
HE'S JUST ANOTHER
BLUNDERING AMERICAN.
WE MUSTN'T UNDERESTIMATE
AMERICAN BLUNDERING.
I WAS WITH THEM
WHEN THEY BLUNDERED
INTO BERLIN IN 1918.
AS TO LASZLO,
WE WANT HIM WATCHED
24 HOURS A DAY.
AT THIS VERY MOMENT,
HE'S ON HIS WAY HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO.
I'M DELIGHTED
TO SEE YOU BOTH.
DID YOU HAVE
A GOOD NIGHT'S REST?
I SLEPT VERY WELL.
THAT'S STRANGE.
NOBODY'S SUPPOSED
TO SLEEP WELL
IN CASABLANCA.
MAY WE PROCEED
TO THE BUSINESS?
WITH PLEASURE.
WON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
VERY WELL.
LET'S NOT MINCE WORDS.
YOU ARE AN ESCAPED
PRISONER OF THE REICH.
SO FAR YOU HAVE
ELUDED US.
YOU HAVE REACHED
CASABLANCA.
IT'S MY DUTY TO SEE THAT
YOU STAY IN CASABLANCA.
WHETHER OR NOT YOU SUCCEED
IS PROBLEMATIC.
CAPTAIN RENAULT'S
SIGNATURE
IS NECESSARY
ON EVERY EXIT VISA.
WILL HERR LASZLO
RECEIVE A VISA?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
MY REGRETS, MONSIEUR.
PERHAPS I SHALL LIKE IT
IN CASABLANCA.
AND
MADEMOISELLE?
YOU NEEDN'T BE
CONCERNED ABOUT ME.
IS THAT ALL
YOU WISH TO TELL US?
DON'T BE
IN SUCH A HURRY.
YOU HAVE ALL THE TIME
IN THE WORLD.
YOU MAY BE IN CASABLANCA
INDEFINITELY,
OR YOU MAY LEAVE
FOR LISBON TOMORROW
ON ONE CONDITION.
AND THAT IS?
YOU KNOW THE LEADER
OF THE UNDERGROUND
MOVEMENT IN PARIS,
IN PRAGUE, IN BRUSSELS,
IN AMSTERDAM,
IN OSLO, IN BELGRADE,
AND ATHENS.
EVEN BERLIN.
YES, EVEN IN BERLIN.
IF YOU'LL FURNISH ME WITH
THEIR NAMES AND WHEREABOUTS,
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR VISA
IN THE MORNING.
AND THE HONOR OF HAVING
SERVED THE THIRD REICH.
I WAS IN A GERMAN
CONCENTRATION CAMP FOR A YEAR.
THAT'S HONOR ENOUGH
FOR A LIFETIME.
YOU'LL GIVE US
THE NAMES?
IF I DIDN'T GIVE THEM TO YOU
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
WHERE YOU HAD
MORE PERSUASIVE METHODS
AT YOUR DISPOSAL,
I CERTAINLY WON'T
GIVE THEM TO YOU NOW.
WHAT IF YOU KILL THESE MEN?
WHAT IF YOU
MURDERED ALL OF US?
FROM EVERY CORNER
OF EUROPE, HUNDREDS,
THOUSANDS WOULD RISE
TO TAKE OUR PLACES.
EVEN NAZIS CAN'T
KILL THAT FAST.
YOU HAVE A REPUTATION
FOR ELOQUENCE
WHICH I NOW UNDERSTAND.
BUT IN ONE RESPECT
YOU ARE MISTAKEN.
YOU SAID THE REICH'S ENEMIES
COULD BE REPLACED.
THERE'S ONE EXCEPTION.
NO ONE COULD REPLACE YOU
IF ANYTHING UNFORTUNATE
SHOULD OCCUR TO YOU
WHILE YOU WERE
TRYING TO ESCAPE.
YOU WON'T DARE
TO INTERFERE WITH ME HERE.
THIS IS STILL
UNOCCUPIED FRANCE.
ANY VIOLATION OF NEUTRALITY
WOULD REFLECT ON RENAULT.
INSOFAR AS IT IS
IN MY POWER.
THANK YOU.
LAST NIGHT, YOU EVINCED
INTEREST IN SIGNOR UGARTE.
YES.
YOU HAVE
A MESSAGE FOR HIM.
NOTHING IMPORTANT,
BUT MAY I SPEAK TO HIM NOW?
YOU WOULD FIND
THE CONVERSATION
A TRIFLE ONE-SIDED.
SIGNOR UGARTE'S DEAD.
I'M MAKING OUT
THE REPORT NOW.
WE HAVEN'T QUITE DECIDED
WHETHER HE COMMITTED SUICIDE
OR DIED
TRYING TO ESCAPE.
ARE YOU FINISHED WITH US?
FOR THE TIME
BEING.
GOOD DAY.
UNDOUBTEDLY THEIR NEXT STEP
WILL BE TO THE BLACK MARKET.
ANOTHER VISA PROBLEM
HAS COME UP.
SHOW HER IN.
YES, SIR.
SORRY. WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO HANDLE THE POLICE.
THIS IS A JOB
FOR SIGNOR FERRARI.
IT CAN BE MOST HELPFUL
TO KNOW HIM.
HE HAS A MONOPOLY
ON THE BLACK MARKET.
YOU'LL FIND HIM
AT THE BLUE PARROT.
THANKS.
DON'T BE TOO
DOWNHEARTED.
PERHAPS YOU CAN
COME TO TERMS
WITH CAPTAIN RENAULT.
HELLO, FERRARI.
GOOD MORNING,
RICK.
I SEE THE BUS IS IN.
I'LL TAKE
MY SHIPMENT WITH ME.
NO HURRY. I'LL HAVE IT
SENT OVER. HAVE A DRINK.
EVERY TIME YOU SEND
MY SHIPMENT OVER,
IT'S ALWAYS
A LITTLE SHORT.
CARRYING CHARGES,
MY BOY.
HERE, SIT DOWN.
THERE'S SOMETHING I WANT
TO TALK OVER WITH YOU.
THE BOURBON.
THE NEWS ABOUT UGARTE
UPSETS ME.
YOU'RE A FAT HYPOCRITE.
YOU DON'T FEEL ANY SORRIER
FOR UGARTE THAN I DO.
OF COURSE NOT.
WHAT UPSETS ME
IS THAT UGARTE'S DEAD,
AND NO ONE KNOWS WHERE THOSE
LETTERS OF TRANSIT ARE.
PRACTICALLY NO ONE.
IF I COULD
LAY MY HANDS ON THEM,
I COULD MAKE A FORTUNE.
SO COULD I, AND I'M
A POOR BUSINESSMAN.
I HAVE A PROPOSITION
FOR WHOEVER HAS
THOSE LETTERS.
I'LL HANDLE
THE ENTIRE TRANSACTION,
TAKE ALL THE RISK,
FOR A SMALL PERCENTAGE.
AND THE CARRYING
CHARGES?
NATURALLY THERE WILL BE
A FEW INCIDENTAL EXPENSES.
THAT'S THE PROPOSITION
I HAVE
FOR WHOEVER
HAS THOSE LETTERS.
I'LL TELL HIM
WHEN HE COMES IN.
I THINK YOU KNOW
WHERE THOSE LETTERS ARE.
YOU'RE IN GOOD COMPANY.
RENAULT AND STRASSER
PROBABLY THINK SO, TOO.
THAT'S WHY
I CAME OVER HERE,
TO GIVE THEM A CHANCE
TO RANSACK MY PLACE.
DON'T BE A FOOL. TAKE ME
INTO YOUR CONFIDENCE.
YOU NEED A PARTNER.
EXCUSE ME.
I'LL BE GETTING BACK.
GOOD MORNING.
SIGNOR FERRARI'S
THE FAT GENT AT THE TABLE.
YOU WILL NOT FIND A TREASURE
LIKE THIS IN ALL MOROCCO.
ONLY 700 FRANCS.
YOU'RE BEING CHEATED.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THANK YOU.
THE LADY'S A FRIEND
OF RICK'S.
FOR FRIENDS OF RICK'S,
WE HAVE A SMALL DISCOUNT.
DID I SAY 700?
YOU CAN HAVE IT
FOR 200.
I'M SORRY I WAS
IN NO CONDITION
TO RECEIVE YOU
LAST NIGHT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
FOR SPECIAL FRIENDS
OF RICK'S,
A SPECIAL DISCOUNT--
100 FRANCS.
YOUR STORY HAD ME
A LITTLE CONFUSED.
MAYBE IT WAS THE BOURBON.
I HAVE SOME TABLECLOTHS,
SOME NAPKINS.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT INTERESTED.
PLEASE, ONE MINUTE.
WHY DID YOU COME BACK,
TO TELL ME WHY
YOU RAN OUT ON ME
AT THE RAILWAY STATION.
YES.
YOU CAN TELL ME NOW.
I'M REASONABLY SOBER.
I DON'T THINK I WILL.
WHY NOT? I GOT STUCK
WITH THE RAILWAY TICKET.
I THINK I'M ENTITLED
TO KNOW.
LAST NIGHT, I SAW WHAT
HAS HAPPENED TO YOU.
THE RICK I KNEW
IN PARIS,
I COULD TELL HIM.
HE WOULD UNDERSTAND.
THE ONE WHO LOOKED AT ME
WITH SUCH HATRED...
I'LL BE LEAVING
CASABLANCA SOON.
WE'LL NEVER SEE
EACH OTHER AGAIN.
WE KNEW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT EACH OTHER
WHEN WE WERE IN LOVE
IN PARIS.
IF WE LEAVE IT THAT WAY,
MAYBE WE'LL REMEMBER
THOSE DAYS
AND NOT CASABLANCA.
NOT LAST NIGHT.
DID YOU RUN OUT ON ME
BECAUSE YOU
COULDN'T TAKE IT--
HIDING FROM THE POLICE,
RUNNING AWAY ALL THIS TIME?
YOU CAN BELIEVE THAT
IF YOU WANT TO.
I'M NOT
RUNNING AWAY ANYMORE.
I'M SETTLED NOW--
ABOVE A SALOON, IT'S TRUE,
BUT WALK UP A FLIGHT.
I'LL BE EXPECTING YOU.
ALL THE SAME, SOMEDAY
YOU'LL LIE TO LASZLO.
YOU'LL BE THERE.
NO, RICK.
NO. YOU SEE,
VICTOR LASZLO'S
MY HUSBAND.
AND WAS, EVEN WHEN
I KNEW YOU IN PARIS.
I WAS JUST TELLING
MONSIEUR LASZLO
THAT UNFORTUNATELY
I'M NOT ABLE
TO HELP HIM.
THE WORD
HAS GONE AROUND.
AS LEADER OF ALL
ILLEGAL ACTIVITIES
IN CASABLANCA,
I'M AN INFLUENTIAL
AND RESPECTED MAN.
IT WOULDN'T BE WORTH
MY LIFE
TO DO ANYTHING
MONSIEUR LASZLO.
YOU, HOWEVER, ARE
A DIFFERENT MATTER.
SIGNOR FERRARI THINKS
IT MIGHT JUST BE POSSIBLE
TO GET AN EXIT VISA
FOR YOU.
YOU MEAN FOR ME
TO GO ON ALONE?
Ferrari:
AND ONLY ALONE.
I'LL STAY HERE
AND KEEP ON TRYING.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
BE FRANK.
IT WOULD TAKE
A MIRACLE
TO GET YOU OUT
OF CASABLANCA,
AND THE GERMANS
OUTLAWED MIRACLES.
WE ARE ONLY INTERESTED
IN 2 VISAS.
PLEASE, ILSA,
DON'T BE HASTY.
YOU TWO WILL WANT
TO DISCUSS THIS.
EXCUSE ME.
I'LL BE AT THE BAR.
I WON'T LET YOU
STAY HERE.
YOU MUST GET TO AMERICA.
SOMEHOW I'LL JOIN YOU.
IF THE SITUATION
WERE DIFFERENT.
IF I HAD TO STAY
AND THERE WERE
ONLY VISA FOR ONE,
WOULD YOU TAKE IT?
YES, I WOULD.
YES, I SEE.
WHEN I HAD TROUBLE
GETTING OUT OF LILLES,
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LEAVE ME THERE?
WHEN I WAS SICK
IN MARSEILLES
AND HELD YOU UP
FOR 2 WEEKS,
AND YOU WERE IN
DANGER EVERY MINUTE,
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LEAVE ME THEN?
I MEANT TO, BUT SOMETHING
ALWAYS HELD ME UP.
I LOVE YOU
VERY MUCH, ILSA.
YOUR SECRET WILL BE
SAFE WITH ME.
FERRARI'S WAITING
FOR OUR ANSWER.
NOT MORE THAN
50 FRANCS, THOUGH.
WE HAVE DECIDED,
SIGNOR FERRARI.
FOR THE PRESENT, WE'RE ONLY
LOOKING FOR 2 EXIT VISAS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD LUCK, BUT BE CAREFUL.
YOU KNOW THAT
YOU'RE BEING SHADOWED?
OF COURSE.
IT BECOMES AN INSTINCT.
IN ONE RESPECT, YOU ARE
A VERY FORTUNATE MAN, MONSIEUR.
I MOVE TO MAKE ONE MORE
SUGGESTION. WHY, I DON'T KNOW,
BECAUSE IT CANNOT
POSSIBLY PROFIT ME.
HAVE YOU HEARD
ABOUT SIGNOR UGARTE
AND THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
YES. SOMETHING.
THEY WEREN'T ON UGARTE
WHEN THEY ARRESTED HIM.
WHERE ARE THEY?
NOT FOUR SURE.
I'LL VENTURE TO GUESS
THAT UGARTE LEFT THEM
WITH MONSIEUR RICK.
RICK?
ONE NEVER KNOWS
WHAT RICK WILL DO OR WHY,
BUT IT IS WORTH A CHANCE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD DAY.
GOODBYE. THANK YOU
FOR YOUR COFFEE.
I SHALL MISS THAT
WHEN WE LEAVE
CASABLANCA.
GRACIOUS OF YOU TO SHARE IT
WITH ME. GOOD DAY.
GOOD DAY.
[PIANO PLAYING]
HERE'S TO YOU, SIR.
GOOD LUCK.
I'D BETTER BE GOING.
MY CHECK, PLEASE.
I HAVE TO WARN YOU.
THIS IS A DANGEROUS PLACE
FULL OF VULTURES.
VULTURES EVERYWHERE.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
GOODBYE, SIR.
A PLEASURE TO MEET YOU.
I'M SORRY.
MONSIEUR RICK, YOU ARE GETTING
TO BE YOUR BEST CUSTOMER.
DRINKING? NOW YOU'RE BEGINNING
TO LIVE LIKE A FRENCHMAN.
THAT'S SOME GOING-OVER
YOUR MEN GAVE MY PLACE.
WE BARELY GOT CLEANED UP
IN TIME TO OPEN.
I TOLD STRASSER
THE LETTERS WEREN'T HERE,
BUT I TOLD MY MEN TO BE
ESPECIALLY DESTRUCTIVE.
YOU KNOW HOW THAT
IMPRESSES GERMANS.
RICK, HAVE YOU GOT
THOSE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
ARE YOU PRO-VICHY
OR FREE FRENCH?
SERVES ME RIGHT FOR ASKING
A DIRECT QUESTION.
THE SUBJECT IS CLOSED.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE
A LITTLE LATE.
HA HA HA!
SO YVONNE'S GONE OVER
TO THE ENEMY?
WHO KNOWS?
IN HER OWN WAY,
SHE MAY CONSTITUTE
AN ENTIRE SECOND FRONT.
IT'S TIME FOR ME TO FLATTER
MAJOR STRASSER A LITTLE.
SACHA!
FRENCH 75s.
WE'LL HAVE
A WHOLE ROW, SACHA,
STARTING HERE
AND ENDING HERE!
WE WILL BEGIN
WITH 2.
VOUS N'ETES PAS
FRANCAISE VOUS,
D'ALLER AVEC
LES BOCHES COMME CA!
DE QUOI
VOUS MELEZ-VOUS?
NO, NO, NO.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
WOULD YOU KINDLY REPEAT IT?
IT'S NONE
OF YOUR BUSINESS!
I'LL MAKE IT
MY BUSINESS.
ARRETEZ,
JE VOUS EN PRIE!
JE VOUS EN PRIE,
ARRETEZ!
I DON'T LIKE
DISTURBANCES HERE.
EITHER LAY OFF POLITICS
OR GET OUT!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
YOU SEE, CAPTAIN,
THE SITUATION IS NOT AS MUCH
UNDER CONTROL
AS YOU BELIEVE.
WE'RE TRYING TO COOPERATE
WITH YOUR GOVERNMENT.
WE CANNOT REGULATE
OUR PEOPLE'S FEELINGS.
ARE YOU CERTAIN
WHICH SIDE YOU ARE ON?
I HAVE NO CONVICTION.
I BLOW WITH THE WIND.
THE PREVAILING WIND
HAPPENS TO BE FROM VICHY.
AND IF IT SHOULD
CHANGE?
SURELY THE REICH DOESN'T
ADMIT THAT POSSIBILITY.
WE'RE CONCERNED ABOUT
MORE THAN CASABLANCA.
WE KNOW EVERY FRENCH
PROVINCE IN AFRICA
IS HONEYCOMBED
WITH TRAITORS
WAITING FOR THEIR CHANCE,
PERHAPS FOR A LEADER.
A LEADER? LIKE LASZLO?
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS
IF YOU LET HIM GO.
IT MAY BE TOO DANGEROUS
IF YOU LET HIM STAY.
I SEE WHAT YOU MEAN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
THANK YOU, CARL.
CARL, SIT DOWN.
HAVE A BRANDY WITH US.
TO CELEBRATE OUR LEAVING
FOR AMERICA TOMORROW.
THANK YOU. I THOUGHT
YOU WOULD ASK ME,
SO I BROUGHT THE GOOD BRANDY...
AND...A THIRD GLASS.
AT LAST,
THE DAY IS CAME!
WE ARE SPEAKING
NOTHING BUT ENGLISH NOW.
SO WE SHOULD FEEL
AT HOME IN AMERICA.
VERY NICE IDEA.
HA HA.
TO AMERICA.
LIEBCHEN, SWEETNESS,
WHAT WATCH?
10:00 WATCH.
SUCH MUCH?
YOU WILL GET ALONG
BEAUTIFULLY IN AMERICA.
HOW'S LADY LUCK
TREATING YOU?
OH, TOO BAD.
YOU'LL FIND HIM
OVER THERE.
MONSIEUR RICK?
YES.
COULD I SPEAK
TO YOU, PLEASE?
HOW DID YOU GET IN HERE?
YOU'RE UNDERAGE.
I CAME WITH
CAPTAIN RENAULT.
OH, I SHOULD HAVE
KNOWN.
MY HUSBAND
IS WITH ME, TOO.
HE IS? CAPTAIN RENAULT'S
GETTING BROAD-MINDED.
WILL YOU HAVE A DRINK?
OF COURSE NOT.
DO YOU MIND IF I DO?
WHAT KIND OF A MAN
IS CAPTAIN RENAULT?
LIKE ANY OTHER,
ONLY MORE SO.
NO, I MEAN, IS HE TRUSTWORTHY?
IS HIS WORD--
WAIT. WHO TOLD YOU
TO ASK ME THAT?
HE DID.
CAPTAIN RENAULT DID.
I THOUGHT SO.
WHERE'S YOUR HUSBAND?
AT THE ROULETTE TABLE,
TRYING TO WIN ENOUGH
FOR OUR EXIT VISAS.
OF COURSE HE'S LOSING.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN MARRIED?
8 WEEKS.
WE COME FROM BULGARIA.
THINGS ARE VERY
BAD THERE.
THE DEVIL HAS THE PEOPLE
BY THE THROAT.
JAN AND I, WE DO NOT
WANT OUR CHILDREN
TO GROW UP
IN SUCH A COUNTRY.
SO YOU DECIDED
TO GO TO AMERICA.
YES, BUT WE HAVEN'T
MUCH MONEY.
TRAVELING IS SO EXPENSIVE
AND DIFFICULT.
IT WAS MUCH MORE
THAN WE THOUGHT TO GET HERE.
THEN CAPTAIN RENAULT
SEES US.
HE IS SO KIND.
HE WANTS TO HELP US.
YES. I'LL BET.
HE SAYS HE CAN GIVE US
AN EXIT VISA,
BUT WE HAVE NO MONEY.
HE KNOWS THAT, AND
HE'S STILL WILLING
TO GIVE YOU A VISA?
YES.
YOU WANT TO KNOW...
WILL HE KEEP HIS WORD?
HE ALWAYS HAS.
OH.
MONSIEUR,
YOU ARE A MAN.
IF SOMEONE LOVED YOU
VERY MUCH,
SO THAT YOUR HAPPINESS WAS
THE ONLY THING THAT SHE WANTED,
BUT SHE DID A BAD THING
TO MAKE CERTAIN OF IT,
COULD YOU FORGIVE HER?
NOBODY EVER LOVED ME
THAT MUCH.
AND HE NEVER KNEW.
AND THE GIRL KEPT THIS BAD
THING LOCKED IN HER HEART.
THAT WOULD BE ALL RIGHT,
WOULDN'T IT?
YOU WANT MY ADVICE?
YES, PLEASE.
GO BACK TO BULGARIA.
OH, BUT IF YOU KNEW
WHAT IT MEANS TO US
TO LEAVE EUROPE,
TO GET TO AMERICA!
OH, BUT IF JAN
SHOULD FIND OUT...
HE'S SUCH A BOY.
IN MANY WAYS, I'M SO MUCH
OLDER THAN HE IS.
YES, WELL, EVERYBODY IN
CASABLANCA HAS PROBLEMS.
YOURS MAY WORK OUT.
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU, MONSIEUR.
GOOD EVENING. YOU SEE,
HERE WE ARE AGAIN.
I TAKE THAT AS A GREAT
COMPLIMENT TO SAM.
I SUPPOSE HE MEANS PARIS
OF, WELL, HAPPIER DAYS.
HE DOES.
COULD WE HAVE A
TABLE NEAR HIM?
AND AS FAR FROM MAJOR
STRASSER AS POSSIBLE?
THE GEOGRAPHY MAY BE
DIFFICULT TO ARRANGE.
PAUL, TABLE 30.
RIGHT THIS WAY,
IF YOU PLEASE.
I'LL HAVE SAM PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY.
I BELIEVE THAT'S
YOUR FAVORITE TUNE.
THANK YOU.
[PLAYS AS TIME GOES BY]
TWO COGNAC, PLEASE.
COGNAC.
MARQUONS LES JEUX,
MESDAMES ET MESSIEURS.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
MESDAMES ET MESSIEURS,
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
DO YOU WISH TO PLACE
ANOTHER BET, SIR?
NO. NO. I GUESS NOT.
HAVE YOU TRIED
22 TONIGHT?
I SAID 22.
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
FINIS.
VINGT-DEUX!
VINGT-DEUX.
LEAVE IT THERE.
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
FINIS.
VINGT-DEUX!
CASH IT IN,
AND DON'T COME BACK.
FINIS.
ARE YOU SURE
THIS PLACE IS HONEST?
HONEST? AS HONEST
AS THE DAY IS LONG!
HOW ARE WE
DOING TONIGHT?
A COUPLE
OF THOUSAND LESS
THAN I THOUGHT
THERE WOULD BE.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MONSIEUR RICK...I...
I...OH!
JUST A LUCKY GUY.
MONSIEUR RICK, MAY I
GET YOU A CUP OF COFFEE?
NO, THANKS, CARL.
MONSIEUR RICK...
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
MAY I GIVE YOU--
NOT HERE, PLEASE.
COME TO MY OFFICE
IN THE MORNING.
WE'LL DO EVERYTHING
BUSINESSLIKE.
WE'LL BE THERE AT 6:00.
I'LL BE THERE
AT 10:00.
I'M HAPPY
FOR BOTH YOU.
IT'S VERY STRANGE
THAT YOU WON.
MAYBE NOT SO STRANGE.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
THANK YOU,
CAPTAIN RENAULT.
NO! IS IT TRUE?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
BOSS, YOU'VE DONE
A BEAUTIFUL THING!
GO AWAY,
YOU CRAZY RUSSIAN.
AS I SUSPECTED,
YOU'RE A RANK SENTIMENTALIST.
YEAH. WHY?
WHY DO YOU INTERFERE
WITH MY LITTLE ROMANCES?
PUT IT DOWN
AS A GESTURE TO LOVE.
I'LL FORGIVE YOU
THIS TIME,
BUT I'LL BE IN TOMORROW
WITH A BREATHTAKING BLONDE,
AND IT'LL MAKE ME
VERY HAPPY IF SHE LOSES.
MONSIEUR BLAINE, I WONDER
IF I COULD TALK TO YOU.
GO AHEAD.
WELL, ISN'T THERE
SOME OTHER PLACE?
IT'S RATHER CONFIDENTIAL,
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY.
IN MY OFFICE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
I GET OUT OF CASABLANCA.
I AM ONE OF THE LEADERS
OF A GREAT MOVEMENT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT MEANS
TO THE LIVES OF
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
THAT I REACH AMERICA
AND CONTINUE MY WORK.
THE PROBLEMS OF THE WORLD
AREN'T IN MY DEPARTMENT.
I'M A SALOON KEEPER.
MY FRIENDS
IN THE UNDERGROUND
TELL ME YOU'VE
QUITE A RECORD.
YOU RAN GUNS
TO ETHIOPIA,
YOU FOUGHT
FASCISTS IN SPAIN.
WHAT OF IT?
ISN'T IT STRANGE
THAT YOU'RE ALWAYS
FIGHTING ON THE SIDE
OF THE UNDERDOG?
YES. I FOUND THAT
AN EXPENSIVE HOBBY, TOO,
BUT I NEVER WAS
MUCH OF A BUSINESSMAN.
WOULD YOU APPRECIATE AN
OFFER OF 100,000 FRANCS?
YES, I'D APPRECIATE IT,
BUT I DON'T ACCEPT IT.
200,000.
YOU COULD MAKE IT
A MILLION OR 3.
MY ANSWER WOULD BE
THE SAME.
THERE MUST BE
SOME REASON
WHY YOU WON'T
LET ME HAVE THEM.
THERE IS. I SUGGEST
YOU ASK YOUR WIFE.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
I SAID ASK YOUR WIFE.
MY WIFE?
YES.
[SINGING
DIE WACHT AM RHEIN]
PLAY LA MARSEILLAISE.
PLAY IT.
♫ ALLONS,
ENFANTS DE LA PATRIE ♫
♫ LE JOUR DE GLOIRE
EST ARRIVE ♫
♫ CONTRE NOUS
DE LA TYRANNIE ♫
♫ L'ETENDARD SANGLANT
EST LEVE ♫
♫ L'ETENDARD
SANGLANT EST LEVE ♫
♫ ENTENDEZ-VOUS,
DANS LES CAMPAGNES ♫
♫ MUGIR
CES FEROCES SOLDATS? ♫
♫ ILS VIENNENT
JUSQUE DANS NOS BRAS ♫
♫ EGORGER NOS FILS
ET NOS COMPAGNES ♫
♫ AUX ARMES, CITOYENS! ♫
♫ FORMEZ VOS BATAILLONS! ♫
♫ MARCHONS! ♫
♫ QU'UN SANG IMPUR ♫
♫ ABREUVE NOS SILLONS! ♫
VIVE LA FRANCE!
VIVE LA DEMOCRATIE!
[CHEERING]
VIVE LA FRANCE!
VIVE LA DEMOCRATIE!
IF LASZLO'S PRESENCE
IN A CAFE CAN INSPIRE
THIS UNFORTUNATE
DEMONSTRATION,
WHAT MORE WILL HIS PRESENCE
IN CASABLANCA BRING ON?
I ADVISE THAT THIS PLACE
BE SHUT UP AT ONCE.
BUT EVERYBODY'S HAVING
SUCH A GOOD TIME.
YES, MUCH TOO GOOD.
CLOSE THE PLACE.
BUT I HAVE NO EXCUSE
TO CLOSE IT.
FIND ONE.
SANTE.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
EVERYBODY IS TO
LEAVE IMMEDIATELY!
THIS CAFE IS CLOSED
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE!
CLEAR THE ROOM AT ONCE!
HOW CAN HE CLOSE ME UP?
ON WHAT GROUNDS?
I'M SHOCKED TO FIND
GAMBLING GOING ON HERE!
YOUR WINNINGS, SIR.
OH, THANK YOU.
EVERYBODY OUT!
MADEMOISELLE, AFTER
THIS DISTURBANCE,
IT ISN'T SAFE FOR LASZLO
TO STAY IN CASABLANCA.
THIS MORNING YOU IMPLIED
IT WASN'T SAFE
FOR HIM TO LEAVE.
TRUE, EXCEPT
FOR ONE DESTINATION.
TO RETURN
TO OCCUPIED FRANCE--
OCCUPIED FRANCE?
UNDER A SAFE
CONDUCT FROM ME.
WHAT VALUE IS THAT?
YOU MAY RECALL
WHAT GERMAN GUARANTEES
HAVE BEEN WORTH IN THE PAST.
THERE ARE ONLY
2 ALTERNATIVES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
IT IS POSSIBLE
THE FRENCH AUTHORITIES
COULD PUT HIM IN
A CONCENTRATION CAMP.
THE OTHER ALTERNATIVE?
MY DEAR MADEMOISELLE,
PERHAPS YOU HAVE
ALREADY OBSERVED
THAT IN CASABLANCA
HUMAN LIFE IS CHEAP.
GOOD NIGHT,
MADEMOISELLE.
GARCON?
WHAT HAPPENED
WITH RICK?
WE'LL DISCUSS IT
LATER.
OUR FAITHFUL FRIEND
IS STILL THERE.
VICTOR,
PLEASE DON'T GO
TO THE UNDERGROUND
MEETING TONIGHT.
I MUST. BESIDES,
IT ISN'T OFTEN
A MAN CAN DISPLAY HEROICS
BEFORE HIS WIFE.
DON'T JOKE.
AFTER MAJOR STRASSER'S
WARNING TONIGHT,
I AM FRIGHTENED.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I'M FRIGHTENED, TOO.
SHALL I REMAIN HERE
IN A HOTEL ROOM, HIDING,
OR SHALL I CARRY ON
THE BEST I CAN?
WHATEVER I'D SAY,
YOU'D CARRY ON.
TELL ME ABOUT RICK.
WHAT DID YOU FIND OUT?
APPARENTLY
HE HAS THE LETTERS.
YES?
BUT NO INTENTION
OF SELLING THEM.
ONE WOULD THINK IF SENTIMENT
WOULDN'T PERSUADE HIM,
MONEY WOULD.
DID HE GIVE YOU
ANY REASON?
HE SUGGESTED
I ASK YOU.
ASK ME?
YES, HE SAID,
"ASK YOUR WIFE."
I DON'T KNOW
WHY HE SAID THAT.
OUR FRIEND OUTSIDE WILL THINK
WE HAVE RETIRED BY NOW.
I'LL BE GOING
IN A FEW MINUTES.
ILSA, I--
YES?
WHEN I WAS IN
THE CONCENTRATION CAMP,
WERE YOU LONELY
IN PARIS?
YES, VICTOR, I WAS.
I KNOW HOW IT IS
TO BE LONELY.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WISH TO TELL ME?
NO, VICTOR,
THERE ISN'T.
I LOVE YOU VERY MUCH,
MY DEAR.
YES.
YES, I KNOW.
VICTOR, WHATEVER I DO,
WILL YOU BELIEVE
THAT I--THAT--
YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE
TO SAY IT. I'LL BELIEVE.
GOOD NIGHT, DEAR.
GOOD NIGHT.
VICTOR.
YES, DEAR?
BE CAREFUL.
OF COURSE
I'LL BE CAREFUL.
WELL, YOU ARE IN PRETTY
GOOD SHAPE, HERR RICK.
HOW LONG CAN I
AFFORD TO STAY CLOSED?
2 WEEKS, MAYBE 3.
MAYBE I WON'T HAVE TO.
A BRIBE HAS WORKED BEFORE.
IN THE MEANTIME, EVERYBODY
STAYS ON SALARY.
THANK YOU.
SACHA WILL BE HAPPY.
I OWE HIM MONEY.
FINISH LOCKING UP,
WILL YOU, CARL?
YES. THEN I AM GOING
TO THE MEETING OF--
DON'T TELL ME
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
I WON'T.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, MR. RICK.
HOW DID YOU GET IN?
THE STAIRS
FROM THE STREET.
I TOLD YOU THIS MORNING
YOU'D COME AROUND,
BUT THIS IS AHEAD
OF SCHEDULE. SIT DOWN.
RICHARD, I HAD TO
SEE YOU.
OH, IT'S RICHARD AGAIN.
WE'RE BACK IN PARIS.
IS YOUR VISIT ISN'T CONNECTED
WITH THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
AS LONG AS I HAVE THOSE,
I'LL NEVER BE LONELY.
ASK ANY PRICE, BUT I
MUST HAVE THOSE LETTERS.
I WENT THROUGH THAT
WITH YOUR HUSBAND. NO DEAL.
I'M ASKING YOU TO
PUT YOUR FEELINGS ASIDE
FOR SOMETHING
MORE IMPORTANT.
DO I HAVE TO
HEAR AGAIN
WHAT A GREAT MAN
YOUR HUSBAND IS,
WHAT AN IMPORTANT CAUSE
HE'S FIGHTING FOR?
IT WAS YOUR CAUSE,
TOO. IN YOUR WAY,
YOU WERE FIGHTING
FOR THE SAME THING.
I'M NOT FIGHTING FOR ANYTHING
ANYMORE EXCEPT MYSELF.
I'M THE ONLY CAUSE
I'M INTERESTED IN.
RICHARD, WE LOVED
EACH OTHER ONCE.
IF THOSE DAYS MEANT
ANYTHING AT ALL TO YOU--
I WOULDN'T BRING UP PARIS.
IT'S POOR SALESMANSHIP.
PLEASE LISTEN TO ME.
IF YOU ONLY
KNEW THE TRUTH.
I WOULDN'T BELIEVE YOU,
NO MATTER WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU'D SAY ANYTHING
TO GET WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU WANT TO FEEL SORRY
FOR YOURSELF, DON'T YOU?
THERE'S SO MUCH
AT STAKE.
ALL YOU THINK OF
IS YOUR OWN FEELING.
ONE WOMAN HAS HURT YOU,
AND YOU TAKE YOUR REVENGE
ON THE WHOLE WORLD.
YOU'RE A COWARD
AND A WEAKLING.
NO. NO, RICHARD.
I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY, BUT YOU
ARE OUR LAST HOPE.
IF YOU DON'T HELP US,
VICTOR LASZLO
WILL DIE IN CASABLANCA.
WHAT OF IT? I'M GOING
TO DIE IN CASABLANCA.
IT'S A GOOD SPOT FOR IT.
NOW, IF YOU--
ALL RIGHT, I TRIED
TO REASON WITH YOU.
I TRIED EVERYTHING.
NOW I WANT
THOSE LETTERS.
GET THEM FOR ME.
I DON'T HAVE TO.
I GOT THEM RIGHT HERE.
PUT THEM ON THE TABLE.
NO.
FOR THE LAST TIME,
PUT THEM ON THE TABLE.
IF LASZLO AND THE CAUSE
MEAN SO MUCH,
YOU WON'T STOP AT ANYTHING.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL
MAKE IT EASIER FOR YOU.
GO AHEAD AND SHOOT.
YOU'LL BE
DOING ME A FAVOR.
RICHARD.
I TRIED TO STAY AWAY.
I THOUGHT I WOULD
NEVER SEE YOU AGAIN,
THAT YOU WERE
OUT OF MY LIFE.
THE DAY
YOU LEFT PARIS...
IF YOU KNEW WHAT
I WENT THROUGH.
IF YOU KNEW HOW MUCH
I LOVED YOU.
HOW MUCH
I STILL LOVE YOU.
AND THEN?
IT WASN'T LONG
AFTER WE WERE MARRIED
THAT VICTOR WENT BACK
TO CZECHOSLOVAKIA.
THEY NEEDED HIM
IN PRAGUE,
BUT THERE THE GESTAPO
WERE WAITING FOR HIM.
JUST A 2-LINE ITEM
IN THE PAPER,
"VICTOR LASZLO
APPREHENDED.
SENT TO
CONCENTRATION CAMP."
I WAS FRANTIC.
FOR MONTHS
I TRIED TO GET WORD.
THEN IT CAME.
HE WAS DEAD--
SHOT TRYING TO ESCAPE.
I WAS LONELY.
I HAD NOTHING--
NOT EVEN HOPE.
THEN I MET YOU.
WHY WEREN'T YOU
HONEST WITH ME?
WHY DID YOU KEEP
YOUR MARRIAGE A SECRET?
IT WASN'T MY SECRET.
VICTOR WANTED IT
THAT WAY.
OUR CLOSEST FRIENDS
DIDN'T KNOW.
HE WANTED TO PROTECT ME.
I KNEW ABOUT HIS WORK.
IF THE GESTAPO KNEW
I WAS HIS WIFE,
IT WOULD BE DANGEROUS
FOR ME
AND FOR THOSE
WORKING WITH US.
WHEN DID YOU FIRST
FIND OUT HE WAS ALIVE?
JUST BEFORE YOU AND I
WERE TO
LEAVE PARIS TOGETHER.
A FRIEND TOLD ME
VICTOR WAS ALIVE.
THEY WERE HIDING HIM
IN A FREIGHT CAR
ON THE OUTSKIRTS
OF PARIS.
HE WAS SICK.
HE NEEDED ME.
I WANTED TO TELL YOU,
BUT I DIDN'T DARE.
I KNEW YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE LEFT PARIS
AND THE GESTAPO
WOULD HAVE CAUGHT YOU.
SO I...WELL,
YOU KNOW THE REST.
WELL, IT'S STILL
A STORY WITHOUT AN ENDING.
WHAT ABOUT NOW?
NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
I KNOW THAT I'LL NEVER
HAVE THE STRENGTH
TO LEAVE YOU AGAIN.
AND LASZLO?
YOU'LL HELP HIM,
WON'T YOU?
YOU'LL SEE
THAT HE GETS OUT.
THEN HE'LL HAVE
HIS WORK--
ALL THAT HE'S
BEEN LIVING FOR.
ALL EXCEPT ONE.
HE WON'T HAVE YOU.
I CAN'T FIGHT IT
ANYMORE.
I RAN AWAY
FROM YOU ONCE.
I CAN'T DO IT AGAIN.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S RIGHT ANY LONGER.
YOU HAVE TO THINK
FOR BOTH OF US,
FOR ALL OF US.
ALL RIGHT.
I WILL.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
I WISH I DIDN'T
LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
I THINK
WE LOST THEM.
YES. I'M AFRAID THEY CAUGHT
SOME OF THE OTHERS.
COME INSIDE.
COME.
COME, MR. LASZLO.
I WILL HELP YOU...
IMMEDIATELY.
THANK YOU.
[VOICES]
CARL, WHAT HAPPENED?
THE POLICE BREAK UP
OUR MEETING, HERR RICK.
WE ESCAPED
IN THE LAST MOMENT.
COME UP HERE.
TURN OUT THE LIGHT
IN THE REAR ENTRANCE.
IT MIGHT
ATTRACT THE POLICE.
SACHA ALWAYS
PUTS IT OUT.
TONIGHT HE FORGOT.
I WILL DO IT.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE MISS LUND HOME.
YES, SIR.
IT'S NOTHING.
JUST A LITTLE CUT.
WE HAD TO GET
THROUGH A WINDOW.
THIS MIGHT
COME IN HANDY.
THANK YOU.
HAD A CLOSE ONE, EH?
YES, RATHER.
DON'T YOU SOMETIMES WONDER
IF IT'S WORTH ALL THIS?
I MEAN, WHAT
YOU'RE FIGHTING FOR.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL QUESTION
WHY WE BREATHE.
IF WE STOP BREATHING,
WE'LL DIE.
IF WE STOP FIGHTING OUR
ENEMIES, THE WORLD WILL DIE.
WHAT OF IT? IT'LL BE
OUT OF ITS MISERY.
YOU KNOW HOW YOU SOUND?
LIKE A MAN TRYING TO CONVINCE
HIMSELF OF SOMETHING
HE DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN HIS HEART.
EACH OF US HAS A DESTINY--
FOR GOOD OR EVIL.
I GET THE POINT.
I WONDER IF YOU DO.
DO YOU KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO ESCAPE FROM YOURSELF?
YOU'LL NEVER SUCCEED.
YOU SEEM TO KNOW
ALL ABOUT MY DESTINY.
I KNOW A GOOD DEAL MORE
ABOUT YOU THAN YOU SUSPECT.
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
IN LOVE WITH A WOMAN.
IT'S PERHAPS
A STRANGE CIRCUMSTANCE
THAT WE BOTH SHOULD BE
IN LOVE WITH THE SAME WOMAN.
THE FIRST EVENING
I CAME TO THIS CAFE,
I KNEW THERE WAS SOMETHING
BETWEEN YOU AND ILSA.
SINCE NO ONE'S TO BLAME,
I DEMAND NO EXPLANATION.
I ASK ONLY ONE THING.
YOU WON'T GIVE ME
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
ALL RIGHT, BUT I
WANT MY WIFE TO BE SAFE.
I ASK YOU TO USE THE LETTERS
TO TAKE HER AWAY.
YOU LOVE HER
THAT MUCH?
YOU THINK OF ME
ONLY AS A LEADER OF A CAUSE.
I'M ALSO A HUMAN BEING.
YES, I LOVE HER THAT MUCH.
MONSIEUR LASZLO?
YES?
COME WITH US. WE HAVE
A WARRANT FOR YOUR ARREST.
ON WHAT CHARGE?
CAPTAIN RENAULT WILL
DISCUSS THAT WITH YOU LATER.
IT SEEMS THAT DESTINY
HAS TAKEN A HAND.
YOU KNOW YOU HAVEN'T
ANY ACTUAL PROOF.
THIS ISN'T GERMANY
OR OCCUPIED FRANCE.
YOU CAN ONLY FINE HIM
AND GIVE HIM 30 DAYS.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
LET HIM GO NOW.
I'D ADVISE YOU NOT TO BE
TOO INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO LASZLO.
IF YOU HELPED HIM
ESCAPE--
WHY WOULD I STICK
MY NECK OUT FOR LASZLO?
1--YOU BET 10,000 FRANCS
HE'D ESCAPE.
2--YOU'VE GOT
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
DON'T BOTHER TO DENY IT.
AND YOU MIGHT DO IT
BECAUSE YOU DON'T LIKE
STRASSER'S LOOKS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I DON'T LIKE THEM,
EITHER.
THEY'RE ALL
EXCELLENT REASONS.
DON'T COUNT TOO MUCH
ON MY FRIENDSHIP.
IN THIS MATTER,
I'M POWERLESS.
BESIDES, I MIGHT LOSE
THE 10,000 FRANCS.
YOU'RE NOT VERY SUBTLE,
BUT YOU ARE EFFECTIVE.
I GET THE POINT.
YES, I HAVE THE LETTERS.
I INTEND USING THEM MYSELF.
I'M LEAVING CASABLANCA
ON THE LAST PLANE TONIGHT.
I'M TAKING A FRIEND--
ONE YOU'LL APPRECIATE.
WHAT FRIEND?
ILSA LUND.
THAT SHOULD PUT YOUR MIND
TO REST ABOUT LASZLO--
THE LAST MAN I WANT
TO SEE IN AMERICA.
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TELL ME THIS.
YOU HAVE THE LETTERS
OF TRANSIT.
YOU CAN LEAVE
ANYTIME YOU PLEASE.
WHY ARE YOU STILL
INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO LASZLO?
I'M NOT.
BUT I AM INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO ILSA AND ME.
WE HAVE A LEGAL RIGHT
TO GO, THAT'S TRUE,
BUT PEOPLE HAVE BEEN HELD
IN SPITE OF THEIR RIGHTS.
WHY SHOULD
WE HOLD YOU?
ILSA'S LASZLO'S WIFE.
SHE PROBABLY KNOWS THINGS
STRASSER WOULD LIKE TO KNOW.
I'LL MAKE A DEAL.
INSTEAD OF THIS PETTY CHARGE,
GET SOMETHING BIG
THAT WOULD CHUCK HIM IN
A CONCENTRATION CAMP FOR YEARS.
IT'D BE QUITE A FEATHER
IN YOUR CAP, WOULDN'T IT?
IT CERTAINLY WOULD.
GERMANY--VICHY
WOULD BE VERY GRATEFUL.
THEN RELEASE HIM.
BE AT MY PLACE A HALF HOUR
BEFORE THE PLANE LEAVES.
I'LL HAVE LASZLO COME THERE
TO PICK UP
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT--
THAT'LL GIVE YOU THE CRIMINAL
GROUNDS FOR ARREST.
YOU GET HIM,
AND WE GET AWAY.
TO THE GERMANS, THAT LAST ONE
WILL BE JUST A MINOR ANNOYANCE.
THERE'S STILL SOMETHING
I DON'T QUITE UNDERSTAND.
MISS LUND--SHE'S
VERY BEAUTIFUL, YES,
BUT YOU WERE NEVER
INTERESTED IN ANY WOMAN.
SHE ISN'T
JUST ANY WOMAN.
I SEE. HOW DO I KNOW
YOU'LL KEEP YOUR WORD?
I'LL MAKE THE ARRANGEMENTS
RIGHT NOW WITH LASZLO
IN THE VISITORS' PEN.
RICKY,
I'LL MISS YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
IN CASABLANCA
WHO HAS EVEN LESS
SCRUPLES THAN I.
THANKS.
GO AHEAD, RICKY.
CALL OFF YOUR WATCHDOGS
WHEN YOU LET HIM GO.
I DON'T WANT THEM AROUND
THIS AFTERNOON.
I'M TAKING NO CHANCES,
NOT EVEN WITH YOU.
SHALL WE
DRAW UP PAPERS,
OR IS A HANDSHAKE
GOOD ENOUGH?
CERTAINLY
NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
BUT SINCE I'M IN A
HURRY, IT'LL HAVE TO DO.
AH, TO LEAVE CASABLANCA
AND GO TO AMERICA--
YOU'RE A LUCKY MAN.
BY THE WAY,
MY AGREEMENT WITH SAM
IS THAT HE GETS
25% OF THE PROFITS.
I HAPPEN TO KNOW IT'S 10%,
BUT HE'S WORTH 25.
ABDUL, CARL, AND SACHA
STAY, OR I DON'T SELL.
OF COURSE. RICK'S WOULDN'T
BE RICK'S WITHOUT THEM.
WELL, SO LONG.
DON'T FORGET,
YOU OWE RICK'S
100 CARTONS OF
AMERICAN CIGARETTES.
I SHALL REMEMBER
TO PAY IT TO MYSELF.
[BANGING ON DOOR]
YOU'RE LATE.
I WAS INFORMED
JUST AS LASZLO WAS
LEAVING THE HOTEL,
SO I KNEW
I'D BE ON TIME.
I ASKED YOU TO TIE UP
YOUR WATCHDOGS.
HE WON'T BE
FOLLOWED HERE.
THIS PLACE WON'T BE
THE SAME WITHOUT YOU.
I KNOW, BUT I'VE ALREADY
SPOKEN TO FERRARI.
YOU'LL STILL
WIN AT ROULETTE.
IS EVERYTHING READY?
I HAVE
THE LETTERS.
WHEN WE SEARCHED THE PLACE,
WHERE WERE THEY?
SAM'S PIANO.
SERVES ME RIGHT
FOR NOT BEING MUSICAL.
[BRAKES SQUEAL]
HERE THEY ARE.
YOU'D BETTER
WAIT IN MY OFFICE.
HERE.
RICHARD, VICTOR THINKS
I'M LEAVING WITH HIM.
HAVEN'T YOU TOLD HIM?
NO, NOT YET.
IT'S ALL RIGHT?
YOU ARRANGED EVERYTHING?
YES. WE'LL TELL HIM
AT THE AIRPORT.
THE LESS TIME TO THINK,
THE EASIER FOR ALL OF US.
PLEASE TRUST ME.
YES, I WILL.
MONSIEUR BLAINE, I DON'T
KNOW HOW TO THANK YOU.
SAVE IT. WE'VE LOTS
OF THINGS TO DO.
I BROUGHT
THE MONEY.
KEEP IT. YOU'LL
NEED IT IN AMERICA.
BUT WE
MADE A DEAL.
NEVER MIND. WILL YOU
HAVE TROUBLE IN LISBON?
NO. IT'S ALL ARRANGED.
GOOD. THE LETTERS ARE
ALL MADE OUT IN BLANK.
JUST FILL IN
THE SIGNATURES.
VICTOR LASZLO?
VICTOR LASZLO,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST...
ON THE CHARGE
OF ACCESSORY
TO THE MURDER
OF THE COURIERS
FROM WHOM THESE LETTERS
WERE STOLEN.
YOU'RE SURPRISED
ABOUT MY FRIEND RICKY?
THE EXPLANATION
IS QUITE SIMPLE.
LOVE, IT SEEMS, HAS
TRIUMPHED OVER VIRTUE.
NOT SO FAST, LOUIS.
NOBODY IS GOING
TO BE ARRESTED,
NOT FOR A WHILE YET.
HAVE YOU TAKEN LEAVE
OF YOUR SENSES?
I HAVE.
SIT DOWN.
I WOULDN'T LIKE
TO SHOOT YOU,
BUT I WILL IF YOU
TAKE ONE MORE STEP.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I WILL SIT DOWN.
KEEP YOUR HANDS
ON THE TABLE.
I WONDER IF YOU REALIZE
WHAT THIS MEANS.
I DO. WE'LL DISCUSS
THAT LATER.
"CALL OFF YOUR
WATCHDOGS," YOU SAID.
CALL THE AIRPORT. LET
ME HEAR YOU TELL THEM.
THIS GUN'S POINTED
RIGHT AT YOUR HEART.
THAT IS MY
LEAST VULNERABLE SPOT.
HELLO?
IS THAT THE AIRPORT?
EH?
CAPTAIN RENAULT SPEAKING.
THERE'LL BE 2 LETTERS OF TRANSIT
FOR THE LISBON PLANE.
THERE'S TO BE NO TROUBLE
ABOUT THEM.
GOOD.
HELLO? HELLO?
[BUZZER]
MY CAR, QUICKLY.
JAWOHL, MAJOR.
THIS IS MAJOR STRASSER.
HAVE A SQUAD OF POLICE
MEET ME AT THE AIRPORT
AT ONCE, DO YOU HEAR?
HELLO, HELLO,
RADIO TOWER?
LISBON PLANE TAKING OFF
IN 10 MINUTES. EAST RUNWAY.
VISIBILITY,
1 1/2 MILES.
LIGHT GROUND FOG.
DEPTH OF FOG,
APPROXIMATELY 500.
CEILING UNLIMITED.
THANK YOU.
LOUIS, HAVE YOUR MAN
GO WITH MR. LASZLO.
TAKE CARE
OF HIS LUGGAGE.
ANYTHING YOU SAY.
PUT MR. LASZLO'S LUGGAGE
ON THE PLANE.
YES, SIR.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
YOU FILL IN THE NAMES.
THAT'LL MAKE IT
EVEN MORE OFFICIAL.
YOU THINK OF EVERYTHING,
DON'T YOU?
THE NAMES ARE MR.
AND MRS. VICTOR LASZLO.
WHY MY NAME,
RICHARD?
BECAUSE YOU'RE
GETTING ON THAT PLANE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I'M STAYING HERE
WITH HIM
TILL THE PLANE
GETS SAFELY AWAY.
NO, RICHARD.
LAST NIGHT--
LAST NIGHT WE SAID
A GREAT MANY THINGS.
YOU SAID I SHOULD
THINK FOR BOTH OF US.
WELL, I HAVE.
IT ALL ADDS UP TO ONE THING.
YOU'RE GETTING
ON THAT PLANE.
RICHARD, NO. I--
YOU'VE GOT LISTEN TO ME.
9 CHANCES OUT OF 10,
IF YOU STAYED,
WE'D PROBABLY BOTH WIND UP
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP.
ISN'T THAT TRUE, LOUIS?
I'M AFRAID MAJOR STRASSER
WOULD INSIST.
YOU'RE SAYING THIS
ONLY TO MAKE ME GO.
I'M SAYING IT
BECAUSE IT'S TRUE.
INSIDE, WE BOTH KNOW
YOU BELONG WITH VICTOR.
YOU'RE PART OF HIS WORK,
THE THING THAT KEEPS HIM GOING.
IF THAT PLANE LEAVES THE GROUND
AND YOU'RE NOT WITH HIM,
YOU'LL REGRET IT.
MAYBE NOT TODAY,
MAYBE NOT TOMORROW,
BUT SOON, AND FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE.
BUT WHAT ABOUT US?
WE'LL ALWAYS HAVE PARIS.
WE DIDN'T HAVE IT.
WE'D LOST IT UNTIL YOU CAME
TO CASABLANCA.
WE GOT IT BACK
LAST NIGHT.
WHEN I SAID I
WOULD NEVER LEAVE YOU.
AND YOU NEVER WILL,
BUT I'VE GOT A JOB
TO DO, TOO.
WHERE I'M GOING,
YOU CAN'T FOLLOW.
WHAT I'VE GOT TO DO,
YOU CAN'T BE PART OF.
I'M NO GOOD
AT BEING NOBLE,
BUT IT DOESN'T
TAKE MUCH TO SEE
THAT THE PROBLEMS
OF THREE LITTLE PEOPLE
DON'T AMOUNT TO A HILL OF BEANS
IN THIS CRAZY WORLD.
SOMEDAY YOU'LL
UNDERSTAND THAT.
NOW, NOW.
HERE'S LOOKING AT YOU, KID.
[HONKS HORN]
EVERYTHING
IS IN ORDER.
ALL EXCEPT
ONE THING.
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD KNOW
BEFORE YOU LEAVE.
I DON'T ASK YOU
TO EXPLAIN ANYTHING.
I'M GOING TO ANYWAY.
BECAUSE IT MAY MAKE
A DIFFERENCE LATER ON.
YOU SAID YOU KNEW
YES. ABOUT ILSA AND ME.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS
AT MY PLACE LAST NIGHT.
SHE CAME THERE FOR
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
ISN'T THAT TRUE?
YES.
SHE TRIED EVERYTHING,
AND NOTHING WORKED.
SHE DID HER BEST
TO CONVINCE ME
THAT SHE WAS STILL
IN LOVE WITH ME.
THAT WAS OVER LONG AGO.
FOR YOUR SAKE,
SHE PRETENDED IT WASN'T,
AND I LET HER PRETEND.
I UNDERSTAND.
HERE IT IS.
THANKS.
I APPRECIATE IT.
WELCOME BACK TO THE FIGHT.
THIS TIME I KNOW
OUR SIDE WILL WIN.
ARE YOU READY, ILSA?
YES, I'M READY.
GOODBYE, RICK.
GOD BLESS YOU.
YOU'D BETTER HURRY
OR YOU'LL MISS THAT PLANE.
WELL, I WAS RIGHT.
YOU ARE A SENTIMENTALIST.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WHAT YOU JUST DID
FOR LASZLO.
THAT FAIRY TALE
YOU INVENTED.
I KNOW A LITTLE
ABOUT WOMEN.
SHE WENT, BUT SHE KNEW
YOU WERE LYING.
ANYWAY, THANKS
FOR HELPING ME OUT.
I SUPPOSE YOU KNOW
THIS WON'T BE PLEASANT
FOR EITHER OF US--
ESPECIALLY FOR YOU.
I'LL HAVE TO ARREST YOU.
AS SOON AS THE PLANE GOES.
WHAT WAS THE MEANING
OF THAT PHONE CALL?
VICTOR LASZLO
IS ON THAT PLANE.
WHY DO YOU STAND HERE?
WHY DON'T YOU STOP HIM?
ASK MONSIEUR RICK.
GET AWAY
FROM THAT PHONE.
I WOULD ADVISE YOU
NOT TO INTERFERE.
I WAS WILLING TO SHOOT
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
AND I'M WILLING
TO SHOOT YOU.
HELLO.
PUT THAT PHONE DOWN.
GET ME THE RADIO TOWER.
PUT IT DOWN.
MON CAPITAINE.
MAJOR STRASSER
HAS BEEN SHOT.
ROUND UP
THE USUAL SUSPECTS.
OUI,
MON CAPITAINE.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
WELL, RICK, YOU'RE
NOT ONLY A SENTIMENTALIST,
BUT YOU'VE
BECOME A PATRIOT.
IT SEEMED LIKE
A GOOD TIME TO START.
I THINK
PERHAPS YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT MIGHT
BE A GOOD IDEA
FOR YOU TO DISAPPEAR
FROM CASABLANCA
FOR A WHILE.
THERE'S A FREE
FRENCH GARRISON
OVER AT BRAZZAVILLE.
I COULD BE INDUCED TO
ARRANGE YOUR PASSAGE.
MY LETTER OF TRANSIT?
I COULD USE A TRIP,
BUT IT DOESN'T
AFFECT OUR BET.
YOU STILL
OWE ME 10,000 FRANCS.
AND THAT 10,000 FRANCS
SHOULD PAY OUR EXPENSES.
OUR EXPENSES?
MM-HMM.
LOUIS, I THINK
THIS IS THE BEGINNING
OF A BEAUTIFUL
FRIENDSHIP.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
[ Woman ]
DEAR MR. STEVENS,
YOU WILL BE SURPRISED...
TO HEAR FROM ME
AFTER ALL THIS TIME.
YOU HAVE BEEN IN MY THOUGHTS
EVER SINCE I HEARD THAT
LORD DARLINGTON HAD DIED.
WE READ IN THE MANCHESTER
GUARDIAN THAT HIS HEIRS PUT
DARLINGTON HALL UP FOR SALE...
BECAUSE THEY NO LONGER WISHED
TO MAINTAIN IT.
THE ARTICLE WENT ON TO SAY
THAT SINCE THERE WERE NO BUYERS
FOR SUCH A LARGE HOUSE,
THE NEW EARL HAD DECIDED
TO DEMOLISH IT...
AND SELL THE STONE
TO A LOCAL BUILDER FOR £5,000.
WE ALSO SAW
SOME RUBBISH IN THE
DAILY MAIL
WHICH MADE MY BLOOD BOIL:
"TRAITOR'S NEST
TO BE PULLED DOWN."
180 GUINEAS?
180?
ARE WE DONE?
[ Pounds Gavel ]
PERHAPS,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
ONE OF THE GREAT HIGHLIGHTS
OF THE SALE: LOT 414,
THE FINE
ELIZABETHAN PORTRAIT,
"A PORTLY GENTLEMAN."
I'LL START THE BIDDING
AT 2,000 GUINEAS.
TWO THOUSAND GUINEAS.
THANK YOU.
TWO-TWO.
TWO-FOUR.
TWO-SIX.
TWO-EIGHT.
THREE THOUSAND.
THREE-TWO.
THREE-FOUR.
THREE-SIX.
THREE-EIGHT.
FOUR THOUSAND GUINEAS.
FOUR AND A HALF THOUSAND.
THANK YOU.
FIVE THOUSAND.
AND A HALF.
SIX THOUSAND.
SEVEN THOUSAND.
AND A HALF.
EIGHT THOUSAND.
NINE THOUSAND.
AND A HALF.
TEN THOUSAND GUINEAS
IS BID.
AND A HALF.
ELEVEN THOUSAND.
AGAINST YOU, SIR,
AT 11,500 GUINEAS.
WE'RE ALL DONE
[ Woman ]
I WAS VERY RELIEVED
TO READ LATER ON...
HOW AN AMERICAN MILLIONAIRE
NAMED LEWIS HAD SAVED
DARLINGTON HALL,
AND THAT YOU WERE
NOT TO BE TURNED OUT
OF YOUR OLD HOME AFTER ALL.
COULD IT POSSIBLY BE
THE SAME CONGRESSMAN LEWIS...
WHO ATTENDED HIS LORDSHIP'S
CONFERENCE IN 1936?
OH, MR. STEVENS, I SO OFTEN
THINK OF THE GOOD OLD DAYS...
WHEN I WAS THE HOUSEKEEPER
AT DARLINGTON HALL.
IT WAS CERTAINLY HARD WORK,
AND I HAVE CERTAINLY KNOWN...
BUTLERS EASIER TO PLEASE
THAN OUR MR. STEVENS,
BUT I REMEMBER
THOSE YEARS WITH YOU AS AMONG
THE HAPPIEST OF MY LIFE.
YOU MUST HAVE A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT STAFF NOW.
NOT MANY OF THE OLD FACES
ARE LIKELY TO
BE AROUND ANYMORE.
I DON'T SUPPOSE THERE'S
MUCH NEED FOR THE SMALL ARMY...
OF FOOTMEN AND UNDERBUTLERS
THAT LORD DARLINGTON EMPLOYED.
MY OWN NEWS
IS NOT VERY CHEERFUL.
IN THE SEVEN YEARS
SINCE I LAST WROTE TO YOU,
I HAVE AGAIN LEFT MY HUSBAND,
AND, SAD TO SAY,
MY MARRIAGE SEEMS TO BE
FINALLY OVER.
I AM STAYING WITH A FRIEND
IN HER BOARDINGHOUSE
IN CLEVEDON.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT MY FUTURE IS.
EVER SINCE CATHERINE,
MY DAUGHTER, GOT MARRIED LAST
YEAR, MY LIFE HAS BEEN EMPTY.
THE YEARS STRETCH BEFORE ME,
AND IF ONLY I KNEW HOW
TO FILL THEM.
BUT I WOULD LIKE
TO BE USEFUL AGAIN.
BURNED AGAIN?
YES.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
THE RULE
IN THE KITCHEN HERE, SIR,
HAS ALWAYS BEEN THAT...
COOK COOKS
THE COOK BREAKFAST,
WHILE HER ASSISTANT
TOASTS THE TOAST.
WHY DON'T WE JUST GET HER
A POP-UP TOASTER?
WE NEED NOT A NEW GADGET,
BUT A REVISED STAFF PLAN.
A STAFF PLAN, HUH?
I DIDN'T KNOW WE HAD ONE.
YES, SIR.
A FAULTY ONE,
UNFORTUNATELY, SIR.
UH-HUH.
SIR, QUITE RECENTLY,
UM, YOU WERE KIND ENOUGH
TO SUGGEST...
THAT I GO ON A LITTLE HOLIDAY,
TAKE A TRIP AROUND THE COUNTRY.
MMM.
ABSOLUTELY.
CERTAINLY.
TAKE A BREAK.
SEE THE WORLD.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WHEN DID YOU LAST SEE
THE WORLD, STEVENS?
TELL ME.
AH, WELL, IN THE PAST,
THE WORLD ALWAYS
USED TO COME...
TO THIS HOUSE,
IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING,
IF I MAY SAY SO, SIR.
YOU MAY SAY SO.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU TAKE OFF
WHEN I'M IN LONDON NEXT WEEK?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU CAN TAKE THE CAR.
TAKE THE DAIMLER.
GOOD LORD, SIR.
I COULDN'T POSSIBLY.
YOU AND THAT DAIMLER
BELONG TOGETHER, STEVENS.
YOU WERE MADE
FOR EACH OTHER.
THAT'S MOST KIND OF YOU,
I MUST SAY, SIR. MOST KIND.
I HAD INTENDED TO TRAVEL
TO THE WEST COUNTRY...
WHERE, I UNDERSTAND,
WE HAVE SOME SPLENDID SCENERY.
AND I MIGHT, INCIDENTALLY,
BE ABLE TO SOLVE OUR
STAFF PROBLEMS...
WHILE I'M IN THAT PART
OF THE WORLD.
UM, A FORMER HOUSEKEEPER,
AT PRESENT LIVING IN CLEVEDON,
HAS INDICATED TO ME, SIR,
THAT SHE MIGHT BE PREPARED
TO RETURN TO SERVICE.
WHAT'S THIS, YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
OR A FORMER ATTACHMENT?
OH, NO, SIR.
NO, SIR.
NO, BUT... A VERY ABLE
HOUSEKEEPER, SIR.
A MOST ABLE
HOUSEKEEPER.
UM, I WAS JUST KIDDING,
STEVENS. SORRY.
YES, SIR.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE BEST
ABOUT YOUR PAPERS OVER HERE?
THESE OBITUARIES.
EVERY SON-OF-A-GUN GETS
THIS STATELY FUNERAL ORATION.
IT'S NOT AN ART WE HAVE
IN THE UNITED STATES.
INDEED, SIR.
- THANK YOU, STEVENS.
- MR. LEWIS.
[ Stevens ]
DEAR MRS. BENN,
I PROPOSE TO REACH CLEVEDON...
ON THURSDAY THE THIRD
OF OCTOBER AROUND 4:00 P.M.
I WOULD BE GRATEFUL FOR A LINE
FROM YOU TO REACH ME...
IN CARE OF THE POST OFFICE
AT COLLINGBOURNE,
NEAR HUNGERFORD,
WHERE I AM PLANNING TO STOP.
MRS. BENN, I ALWAYS SAID
YOU POSSESSED AN
AMAZING MEMORY.
MY NEW EMPLOYER IS,
INDEED, CONGRESSMAN LEWIS,
THOUGH HE IS NOW RETIRED
FROM POLITICAL LIFE
IN THE UNITED STATES.
[ Door Closing ]
HE'S ALREADY TAKEN UP RESIDENCE
AT DARLINGTON HALL...
AND WILL SOON BE JOINED
BY HIS FAMILY.
BUT, I REGRET TO SAY,
WE ARE WOEFULLY UNDERSTAFFED
FOR A HOUSE THIS SIZE.
MRS. BENN, WILL YOU
PERMIT ME ONCE AGAIN
TO SING YOUR PRAISES?
LET ME STATE THAT WHEN
YOU LEFT US TO GET MARRIED,
NO HOUSEKEEPER EVER MANAGED
TO REACH YOUR HIGH STANDARD
IN ANY DEPARTMENT.
[ Barking ]
[ Stevens ]
I WELL REMEMBER YOUR FIRST
ARRIVAL AT DARLINGTON HALL.
YOU CAME SOMEWHAT UNEXPECTEDLY,
ONE MIGHT EVEN SAY IMPULSIVELY,
WHILE WE WERE DEAD
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE CHILDGROVE MEET.
THAT DAY IS MARKED IN MY MEMORY
IN ANOTHER WAY AS WELL.
IT WAS THE LAST TIME
HIS LORDSHIP SEEMED HAPPY...
TO WELCOME HIS NEIGHBORS,
AS IN THE OLD DAYS.
OF COURSE, IT HAD BEEN YEARS
SINCE ANY OF THEM HAD
COAXED HIM TO HUNT.
IT WAS NEVER A SPORT
HIS LORDSHIP ENJOYED
OR APPROVED OF.
[ Dogs Yelping ]
AH, GOOD MORNING, AYRES.
MY LORD,
NICE TO SEE YOU.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Indistinct,
Both Laughing ]
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
[ Darlington ] ENJOYING
THEMSELVES IN AMERICA?
MARVELOUSLY.
WHERE ARE THEY?
CENTRAL PARK
WEST.
[ Horn Trumpeting ]
COME ON!
GO ON!
[ Stevens ]
I FEAR I MAY HAVE BEEN
A LITTLE UNWELCOMING AT FIRST,
EVEN A LITTLE SHORT.
YOU PRESENTED
THE MOST EXCELLENT REFERENCES
THAT I'VE EVER SEEN,
WHICH PROVED TO BE
WELL DESERVED, INDEED.
ALTHOUGH, I CONFESS,
I DID HAVE MY DOUBTS
ON ACCOUNT OF YOUR YOUTH.
WELL, NO GENTLEMAN CALLERS
ALLOWED, OF COURSE.
YOU WILL FORGIVE
MY MENTIONING IT,
BUT WE HAVE HAD PROBLEMS...
OF THAT SORT BEFORE,
FROM INSIDE THE HOUSE TOO.
THE PREVIOUS HOUSEKEEPER
TOOK IT INTO HER HEAD
TO RUN OFF WITH THE UNDERBUTLER.
IF TWO MEMBERS OF STAFF
HAPPEN TO FALL IN LOVE...
AND DECIDE TO GET MARRIED,
THERE IS NOTHING ONE CAN SAY.
BUT WHAT I DO FIND
A MAJOR IRRITATION...
ARE THOSE PERSONS WHO ARE
SIMPLY GOING FROM POST TO POST
LOOKING FOR ROMANCE.
HOUSEKEEPERS ARE
PARTICULARLY GUILTY HERE.
NO OFFENSE INTENDED,
OF COURSE.
NONE TAKEN.
I KNOW FROM MY OWN
EXPERIENCE HOW A HOUSE
IS AT SIXES AND SEVENS...
ONCE THE STAFF START
MARRYING EACH OTHER.
YES, INDEED.
MIGHT I HAVE A WORD
WITH YOU, SIR?
OF COURSE.
MY LORD, IT'S REGARDING
THE UNDERBUTLER...
AND THE HOUSEKEEPER
WHO RAN OFF TOGETHER
LAST MONTH.
AH. BAD BUSINESS.
HOW ARE YOU MANAGING?
I BELIEVE I'VE FOUND TWO
FIRST-RATE REPLACEMENTS, SIR.
MISS KENTON, A YOUNG WOMAN
WITH EXCELLENT REFERENCES,
VERY PLEASING DEMEANOR,
APPEARS TO BE VERY ABLE.
AND A MAN WITH CONSIDERABLE
EXPERIENCE OF BUTLERING, SIR,
NOW OF A CERTAIN AGE
AND HAPPY TO TAKE ON
THE POST OF UNDERBUTLER.
- NAME?
- STEVENS, SIR.
STEVENS?
YES, SIR.
THAT'S YOUR NAME.
YES,
HE'S MY FATHER, SIR.
REALLY? WELL,
COULDN'T DO BETTER, I'M SURE.
I'D LIKE TO SEE HIM SOMETIME.
- HE'S OUTSIDE THE DOOR, SIR.
- GOOD. WELL, BRING HIM IN.
THANK YOU, MY LORD.
FATHER?
MR. STEVENS,
HOW DO YOU DO?
MY LORD.
VERY GOOD MAN HERE,
YOUR SON.
HE DOES THE HOUSE
GREAT SERVICE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WE'D DO WITHOUT HIM.
PROUD OF HIM, ARE YOU?
VERY PROUD, MY LORD.
QUITE RIGHT TOO.
YES. WELL, VERY GLAD
TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
THANK YOU, MY LORD.
OH, STEVENS.
WHAT ARE WE AT DINNER TONIGHT?
FOURTEEN?
SIXTEEN?
TWELVE, SIR.
RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, MY LORD.
[ Panting ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Gasps ]
OH, MR. STEVENS.
YES?
THIS SILVER PITCHER SEEMS
QUITE OUT OF PLACE HERE.
DINING ROOM.
OH, THANK YOU.
THANKS.
WELL SPOTTED, MISS KENTON.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Kenton ]
HELLO, JOHN.
HELLO, WILLIAM.
[ Knocking ]
HELLO.
MR. STEVENS, I THOUGHT
THESE MIGHT BRIGHTEN
YOUR PARLOR A LITTLE.
BEG YOUR PARDON?
[ Chuckles ]
I THOUGHT THEY MIGHT
CHEER THINGS UP FOR YOU.
OH, THAT'S VERY KIND
OF YOU. UM--
IF YOU LIKE, MR. STEVENS,
I COULD BRING IN SOME MORE
CUTTINGS FOR YOU.
THANK YOU, MISS KENTON,
BUT I REGARD THIS ROOM
AS MY PRIVATE PLACE OF WORK...
AND I-- I PREFER TO KEEP
DISTRACTIONS TO A MINIMUM.
WOULD YOU CALL FLOWERS
A DISTRACTION THEN,
MR. STEVENS?
I APPRECIATE YOUR KINDNESS,
MISS KENTON, BUT, UH, I PREFER
TO KEEP THINGS AS THEY ARE.
AND SINCE YOU ARE HERE, THERE
IS A MATTER I WANTED TO MENTION
TO YOU. JUST A SMALL MATTER.
I HAPPENED TO BE WALKING PAST
THE KITCHEN YESTERDAY MORNING...
AND I HEARD YOU CALLING
TO SOMEONE NAME WILLIAM.
MAY I ASK WHO IT WAS YOU WERE
ADDRESSING BY THAT NAME?
WHY, MR. STEVENS,
I SHOULD THINK I WAS
ADDRESSING YOUR FATHER.
OH.
THERE ARE NO OTHER WILLIAMS
IN THIS HOUSE, I TAKE IT.
TRUE.
MAY I ASK YOU IN FUTURE,
MISS KENTON, TO ADDRESS
MY FATHER AS "MR. STEVENS"?
IF YOU ARE SPEAKING OF HIM
TO A THIRD PARTY
YOU MAY WISH...
TO CALL HIM "MR. STEVENS, SR.,"
TO DISTINGUISH HIM FROM MYSELF.
SO I WOULD BE MOST GRATEFUL
TO YOU, MISS KENTON.
I DON'T QUITE...
HMM?
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE
GETTING AT, MR. STEVENS.
I AM THE HOUSEKEEPER
IN THIS HOUSE,
AND YOUR FATHER
IS THE UNDERBUTLER.
IN OTHER HOUSES I WAS ACCUSTOMED
TO ADDRESS THE UNDERSERVANTS
BY THEIR CHRISTIAN NAMES.
HMM. MISS KENTON, IF YOU WOULD
STOP TO THINK FOR A MOMENT,
YOU WOULD REALIZE
HOW INAPPROPRIATE IT IS...
FOR ONE, SUCH AS YOURSELF,
TO ADDRESS AS "WILLIAM"
SOMEONE SUCH AS MY FATHER.
WELL, I'M SURE, MR. STEVENS,
IT MUST HAVE BEEN VERY GALLING
FOR YOUR FATHER...
TO BE CALLED "WILLIAM"
BY ONE SUCH AS MYSELF.
MISS KENTON, ALL I AM SAYING
IS THAT MY FATHER IS A PERSON
FROM WHOM,
IF YOU WISH
TO BE MORE OBSERVANT,
YOU MAY LEARN MANY THINGS.
I'M MOST GRATEFUL FOR
YOUR ADVICE, MR. STEVENS,
BUT DO PLEASE TELL ME
WHAT MARVELOUS THINGS MIGHT
I LEARN FROM YOUR FATHER?
I MIGHT POINT OUT
THAT YOU ARE STILL...
OFTEN UNSURE OF WHAT GOES WHERE
AND WHICH ITEM IS WHICH.
I'M SURE MR. STEVENS, SR.,
IS VERY GOOD AT HIS JOB,
BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU,
MR. STEVENS, THAT I AM
VERY GOOD AT MINE.
- OH, OF COURSE.
- THANK YOU. AND NOW, IF YOU
WILL PLEASE EXCUSE ME.
MISS KENTON--
[ Door Closes ]
[ Retreating Footsteps ]
OH, WELL.
[ Chuckles ]
SHALL I PUT IT
ON THERE?
MAYBE JUST
ON THE PANTRY.
MY COMPLIMENTS
TO THE COOK, BETTY,
PLEASE.
WHAT A LOVELY PIECE
OF CRACKLING.
[ Girls Giggling ]
I'M SURE YOU SAID SOMETHING
WONDERFULLY WITTY, CHARLES,
WHICH YOU MIGHT LIKE TO
SHARE WITH THE REST OF US,
WHO WERE NOT SO FORTUNATE
AS ENOUGH TO HEAR YOU.
I SAID HOW THE SPROUTS
IS DONE JUST THE WAY
I LIKE THEM, MR. STEVENS.
- CRISP-LIKE, NOT MUSHY.
- "SPROUTS ARE DONE," CHARLES,
NOT "SPROUTS IS DONE."
- ISN'T THAT RIGHT, GEORGE?
- YES, MR. STEVENS.
FORGIVE THE CORRECTION,
I'M SURE, CHARLES,
AS I WOULD HAVE DONE
AT YOUR AGE, FOR THE SAKE
OF MY EDUCATION.
I'M SURE EVEN YOU,
CHARLES,
HAVE AMBITIONS TO RISE
IN YOUR PROFESSION.
OH, YES, MR. STEVENS.
I'D LIKE TO BE A BUTLER,
TO BE CALLED MISTER
AND NOT CHARLIE,
AND SIT IN MY OWN PANTRY
BY MY OWN FIRE,
SMOKING MY CIGAR.
I WONDER IF YOU REALIZE
WHAT IT REALLY TAKES
TO BE A GREAT BUTLER?
TAKES DIGNITY,
THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES.
THANK YOU, MR. STEVENS.
DIGNITY, THAT'S RIGHT.
DIGNITY.
THIS IS THE OFFICIAL
DEFINITION...
AS GIVEN IN OUR QUARTERLY,
THE GENTLEMEN'S GENTLEMAN.
"A GREAT BUTLER MUST BE
POSSESSED OF DIGNITY--"
"...IN KEEPING
WITH HIS POSITION."
THERE WAS THIS
ENGLISH BUTLER IN INDIA.
ONE DAY HE GOES
IN THE DINING ROOM,
AND WHAT'S HE SEE
UNDER THE TABLE?
- A TIGER.
- [ Woman Gasps ]
NOT TURNING A HAIR, HE GOES
STRAIGHT TO THE DRAWING ROOM.
[ Coughs ]
"EXCUSE ME, MY LORD."
AND WHISPERING, SO AS NOT
TO UPSET THE LADIES,
"I'M VERY SORRY, MY LORD.
THERE APPEARS TO BE A TIGER
IN THE DINING ROOM.
PERHAPS HIS LORDSHIP WILL
PERMIT USE OF THE 12-BORES?"
WELL, THEY GO ON
DRINKING THEIR TEA.
AND THEN THERE'S
THREE GUNSHOTS.
WHY, THEY DON'T
THINK NOTHING OF IT,
THIS BEING OUT IN INDIA
WHERE THEY'RE USED TO ANYTHING.
WHEN THE BUTLER IS BACK
TO REFRESH THE TEAPOTS,
HE'S AS COOL
AS A CUCUMBER.
"DINNER WILL BE SERVED
AT THE USUAL TIME, MY LORD,
"AND I AM PLEASED
TO SAY THERE WILL BE NO
DISCERNIBLE TRACES LEFT...
"OF THE RECENT OCCURRENCE
BY THAT TIME.
[ Laughing ]
"I REPEAT, SIR, THERE WILL BE
NO DISCERNIBLE TRACES LEFT...
OF THE RECENT OCCURRENCE
BY THAT TIME."
[ Laughing ]
WONDERFUL STORY, MR. STEVENS.
WONDERFUL STORY.
THANK YOU, MR. STEVENS.
THAT'S THE IDEAL, CHARLES,
THAT WE SHOULD ALL AIM FOR.
DIGNITY.
[ Bell Ringing ]
IT'S FOR YOU,
MR. STEVENS.
- THANK YOU.
- IT'S FOR MR. STEVENS, SR.,
MR. STEVENS.
THANK YOU, MISS KENTON.
MARY,
WOULD YOU PUT
MR. STEVENS, SR.'S PLATE
WITH COOK TO KEEP IT WARM.
THANK YOU.
[ Mary ]
YES, MISS KENTON.
- THANK YOU, MISS KENTON.
- NOT AT ALL, MR. STEVENS.
[ Sighing ]
[ Groans ]
MR. STEVENS, IF YOU ARE
SEARCHING FOR YOUR DUSTPAN,
YES?
IT IS OUTSIDE
ON THE LANDING.
MY DUSTPAN?
YOUR DUSTPAN.
YOU'VE LEFT IT ON THE LANDING.
I HAVEN'T BEEN USING
A DUSTPAN, MISS.
OH, REALLY?
THEN IT MUST HAVE BEEN
SOMEBODY ELSE.
I DON'T FOLLOW YOU.
MY MISTAKE, NO DOUBT.
ONE OF MANY.
[ Footsteps ]
MR. STEVENS.
MORNING, SIR.
I'VE INVITED
GISCARD DUPONT D'IVRY...
TO JOIN US
AS THE FRENCH DELEGATE.
HE'LL NEVER COME!
I'M GLAD TO SAY
THAT I JUST HAD WORD
OF HIS ACCEPTANCE.
I SAY!
BUT DUPONT IS FANATICALLY
ANTI-GERMAN.
I REMEMBER A SPEECH
HE GAVE IN GENEVA IN '33...
THAT MADE ME ASHAMED TO BE SEEN
AS AN ALLY OF THE FRENCH.
I MEAN TO SAY, IT'S NOT
THE ENGLISH WAY OF CARRYING ON.
NO, IT IS NOT.
AND IT IS PRECISELY
THE PURPOSE...
OF OUR CONFERENCE
TO DISCUSS THESE MATTERS
INFORMALLY,
FAR AWAY
FROM THE TO-DO OF A LARGE,
INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE.
HERE IN THE FRIENDLY
AND RELAXED...
ATMOSPHERE
OF ONE'S HOME,
WE MAY HAVE A CHANCE TO BRING
AROUND OTHERS, LIKE THE FRENCH,
TO OUR POINT OF VIEW.
- AND THAT OF THE GERMANS.
- [ Darlington ] AND THAT
OF THE GERMANS.
[ Man ] I'M SORRY, SIR.
I'M SO SORRY TO INTERRUPT,
BUT I DON'T SEE HOW...
WE CAN ASSOCIATE OURSELVES NOW
WITH THE GERMANS, YOU KNOW,
WITH THE NAZI PARTY.
THEY HAVE ACTUALLY
TORN UP AND TRAMPLED ON
EVERY SINGLE TREATY...
AND SEEM TO BE
A WORSE THREAT THAN EVER
TO THE WHOLE OF EUROPE,
NOT TO MENTION THEIR BRUTAL
DICTATORSHIP AT HOME.
[ Darlington ]
MY DEAR BOY,
WHEN I WAS IN BERLIN,
I SAW, AT LAST,
A HAPPY GERMAN PEOPLE,
WITH JOBS AND BREAD
AND PRIDE IN THEIR COUNTRY
AND LOVE OF THEIR LEADER.
AND WHAT ABOUT THE JEWS?
MR. STEVENS,
WAS IT HIS LORDSHIP'S WISH...
THAT THE CHINAMAN FROM THE
CABINET ROOM SHOULD BE EXCHANGED
WITH THE ONE OUTSIDE THE DOOR?
CHINAMAN?
YES.
THE CHINAMAN
FROM THE CABINET ROOM
IS NOW OUTSIDE THIS DOOR.
- COME AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
- I'M BUSY AT THE MOMENT.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS POP
YOUR HEAD OUTSIDE THIS DOOR
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
- IT WON'T TAKE A MOMENT.
- I WILL LOOK INTO THE MATTER
IN DUE COURSE, MISS KENTON.
YOU THINK
IT MIGHT BE A FANTASY?
A FANTASY ON MY PART,
DUE TO MY INEXPERIENCE?
I'M BUSY IN THIS ROOM,
MISS KENTON.
I SHALL WAIT.
OUTSIDE.
LOOK AT IT!
IS THAT OR IS IT NOT
THE WRONG CHINAMAN?
MISS KENTON, I'M VERY BUSY,
AND I'M SURPRISED THAT YOU
HAVE NOTHING BETTER TO DO...
THAN STAND AROUND ALL DAY.
MR. STEVENS, LOOK AT THAT
CHINAMAN AND TELL ME THE TRUTH!
MISS KENTON, I WOULD ASK YOU
TO KEEP YOUR VOICE DOWN.
WHAT WOULD THE OTHER
SERVANTS THINK TO HEAR US
SHOUTING ABOUT CHINAMEN?
I WOULD ASK YOU,
MR. STEVENS,
TO TURN AROUND AND LOOK
AT THE CHINAMAN.
IT IS A SMALL MISTAKE,
A TRIVIAL MISTAKE.
YOUR FATHER IS ENTRUSTED
WITH MORE THAN A MAN
OF HIS AGE CAN COPE WITH.
I'M CONCERNED FOR HIM.
MR. STEVENS.
PLEASE LET ME PASS.
MR. STEVENS, IT WAS YOUR
FATHER WHO LEFT THE DUSTPAN
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE FLOOR.
IT IS HE WHO IS LEAVING POLISH
ON THE CUTLERY. IT IS HE WHO
HAS CONFUSED THE CHINAMEN.
YOU MUST RECOGNIZE THIS
BEFORE HE COMMITS A MAJOR ERROR.
I'M AFRAID YOU CAN'T TALK TO ME
LIKE THIS, MISS KENTON.
I'M AFRAID I MUST, MR. STEVENS.
I'M GIVING YOU SERIOUS ADVICE.
YOUR FATHER SHOULD BE RELIEVED
OF A NUMBER OF HIS DUTIES
FOR HIS OWN GOOD.
WHATEVER YOUR FATHER ONCE WAS,
HE NO LONGER HAS THE SAME
ABILITY OR STRENGTHS.
I THANK YOU FOR YOUR ADVICE,
MISS KENTON.
NOW PERHAPS YOU WILL ALLOW ME
TO GO ABOUT MY BUSINESS.
OH, I NEVER MEANT TO KEEP YOU
FROM YOUR BUSINESS, MR. STEVENS.
THANK YOU.
IT'S VITAL THAT WE'VE
AGREED TO COMMON POLICY
BEFORE THE ARRIVAL OF, UH--
YOUR FRENCHMAN,
WHAT'S HIS NAME AGAIN?
GISCARD DUPONT D'IVRY.
WE ARE ALSO EXPECTING
THE AMERICAN DELEGATE,
CONGRESSMAN LEWIS,
TO ARRIVE ON THE SAME DAY.
WHO IS HE,
THIS AMERICAN?
WELL, HE'S RATHER
AN UNKNOWN QUANTITY.
HE'S A YOUNG CONGRESSMAN
FROM PENNSYLVANIA.
SITS ON SOME SORT OF POWERFUL
FOREIGN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE.
YES, I BELIEVE, HEIR TO ONE
OF THOSE AMERICAN FORTUNES.
MEAT PACKING?
TROLLEY CARS?
OR DRY GOODS? [ Laughs ]
WHAT ARE DRY GOODS?
EVIDENTLY,
SOMETHING THAT AMERICANS
MAKE A LOT OF MONEY IN.
[ Darlington ]
NO, I THINK MR. LEWIS'S FORTUNE
COMES FROM COSMETICS, ACTUALLY.
IT'S OLD
MR. STEVENS.
GET A CUSHION, QUICKLY!
A BLANKET!
[ Groaning ]
HERE YOU ARE.
HERE.
[ Muttering ]
THE SILVER--
THERE, THERE.
AH, MY LORD. SORRY.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE TRIPPED OVER
WITH THE TRAY.
YES, I SAW IT, SIR,
FROM THE WINDOW.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
THIS HAS NEVER
HAPPENED BEFORE, SIR.
MAY I TELEPHONE THE DOCTOR?
YES, DO. YES.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M SORRY.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M SORRY, MY LORD.
[ Darlington ]
OH, STEVENS.
AH, YES, MY LORD.
YOUR FATHER
FEELING BETTER?
YES, HE'S MADE A FULL RECOVERY,
I'M HAPPY TO SAY, SIR.
GOOD.
BUT NONE OF US WISH
TO SEE ANYTHING OF THAT SORT
EVER HAPPEN AGAIN, DO WE?
I MEAN, YOUR FATHER
COLLAPSING AND ALL THAT.
INDEED NOT, MY LORD.
AND IT COULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE,
AT ANY TIME.
LOOK HERE, STEVENS. THE FIRST
OF THE FOREIGN DELEGATES...
WILL BE ARRIVING HERE
IN LESS THAN A FORTNIGHT.
YES, WE ARE
WELL PREPARED, MY LORD.
WELL, I'M SURE YOU ARE.
AND WHAT HAPPENS
WITHIN THIS HOUSE
DURING THE CONFERENCE...
COULD HAVE, UH, CONSIDERABLE
REPERCUSSIONS ON THE WHOLE
COURSE THAT EUROPE IS TAKING.
YES, MY LORD.
YES, IT MEANS
A GREAT DEAL.
AND I MAY AS WELL TELL YOU,
STEVENS, IT MEANS A GREAT
DEAL TO ME, PERSONALLY.
I HAD A GERMAN FRIEND,
KARL-HEINZ BREMANN.
WE FOUGHT ON OPPOSITE SIDES
IN THE WAR.
WE ALWAYS SAID WHEN THIS
WRETCHED BUSINESS IS OVER,
WE'LL SIT DOWN AND HAVE
A DRINK TOGETHER,
LIKE GENTLEMEN.
THE VERSAILLES TREATY
MADE A LIAR OF ME.
YES, A LIAR, STEVENS.
BECAUSE THE TERMS THAT WE,
THE VICTOR, IMPOSED...
WERE SO HARSH, THAT GERMANY
WAS SIMPLY FINISHED.
WELL, ONE DOESN'T DO THAT
TO A DEFEATED FOE.
NO, ONCE YOU'VE GOT YOUR
MAN ON THE CANVAS, THAT
OUGHT TO BE THE END OF IT.
MY FRIEND BREMANN WAS, UH,
RUINED BY INFLATION.
COULDN'T GET A JOB
IN POSTWAR GERMANY.
KILLED HIMSELF.
SHOT HIMSELF...
IN A RAILWAY CARRIAGE
BETWEEN HAMBURG AND BERLIN.
WELL, EVER SINCE THAT TIME,
I FELT IT MY DUTY, MY JOB,
STEVENS,
TO HOLD OUT
A HELPING HAND TO GERMANY,
GIVE HER A FAIR CHANCE.
SO, YOU SEE, STEVENS,
THIS CONFERENCE IS CRUCIAL,
AND WE REALLY CAN'T RUN
THE RISK OF ANY ACCIDENTS.
LOOK HERE.
IT ISN'T A QUESTION
OF YOUR FATHER LEAVING US.
YOU'RE SIMPLY BEING ASKED
TO RECONSIDER HIS DUTIES.
OF COURSE, MY LORD.
I UNDERSTAND FULLY.
GOOD.
WELL, I'LL LEAVE YOU
TO THINK ABOUT IT THEN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Rooster Crowing ]
HUGH?
SIR?
LOOK, I'M SHORTHANDED
IN THE DINING ROOM TONIGHT.
I CAN USE YOU
IN THE SERVERY, ALL RIGHT?
THANK YOU,
MR. STEVENS, SIR.
SMARTEN UP. LOOK SHARP.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Knocking ]
GOOD MORNING.
I MIGHT HAVE KNOWN
YOU'D BE UP AND READY
FOR THE DAY.
I'VE BEEN UP
FOR TWO HOURS.
THAT'S NOT MUCH SLEEP.
IT'S ALL THE SLEEP I NEED.
YES.
I'VE COME TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING.
WELL, TALK THEN.
I HAVEN'T GOT ALL MORNING.
I'LL COME STRAIGHT
TO THE POINT.
DO, AND BE DONE WITH IT.
SOME OF US HAVE GOT WORK
TO BE GETTING ON WITH.
YES.
THERE'S TO BE A VERY IMPORTANT
INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE
IN THIS HOUSE NEXT WEEK.
PEOPLE OF GREAT STATURE
WILL BE HIS LORDSHIP'S GUESTS.
WE MUST ALL PUT
OUR BEST FOOT FORWARD.
BECAUSE OF FATHER'S
RECENT ACCIDENT,
IT HAS BEEN SUGGESTED
THAT YOU NO LONGER
WAIT AT TABLE.
I'VE--
I'VE WAITED AT TABLE
EVERY DAY...
FOR THE LAST 54 YEARS.
IT HAS ALSO BEEN DECIDED
THAT YOU SHOULD NO LONGER
CARRY HEAVY TRAYS.
NOW HERE'S A REVISED LIST
OF YOUR DUTIES.
BUT I FELL... BECAUSE
OF THOSE PAVING STONES!
THEY'RE CROOKED.
WHY DON'T YOU GET THEM
PUT RIGHT BEFORE SOMEONE
ELSE DOES THE SAME THING.
YOU WILL READ THE REVISED LIST
OF YOUR DUTIES, FATHER.
GET THOSE STONES PUT RIGHT.
YOU DON'T WANT ALL THOSE
GENTLEMEN OF STATURE...
TRIPPING UP AND BREAKING
THEIR NECKS, DO YOU?
NO, INDEED, I DON'T.
- MR. STEVENS.
- WHAT IS IT?
NOW, YOU HAVE
WHAT WE CAN CALL
A ROVING COMMISSION.
IN OTHER WORDS,
YOU MAY EXERCISE
YOUR OWN JUDGMENT,
BUT WITHIN CERTAIN
LIMITS, OF COURSE.
NOW, HERE ARE THE MOPS,
AND, UM, HERE.
ARE THESE ME MOPS?
RIGHT.
YOUR BRUSHES.
ME BRUSHES...
YES.
AND ME MOPS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT, UH--
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME
TO DO WITH THEM?
WELL, I THINK YOU KNOW
WELL ENOUGH WHAT TO DO
WITH THEM, FATHER.
LOOK FOR DUST
AND DIRT.
AND IF I FIND ANY
DUST OR DIRT,
I'LL GIVE THEM
A GOOD GOING-OVER
WITH THIS MOP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YES.
NOW, WHAT I SUGGEST
YOU START OFF WITH, UM,
ARE THE BRASSES
ON THE DOORS.
ALL RIGHT.
UH, THERE'S THAT DOOR THERE,
THEN THE DOOR THAT'S OPEN,
AND THEN THERE'S
THIS DOOR HERE...
AND THIS ONE HERE.
LISTEN.
HERE YOU ARE.
HERE'S YOUR POLISH
AND YOUR DUSTER.
HISTORY
COULD WELL BE MADE...
UNDER THIS ROOF
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
YOU CAN,
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU,
TAKE GREAT PRIDE IN THE ROLE
YOU WILL PLAY ON THIS
MOMENTOUS OCCASION.
IMAGINE YOURSELF
THE HEAD OF A BATTALION,
EVEN IF IT IS ONLY FILLING
THE HOT WATER BOTTLES.
EACH ONE OF YOU HAS
HIS OWN PARTICULAR DUTY...
OR HER PARTICULAR DUTY,
IF THE CAP FITS.
POLISHED BRASS,
BRILLIANT SILVER, MAHOGANY
SHINING LIKE A MIRROR.
THAT IS THE WELCOME
WE WILL SHOW
THESE FOREIGN VISITORS...
TO LET THEM KNOW THEY ARE
IN ENGLAND,
PILLOWS NICE AND STRAIGHT.
WHERE ORDER
AND TRADITION...
STILL PREVAIL.
[ Car Approaching ]
THANK YOU, BARNDT.
MY LORD, MR. LEWIS,
THE AMERICAN GENTLEMAN,
HAS ARRIVED, SIR.
HE WASN'T EXPECTED
TILL TOMORROW. WHAT
HAVE YOU DONE WITH HIM?
MR. LEWIS HAS BEEN
SHOWN UPSTAIRS, MY LORD.
THANK YOU.
OH, STEVENS.
MY GODSON, CARDINAL, TELLS ME
HE'S SHORTLY TO BECOME ENGAGED
TO BE MARRIED.
OH, INDEED, SIR.
I OFFER MY CONGRATULATIONS.
OH, THANK YOU, STEVENS.
[ Laughs ]
I FEEL VERY RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE BOY.
NOT ONLY IS HE MY GODSON,
BUT HIS FATHER, SIR DAVID,
WAS MY CLOSEST FRIEND,
AS YOU KNOW.
AND NOW THAT HE'S GONE,
WELL, I, UH,
FEEL IN PLACE OF A FATHER
TO THE BOY.
I'VE APPOINTED HIM AS MY
SECRETARY AT THE CONFERENCE,
AS I'VE SAID.
AND SO FAR
HE'S BEEN JOLLY THOROUGH
IN HELPING ME TO PREPARE.
STEVENS, I REALIZE THIS IS
A SOMEWHAT IRREGULAR THING
TO ASK YOU TO DO.
I SHOULD BE VERY GLAD TO BE
OF ANY ASSISTANCE, MY LORD.
SORRY TO BRING UP
A THING LIKE THIS,
BUT I JUST CAN'T SEE HOW
ON EARTH TO MAKE IT GO AWAY.
YOU ARE FAMILIAR, I TAKE IT,
WITH THE FACTS OF LIFE?
MY LORD?
THE FACTS OF LIFE,
STEVENS.
BIRDS, BEES.
I MEAN, YOU ARE FAMILIAR,
AREN'T YOU?
I'M AFRAID I DON'T
QUITE FOLLOW YOU, SIR.
WELL, LET ME PUT MY CARDS
ON THE TABLE, STEVENS.
I'M SO FRIGHTFULLY BUSY
WITH THIS CONFERENCE.
OF COURSE,
YOU'RE VERY BUSY TOO, BUT...
SOMEONE HAS TO TELL HIM.
IN A WAY, IT WOULD BE
EASIER FOR YOU.
LESS AWKWARD.
I FIND THE TASK RATHER
DAUNTING, I'M AFRAID.
I MIGHT NOT GET AROUND TO IT
BEFORE REGINALD'S WEDDING DAY.
OF COURSE, THIS GOES FAR BEYOND
THE CALL OF DUTY, STEVENS.
[ Laughs ]
WHY, I SHALL
DO MY BEST, MY LORD.
I'D BE GRATEFUL
IF YOU'D EVEN TRY, STEVENS.
IT'D BE A LOT OFF MY MIND.
LOOK HERE. THERE'S NO NEED
TO MAKE A SONG AND DANCE OF IT.
JUST CONVEY THE BASIC FACTS
AND BE DONE WITH IT.
[ Airplane Droning Overhead ]
OOH!
GOD, STEVENS!
[ Sighs ]
SORRY.
MOST SORRY, SIR.
BUT I DO HAVE SOMETHING
TO CONVEY TO YOU
RATHER URGENTLY, SIR.
IF I MAY BE PERMITTED,
I'LL COME STRAIGHT
TO THE POINT.
UM, PERHAPS YOU WILL HAVE
NOTICED THIS MORNING, SIR,
THE DUCKS AND THE GEESE...
BY THE POND?
DUCKS AND GEESE.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO, STEVENS.
WELL, PERHAPS THE BIRDS
AND THE FLOWERS THEN?
OR THE SHRUBS
AND THE BEES?
NO, I'VE NOT SEEN ANY BEES.
YES, WELL, THIS IS, IN FACT,
NOT THE BEST TIME
OF THE YEAR...
TO SEE THEM IN THEIR
FULL GLORY, SIR.
WHAT, THE BEES?
UH, NO, SIR. WHAT I'M
TRYING TO SAY, SIR, IS THAT
WITH THE ARRIVAL OF SPRING...
WE SHALL SEE A MOST REMARKABLE
AND PROFOUND CHANGE IN ALL
THESE SURROUNDINGS, SIR.
YEAH. YEAH,
I'M SURE THAT'S RIGHT.
THE GROUNDS ARE NOT
AT THEIR BEST JUST NOW.
NO, SIR.
BUT I WASN'T PAYING
MUCH ATTENTION...
TO THE OLD GLORIES OF NATURE
BECAUSE IT'S RATHER WORRYING--
DUPONT D'IVRY HAS JUST ARRIVED
IN THE FOULEST MOOD IMAGINABLE,
WHICH IS THE LAST THING
THAT ANYONE WANTS.
OH, MONSIEUR DUPONT D'IVRY
HAS ARRIVED, SIR?
YEAH. HALF AN HOUR AGO,
IN A REALLY FOUL MOOD.
AH, WELL, IN THAT CASE,
UM, PLEASE EXCUSE ME.
I'D BETTER GO
AND ATTEND TO HIM, SIR.
RIGHT, STEVENS.
IT WAS KIND OF YOU
TO TALK TO ME.
NOT AT ALL, SIR.
UM, IN FACT, I DO HAVE
ONE OR TWO WORDS MORE...
TO CONVEY TO YOU
ON THE TOPIC OF, UM--
WELL, AS YOU PUT IT
MOST ADMIRABLY, SIR,
"THE GLORIES OF NATURE."
BUT IT WILL HAVE TO WAIT
FOR ANOTHER OCCASION, SIR.
THANK YOU.
WELL, I'LL LOOK FORWARD
TO THAT THEN, STEVENS.
- I'M MORE OF A FISH MAN MYSELF.
- FISH, SIR?
YES, I KNOW ALL ABOUT FISH,
FRESHWATER AND SALT.
AH. WELL, ALL LIVING
CREATURES WOULD BE RELEVANT
TO OUR DISCUSSION, SIR.
IF YOU WILL EXCUSE ME.
I HAD NO IDEA THAT
MONSIEUR DUPONT D'IVRY
HAD ARRIVED, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[ Groaning,
Speaking French ]
[ Speaking French,
Sighs ]
MAY I BE OF
ASSISTANCE, SIR?
OH, THE BUTLER.
UM, I HAVE SORE FEET,
SO I NEED A BASIN WITH
WARM WATER AND SALTS,
PLEASE.
YES, MONSIEUR. I'LL ARRANGE
THAT WITH THE HOUSEKEEPER
STRAIGHT AWAY, SIR.
[ Speaking French ]
WARM WATER AND SALTS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
MONSIEUR DUPONT.
[ Speaking French ]
OUI.
AH, HOW DO YOU DO.
BUT I SPEAK ENGLISH.
OH, GOOD.
THAT'S LUCKY FOR ME.
I'M JACK LEWIS,
THE U.S. DELEGATE,
AND I WONDER IF
WE COULD SPEAK PRIVATELY
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
YES, OF COURSE.
BUT FOR THE MOMENT
I HAVE BLISTERS...
DUE TO SOME
INFERNAL SIGHTSEEING
THEY MADE ME DO IN LONDON.
YOU KNOW, I HAD ALREADY
SEEN THE TOWER OF LONDON.
UH-HUH.
SIR, I ARRIVED HERE
A DAY EARLY...
AND I'VE DISCOVERED THAT
THINGS ARE NOT MOVING...
IN A DIRECTION
THAT I THINK YOU WOULD
ENTIRELY APPROVE OF.
OH?
[ Speaking French ]
[ Servant ]
I'LL TAKE YOUR LUGGAGE.
IT WILL BE IN YOUR ROOMS.
[ Speaking German ]
[ Indistinct ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Bells Ringing ]
[ Darlington ] GERMAN
REARMAMENT IS AN ACCOMPLISHED
FACT TO BE ACCEPTED.
IT IS IN OUR OWN INTEREST
TO HAVE A FREE, EQUAL
AND STRONG GERMANY,
INSTEAD OF THE PROSTRATE NATION
UPON WHOM AN UNFAIR PEACE TREATY
WAS IMPOSED 16 YEARS AGO.
THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE BEEN
IN GERMANY RECENTLY...
CAN ONLY THRILL, AS I AM,
TO THE SIGNS OF REBIRTH
ENCOUNTERED EVERYWHERE.
...TO ASSIST GERMANY
IN HER VIRILE STRUGGLE
FOR ECONOMIC RECOVERY,
INCLUDING SUPPORT FOR
HER FAIR DEMAND FOR
EQUALITY OF ARMAMENTS...
AND UNIVERSAL
MILITARY SERVICE
FOR GERMAN YOUTH.
IF WE, IN POSTWAR EUROPE--
AND I MAY ADD,
I NEED MORE WATER.
WHILE STRIVING FOR OUR
OWN ECONOMIC RECOVERY--
I NEED ANOTHER BASIN...
TO BATHE MY FEET.
WON'T YOU
FOLLOW ME, SIR?
[ Speaker Continues
Indistinctly ]
[ Applause ]
EXCUSE ME.
MONSIEUR DUPONT.
OUI?
WE HAVE TO TALK, SIR.
[ Stevens ]
UH, THIS WAY, SIR.
MONSIEUR DUPONT.
MY FRIEND,
I AM IN AGONY.
TOO TIGHT SHOES.
I BLAME MYSELF.
IT'S VANITY.
SIR, YOU AND I ARE GOING
TO HAVE TO DO SOME FAST
MANEUVERING BACK THERE...
IF WE WANT TO RESTRAIN
THE GERMANS.
WOULD YOU PLEASE COME
THIS WAY, GENTLEMEN?
YES.
OH, BUTLER, PLEASE,
COULD YOU HELP ME WITH
THE FEET, UH, SHOES.
AH, YES.
OF COURSE, SIR.
TAKE IT OFF.
NOW, YOU HEARD ALL THAT
IN THERE ABOUT EQUALITY
OF ARMAMENTS FOR GERMANY...
AND UNIVERSAL
MILITARY SERVICE.
MR. STEVENS.
YES?
SORRY, SIR.
OH, I'LL MANAGE.
THANK YOU.
WHAT?
UNIVERSAL
MILITARY SERVICE?
[ Door Closes ]
WHAT IS IT?
I'M SORRY,
MR. STEVENS.
YOUR FATHER'S BEEN
TAKEN ILL, SIR.
WHERE?
OUTSIDE THE CHINESE
BEDROOM, SIR.
GERMANY WANTS PEACE
AS MUCH AS WE DO.
SHE NEEDS PEACE.
[ Groaning ]
HERE, LET ME
HELP YOU WITH THAT.
[ Grunting ]
THANK YOU.
UM, THANK YOU, CHARLES.
UM, I WANT YOU TO TAKE A BASIN
OF HOT WATER AND SALTS...
TO MR. DUPONT D'IVRY
IN THE BILLIARDS ROOM.
IS THAT UNDERSTOOD?
YES, MR. STEVENS.
GOOD. DO IT.
FATHER?
FATHER.
MMM.
[ Sighing ]
MR. STEVENS.
YES?
I HAVE MORE TIME
THAN YOU AT THE MOMENT.
I'LL LOOK AFTER HIM.
I'VE CALLED
THE DOCTOR.
THANK YOU, MISS KENTON.
THANK YOU.
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
DOCTOR?
AH, YES.
HELLO, STEVENS.
UH, YOUR FATHER'S
NOT SO GOOD, I'M AFRAID.
AH.
THANK YOU.
IF HE DETERIORATES,
CALL ME, WILL YOU?
YES, SIR. THANK YOU.
HOW OLD IS HE?
70? 72?
75, SIR.
I SEE. WELL, AS I SAY,
IF HE DETERIORATES,
LET ME KNOW.
THANK YOU.
I WILL, SIR.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Ringing ]
- [ Bell Ringing ]
- [ Bells Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
MORE HASTE, LESS SPEED,
ALL RIGHT?
WATCH THAT FIRE.
[ Indistinct ]
NOW, THERE'S SOMETHING MISSING.
WHAT IS IT?
THE SPOON FROM
THE CRUET SET, SIR.
GOOD.
WELL OBSERVED.
NOW, NEVER TOUCH
THE LIP OF THE GLASS.
GOOD.
[ Whistling ]
GLASS FIRST
AND THEN--
[ Whistling ]
IS EVERYTHING IN HAND
DOWNSTAIRS?
OH, YES.
WE'RE PREPARING DINNER.
IT'S THE LAST DINNER
OF THE CONFERENCE,
SO YOU CAN IMAGINE
THE ATMOSPHERE IN THE KITCHEN.
BUT IS EVERYTHING IN HAND?
YES, YES.
I THINK WE'RE UP TO SCRATCH.
AND HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
ARE YOU FEELING ANY BETTER?
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVE TO TELL YOU.
[ Sighs ]
I HAVE SO MUCH
TO DO, FATHER.
WHY DON'T WE TALK
IN THE MORNING?
JIM...
I FELL OUT OF LOVE
WITH YOUR MOTHER.
I LOVED HER ONCE,
BUT LOVE
WENT OUT OF ME...
WHEN I FOUND HER
CARRYING ON.
A GOOD SON.
PROUD OF YOU.
[ Sighing ]
I HOPE I'VE BEEN
A GOOD FATHER TO YOU.
TRIED ME BEST.
YOU BETTER
GET DOWN THERE...
OR HEAVEN ONLY KNOWS
WHAT THEY'LL BE UP TO.
YEAH, GO ON.
GO ON!
WE'LL TALK
IN THE MORNING.
[ Guests Chattering ]
[ Bell Rings,
Guests Quiet ]
[ Woman ]
ON THE LAST DAY
OF OUR CONFERENCE,
PERMIT ME TO SAY
HOW IMPRESSED I HAVE BEEN...
WITH THE SPIRIT OF GOOD WILL
THAT HAS PREVAILED.
GOOD WILL FOR GERMANY.
AND WITH TEARS IN MY EYES
I SEE THAT EVERYONE HERE...
HAS RECOGNIZED
OUR RIGHT TO BE,
ONCE AGAIN,
A STRONG NATION.
AND WITH MY HAND
ON MY HEART,
I DECLARE...
THAT GERMANY
NEEDS PEACE...
AND DESIRES ONLY PEACE.
PEACE WITH ENGLAND...
AND PEACE WITH FRANCE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I, TOO,
HAVE BEEN IMPRESSED.
YES, DEEPLY IMPRESSED
BY THE GENUINE DESIRE...
FOR PEACE MANIFESTED
AT THIS CONFERENCE.
UNLIKE OUR AMERICAN
COLLEAGUE,
WE IN EUROPE KNOW
THE HORRORS OF WAR,
AND WHETHER WE ARE FRENCH
OR ENGLISH OR ITALIAN OR GERMAN,
OUR ONE DESIRE IS TO NEVER
HAVE TO EXPERIENCE THEM AGAIN.
INDEED.
[ D'Ivry ]
IMPRESSED, OH,
OR I MAY SAY TOUCHED,
BY THE WORDS OF GOOD WILL
AND FRIENDSHIP I HAVE HEARD,
I PROMISE YOU THAT
I SHALL DO MY UTMOST...
TO CHANGE THE POLICY
OF MY COUNTRY...
TOWARDS THAT NATION
WHICH WAS ONCE OUR FOE,
BUT IS NOW,
I MAY VENTURE TO SAY,
A FRIEND.
[ Man ]
INDEED.
[ Applause ]
SIR, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT MY COUNTRY HOPED
YOU WOULD SAY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE UNITED STATES
DOESN'T WANT WAR...
ANY MORE THAN YOU DO.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
NEITHER WOULD WE CARE
FOR PEACE AT ANY PRICE,
BECAUSE SOME PRICES
YOU MAY FIND...
ARE TOO OUTRAGEOUSLY
HIGH TO PAY.
BUT LET'S NOT
GET INTO THAT NOW.
WE MAY ALL HAVE TO
SOON ENOUGH.
FOR THE MOMENT, LET US
SIMPLY RAISE OUR GLASSES
TO LORD DARLINGTON...
IN GRATITUDE FOR HIS
MAGNIFICENT HOSPITALITY.
[ Lewis ]
LORD DARLINGTON.
[ All ]
LORD DARLINGTON--
[ Clears Throat,
Rings Glass ]
LORD DARLINGTON IS A CLASSIC
ENGLISH GENTLEMAN
OF THE OLD SCHOOL:
DECENT AND HONORABLE
AND WELL-MEANING.
SO ARE ALL OF YOU HERE:
ALL DECENT AND HONORABLE
AND WELL-MEANING GENTLEMEN.
IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE
AND A PRIVILEGE FOR ME
TO VISIT WITH YOU HERE.
BUT-- NOW, EXCUSE ME,
I HAVE TO SAY THIS--
YOU ARE, ALL OF YOU,
AMATEURS,
AND INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
SHOULD NEVER BE RUN
BY GENTLEMEN AMATEURS.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
OF WHAT SORT OF A PLACE...
THE WORLD IS BECOMING
ALL AROUND YOU?
THE DAYS WHEN YOU COULD
JUST ACT OUT OF YOUR NOBLE
INSTINCTS ARE OVER.
EUROPE HAS BECOME
THE ARENA OF REALPOLITIK,
THE POLITICS OF REALITY.
IF YOU LIKE,
"REAL POLITICS."
AND WHAT YOU NEED IS NOT
GENTLEMEN POLITICIANS,
BUT REAL ONES.
YOU NEED PROFESSIONALS
TO RUN YOUR AFFAIRS OR
YOU'RE HEADED FOR DISASTER.
SO I PROPOSE A TOAST, GENTLEMEN,
TO THE PROFESSIONALS.
MR. STEVENS.
WHAT?
WELL, I HAVE NO WISH
TO ENTER INTO A QUARREL...
ON THIS, OUR LAST
EVENING TOGETHER.
BUT LET ME SAY THIS.
WHAT YOU DESCRIBE
AS "AMATEURISM"...
IS WHAT I THINK
MOST OF US HERE STILL
PREFER TO CALL "HONOR."
MISS KENTON WOULD LIKE
TO SEE YOU OUTSIDE AT ONCE,
SIR, CONCERNING YOUR FATHER.
[ Darlington ] AND I SUGGEST
THAT YOUR "PROFESSIONALISM"
MEANS GREED AND POWER,
RATHER THAN TO SEE
JUSTICE AND GOODNESS
PREVAIL IN THE WORLD.
I'VE NEVER CONCEALED
FROM MYSELF...
THAT WHAT WE WERE
ASKING OF GERMANY...
WAS A COMPLETE BREAK
FROM THE TRADITION
OF THIS COUNTRY.
THANK YOU.
[ Guests Applauding,
Murmuring ]
[ Door Closes ]
MISS KENTON?
[ Whispering ]
YES.
MR. STEVENS,
I'M VERY SORRY.
YOUR FATHER PASSED AWAY
FOUR MINUTES AGO.
OH, I SEE.
I'M SO VERY SORRY. I--
I WISH THERE WAS SOMETHING
I COULD SAY.
YES.
WILL YOU COME UP
AND SEE HIM?
I'M VERY BUSY
AT THE MOMENT,
MISS KENTON.
IN A LITTLE WHILE,
PERHAPS.
IN THAT CASE,
WILL YOU PERMIT ME
TO CLOSE HIM EYES?
I WOULD BE MOST GRATEFUL,
MISS KENTON. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
AH, MISS KENTON.
YES?
MY FATHER WOULD WISH ME
TO CARRY ON WITH MY WORK.
I CAN'T LET HIM DOWN.
NO.
OF COURSE.
THANK YOU.
♫♫ [ Piano ]
♫♫
♫♫ [ Singing In German ]
STEVENS.
HELLO, SIR.
I'D REALLY LIKE TO CONTINUE
OUR LITTLE CHAT SOMETIME.
YES, SIR?
ABOUT NATURE.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
AH.
I THINK I SHOULD
COME BACK IN THE SPRING
WHEN EVERYTHING'S BURGEONING.
YES, SIR,
INDEED.
NOW, AS I SAID BEFORE,
MY MAIN INTEREST HAS
ALWAYS BEEN IN FISH.
FISH?
WHEN I WAS SMALL,
I KEPT TROPICAL FISH
IN A TANK.
INDEED, SIR.
I HARBORED QUITE A PASSION
FOR THEM, ACTUALLY.
YES, SIR.
I'LL HAVE ANOTHER DROP OF THAT,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, I'M PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU.
NOT FEELING UNWELL?
NO, SIR. A LITTLE
TIRED PERHAPS.
♫♫
[ Finishing Song ]
WONDERFUL.
OH, WHAT A BEAUTIFUL OPERA
TO BRING TO THIS HOUSE.
THANK YOU.
VERY NICE.
I JUST WANTED TO SAY,
I HOPE THERE'S NO
HARD FEELINGS, SIR.
OH, MY DEAR GOOD CHAP,
I LIKE A GOOD, CLEAN FIGHT.
[ Chuckles ]
YES, GIVING AS GOOD
AS ONE GETS.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW,
I HAVE THE GREATEST RESPECT
FOR THE ENGLISH, SIR.
I LOVE IT OVER HERE.
IN FACT, MY FAMILY USED
TO BRING US HERE AS KIDS,
SO I'VE ALWAYS FELT
RIGHT AT HOME.
AH.
ANYWAY, THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME.
YES.
YOU ALL RIGHT,
STEVENS?
YES, PERFECTLY, MY LORD.
UM, THANK YOU.
YOU, UH, COMING DOWN
WITH A COLD OR SOMETHING?
YES, IT'S, UH,
BEEN A LONG DAY.
IT'S BEEN A HARD DAY
FOR BOTH OF US.
YES, SIR.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
[ Man ]
DARLINGTON.
TRIMMER?
[ Indistinct Talking ]
[ Woman Coughing ]
MISS KENTON.
MR. STEVENS.
MY CONDOLENCES,
STEVENS.
IT WAS A STROKE,
A SEVERE STROKE.
HE WOULDN'T HAVE
SUFFERED MUCH PAIN.
THANK YOU
FOR TELLING ME.
UH, DOCTOR,
THERE'S A DISTINGUISHED
FOREIGN GENTLEMAN...
IN THE BILLIARD ROOM
IN NEED OF ATTENTION.
URGENT?
HIS FEET.
FEET?
YES.
UH, I'LL TAKE YOU
TO HIM.
IF IT'S URGENT.
YES, IT IS URGENT.
THE GENTLEMAN
IS IN PAIN.
MR. STEVENS,
MY CONDOLENCES.
THANK YOU, MISS KENTON.
IT IS MOST KIND OF YOU.
MISS KENTON.
THANK YOU.
[ Church Bell Tolling ]
GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS STEVENS.
AFTERNOON, SIR.
I'M HOPING
THERE'S A LETTER FOR ME.
STEVENS. STEVENS.
I'LL JUST CHECK FOR YOU,
SIR.
JAMES STEVENS.
STEVENS. STEVENS.
AH, YES.
AH, I'D LIKE--
I'D LIKE TWO APPLES.
THERE YOU ARE.
THANK YOU.
YOU ARE TOURING
IN THESE PARTS?
YES, I'M ON MY WAY
TO CLEVEDON.
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
THAT'LL BE THREE PENCE,
PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
AND YOU'D BE
COMING FROM?
OXFORDSHIRE.
- OH, WHEREABOUTS
IN OXFORDSHIRE?
- HMM? SORRY?
WHEREABOUTS
IN OXFORDSHIRE?
DARLINGTON.
THAT RINGS A BELL.
WASN'T THERE
A LORD DARLINGTON?
SOME SORT OF NAZI?
GOT US IN THE WAR, THEY SAY.
I'M THE BUTLER
AT DARLINGTON HALL,
AND MY EMPLOYER IS MR. LEWIS,
AN AMERICAN GENTLEMAN.
OH, YES?
I HAVE NO ACQUAINTANCE
OF THE FORMER OWNER.
YOUR CHANGE.
[ Kenton ]
I SHOULD BE GLAD TO MEET YOU
AT THE SEA VIEW HOTEL,
SITUATED OPPOSITE THE PIER.
WE'LL HAVE SUCH A LOT
TO TALK ABOUT, AND I SHALL
HAVE MANY QUESTIONS TO ASK YOU.
EXCEPT FOR YOU, I SEEM
TO HAVE LOST TOUCH WITH ALL
OUR FRIENDS AT DARLINGTON HALL,
BUT THAT'S NO WONDER;
IT WAS A LONG TIME AGO...
AND A LOT HAS HAPPENED
IN BETWEEN.
WHO COULD EVER KEEP TRACK
OF ALL THE DIFFERENT PEOPLE
HIS LORDSHIP ONCE EMPLOYED?
- MY LORD, YOU RANG?
- I HEAR THE YOUNG LADIES
FROM GERMANY HAVE ARRIVED.
YES, MY LORD,
THEY'RE JUST OUTSIDE.
I'D LIKE TO
SAY HELLO TO THEM,
PRACTICE MY GERMAN.
THEY DO SPEAK EXCELLENT
ENGLISH, MY LORD.
GOOD. GOOD.
WELL, ASK THEM TO COME IN.
[ Footsteps,
Door Opens ]
THIS IS ELSA,
AND THIS IS IRMA.
HABEN SIE
EINE GUTE REISE GEHABT?
I'M JUST ASKING THEM
IF THEY HAD A GOOD JOURNEY.
I-IT WAS LONG, MY LORD.
HABEN SIE GUTE ANGEKOMMEN?
WAS HALTEN SIE VOM WETTER?
I'M ASKING THEM WHAT
THEY THINK OF THE WEATHER.
WE'RE VERY GRATEFUL
TO YOU, MY LORD,
FOR LETTING US COME HERE.
OUR PARENTS
ARE VERY GRATEFUL.
OH, NOT AT ALL.
NOT AT ALL.
- MISS KENTON WILL LOOK
AFTER YOU. WON'T YOU?
- OH, INDEED, MY LORD.
WELCOME TO DARLINGTON HALL.
WILLKOMMEN TO
DARLINGTON HALL?
THANK YOU, MY LORD.
THANK YOU.
WILL THERE BE
ANYTHING ELSE, MY LORD?
NO, NO.
[ Lord Darlington ]
SIR GEOFFREY,
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
[ Indistinct Talking ]
HOW DO YOU DO?
WELL, COME IN.
MR. BENN.
MR. STEVENS.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU'D LIKE TO
WAIT HERE FOR A WHILE--
[ Bell Ringing ]
OH! MR. BENN!
MISS KENTON.
AREN'T YOU STILL
AT STANTON LACEY?
NO, I'VE BEEN WITH
SIR GEOFFREY FOR SOME TIME.
MISS KENTON.
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED
ONE BIT.
THANK YOU.
PERHAPS WE COULD MEET
LATER FOR TEA.
I HOPE SO.
GOOD.
SO, GENTLEMEN, YOU SPEAK OF
JEWS AND GYPSIES, NEGROES,
SO ON AND SO FORTH.
BUT ONE HAS TO REGARD
THE RACIAL LAWS
OF THE FASCISTS...
AS A SANITARY MEASURE
MUCH OVERDUE, IN MY OPINION.
BUT IMAGINE TRYING TO ENFORCE
SUCH A RULE IN THIS COUNTRY.
MY LORD, MY LORD,
YOU CANNOT RUN A COUNTRY
WITHOUT A PENAL SYSTEM.
HERE WE CALL THEM
PRISONS.
OVER THERE THEY CALL THEM
CONCENTRATION CAMPS.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
AH, STEVENS, IS THERE
ANY MEAT OF ANY KIND
IN THIS SOUP?
NO, I THINK IT'S
MUSHROOM STOCK, SIR.
MUSHROOM ENDS AND SKINS,
ONIONS AND CELERY.
NO MEAT AT ALL.
COLD WATER, AND THEN
COOK ADDS SHERRY.
I HEAR YOU HAVE ONE OF THOSE
LABOUR FELLOWS STANDING
FROM YOUR CONSTITUENCY.
OVER THERE, CORRECT ME
IF I'M WRONG, SIR GEOFFREY--
THEY'VE GOT RID OF ALL THAT
TRADE UNION RUBBISH.
BELIEVE ME, NO WORKERS
STRIKE IN GERMANY.
AND EVERYONE'S
KEPT IN LINE.
IT'S NO WONDER THIS COUNTRY
IS GOING DOWN THE DRAIN.
IT IS INTERNALLY DISEASED.
AH, STEVENS, THE CROUTON.
I THINK THERE MAY BE SOME
BUTTER HERE. DO YOU KNOW?
I-I'M AFRAID
THERE MAY BE, SIR.
♫ ROLL ALONG
PRAIRIE MOON ♫
♫ ROLL ALONG... ♫
WELL, YOU'VE MADE YOURSELF
A COZY LITTLE NEST HERE.
SEEMS TO ME,
MR. STEVENS, YOU MUST BE
A WELL-CONTENTED MAN.
♫ PRAIRIE MOON ♫
MMM.
IN MY PHILOSOPHY, MR. BENN,
A MAN CANNOT CALL HIMSELF
WELL-CONTENTED...
UNTIL HE HAS DONE
ALL HE CAN...
TO BE OF SERVICE
TO HIS EMPLOYER.
OF COURSE, THIS ASSUMES
THAT ONE'S EMPLOYER IS
A SUPERIOR PERSON,
NOT ONLY IN RANK OR WEALTH,
BUT IN MORAL STATURE.
IN YOUR OPINION,
WHAT'S GOING ON UP THERE
HAS MORAL STATURE, DOES IT?
WISH I COULD BE SO SURE,
BUT I'M NOT.
I'VE HEARD
SOME VERY FISHY THINGS,
MR. STEVENS. VERY FISHY.
I HEAR NOTHING, MR. BENN.
♫ FAR AWAY
SHED YOUR BEAMS ♫
AH! LISTEN.
♫ ON THE BOY OF MY DREAMS ♫
THAT'S SO TOUCHING,
ISN'T IT?
♫ TELL HIM TOO
I'VE BEEN TRUE ♫
TO LISTEN TO THESE
GENTLEMEN'S CONVERSATIONS...
♫ PRAIRIE MOON ♫
WOULD DISTRACT ME
FROM MY WORK.
- ♫ THERE'S A WONDERFUL LIGHT
IN THE SKY TONIGHT ♫♫
- AH, MISS KENTON.
IT'S FRESH SODA.
OH.
THANK YOU, MR. BENN.
WOULD YOU BE JOINING US
FOR A DRINK?
OH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
BUT IT'S VERY LATE AND
I HAVE AN EARLY START.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, MR. STEVENS.
GOOD NIGHT,
MISS KENTON.
GOOD-LOOKING WOMAN.
HMM?
MISS KENTON.
IT WAS NEVER THE SAME
AFTER SHE LEFT
STANTON LACEY.
I HANDED IN
MY OWN NOTICE
SIX MONTHS LATER.
I'D BE LOST WITHOUT HER.
A FIRST-RATE HOUSEKEEPER
IS ESSENTIAL IN A HOUSE
LIKE THIS,
WHERE GREAT AFFAIRS ARE
DECIDED BETWEEN THESE WALLS.
GOOD MORNING.
MY LORD, SIR.
[ Lord Darlington Reading ]
"WE CERTAINLY DO THE JEWS
NO INJUSTICE WHEN WE SAY...
"THE REVELATION OF CHRIST
IS SIMPLY INCOMPREHENSIBLE
AND HATEFUL TO THEM.
"ALTHOUGH HE APPARENTLY
SPRANG FROM THEIR MIDST,
"HE EMBODIES,
NEVERTHELESS, THE NEGATION
OF THEIR WHOLE NATURE,
"A MATTER IN WHICH
THE JEWS ARE FAR MORE
SENSITIVE THAN WE ARE.
"THIS CLEAR DEMONSTRATION
OF THE DEEP CLEFT...
"THAT SEPARATES US EUROPEANS
FROM THE JEW...
"IS BY NO MEANS
GIVEN IN ORDER TO LET
RELIGIOUS PREJUDICE,
"WITH ITS DANGEROUS BIAS,
SETTLE THE MATTER,
"BUT BECAUSE I THINK
THAT THE PERCEPTION...
OF TWO SO FUNDAMENTALLY
DIFFERENT NATURES
REVEALS A REAL GULF--"
[ Rattling ]
[ Door Closes ]
STEVENS.
YES, MY LORD?
WE HAVE SOME REFUGEE GIRLS
ON THE STAFF AT THE MOMENT,
I BELIEVE.
WE DO, MY LORD.
TWO HOUSEMAIDS,
ELSA AND IRMA.
YOU'LL HAVE TO LET THEM GO,
I'M AFRAID.
LET THEM GO,
MY LORD?
IT'S REGRETTABLE, STEVENS,
BUT WE-- WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
YOU'VE GOT TO SEE
THE WHOLE THING IN CONTEXT.
I HAVE THE WELL-BEING
OF MY GUESTS TO CONSIDER.
MY LORD,
MAY I SAY...
THEY WORK
EXTREMELY WELL,
THEY'RE INTELLIGENT,
POLITE AND VERY CLEAN.
I'M SORRY, STEVENS,
BUT I'VE LOOKED INTO
THIS MATTER VERY CAREFULLY.
THERE ARE LARGER ISSUES
AT STAKE.
I'M SORRY, BUT THERE IT IS.
THEY'RE JEWS.
YES, MY LORD.
THANK YOU.
I'M AMAZED THAT
YOU CAN STAND THERE...
AS IF YOU WERE JUST...
DISCUSSING ORDERS
FOR THE LARDER!
I SIMPLY CAN'T BELIEVE IT!
YOU'RE SAYING ELSA AND IRMA
ARE TO BE DISMISSED
BECAUSE THEY'RE JEWISH.
HIS LORDSHIP
HAS MADE HIS DECISION.
THERE IS NOTHING
FOR YOU AND I TO DISCUSS.
IF THOSE GIRLS HAVE NO WORK,
THEY COULD BE SENT BACK
TO GERMANY!
- IT IS OUT OF OUR HANDS.
- I'M TELLING YOU,
MR. STEVENS,
IF YOU DISMISS
MY GIRLS TOMORROW,
IT WILL BE WRONG, A SIN,
AS ANY SIN EVER WAS ONE.
THERE ARE MANY THINGS
YOU AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
IN THIS WORLD OF TODAY,
WHEREAS HIS LORDSHIP
UNDERSTANDS FULLY...
AND HAS STUDIED
THE LARGER ISSUES AT STAKE
CONCERNING, SAY, THE, UM--
THE NATURE OF JEWRY AND--
MR. STEVENS,
I WARN YOU.
IF THOSE GIRLS GO,
I SHALL LEAVE THIS HOUSE.
OH, MISS KENTON.
PLEASE.
[ Thunderclap ]
THESE REFERENCES,
I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
ARE... QUITE RESERVED.
NOW, WHY EXACTLY DID YOU
LEAVE YOUR LAST EMPLOYMENT?
THEY DIDN'T WANT ME
ANYMORE.
WELL, WHY NOT?
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY JUST DIDN'T
WANT ME ANYMORE.
THEY SAY
SHE WORKS WELL.
WOULD YOU PLEASE
WAIT OUTSIDE?
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Door Closes ]
SHE'S UNSUITABLE.
NOT AT ALL.
I WANT HER.
WHAT?
- SHE'LL BE UNDER
MY SUPERVISION.
- SHE'S NOT SUITABLE.
SHE'LL DO WELL.
I'LL SEE TO IT.
WELL, THEN, IT IS ENTIRELY
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY,
MISS KENTON.
DIDN'T YOU SAY
YOU WERE LEAVING BECAUSE
OF THE GERMAN GIRLS?
- I'M NOT LEAVING.
I'VE NOWHERE TO GO.
- OH?
I HAVE NO FAMILY.
I'M A COWARD.
- NO, NO--
- YES, I AM A COWARD.
I'M FRIGHTENED OF LEAVING,
AND THAT'S THE TRUTH.
ALL I SEE OUT IN THE WORLD
IS LONELINESS,
AND IT FRIGHTENS ME.
THAT'S ALL
MY HIGH PRINCIPLES
ARE WORTH, MR. STEVENS.
I'M ASHAMED OF MYSELF.
MISS KENTON, YOU MEAN
A GREAT DEAL TO THIS HOUSE.
YOU'RE EXTREMELY IMPORTANT
TO THIS HOUSE, MISS KENTON.
AM I?
YES!
YES.
NOW LOOK HERE, UM,
IF YOU'RE REALLY SURE
ABOUT THIS YOUNG WOMAN,
YOU'D BETTER
CALL HER BACK IN.
[ Sighs Sharply ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Kenton ]
MISS HULL?
MISS HULL,
WE WOULD LIKE YOU
TO START NEXT WEEK.
YOU WILL BE DIRECTLY
RESPONSIBLE TO MISS KENTON.
SHE WILL EXPLAIN THE RULES
OF THE HOUSE TO YOU.
NUMBER ONE,
NO GENTLEMEN CALLERS
OR OTHER SUCH.
YES, SIR.
GOOD.
WELCOME.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU,
MISS KENTON.
WELL DONE.
I'LL SHOW YOU
TO YOUR ROOM.
[ Engine Stalling,
Sputtering ]
[ Engine Stops ]
[ Engine Grinding ]
[ Knocking, Sputtering ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Car Approaching ]
[ Stevens,
Indistinct ]
[ Car Stopping ]
[ Stevens ]
I'D FORGOTTEN HOW MUCH PETROL
THE OLD DAIMLER USES.
I DARE SAY IT'S QUITE
AN IMPRACTICAL MOTOR...
TO BE GOING ABOUT
THE COUNTRY IN, MR., UM--
SMITH'S MY NAME, SIR.
HARRY SMITH.
IT'S A PRIVILEGE TO
HAVE YOU HERE IN MOSCOMBE.
IT'S A PRIVILEGE TO BE HERE.
YOUR HEALTH, SIR.
DR. CARLISLE USUALLY
DROPS IN THIS TIME OF NIGHT.
HE'LL BE PLEASED
TO MEET YOU.
HE'S A GENTLEMAN
LIKE YOURSELF.
YES?
[ Smith ] I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU CALL A GENTLEMAN.
IT'S A NAME EVERY MAN IN
THIS COUNTRY HAS A RIGHT TO.
THERE'S HARRY SMITH NOW, SIR,
GIVING YOU AN EARFUL OF HIS,
UH, PHILOSOPHY.
IT'S ONE OF THE ADVANTAGES
AND PRIVILEGES OF
BEING BORN ENGLISH...
THAT YOU CAN EXPRESS
YOUR OPINION FREELY...
OH.
AND VOTE IN A NEW
MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT.
THAT'S WHAT WE
FOUGHT HITLER FOR.
HAVE YOU HAD MUCH TO DO
WITH POLITICS, SIR?
UM, NOT DIRECTLY SUCH, NO,
PARTICULARLY IN THESE DAYS.
UM, PERHAPS MORE SO
IN THE EARLY 1930'S
AND JUST BEFORE THE WAR.
MY CONCERN WAS MORE
INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS.
FOREIGN POLICY,
SO TO SPEAK.
UH, NOT THAT I EVER
HELD HIGH OFFICE, MIND YOU.
UM, NO, A-ANY INFLUENCE
I EXERTED...
WAS, UH, IN
AN UNOFFICIAL CAPACITY.
EXCUSE ME, SIR, BUT HAVE YOU
EVER MET MR. CHURCHILL?
YES, UH, HE CAME
TO THE HOUSE OCCASIONALLY,
BACK, AGAIN, IN THE 1930'S.
[ Harry ]
CHURCHILL?
BLOODY WARMONGER!
OH, HARRY, COME ON.
HONESTLY, HARRY.
REALLY.
[ Indistinct Talking ]
HE WASN'T CONTENT TO
FIGHT GERMANS, WAS HE?
HE SENT THE TROOPS IN
AGAINST THE MINERS!
[ Man ] WHAT WOULD WE
HAVE DONE WITHOUT HIM
IN THE WAR, HARRY?
[ Harry ] HE DID A GOOD JOB,
BUT HE SHOULD'VE STEPPED DOWN--
OH, HARRY, CALM DOWN.
[ Man ] AND MR. EDEN?
[ Harry ] HE MADE A RIGHT
BUGGER OF SUEZ, DIDN'T HE?
YES, I MET MR. EDEN.
YES, OCCASIONALLY.
HOW DO YOU DO?
RICHARD CARLISLE.
ROTTEN BIT OF LUCK ABOUT
YOUR MOTOR CAR, BUT NICE
TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
EVERYONE
HAS BEEN MOST KIND.
GENTLEMAN KNOWS A LOT
ABOUT FOREIGN AFFAIRS.
OH, IS THAT SO,
INDEED?
YES,
IN AN UNOFFICIAL CAPACITY.
HE KNOWS MR. CHURCHILL.
[ Man ]
AND MR. EDEN.
REALLY?
YES, WELL, UM,
IT WAS MY GOOD FORTUNE...
TO HAVE, UM, CONSORTED
WITH MANY MEN OF INFLUENCE...
FROM EUROPE
AND, UH, FROM AMERICA.
AND, UM--
UH, WELL, MR. TAYLOR,
I OUGHT TO RETIRE NOW...
BECAUSE I AM FEELING
RATHER, UH, TIRED.
NO WONDER, SIR,
RUNNING OUT OF PETROL...
AND HAVING TO LISTEN TO
HARRY SMITH'S POLITICAL
OPINIONS.
[ Chuckling ]
STEP THIS WAY, SIR.
I'VE A VISIT TO MAKE IN
STANBURY IN THE MORNING.
I'D BE HAPPY
TO GIVE YOU A LIFT,
SAVE YOU THE WALK.
WE COULD PICK UP A CAN
OF PETROL ON THE WAY.
I'D HATE TO INCONVENIENCE YOU.
OH, NOT AT ALL.
WOULD 7:30 SUIT YOU?
YOU'LL ENJOY TALKING
TO DR. CARLISLE, SIR.
WATCH THIS STEP.
EXCUSE HARRY SMITH, SIR.
HE WILL GO ON ABOUT
HIS POLITICS.
I'M NOT SAYING
HE'S NOT RIGHT.
DEMOCRACY IS WHAT
WE FOUGHT HITLER FOR.
THERE'S QUITE A FEW LADS
WE LOST IN THIS VILLAGE,
INCLUDING OUR SON HERE.
DUNKERQUE.
I'LL GET YOU
A BLANKET, SIR.
I LEFT A RAZOR
AND SOME SOAP ON THE BASIN.
THANK YOU.
[ Man ] HOW CAN YOU
SAY THINGS LIKE THAT?
[ Indistinct Talking ]
YOU CANNOT GO WRONG IF YOU
LISTEN TO THE OPINIONS...
OF YOUR ORDINARY
MAN IN THE STREET.
THEY'RE PERFECTLY
ENTITLED TO GIVE A,
SUCH AN OLD-FASHIONED VIEW.
GIVE AN OPINION ON POLITICS.
THEY HAVE NO
QUALIFICATIONS WHATSOEVER.
OF COURSE THEY HAVE.
NO.
STEVENS, MR. SPENCER
WOULD LIKE A WORD WITH YOU.
SIR.
MY GOOD MAN,
I HAVE A QUESTION FOR YOU.
YES, SIR?
DO YOU SUPPOSE
THE DEBT SITUATION
REGARDING AMERICA...
IS A SIGNIFICANT FACTOR
IN THE PRESENT
LOW LEVELS OF TRADE...
OR A RED HERRING,
AND THAT THE ABANDONMENT
OF THE GOLD STANDARD...
IS AT THE ROOT
OF THE PROBLEM?
I'M SORRY, SIR, BUT...
I AM UNABLE TO BE OF
ASSISTANCE IN THIS MATTER.
OH, DEAR, WHAT A PITY.
WELL, PERHAPS YOU CAN
HELP US ON ANOTHER MATTER.
OH, NO.
[ Chuckling ]
DO YOU THINK THAT
THE CURRENCY PROBLEM
IN EUROPE...
WOULD BE ALLEVIATED
BY AN ARMS AGREEMENT...
BETWEEN THE FRENCH
AND THE BOLSHEVIKS?
I'M SORRY, SIR,
BUT I'M...
UNABLE TO BE
OF ASSISTANCE
IN THIS MATTER.
VERY WELL, STEVENS.
THAT'LL BE ALL.
UH, ONE MOMENT,
DARLINGTON.
I HAVE ANOTHER QUESTION
TO PUT TO OUR GOOD MAN HERE.
OH, NO.
MY GOOD FELLOW,
DO YOU SHARE
OUR OPINION...
THAT MONSIEUR DALADIER'S
RECENT SPEECH...
ON THE SITUATION
IN NORTH AFRICA
WAS SIMPLY A RUSE...
TO SCUPPER
THE NATIONALIST FRINGE
OF HIS OWN DOMESTIC PARTY?
I AM SORRY, SIR.
I AM UNABLE TO BE
OF ASSISTANCE...
IN ANY
OF THESE MATTERS.
YOU SEE, GENTLEMEN,
OUR GOOD MAN HERE IS UNABLE
TO ASSIST US IN THESE MATTERS.
AND YET WE STILL
GO ALONG WITH THE NOTION...
THAT THIS NATION'S DECISIONS
BE LEFT IN THE HANDS
OF OUR GOOD MAN HERE...
AND A FEW MILLIONS LIKE HIM.
YOU MAY AS WELL
ASK THE MOTHERS' UNION
TO ORGANIZE A WAR CAMPAIGN.
THANK YOU, STEVENS.
THANK YOU, MY LORD.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YES, WELL,
YOU CERTAINLY PROVED
YOUR POINT THERE, SPENCER.
Q.E.D., I THINK.
NO, NOT AT ALL.
[ Chuckling ]
OH, YES, HE HAS.
[ Carlisle ]
WHAT DID YOU MAKE OF
THE CITIZENS OF MOSCOMBE?
NOT SUCH A BAD BUNCH.
OH, NO, SIR.
MR. AND MRS. TAYLOR
WERE EXTREMELY KIND.
I SAY, I HOPE YOU DON'T
THINK ME VERY RUDE,
BUT, UM,
YOU AREN'T A MANSERVANT
OF SOME SORT, ARE YOU?
UM... YES, SIR,
I AM INDEED.
IN FACT,
I'M THE BUTLER
OF DARLINGTON HALL...
NEAR OXFORD.
IT WASN'T MY INTENTION
TO DECEIVE ANYONE, SIR.
NO NEED TO EXPLAIN.
I CAN QUITE SEE
HOW IT HAPPENED.
DARLINGTON.
WASN'T THERE A LORD DARLINGTON
INVOLVED IN ALL THAT
APPEASEMENT BUSINESS...
THAT GOT US INTO THE WAR?
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I NEVER KNEW
THAT LORD DARLINGTON.
MY EMPLOYER'S
AN AMERICAN GENTLEMAN.
MR. LEWIS.
OH, YES.
LORD DARLINGTON
WAS AMONG THOSE...
WHO TRIED TO MAKE A DEAL
WITH HITLER.
THEN THERE WAS A CASE
AFTER THE WAR...
WHERE HE SUED A NEWSPAPER
FOR LIBEL.
THE EXPRESS, WAS IT?
NEWS CHRONICLE?
I COULDN'T SAY,
SIR.
ANYWAY, HE LOST.
HE WAS LUCKY, REALLY,
NOT TO HAVE BEEN
TRIED FOR TREASON.
THERE IT IS,
JUST AHEAD.
[ Petrol Pouring ]
SIR, I MUST CONFESS
THAT I FAILED TO
TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
I DID KNOW LORD DARLINGTON,
AND I CAN DECLARE THAT HE
WAS A TRULY GOOD MAN,
A GENTLEMAN
THROUGH AND THROUGH,
TO WHOM
I'M PROUD TO HAVE GIVEN
MY BEST YEARS OF SERVICE.
WELL, THAT SHOULD GET YOU
TO THE NEXT PETROL STATION.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, SIR.
I'M MOST GRATEFUL.
BUT DID YOU...
SHARE HIS OPINIONS?
WHO?
LORD DARLINGTON.
I WAS HIS BUTLER;
I WAS THERE TO SERVE HIM,
NOT TO AGREE OR DISAGREE.
- YOU TRUSTED HIM?
- YES, I DID, COMPLETELY.
AND AT THE END OF HIS LIFE
HIS LORDSHIP HIMSELF ADMITTED...
THAT HE'D BEEN MISTAKEN,
THAT HE'D BEEN
TOO GULLIBLE AND HAD
LET HIMSELF BE TAKEN IN.
I SEE.
YES.
WELL, THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU'VE BEEN MOST KIND.
THANK YOU.
JUST KEEP GOING
STRAIGHT UP HERE...
YES.
AND TURN LEFT
AT THE FIRST CROSSROADS.
I SAY, I DON'T WANT TO BE
A BORE, BUT I'M INTRIGUED.
I MEAN, WHERE DO YOU STAND
ON ALL THAT?
IF A MISTAKE WAS TO BE MADE,
WOULDN'T YOU RATHER
HAVE MADE YOUR OWN?
[ Chuckles ]
DO FORGIVE ME
FOR BEING SO INQUISITIVE.
NOT AT ALL, SIR.
IN A VERY SMALL WAY,
I DID MAKE MY OWN MISTAKE,
BUT I MIGHT STILL HAVE
A CHANCE TO SET MINE RIGHT.
IN FACT, I'M ON MY WAY
TO TRY AND DO SO NOW.
YES.
TRY THE IGNITION.
[ Engine Starting ]
WELL, THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M MOST GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR HELP.
GOOD LUCK. IT'S BEEN...
INTERESTING TALKING TO YOU.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Lord Darlington ]
OH, STEVENS.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
LORD HALIFAX WAS VERY
IMPRESSED WITH THE SILVER.
TOLD HIM
IT WAS ALL YOUR DOING.
SENT HIS COMPLIMENTS.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
OH, STEVENS, I'VE BEEN
MEANING TO ASK YOU.
THAT BUSINESS LAST YEAR
ABOUT THE JEWISH MAIDS, UM--
I SUPPOSE THERE'S
NO WAY OF TRACING THEM,
IS THERE?
THAT WOULD BE DIFFICULT, SIR.
I TRIED TO OBTAIN A POSITION
FOR THEM IN SURREY,
BUT THERE WAS ROOM
ONLY FOR ONE, AND THE GIRLS
DIDN'T WANT TO BE SEPARATED.
WELL, TRY ANYWAY,
STEVENS.
ONE WOULD LIKE TO DO
SOMETHING FOR THEM.
YES, SIR.
IT WAS WRONG,
WHAT OCCURRED.
I'M SORRY ABOUT IT.
VERY SORRY.
GOOD MORNING!
GOOD MORNING,
MR. STEVENS.
UM, YES, HIS LORDSHIP ASKED
ABOUT THE JEWISH GIRLS.
ELSA AND IRMA?
YES, HE WONDERED
WHERE THEY WERE.
HE SAID IT WAS WRONG
TO DISMISS THEM.
I THOUGHT YOU SHOULD LIKE
TO KNOW, BECAUSE YOU WERE AS
DISTRESSED AS I WAS ABOUT IT.
AS YOU WERE?
AS I RECALL, YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS ONLY RIGHT AND PROPER
THEY SHOULD BE SENT PACKING.
REALLY, MISS KENTON,
THAT IS MOST UNFAIR.
OF COURSE I WAS UPSET.
VERY MUCH SO.
I DON'T LIKE
THAT SORT OF THING
HAPPENING IN THIS HOUSE.
I WISH YOU'D TOLD ME SO.
IT WOULD HAVE HELPED ME...
IF I'D KNOWN YOU FELT
THE SAME WAY I DID.
WHY, MR. STEVENS,
DO YOU ALWAYS HAVE
TO HIDE WHAT YOU FEEL?
[ Door Opens ]
MISS--
LIZZIE, HAVE YOU FINISHED
THE LAUNDRY BAGS?
YES, MISS KENTON.
GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YES, I TAKE MY HAT OFF
TO YOU, MISS KENTON.
THAT GIRL HAS COME ALONG WELL.
YOU WERE RIGHT AND I WAS WRONG.
LOOK AT THAT SMILE
ON YOUR FACE.
HMM? WHAT SMILE?
THAT TELLS
AN INTERESTING STORY
IN ITSELF.
WOULDN'T YOU SAY SO,
MR. STEVENS?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT STORY IS THAT?
SHE'S A VERY PRETTY GIRL.
DON'T YOU THINK?
IS SHE?
MMM.
YOU DON'T LIKE TO HAVE
PRETTY GIRLS ON THE STAFF,
I'VE NOTICED.
MIGHT IT BE
THAT OUR MR. STEVENS
FEARS DISTRACTION?
CAN IT BE THAT
OUR MR. STEVENS IS
FLESH AND BLOOD AFTER ALL...
AND CANNOT TRUST HIMSELF?
HMM?
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M DOING,
MISS KENTON?
I'M PLACING
MY THOUGHTS ELSEWHERE
WHILE YOU CHATTER AWAY.
THEN WHY IS
THAT GUILTY SMILE
STILL ON YOUR FACE?
IT'S NOT A GUILTY SMILE,
IT'S SIMPLY AMUSED...
BY THE SHEER NONSENSE
YOU SOMETIMES TALK.
IT IS A GUILTY SMILE.
THAT'S WHY YOU DIDN'T
WANT TO TAKE HER ON:
SHE WAS TOO PRETTY.
YOU MUST BE RIGHT,
MISS KENTON.
YOU ALWAYS ARE.
[ Giggles ]
COME HERE.
CHARLIE!
COME ON.
QUIT IT!
[ Laughing ]
[ Bell Clanging ]
[ Sighs ]
LIZZIE,
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED TO BE
TURNING DOWN THE BEDS?
WELL, YOU'D BETTER
GET ON WITH IT THEN,
HADN'T YOU?
HAVE YOU TOLD HER YET?
WELL, YOU BETTER GET ON
WITH IT THEN, HADN'T YOU?
WHAT CAN I SAY TO HER?
SHE'D NEVER
UNDERSTAND ABOUT US.
WHY WOULDN'T SHE?
SHE'S OLD.
SHE MUST BE AT LEAST 30.
PERHAPS SHE DOESN'T
FEEL OLD.
FOR INSTANCE, WHO DO YOU
THINK THOSE PRETTY FLOWERS
ARE FOR SHE'S BEEN PICKING?
COME HERE.
GIVE US A KISS.
[ Inhaling Deeply ]
FLOWERS.
HMM?
YOU'RE READING.
YES.
IT'S VERY DIM IN HERE.
CAN YOU SEE?
YES, THANK YOU.
WHAT YOU READING?
A BOOK.
HMM. YES, WELL,
WHAT SORT OF BOOK?
IT'S A BOOK,
MISS KENTON,
A BOOK.
WHAT'S THE BOOK?
ARE YOU SHY
ABOUT YOUR BOOK?
NO.
WHAT IS IT?
[ Sighing ]
IS IT RACY?
RACY?
ARE YOU READING
A RACY BOOK?
DO YOU THINK RACY BOOKS
ARE TO BE FOUND ON
HIS LORDSHIP'S SHELVES?
HOW WOULD I KNOW?
WHAT IS IT?
LET ME SEE IT.
LET ME SEE YOUR BOOK.
PLEASE LEAVE ME ALONE,
MISS KENTON.
WHY WON'T YOU
SHOW ME YOUR BOOK?
THIS IS MY PRIVATE TIME.
YOU'RE INVADING IT.
OH, IS THAT SO?
YES.
I'M INVADING
YOUR PRIVATE TIME, AM I?
YES.
WHAT'S IN THAT BOOK?
COME ON, LET ME SEE.
OR ARE YOU PROTECTING ME?
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
WOULD I BE SHOCKED?
WOULD IT RUIN MY CHARACTER?
LET ME SEE IT.
WELL.
OH, DEAR.
IT'S NOT SCANDALOUS AT ALL.
IT'S JUST A SENTIMENTAL
OLD LOVE STORY.
YES.
I READ THESE BOOKS--
ANY BOOKS--
TO DEVELOP
MY COMMAND AND KNOWLEDGE
OF THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE.
I READ TO FURTHER
MY EDUCATION, MISS KENTON.
I REALLY MUST ASK YOU
PLEASE...
NOT TO DISTURB
THE FEW MOMENTS
I HAVE TO MYSELF.
COME IN.
[ Kenton ]
WHAT IS IT, LIZZIE?
I'M WANTIN' TO
GIVE YOU MY NOTICE,
MISS KENTON, PLEASE.
OH. WHY?
CHARLIE AND ME,
WE'RE GETTING MARRIED.
OH, LIZZIE,
HAVE YOU THOUGHT
ABOUT THIS CAREFULLY?
YES, MISS KENTON,
I HAVE.
YOU'VE BEEN GETTING ON
VERY WELL HERE.
YOU HAVE A FINE CAREER
BEFORE YOU,
IF YOU STICK TO IT.
CHARLIE AND ME'S
GETTING MARRIED.
CHARLIE AND I.
LIZZIE, I WISH I KNEW
WHAT TO SAY TO YOU.
I'VE SEEN THIS HAPPEN
SO MANY TIMES BEFORE.
A YOUNG GIRL RUSHING
INTO MARRIAGE, ONLY TO BE
DISAPPOINTED IN THE END.
AND WHAT ABOUT MONEY?
WE DON'T HAVE ANY.
BUT WHO CARES?
YOU'LL FIND...
IT'S NOT EASY TO LIVE POOR.
WE HAVE EACH OTHER.
THAT'S ALL ANYONE
CAN EVER NEED.
VERY WELL, LIZZIE.
IF YOU'RE SO SURE.
YES, MISS KENTON.
THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Laughing ]
YES!
[ Bell Ringing ]
WE DID ALL WE COULD
FOR THEM.
I TOLD HIM, UH,
I HAD MY EYE ON HIM...
AS A POSSIBLE UNDERBUTLER
IN A YEAR OR SO,
BUT, UM--
NO, MR. CHARLIE
KNOWS BEST.
SHE'S SURE
TO BE LET DOWN.
MMM.
IT'S NO USE CRYING
OVER SPILT MILK.
BESIDES, WE HAVE FAR MORE
IMPORTANT MATTERS TO DISCUSS:
NEXT WEEK'S MEETING.
HIS LORDSHIP IS PLANNING--
DO WE HAVE TO
DISCUSS THIS TONIGHT?
SORRY?
I'M-- I'M TIRED,
MR. STEVENS.
I'VE HAD A VERY BUSY DAY.
DON'T YOU REALIZE THAT?
I'M VERY TIRED.
I--
I'M VERY, VERY TIRED.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
MISS KENTON, I--
I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
I THOUGHT THESE
QUIET EVENING DISCUSSIONS
WERE USEFUL TO US IN OUR WORK,
BUT NOW I SEE THAT THEY
ARE A BURDEN TO YOU.
I WAS ONLY SAYING
I WAS TIRED TONIGHT.
NO, NO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
OUR MEETINGS ARE A BURDEN
AFTER A LONG DAY'S WORK.
PERHAPS WE'D BETTER
DISCONTINUE THEM.
NO, REALLY,
THEY'RE VERY USEFUL.
IT WAS ONLY TONIGHT.
I THANK YOU
FOR THE COCOA.
IN FUTURE, WE SHALL
COMMUNICATE ONLY DURING
THE COURSE OF THE DAY,
IF NECESSARY
BY WRITTEN MESSAGE.
I WISH YOU
A VERY GOOD NIGHT,
MISS KENTON.
MR. STEVENS!
I SHALL BE TAKING
MY DAY OFF TOMORROW.
I'LL BE BACK
IN THE HOUSE BY 9:30.
CERTAINLY.
GOOD NIGHT.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Indistinct Talking ]
HEY, TOM.
HELLO.
NO, I'M GLAD TO BE
OUT OF IT.
THERE WAS SOMETHING
ABOUT SIR GEOFFREY
AND HIS BLACK SHIRTS.
GAVE ME THE CREEPS.
MR. STEVENS
SAYS IT'S UP TO US
TO RUN THE HOUSE...
AND LEAVE THE REST
WHERE IT BELONGS.
YOU DON'T AGREE,
MR. BENN.
NO.
[ Clears Throat ]
NOR DO I, REALLY.
IF I DON'T LIKE SOMETHING,
I WANT TO BE IN A POSITION
TO SAY "STUFF IT."
UM, IF YOU'LL PARDON
THE EXPRESSION, MISS KENTON.
BUT THEN I SUPPOSE
I'M NOT A REAL PROFESSIONAL,
LIKE MR. STEVENS.
IT'S MR. STEVENS'S
WHOLE LIFE.
WELL, IT'S NOT MINE.
AND TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I DON'T WANT TO GO BACK
IN SERVICE.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO INSTEAD,
MR. BENN?
TOM'S THE NAME.
TOM.
WHAT EMPLOYMENT
WOULD YOU TAKE UP?
WELL, I'D REALLY LIKE
TO BE ON MY OWN.
START A LITTLE SHOP
SOMEWHERE.
NEWSPAPERS AND TOBACCO.
OR EVEN A BOARDINGHOUSE,
DOWN IN THE WEST COUNTRY
WHERE I COME FROM.
CLEVEDON. IT'S A GOOD PLACE
FOR A BOARDINGHOUSE.
BY THE SEA.
UH, WOULD I GET YOU
ANOTHER CIANTI, MISS KENTON?
WELL, IT'S ALMOST 9:30.
GO ON. IT'S YOUR DAY OFF,
ISN'T IT?
YOU'RE NOT IN THE ARMY
THAT YOU'VE GOT TO BE
BACK IN BARRACKS.
[ Laughing ]
ALL RIGHT THEN.
GOOD.
CAN I HAVE
HALF A CIANTI, PLEASE?
[ Publican ] YEAH, HALF, SIR.
[ Indistinct Talking
Continues ]
[ Cash Register Rings ]
WHAT ABOUT YOURSELF
THEN, SARAH?
THAT'S A SERIOUS SORT
OF A NAME-- SARAH.
[ Laughs ]
THEY USED TO CALL ME SALLY
WHEN MY MUM WAS STILL ALIVE.
SALLY. THAT'S NICE.
IS IT YOUR INTENTION
TO REMAIN IN SERVICE?
IT'S A GOOD PROFESSION,
ONCE YOU GET TO A
RESPONSIBLE POSITION.
MR. STEVENS SAYS
WE'RE VERY FORTUNATE--
WE'RE
NOT TALKING ABOUT MR. STEVENS.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT YOU.
SUPPOSING SOMEONE
WAS TO ASK YOU...
IF YOU'D LIKE TO COME IN
ON A SMALL BOARDINGHOUSE
BY THE SEA.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S A THEORETICAL QUESTION,
SO I HAVEN'T REALLY GIVEN IT
ANY THOUGHT, MR. BENN.
TOM.
SUPPOSING IT WASN'T
THEORETICAL, SALLY.
IT'S BEEN YEARS SINCE
ANYONE'S CALLED ME THAT.
IT FEELS FUNNY.
NICE, THOUGH?
YES.
[ Church Bell Tolling ]
IT'S VERY LATE.
[ Indistinct Talking ]
WILL THERE BE
ANYTHING ELSE, MY LORD?
WHAT?
OH. STEVENS.
NO. NO.
THANK YOU, STEVENS.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, MY LORD.
[ Thunder ]
MR. CARDINAL,
GOOD EVENING.
WILLIAM, HOW ARE YOU?
VERY WELL, SIR.
DELIGHTED.
AND YOUR WIFE?
SHE'S VERY WELL TOO.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
STEVENS!
HOW ARE YOU?
VERY WELL, SIR.
I'VE GONE AND GOT MYSELF
IN A BIT OF A MESS
WITH ARRANGEMENTS.
DO YOU THINK HIS LORDSHIP
WOULD PUT ME UP FOR THE NIGHT?
I'LL TELL HIM YOU'RE HERE.
YOU'RE LOOKING VERY SMART.
I HOPE THERE'S NOTHING
SPECIAL ON TONIGHT.
HIS LORDSHIP IS EXPECTING
SOME GENTLEMEN AFTER DINNER.
OH, I SEE.
I'VE GOT MY COLUMN
TO WRITE ANYWAY.
YOU'RE IN GOOD TIME
TO JOIN HIM FOR DINNER.
I HOPED I WOULD BE.
AND HOW IS
MY GODFATHER? FIT?
HE'S VERY WELL, SIR.
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME REFRESHMENT?
WHISKEY WOULD BE LOVELY.
WHO IS HE EXPECTING?
I AM UNABLE
TO HELP YOU THERE, SIR.
WHAT, NO IDEA?
NO IDEA AT ALL, SIR.
HUH. WELL, I'D BETTER KEEP
MY HEAD DOWN ALL THE SAME,
DON'T YOU THINK?
I THINK
IT'S A GOOD IDEA, SIR.
[ Knocking ]
COME IN.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
AH, MISS KENTON,
MR. CARDINAL
HAS JUST ARRIVED
OUT OF THE BLUE.
HE'LL BE EXPECTING
HIS USUAL ROOM TONIGHT.
- I SHALL SEE TO IT
BEFORE I LEAVE.
- OH, YOU'RE GOING OUT?
I AM INDEED.
IT'S THURSDAY.
OF COURSE.
I'D FORGOTTEN. SORRY.
IS SOMETHING
THE MATTER?
NO, NO.
UH, SOME VISITORS
ARE EXPECTED TO ARRIVE,
BUT IT DOESN'T INVOLVE YOU.
WE AGREED THAT THURSDAY
IS MY DAY OFF,
BUT IF YOU SHOULD
NEED ME URGENTLY, IT'S--
NO, IT'S PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
MR. STEVENS.
YES?
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO TELL YOU.
MY FRIEND--
THE MAN I'M GOING
TO MEET TONIGHT,
YOU KNOW HIM-- MR. BENN.
OH, YES, MR. BENN.
OF COURSE, YES.
HE HAS ASKED ME
TO MARRY HIM.
I AM THINKING ABOUT IT.
I SEE.
HE'S MOVING BACK TO
THE WEST COUNTRY NEXT MONTH.
HMM.
I'M STILL THINKING
ABOUT IT.
I THOUGHT YOU SHOULD BE
INFORMED OF THE SITUATION.
YES, UH, THANK YOU.
THAT IS MOST KIND OF YOU,
MISS KENTON.
WELL, I TRUST YOU'LL HAVE
A MOST PLEASANT EVENING,
MISS KENTON.
THANK YOU.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
THERE SOMETHING SPECIAL
TONIGHT, SIR?
EH?
YOUR VISITORS TONIGHT.
ARE THEY SPECIAL?
CAN'T TELL YOU, MY BOY.
STRICTLY CONFIDENTIAL.
SO I CAN'T SIT IN
ON IT, THEN?
SIT IN ON WHAT?
WELL, WHATEVER IT IS THAT'S
GOING TO TAKE PLACE TONIGHT.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
CAN'T HAVE SOMEONE LIKE YOU
STICKING YOUR NOSE IN.
- JOURNALIST. WHAT DO YOU
CALL IT? NEWS HOUND.
- [ Chuckling ]
NO, IT WOULDN'T DO AT ALL.
ONCE YOU'VE HAD YOUR FOOD,
BETTER MAKE YOURSELF SCARCE.
[ Cardinal ]
WELL, THAT SOUNDS
PRETTY SPECIAL TO ME.
[ Cars Approaching ]
AH, GOOD EVENING,
PRIME MINISTER.
HOW ARE YOU?
SORRY WE'VE BEEN
RATHER DELAYED.
QUITE UNDERSTAND, SIR.
LORD HALIFAX.
HOW ARE YOU?
VERY NICE TO SEE YOU.
THIS IS MR. FRASER.
HOW DO YOU DO,
MR. FRASER?
[ Car Approaching ]
GOOD EVENING,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
GOOD EVENING.
PLEASE WAIT HERE,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
I'LL INFORM HIS LORDSHIP.
THANK YOU.
[ Speaking In German ]
EXCELLENCE.
[ Murmuring In German ]
AMBASSADOR.
LORD DARLINGTON.
[ Speaking
In German ]
HOW DO YOU DO?
[ Speaking
In German ]
HOW DO YOU DO?
WE DON'T INTEND TO INVOLVE
THE WHOLE BRITISH EMPIRE
IN A WAR...
SIMPLY BECAUSE OF A QUARREL
IN A FARAWAY COUNTRY...
BETWEEN PEOPLE OF WHOM
WE KNOW NOTHING.
TO MY MIND, THE WHOLE
OF CZECHOSLOVAKIA...
IS HARDLY WORTH
THE BONES OF A SINGLE ONE
OF OUR OWN YOUNG MEN.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE HAVE
A SMALL, NOISY AND CORRUPT
WAR GROUP HERE...
WHO DON'T REALIZE
THAT YOU GERMANS ARE...
ONLY MARCHING INTO
YOUR OWN BACK GARDEN.
THE FUHRER
IS A MAN OF PEACE...
TO THE DEPTH
OF HIS SOUL,
BUT HE WILL NOT ALLOW
A SMALL, SECOND-RATE
COUNTRY...
TO THUMB ITS NOSE
AT THE 1,000 YEAR
GERMAN REICH.
[ Indistinct Talking ]
[ Bell Rings ]
I'LL GET IT.
COME ON, WAKE UP!
STAY AWAKE.
COULD YOU CONFIRM
THAT THIS LADY IS
ON THE STAFF HERE, SIR?
YES, OF COURSE.
SHE'S THE HOUSEKEEPER,
MISS KENTON.
THANK YOU, SIR.
MAY I?
OF COURSE, MISS.
SORRY TO HAVE ALARMED YOU.
JUST SECURITY, MISS.
THANK YOU.
I TRUST YOU'VE HAD
A PLEASANT EVENING.
WELL?
DID YOU HAVE
A PLEASANT EVENING?
YES, THANK YOU.
GOOD.
- WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT TOOK PLACE?
- [ Sighs Sharply ]
I HAVE TO RETURN UPSTAIRS.
THERE ARE EVENTS OF THE
UTMOST IMPORTANCE TAKING
PLACE IN THIS HOUSE TONIGHT.
AH.
WHEN ARE THERE NOT?
I ACCEPTED HIS PROPOSAL.
MISS KENTON?
I ACCEPTED MR. BENN'S
PROPOSAL OF MARRIAGE.
MY CONGRATULATIONS.
I AM PREPARED TO
SERVE OUT MY NOTICE,
BUT IF YOU WERE ABLE
TO RELEASE ME EARLIER,
I WOULD BE GRATEFUL.
MR. BENN IS PLANNING TO
LEAVE FOR THE WEST COUNTRY
IN TWO WEEKS' TIME.
I'LL DO MY BEST.
NOW PLEASE EXCUSE ME.
- MR. STEVENS.
- YES, MISS KENTON?
AFTER ALL THE YEARS
I HAVE BEEN IN THIS HOUSE,
YOU HAVE NOTHING ELSE
TO SAY TO ME?
YOU HAVE MY WARMEST...
CONGRATULATIONS.
DID YOU KNOW YOU HAVE BEEN
A VERY IMPORTANT FIGURE...
FOR MR. BENN AND ME?
OH. IN WHAT WAY?
I TELL HIM ALL SORTS
OF THINGS ABOUT YOU.
I TELL HIM STORIES ABOUT YOU,
ABOUT YOUR HABITS,
ABOUT YOUR MANNERISMS.
HE FINDS IT VERY FUNNY,
ESPECIALLY WHEN I SHOW HIM
HOW YOU...
PINCH YOUR NOSE
WHEN YOU PUT PEPPER
ON YOUR FOOD.
THAT ALWAYS HAS US
IN STITCHES.
DOES IT, INDEED?
[ Chuckles ]
WELL, PLEASE
EXCUSE ME, MISS KENTON.
GOOD NIGHT.
AH!
THERE. THANKS.
WE'VE BEEN FRIENDS
A LONG TIME,
HAVEN'T WE?
YES, SIR. THANK YOU, SIR.
I ALWAYS LOOK FORWARD TO
A LITTLE CHAT DOWN HERE.
CARE TO JOIN ME
IN A LITTLE DRINK?
THAT'S MOST KIND,
BUT NO THANK YOU.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, I'M PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU.
NOT FEELING UNWELL,
ARE YOU?
NO, NO.
A LITTLE TIRED, PERHAPS.
I'LL BET YOU ARE TIRED.
WHAT IS IT, 1:00?
COME ON, STEVENS.
I WANT YOU TO SIT DOWN.
WELL, SIR,
I REALLY--
MMM!
SIR.
LOOK, UM,
I DIDN'T COME HERE
TONIGHT BY ACCIDENT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
HAD A TIP-OFF, YOU SEE,
ABOUT, UM,
ABOUT WHAT'S GOING ON
IN THE LIBRARY.
AH, YES.
I DO WISH YOU'D
SIT DOWN, STEVENS.
YOU'RE STANDING THERE
HOLDING THAT TRAY AS IF
YOU'RE ABOUT TO WANDER OFF.
COME ON,
SIT DOWN, DAMN IT!
[ Chuckles ]
THANK YOU, SIR.
THAT'S BETTER.
TELL ME, I DON'T SUPPOSE
THE PRIME MINISTER IS
IN THE LIBRARY, IS HE?
THE PRIME MINISTER, SIR?
MMM.
IN THE LIBRARY-- YOU DON'T
HAVE TO CONFIRM IT--
ARE OUR PRIME MINISTER,
OUR FOREIGN SECRETARY
AND THE GERMAN AMBASSADOR.
ANY IDEA WHAT THEY'RE
TALKING ABOUT IN THERE?
I'M AFRAID NOT, SIR.
TELL ME, STEVENS,
DON'T YOU CARE AT ALL?
AREN'T YOU
IN THE LEAST BIT CURIOUS?
IT IS NOT MY PLACE TO BE
CURIOUS ABOUT SUCH MATTERS.
NOT YOUR PLACE?
AND SUPPOSING I TOLD YOU
THAT, UM,
HIS LORDSHIP IS PRESENTLY
TRYING TO PERSUADE
THE PRIME MINISTER...
TO ENTER INTO A PACT WITH
THAT BUNCH OF CRIMINALS
IN BERLIN.
I'M CERTAIN HIS LORDSHIP
IS ACTING FROM THE HIGHEST
AND NOBLEST MOTIVES, SIR.
[ Laughing ]
DON'T YOU SEE THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT MAKES IT SO ABOMINABLE;
THAT THEY TAKE THESE NOBLE
MOTIVES AND TWIST THEM
TO THEIR OWN FOUL ENDS.
YOU DO, PLEASE, REALIZE
THAT HIS LORDSHIP'S BEEN
THE MOST VALUABLE PAWN...
THAT THE NAZIS HAVE
IN THIS COUNTRY OVER
THE LAST FEW YEARS,
PRECISELY BECAUSE
HE IS GOOD AND HONORABLE.
[ Chuckles ]
IF I ONLY WEREN'T SO DRUNK,
I COULD MAKE YOU UNDERSTAND.
SIR, I DO UNDERSTAND.
HIS LORDSHIP IS WORKING
TO ENSURE PEACE IN OUR TIME.
YES, PEACE IN OUR TIME
ON THEIR BEASTLY TERMS,
STEVENS.
REMEMBER THAT AMERICAN
HERE AT THE CONFERENCE
THREE YEARS AGO...
CALLED LORD DARLINGTON
AN AMATEUR, OUT OF HIS DEPTH?
WELL, HE WAS RIGHT.
HE WAS DEAD RIGHT, STEVENS.
I MEAN, I HARDLY HAVE
TO TELL YOU HOW I FEEL
TOWARD HIS LORDSHIP.
I CARE ABOUT HIM DEEPLY.
DEEPLY!
AND I KNOW YOU DO TOO.
YES, I DO, INDEED.
IN THAT CASE, AREN'T YOU AS
DESPERATE AS I AM TO SEE HIM
MAKE THIS TERRIBLE MISTAKE?
HE'S BEING TRICKED!
DON'T YOU SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON HERE?
OR ARE YOU AS DELUDED
AS HE IS?
OH, DEAR,
NOW I'VE PROBABLY
REALLY OFFENDED YOU.
NO, NOT AT ALL, SIR.
NOT AT ALL.
WELL, SIR,
YOU MUST EXCUSE ME.
THE OTHER GENTLEMEN
ARE CALLING FOR ME, SIR.
THANK YOU.
- MR. STEVENS.
- YES?
YOU MUSTN'T TAKE
ANYTHING I SAID TO HEART.
I WAS VERY FOOLISH
A LITTLE WHILE AGO.
MISS KENTON,
I HAVEN'T TAKEN ANYTHING
YOU SAID TO HEART.
IN FACT,
I CAN HARDLY RECALL
ANYTHING YOU DID SAY.
I WAS JUST BEING
VERY FOOLISH.
I SIMPLY HAVEN'T TIME
TO STAND HERE WITH YOU,
ENGAGING IN IDLE TALK,
MISS KENTON.
[ Sighs ]
I SUGGEST YOU GO
TO BED NOW.
YOU MUST BE VERY TIRED.
GOOD NIGHT, MISS KENTON.
[ Door Opens ]
OH, DAMN IT!
BLAST!
[ Weeping ]
[ Weeping Continues ]
MISS KENTON?
YES, MR. STEVENS?
MISS KENTON, I--
I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO TELL YOU--
IT'S THE SMALL ALCOVE
OUTSIDE THE BREAKFAST ROOM.
IT'S THE NEW GIRL,
OF COURSE.
BUT I FIND IT HAS
NOT BEEN DUSTED IN SOME TIME.
I'LL SEE TO IT,
MR. STEVENS.
THANK YOU, I--
I KNEW YOU WOULD HAVE
WANTED TO BE INFORMED,
MISS KENTON.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Weeping ]
[ Sea Gulls Squawking ]
[ Woman ]
HURRY UP, TREVOR.
COME ON, TRUDY.
HELLO, SALLY.
HI, TOM.
YOU ALL RIGHT THEN?
YES. HOW ARE YOU?
I-I'M GOOD.
COULD WE, UH--
COULD WE TALK
FOR A MOMENT, PLEASE?
NO, NO.
JUST FOR A MOMENT.
WE'LL HAVE TO BE QUICK
BECAUSE I'M GOING OUT.
IT WON'T TAKE LONG.
ALL RIGHT.
THEN WE'LL HAVE TO GO
INTO THE LOUNGE.
AFTERNOON.
HELLO.
NICE LITTLE PLACE,
ISN'T IT?
MM-HMM.
THE SORT OF QUIET
LITTLE BOARDINGHOUSE
I HAD IN MIND FOR US.
WELL, LIKE OTHER THINGS,
UM, IT DIDN'T WORK OUT.
WHAT DID YOU
WANT TO SAY, TOM?
WELL, UM,
I SAW CATHERINE YESTERDAY.
SHE HAD SOME INTERESTING NEWS.
OH!
YEAH.
SHE'S EXPECTING.
OH, MY GOODNESS!
[ Man Clearing Throat ]
SHE WANTS US BOTH
OVER FOR TEA ON SUNDAY.
I-I COULD COME
AND GET YOU.
WE COULD GO TOGETHER
ON THE BUS.
YES, WELL,
WE'LL SEE ABOUT THAT.
HOUSE IS THAT EMPTY
WITHOUT YOU, SAL.
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
YOU'VE CUT YOURSELF
SHAVING.
OH, YEAH,
I KNOW.
CAN'T SEEM TO DO
ANYTHING RIGHT THESE DAYS.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Kenton's Voice ]
"OH, MR. STEVENS, I SO OFTEN
THINK OF THE GOOD OLD DAYS...
"WHEN I WAS THE HOUSEKEEPER
AT DARLINGTON HALL.
I REMEMBER THOSE
YEARS WITH YOU AS AMONG
THE HAPPIEST OF MY LIFE."
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME MORE TEA, SIR?
UM, YES, PLEASE. THANK YOU.
AH, MISS KENTON.
I'M SORRY, MRS. BENN.
MR. STEVENS.
I'M SORRY.
I WAS DELAYED.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
SO... UM, I'VE
ORDERED SOME FRESH TEA.
OH, LOVELY.
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME CAKE?
NO, THANK YOU.
YOU SURE?
OH, YES, ALL RIGHT THEN,
SINCE IT'S A SPECIAL OCCASION.
GOOD.
UH, WAITRESS?
SIR?
COULD WE HAVE
SOME CAKE?
YES, OF COURSE, SIR.
WELL. IT HAS BEEN
A LONG TIME THEN.
YES, INDEED.
YOU HAVEN'T
CHANGED AT ALL.
WELL--
[ Laughs ]
A LITTLE, PERHAPS.
WE'VE ALL CHANGED,
I THINK.
I'D HAVE KNOWN YOU ANYWHERE.
OH. WELL.
[ Chuckles ]
YES. HOW LONG
HAS IT BEEN NOW?
IT MUST BE 20 YEARS.
YES, JUST OVER,
I THINK.
THE TEA SHOULD BE ALONG.
AH.
♫♫
[ Man ]
♫ BLUE MOON ♫
♫ YOU SAW ME STANDING ALONE ♫
♫ WITHOUT A DREAM IN MY HEART ♫
♫ WITHOUT A LOVE OF MY OWN ♫
WE READ ABOUT
THE SUIT FOR LIBEL.
IT WAS A SHAME.
YES.
CALLING HIS LORDSHIP A TRAITOR.
THOSE PAPERS WILL
PRINT ANYTHING.
THEYSHOULD HAVE
LOST THE CASE.
YES.
♫♫ [ Continues ]
WHEN HIS LORDSHIP
WENT TO COURT,
HE SINCERELY EXPECTED
HE WOULD GET JUSTICE.
AND, UH, INSTEAD,
THE NEWSPAPER INCREASED
ITS CIRCULATION...
AND HIS LORDSHIP'S GOOD NAME
WAS DESTROYED FOREVER.
AND, UM, AFTERWARDS,
IN HIS LAST YEARS, WELL--
QUITE HONESTLY,
MRS. BENN, HE--
HIS HEART WAS BROKEN.
I WOULD TAKE HIM TEA
IN THE LIBRARY
AND HE'D BE, UM,
SITTING THERE AND SOMETIMES
HE WOULDN'T EVEN SEE ME,
HE SEEMED SO DEEP
IN HIS OWN THOUGHTS.
AND HIS, UH--
HE'D BE TALKING TO HIMSELF,
HIS LIPS MOVING AS THOUGH
HE WAS ARGUING WITH SOMEONE.
AND THERE WAS NO ONE,
OF COURSE. UM--
NO ONE CAME TO SEE HIM
ANYMORE, YOU SEE.
WHAT ABOUT HIS GODSON,
YOUNG MR. CARDINAL?
OH, MR. CARDINAL
WAS KILLED IN THE WAR.
WAITRESS?
SIR?
MAY I HAVE MY BILL,
PLEASE? THANK YOU.
I'M VERY SORRY.
YES.
♫♫ [ Continues ]
I KNOW YOU REMEMBER
DARLINGTON HALL
IN ITS BEST DAYS,
AND THAT'S HOW HIS LORDSHIP
DESERVES TO BE REMEMBERED,
OF COURSE, BUT, UM--
AND, PERHAPS,
THE GOOD DAYS ARE STARTING
AGAIN NOW THAT MR. LEWIS...
HAS TAKEN UP RESIDENCE,
AND MRS. LEWIS IS EXPECTED
TO ARRIVE SHORTLY.
THEY'RE VERY FORTUNATE
TO HAVE YOU THERE
TO RUN THE HOUSE FOR THEM.
WELL, WE STILL HAVE
PROBLEMS, MISS KENTON--
I'M SORRY. MRS. BENN.
AH, DO FORGIVE ME.
BUT WE STILL HAVE
STAFF PROBLEMS.
YES. YES, YOU MENTIONED IT
IN YOUR LETTER.
YOU SEE, I'M--
AND, UM...
I'LL TELL YOU FRANKLY,
MR. STEVENS,
I HAD BEEN THINKING
OF GOING BACK IN SERVICE.
GOOD.
BUT, UM, NOW THE SITUATION
HAS CHANGED FOR ME...
BECAUSE IF I TAKE UP ANY WORK,
IT WILL HAVE TO BE HERE
IN THE WEST COUNTRY...
BECAUSE, YOU SEE,
CATHERINE, OUR DAUGHTER,
IS EXPECTING A BABY.
AND-- SO, OF COURSE,
I WOULD LIKE TO BE NEAR HER.
OF COURSE.
AND THEN... TO BE NEAR
OUR GRANDCHILD AS HE GROWS UP.
NATURALLY.
OR HER,
IF IT'S
A LITTLE GIRL.
YES.
[ Sea Gulls Squawking ]
[ Indistinct Chattering ]
WHEN I FIRST
LEFT DARLINGTON HALL
ALL THOSE YEARS AGO,
I NEVER REALIZED
I WAS REALLY, TRULY LEAVING.
I BELIEVE I THOUGHT OF IT
AS SIMPLY ANOTHER RUSE,
MR. STEVENS,
TO ANNOY YOU.
IT WAS A SHOCK
TO COME OUT HERE AND FIND
MYSELF ACTUALLY MARRIED.
FOR A LONG TIME I WAS...
VERY UNHAPPY.
BUT THEN CATHERINE WAS BORN,
THE YEARS WENT BY,
AND ONE DAY I REALIZED
I LOVED MY HUSBAND.
♫♫ [ Band ]
YOU SEE, THERE IS
NO ONE, MR. STEVENS,
NO ONE IN THE WORLD
WHO NEEDS ME AS MUCH AS HE DOES.
BUT STILL,
THERE ARE TIMES...
WHEN I THINK
WHAT A TERRIBLE MISTAKE
I'VE MADE WITH MY LIFE.
YES.
WELL, I'M SURE WE ALL
HAVE THESE THOUGHTS...
FROM TIME TO TIME.
♫♫ [ Band Continues ]
[ Sea Gulls Squawking ]
[ Chuckles ]
YES.
[ Bystanders Clapping,
Cheering ]
HMPF.
PEOPLE ALWAYS CHEER WHEN
THEY TURN THE LIGHTS ON
IN THE EVENING.
EVERY TIME.
I WONDER WHY.
THEY DO SAY... THAT
FOR A GREAT MANY PEOPLE,
THE EVENING'S THE BEST
PART OF THE DAY,
THE PART THEY MOST
LOOK FORWARD TO.
AH.
IS THAT SO?
WHAT DO YOU MOST
LOOK FORWARD TO,
MR. STEVENS?
OH, UH... GETTING BACK
TO DARLINGTON HALL,
PRINCIPALLY,
AND STRAIGHTENING OUT
OUR STAFF PROBLEMS.
HMPF.
YOU WERE ALWAYS ABLE
TO DO THAT, MR. STEVENS.
AND YOU HAD QUITE A FEW
TO STRAIGHTEN OUT,
AS I REMEMBER.
[ Chuckling ]
YES, THERE...
ALWAYS WAS WORK, WORK
AND MORE WORK.
AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE SO,
I HAVE NO DOUBT.
HMM.
MR. STEVENS, DON'T YOU WAIT.
THAT BUS IS ALWAYS LATE.
COME IN
OUT OF THE WET.
YOU MUST TAKE GOOD CARE
OF YOURSELF, MRS. BENN.
YOU TOO, MR. STEVENS.
PROMISE ME THAT.
OH, YES, I PROMISE.
YOU MUST TRY TO DO
ALL YOU CAN TO MAKE
THESE YEARS HAPPY ONES...
FOR YOURSELF
AND YOUR HUSBAND.
WE MAY NEVER MEET AGAIN,
MRS. BENN,
THAT IS WHY I AM PERMITTING
MYSELF TO BE SO PERSONAL,
IF YOU WILL FORGIVE ME.
THANK YOU,
MR. STEVENS.
OH, HERE IT COMES.
IT'S ON TIME FOR ONCE.
THANK YOU, MR. STEVENS.
AND THANK YOU SO VERY MUCH
FOR COMING.
IT WAS SO VERY KIND OF YOU.
IT WAS SO NICE
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
IT WAS A PLEASURE TO
SEE YOU AGAIN, MRS. BENN.
GOOD-BYE.
[ Bell Ringing ]
TAKE CARE.
GOOD-BYE.
OH! STEVENS.
YOU SCARED ME. WHERE
DID YOU COME FROM?
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
LIKE THE SUIT?
VERY GOOD, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[ Humming ]
GOOD.
[ Lewis ]
WATCH THE CHANDELIER, NOW.
OKAY.
DROP IT
AT YOUR END.
SWING IT AROUND.
MY LORD, STEVENS.
YOU'RE REALLY GETTING
THINGS GOING HERE.
THIS IS WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
UM--
I'VE HAD TO ASK ANOTHER
THREE GIRLS FROM THE VILLAGE
TO COME UP, SIR.
AND I THINK
I CAN PROMISE YOU THAT
THE HOUSE WILL BE READY...
AND IN SPLENDID SHAPE
BY THE TIME MRS. LEWIS ARRIVES.
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, SIR.
ALSO, I'M EXPECTING
A POSSIBLE NEW HOUSEKEEPER
THIS AFTERNOON.
A MRS. RUTH MUSPRATT.
EXCELLENT REFERENCES.
SHE WAS MATRON
AT A BOY'S PREPARATORY SCHOOL
IN SUSSEX, SIR.
A MATRON, HUH?
YES, SIR.
HUH. WELL, IT SOUNDS LIKE
SHE'LL KNOW HOW TO KEEP US
FROM MISBEHAVING, HUH?
OH, I CERTAINLY
HOPE SO, SIR.
GOOD.
GOOD, STEVENS.
VERY GOOD.
THIS IS WHERE WE HAD
THAT BANQUET BACK IN '35.
REMEMBER?
WE ALL STOOD UP AND...
DELIVERED OURSELVES
OF OUR PRINCIPLES.
GOD KNOWS WHAT I SAID.
SURE GOT WORKED UP
ABOUT IT THOUGH.
WHAT DID I SAY
ANYWAY, STEVENS?
I'M SORRY, SIR,
I WAS TOO BUSY SERVING
TO LISTEN TO THE SPEECHES.
WE'VE GOT A VISITOR HERE.
YOU HAVE TO BE
VERY CAREFUL.
COME ON, COME ON.
ATTA BOY. COME ON.
GENTLY, SIR.
OOH, OOH, EASY.
OKAY, EASY DOES IT.
HMM. OKAY,
COME ON.
IT'S JUST BEING
DRIVEN HIGHER, SIR.
YOU DON'T WANT TO STARTLE IT.
IT WILL COME DOWN.
AH... I THINK IF WE
LEAVE THE WINDOW OPEN--
[ Lewis ]
COME ON.
GOOD.
OUT, OUT.
GO ON.
VERY STILL. YES.
GO ON. GO ON.
GO ON. OUT.
COME ON, OUT!
COME ON.
WELL DONE.
WELL DONE, SIR.
(GAVEL BANGING)
USHER: Silence!
Be upstanding in court!
All persons
who have anything to do
before my lords,
the Queen's justices
of oyer and terminer
and general jail delivery
for the jurisdiction
of the Central Criminal Court
draw near and give
your attendance.
God save the Queen!
What a beautiful day!
I've been hoping
we'd have a bit of sun
for our homecoming.
I always say it's worth
having all the fog
just to appreciate
the sunshine.
Is there too much
of a draught?
Shall I roll
up the window?
Just roll up your mouth.
You talk too much.
If I'd known
how much you talked,
I'd never have come
out of my coma.
This thing weighs a ton.
Now, now, we've been flat
on our back for two months,
we'd better be careful!
(SIGHS)
Lovely, lovely!
It must be perfectly
lovely to live
and work in the inns of court.
How lucky you lawyers are!
Ha! I almost married
a lawyer once.
I was in attendance
when he had his appendectomy
and we became engaged
as soon as he could sit up.
And then peritonitis set in
and he went like that.
He certainly was
a lucky lawyer.
(BELLS CHIMING)
Teeny-weeny steps now,
Sir Wilfrid.
We must remember we had
a teeny-weeny heart attack.
Oh, shut up!
Williams, my cane.
Here he comes!
Good afternoon.
Thank you very much.
Everybody back to work.
Sir Wilfrid,
if you don't mind,
I would like
to read you
a little poem
we've composed
to welcome you back.
That's very touching,
Miss McHugh,
but recite it
after office hours
on your own time.
(GASPS)
Now, back to work.
What's the matter
with you?
Nothing.
I'm just happy
that you're your
old self again.
Any more
sentimentality
around here,
I can instantly go back
to the hospital.
Not very likely.
They won't
take him back.
He wasn't really
discharged, you know,
he was expelled,
for conduct unbecoming
a cardiac patient.
Put these in water,
blabbermouth!
Come on in, Carter.
Look at this room.
It's ugly, old and musty,
and I never knew
I could miss anything so much.
Missed you, too,
you musty old buzzard.
Oh, thank you, sir.
I'm not a religious man,
Sir Wilfrid,
but when they carted you off
in that ambulance,
I went out
and lit a candle.
Why, thank you, Carter.
Actually, sir,
I--I was lighting it
for myself.
If anything
happened to you,
what would happen to me,
after 37 years?
Thirty seven years?
Has it been all that long?
Yes, sir.
This is 1952,
that was in October, 1915.
The shepherd's bush murder.
The chemist accused
of putting cyanide
in his uncle's toothpaste.
Ah.
My first murder trial.
I was more frightened
than the defendant.
The first time I rose
to make an objection,
my wig fell off.
Where's my wig?
Right here.
I've guarded it
with me life.
I hope it still fits.
I lost 30 pounds
in that wretched hospital.
Still, I suppose my head
isn't any smaller.
What's all this?
We've put it in mothballs.
Mothballs?
Am I not to practice again?
Of course you are.
The solicitors
have been breaking
down our doors.
I've lined up
some very interesting
briefs for you, sir.
That's better.
A divorce case,
a tax appeal,
and an important
marine insurance claim.
Oh.
They're nice,
smooth matters
with excellent fees.
No, Carter.
I'm sorry, sir,
but you're not to undertake
any criminal cases,
not any more.
Your doctors have...
Doctors!
They've deprived me
of everything,
alcohol, tobacco,
female companionship.
If only they'd let me
function at my work
on something worthwhile.
Sorry, Sir Wilfrid.
Might as well get
a bigger box,
more mothballs,
put me away, too.
2:30, Sir Wilfrid.
Time for our little nap.
WILFRID: Oh, get out!
And beddy-bye.
We'd better go upstairs now,
get undressed and lie down.
We? What a nauseating
prospect!
Upstairs, please.
Are you aware,
Miss Plimsoll,
while on my sickbed,
I seriously considered
strangling you
with one of your own
rubber tubes?
I would then have
admitted the crime,
retained myself
for the defense.
My lord and members
of the jury,
I hereby enter a plea
of justifiable homicide.
For four months,
this alleged angel of mercy
has pawed, probed,
punctured,
pillaged and plundered
my helpless body,
while tormenting my mind
with a steady drip
of baby talk.
Come along, now,
like a good boy. Oh, no!
You take your hands off me,
Miss Plimsoll,
or I'll strike you
with my cane.
Oh, you'd never do that.
You might break
your cigars.
Cigars? What cigars?
The ones you're smuggling
in your cane.
Cane?
You could be jailed for this.
You had no search warrant
for my cane.
In hospital,
he'd hide cigars and brandy
all over the place.
We called him
Wilfrid the fox.
I'm confiscating these.
Can't I have just one?
No! Upstairs!
A few puffs after meals?
Please!
Well, I'll do it!
Some dark night
when her back is turned,
I'll snatch her thermometer
and plunge it between
her shoulder blades.
So help me, I will!
Oh, no, sir,
you mustn't walk up.
We've installed
something for you here.
It's a lift, sir.
A lift?
I'm getting sick
of this plot
to make me
a helpless invalid.
I think it's
a splendid idea.
Let's try it,
shall we?
Out of there.
I'll try it.
It's my lift,
because it was
my heart attack.
Here you are.
Simply press
this button for up,
and this one for down.
Carter, I warn you,
if this contraption
should collapse...
If the barrister
should fall off
the banister...
This is remarkable, Carter.
Smoothest flight
I've had in years.
Upsy-daisy.
Once more,
to get the feel
of the controls.
Good afternoon,
Carter.
Would it be possible
to see Sir Wilfrid?
I'm sorry I didn't ring up
for an appointment,
but this is urgent.
If it's about a brief,
Mr. Mayhew,
I'm sorry,
but we're full up.
Sir Wilfrid has all
that he can handle.
I'm sure he'll want
this brief.
Serious criminal matter.
Absolutely not,
Mr. Mayhew.
Sir Wilfrid
is still convalescent.
He can't possibly
accept anything
of an over-stimulating
nature.
They've put me on a diet
of bland civil suits.
Hello, Mayhew.
Hello, Wilfrid.
This is very distressing news
about your health.
Distressing?
It's tragic.
You better get yourself
a younger man
with younger arteries.
If you could just
give us a few minutes,
my client is here.
This is Mr. Leonard Vole.
He's in rather
a ghastly mess,
I'm afraid.
How do you do,
Mr. Vole?
Huh! Well, according
to Mr. Mayhew,
I--I'm not doing
at all well.
PLIMSOLL: Sir Wilfrid!
Sir Wilfrid!
You're dawdling again.
Oh, shut up!
Sorry, Mayhew.
Try me again some day
when you've something
not too stimulating,
like a postman
bitten by a stray dog.
Well, I wish you could
help us, Wilfrid,
but I quite understand.
Take care of yourself.
Mayhew! Mayhew!
CARTER: Oh, no.
Sir Wilfrid, please.
Don't worry, Carter,
we won't take the brief,
but Mr. Mayhew's an old friend
and he needs help.
Surely I can give him
a word of advice.
C-Come on, Mayhew,
I'll give you five minutes.
No, no, no, I don't want you,
just Mayhew.
Our nap!
Sir Wilfrid,
our nap!
You go ahead.
Start it without me.
This is your fault,
Mr. Carter.
You should not
have permitted it.
It is not
my fault.
I distinctly
told Sir Wilfrid,
"No criminal cases."
Well, if it's anyone's fault,
I expect it's mine.
Seems silly to me,
but Mr. Mayhew thinks
it's very urgent.
He, uh, he thinks I may
be arrested at any minute.
Arrested for what?
Well, for murder.
Oh.
It's the case
of Mrs. Emily French.
You've probably
seen the reports
in the press.
She was a middle-aged widow,
rather well-off,
living with a housekeeper
at Hampstead.
Mr. Vole had been
with her earlier
in the evening.
When the housekeeper
returned from her day off,
she found her mistress dead,
struck on the back
of the head and killed.
I see.
Vole seems a harmless chap
caught in a web
of circumstantial evidence.
Perhaps if I were to give you
some more of the details,
you might suggest
the strongest line of defense.
I'd probably think
better if you gave me
one of those cigars.
Of course.
There are no previous
convictions, naturally.
He's a man of good character
with an excellent war record.
You'd like him a lot.
They've confiscated
the matches, too.
A light, please.
Give me a light.
As I see it,
the defense may turn
on establishing an alibi
for the night of the murder.
I'm sorry,
I haven't got any matches.
Let me get you some.
Lord, no.
You don't know
Miss Plimsoll.
This will take
all our cunning.
Young man,
you come here, please.
Uh, your solicitor and I
feel you may be able
to enlighten me
on a rather
important point.
Why, yes.
Thank you.
Really, Sir Wilfrid!
You're not in bed yet?
Upstairs!
Give me a match.
I'm sorry.
I never carry them.
What? You said
I'd like him.
But I do have
a lighter.
You're quite right, Mayhew,
I do like him.
Thank you.
Can you imagine
Miss Plimsoll's face
if she saw me now?
Then let's make
absolutely sure
that she doesn't.
Splendid.
With all the instincts
of a skilled criminal.
Thank you, sir.
Here.
Young man, you may
or may not have murdered
a middle-aged widow,
but you've certainly
saved the life
of an elderly barrister.
(LAUGHING) I haven't
murdered anybody.
It's absurd.
Christine, that's my wife,
she thought
I may be implicated,
and that I needed a lawyer.
That's why I went
to see Mr. Mayhew.
Now he thinks
he needs a lawyer,
and now I have two lawyers.
It's rather silly,
don't you...
Mr. Vole, I am a solicitor,
Sir Wilfrid is a barrister.
Only a barrister
can actually plead
a case in court.
LEONARD: Oh, I see.
She shall not even
find the ashes.
Sit down.
Oh, thank you.
Well, I saw in the paper
that poor Mrs. French
had been found dead
with her head bashed in.
And it also said
in the papers
that the police were anxious
to interview me,
since I'd visited Mrs. French
that evening, so...
Well, naturally I went along
to the police station.
Did they caution you?
(SIGHS)
I--I don't quite know.
They...
They asked me
if I'd like to make
a statement,
and said that they'd
write it down,
and that it might be used
against me in court.
Would that be cautioning me?
Oh, well, it can't
be helped now.
Well, they were very polite
and they seemed
quite satisfied.
They seemed satisfied,
Mr. Vole.
He thinks that he made
a statement and that's
the end of it.
Isn't it obvious
to you, Mr. Vole,
that you will be regarded
as the principal
and logical suspect
in this case?
I'm very much afraid
you'll be arrested.
But I've done nothing!
Why should I be arrested?
I mean, this is England,
you don't get arrested
or convicted for something
you haven't done!
We try not to make
a habit of it.
But it does happen
though, doesn't it?
Of course.
There was the case
of that fellow,
what's his name,
Adolph Beck or Becker.
He'd been in jail
for eight years,
and they suddenly found
it was another chap,
altogether.
He'd been innocent
all along.
Very unfortunate,
but restitution
has been made.
He received a free pardon,
a bounty from the Crown,
and was restored
to his normal life.
LEONARD: Yes,
that's all right for him.
But what if it had
been murder?
What if he'd been hanged?
How would they have
restored him
to his normal life then, huh?
Mr. Vole, you must not take
such a morbid point of view.
I'm sorry.
It's just when you tell me
that all these things
are closing in on me,
it's like a nightmare.
Relax, Mr. Vole.
I'm putting you
in the hands of the finest
and most experienced
barrister in London.
Now, Mayhew,
let's get this straight.
I may have done
something highly unethical.
I've taken your cigar
and I'm not taking your case.
I can't.
I'm forbidden.
My doctors would
never allow it.
I'm truly sorry,
young man.
However, if you'd like
the case handled
by someone in these chambers,
I'd recommend
Mr. Brogan-Moore.
You know Brogan-Moore.
Yes, I do,
a very able man.
I second Sir Wilfrid's
recommendation.
All right, sir,
if you say so.
Hold this.
Carter?
Yes, sir?
I would like to see
Brogan-Moore here,
as soon as he comes in
from court.
Very well.
Sir Wilfrid,
I have never known
such insubordination.
No, not even when I was
a nurse in the front lines
during the war.
What war was that?
The Crimean War,
no doubt.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
You'll like Brogan-Moore.
He's had excellent training,
under me.
This morning I had
no lawyers at all.
And now, suddenly,
I have three lawyers.
Perhaps we should
explain to Sir Wilfrid
that I have very
little money.
I shan't be able
to pay all the costs
and fees.
Don't worry,
we will get a fourth
lawyer to sue you.
Well, you won't get
very much, I'm afraid.
I haven't had a job
in four months.
What sort of work
do you do?
Well, uh...
My last job was as
a mechanic with a--
with a motor servicing firm.
The--The foreman
kept riding me all the time.
I took it as long as I could,
and then I--I quit.
WILFRID: And before that?
I worked in a department store
in toys,
uh, demonstrating
children's building sets.
Of course,
that lasted only during
the Christmas rush.
And before that,
I had a job
testing electric blankets.
Electric blankets?
I suppose you're
thinking I'm a bit
of a drifter, sir.
Well, it's true
in a way, but I'm--
I'm really not like that.
Doing my army service
unsettled me a bit.
That and living abroad.
I was stationed in Germany.
It was fine there, though.
That's where I met Christine,
my wife.
She was an actress,
and a good one.
Ah, she's a wonderful wife
to me, too,
but I haven't been
much of a provider,
I'm afraid.
Somehow or other,
I--I just don't seem to be
able to settle down
now that I've come back
to this country.
Of course, if--if
I could just put
my eggbeater across...
Eggbeater?
(LAUGHING) Yes, sir. I, ah,
I'm a bit of an inventor.
Nothing big,
just little household things,
pocket pencil sharpeners,
key-chain flashlights
and that sort of thing.
But my best is really
this eggbeater.
You see, it not only
beats the egg,
but it also separates
the yolk from the white.
Is that really desirable?
LEONARD: If you were
a housewife, Sir Wilfrid,
you'd see it right away.
The only trouble is
that I need money
for manufacturing
and promotion.
I was really hoping
that that's what Mrs. French
might do for me
after I met her.
Oh.
Exactly how did you meet
this Mrs. French?
Well, that's rather funny
in itself.
It was the third of September
I remember distinctly
because it's my
wife's birthday.
I was window-shopping
on Oxford Street,
just sort of...
Daydreaming about
what I'd buy for her,
if I had any money.
(POLICE WHISTLE BLOWING)
You really like
this one?
Oh, very much.
You don't think
it's too, uh, mad?
Mad? Not at all.
A little daring,
perhaps.
I wouldn't recommend it
to every woman.
But you,
why shouldn't you attract
some attention?
Oh, you really
think so?
Absolutely. But if I could
suggest one little thing.
Yes?
Perhaps we could tip it
and bring it back
a bit like that.
Show more of your face.
There.
Oh, my bus.
Goodbye.
Oh, good...
You buy that hat.
I insist.
LEONARD: Actually, it was a...
A ridiculous sort of hat.
A silly thing with ribbons
and flowers.
I'm constantly surprised
that women's hats
do not provoke more murders.
(COUGHING) Go on, please.
Well, I was only trying
to be nice to her,
to make her feel good.
I never dreamed
that I'd see her again,
or the hat.
But you did?
Yes, a few weeks later.
Again, quite by accident.
I was peddling
my eggbeaters
that afternoon
and business
was a little slow...
(GUNS FIRING)
Would you mind, madam.
Your hat!
Oh, it's you!
Hello!
It's your fault, you know,
you chose it yourself.
May I?
Sure, if you like.
(GUNS FIRING)
Thank you.
It's such a bother
taking it off
and putting it
back on again.
That chap on the white horse
is called Jesse James.
Those others have led him
into this ambush.
It's not at all cricket.
Don't worry, Mr. James
shoots his way out.
Oh, he does?
I've seen it before.
I go to the movies
quite a lot.
You do?
Oh, I get so restless at home,
so I go out,
and then I find
I've really no place to go,
so I go to the movies.
Sometimes I see the same one
two or three times.
Ooh!
Toffee?
Oh, yes, please.
At this time
you had no idea
that Mrs. French
was well-off?
No, no,
absolutely not.
We were sitting
in the cheap seats.
All I knew was
that she seemed
to be very lonely,
had no friends
whatsoever.
She and her husband
had lived abroad
for many years,
in British Nigeria.
He was in
the colonial service.
He died in '45,
of a heart attack.
Please, Mayhew,
not while I'm smoking.
Go on, young man.
Well, they finally
polished off Jesse James,
and after we left the movie,
she invited me
to her house for tea.
(EMILY LAUGHING)
Oh!
I think it's the most
fascinating thing
I've ever seen.
Janet, come
and look at this!
I've seen eggbeaters
before, ma'am.
Oh, but this beats
so quickly
and it separates, too.
Ah, ah, it must
be centrifucal.
Or centrifugal,
which is it?
Actually,
it's specific gravity,
but it whips cream, too.
Oh, did you hear
that, Janet?
It whips cream, too.
Ah!
We must have one.
Is it expensive?
Compliments
of the inventor, manufacturer
and sole distributor.
Oh, thank you.
We'll use it constantly.
Won't we, Janet?
Uh, come, Mr. Vole.
We'd better
get out of here.
Janet doesn't like visitors
in her kitchen.
(GIGGLING)
Hah!
Oh, it's a bit chilly
in here, isn't it?
Shall we have a fire?
Why not?
Now, this is
a charming room.
Hubert and I collected
all these things
when we lived
in Africa.
(SIGHS) Hubert was
my husband.
Well, now,
there's a lovable chap.
That's the mask
of the witch doctor.
He always wore it
when he pulled
our servants' teeth,
so Hubert used to call him
a witch dentist.
(LAUGHS)
Hubert was so witty.
Yes, I can see that.
Oh, here's tea.
Janet, let's use our good
silver and china.
(SIGHS)
Oh, no, don't bother,
Mrs. French,
this is perfectly
all right.
Lemon or milk, please?
Oh, I don't really care.
Would you prefer
some sherry?
Sherry would be fine.
We've not got any sherry.
Oh, but we have.
There's that bottle,
the one we bought
last Christmas.
If you care
for an eggnog,
there happens to be
a wasted egg in the kitchen,
all ready and separated.
Do sit down.
And don't mind Janet,
Mr. Vole.
It's just that
she's terribly Scotch.
Oh, is she?
I thought she came
with the collection.
(LAUGHS)
You know,
maybe I'll take a glass
of sherry myself.
I feel like Christmas,
somehow.
(GIGGLES)
LEONARD: After that,
I used to see her
once or twice a week.
She always kept a bottle
of sherry for me.
We'd talk a bit,
play canasta,
listen to her old
gramophone records,
Gilbert and Sullivan mostly.
It's so weird to think
of her now
lying in that living room,
murdered.
I assure you
she's been moved by now.
To leave her around
would be unfeeling,
unlawful and unsanitary.
MAYHEW: Suppose you tell
Sir Wilfrid about the evening
of the murder.
Well, I went around
to see her about 8:00
that evening.
She fixed me a sandwich,
we talked a bit,
listened to The Mikado.
I left about 9:00.
I walked home.
I got there about half-past.
I can prove that,
I can swear to it
in or out of court,
in the witness box,
anywhere.
How much money
did you get from her?
From whom?
From Mrs. French.
Nothing, not a quid.
The truth. How much?
Why should she give me
any money?
Because she was
in love with you.
That's ridiculous.
She liked me.
She--She pampered me
like--like an aunt.
But that's all, I swear!
Why didn't you tell her
you were a married man?
I did tell her.
But you never took
your wife along
when you went there, did you?
No, I didn't.
Why not?
Well, because...
Because what?
Because Mrs. French
was under the impression
Christine and I didn't
get along too well.
Is that true?
No, we love each other!
Then how did she get
that impression?
Did you give it to her?
No, she just seemed
to want to believe it
that way.
But you never corrected
that impression? Why?
Well, I was afraid
she'd lose interest in me.
Because she was rich?
Yes, I suppose so.
And you were after
her money.
Well, yes, in a way.
I was hoping for a loan
for my new invention.
Just a couple
of hundred pounds.
An honest business
proposition,
that's all it would have been.
Is that so wicked?
You knew it was
the housekeeper's day off?
Well, yes, I did.
So you went there
because you knew
she'd be alone?
No, I went there
because I thought
she might be lonely.
All right, lonely.
You and the rich,
lonely widow
all alone in that lonely house
with the gramophone
blaring The Mikado.
Perhaps you turned
up the volume
to drown out her cries.
No, when I left her
she was alive!
But when the housekeeper
came back, she was dead.
The house had been ransacked,
it said so in the papers.
It must have been a burglar.
Look, I didn't do it.
No matter how bad things look,
I didn't do it!
You must believe me!
You do believe me,
don't you?
I do now,
but I wasn't sure.
That's why I subjected
your eyes and my arteries
to that ordeal.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
As for things looking bad,
they don't look bad, Mr. Vole,
they look terrible.
Apparently,
you've no alibi at all.
I have. I left
Mrs. French's at 9:00.
How did you go home,
by bus or underground?
No, I walked.
It was a fine night.
Did anyone see you?
Yes, of course,
Christine saw me
when I got home.
It was 9:26 exactly.
I know because
I went right to work
on this new sort
of clock thing
that I've been
tinkering with.
My wife
will tell you that.
Your wife loves you,
does she not?
Very much.
And I love her.
We're devoted
to each other.
Of course, you realize,
Mr. Vole,
that the testimony
of a devoted wife
does not carry
much weight.
You mean people might think
Christine would tell a lie
on my account?
It has been known,
Mr. Vole.
Blood is thicker
than evidence.
WILFRID: Ah, Brogan-Moore,
come in, come in.
So good to have you out
of hospital.
I didn't get
a full pardon,
I'm out on parole.
You know Mr. Mayhew,
I believe.
This is his client,
Mr. Leonard Vole.
How do you do?
The Emily French murder.
Oh, how do you do?
Badly, thank you.
There's a mass
of circumstantial evidence,
no alibi whatsoever.
It's a hot potato.
Tossing it
right into your lap.
(CHUCKLING) Much obliged.
Your line of defense, however,
will be lack of motive.
You will agree that
we can rule out
a crime of passion, hmm?
That leaves us
with a murder for profit.
Now then,
if Mr. Vole had been
sponging on Mrs. French,
why kill her and cut off
the source of supply?
Or, if he'd been hoping
for a golden egg,
why kill the goose
before it was laid?
No motive.
No motive whatsoever!
You find some flaw
in this line of reasoning?
No, no, it's very sound,
as far as it goes.
Well, it's all yours,
Brogan-Moore.
You'll find Mr. Vole
very responsive
and quite candid.
So candid, in fact,
he's already informed me
we'll have to sue him
for our fees.
Oh, we'll simply put a lien
on Mr. Vole's 680,000.
What 680,000?
The 680,000
Mrs. French left you.
Left me?
They opened Mrs. French's
bank vault today
and found her will.
Congratulations!
680,000!
And I was worried
about a couple of hundred
for that silly eggbeater
of mine, and now...
I must call Christine.
Oh.
This inheritance doesn't
make things look any better
for me though, does it?
No. I wouldn't think so.
So now they'll say
that I did have a motive.
They will, indeed.
680,000 makes
for a very handsome motive.
I thought you were crazy,
but I guess now
they will arrest me,
won't they?
It's not unlikely.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
As a matter of fact,
it's quite likely.
They're on their way up, now.
Look, I knew nothing
about that will.
I had no idea that
Mrs. French
had any intention
of leaving me her money.
And if I didn't know about it,
how could it be a motive?
Mr. Brogan-Moore
will certainly bring
that out in court.
It's our old friend,
Inspector Hearne.
Chief Inspector,
as of last month.
Chief Inspector!
They must think a lot of you
at Scotland Yard.
You're getting
the de luxe treatment.
Oh, in here,
Chief Inspector.
Sorry to disturb you
in your chambers,
Sir Wilfrid.
That's perfectly
all right.
I never object
to the actions
of the police,
except once in a great while
in court.
Yes, sir.
I still have the scars.
You know Mr. Mayhew,
Mr. Brogan-Moore.
This is dangerous
Leonard Vole.
You'd better search him,
he may be armed
with an eggbeater.
INSPECTOR: Is your name
Leonard Vole?
Yes, it is.
I have here a warrant
for your arrest
on the charge
of murdering Emily French
on October the 14th, last.
I must warn you
that anything you say
may be taken down
and used in evidence.
Well, I'm ready.
But must I be handcuffed?
That won't be necessary, sir.
See, I've never been
arrested before,
not even for walking
a dog off a lead
or having a beer
after hours.
There's no disgrace
in being arrested, Mr. Vole.
Kings, prime ministers,
archbishops, even barristers
have stood in the dock.
Somebody better call
my wife and tell her
where they're taking me.
I will,
don't worry.
I'll go to the station
with you and see that
you're properly charged.
You will see to it
that Mr. Vole
is well treated?
We will.
Would you like a cigar?
Pardon me.
That's very kind of you,
Sir Wilfrid.
I'd better not.
It would constitute
a bribe.
(SIGHS)
We ought to be going,
Mr. Vole.
Well, there's one thing
I've learned for sure,
never look in a window
where there are women's hats.
Good day, sir.
Makes a very nice impression,
doesn't he?
Yes, rather.
Did you give him
the monocle test?
Passed with flying colors.
Yes, I hope he does
as well in the dock.
Yeah.
This is sticky,
you know?
Of course it is.
The prosecution will blast him
with their heaviest artillery.
All you'll have
is one little popgun,
an alibi furnished
by his wife.
Isn't that
an intriguing challenge?
I think I'd like it more
if it was less
of a challenge
and less intriguing.
Sorry, Sir Wilfrid,
but Miss Plimsoll
has issued
an ultimatum,
if you're not in bed
in one minute,
she will resign.
Splendid.
Give her a month's pay
and kick her
down the stairs.
Sir Wilfrid,
either you take proper
care of yourself
or I, too,
shall resign.
This is blackmail.
But you're quite right,
Carter.
For my first day,
this has already
been rather hectic.
I should be in bed.
Ah.
Oh, I'd-- I'd better
get in touch with Mrs. Vole
and have her come over.
Will you sit in?
Thank you, no.
I'm in no condition
to cope with emotional wives
drenched in tears.
Ah, Miss Plimsoll,
how alluring you look!
Waiting like a hangman
on the scaffold.
Take me, I'm yours.
Oh, uh, about Mrs. Vole,
handle her gently,
especially when
you break the news
of the arrest.
Bear in mind,
she's a foreigner,
so be prepared
for hysterics
and even a fainting spell.
Better have smelling
salts ready,
a box of tissues
and a nip of brandy.
WOMAN: I do not think
that will be necessary.
I never faint
because I'm not sure that
I will fall gracefully,
and I never use smelling salts
because they puff up the eyes.
I am Christine Vole.
How do you do?
This is Mr. Brogan-Moore.
I am Wilfrid Robarts.
How do you do?
My dear Mrs. Vole,
I'm afraid we have
rather bad news for you.
Don't be afraid,
Sir Wilfrid.
I'm quite disciplined.
There's nothing
to be alarmed about as yet.
Leonard has been arrested
and charged with murder,
is that it?
Yes.
I knew he would be.
I told him so.
I'm glad you're showing
such fortitude.
Call it what you like.
What is the next step?
Your husband
will have to stand trial,
I'm afraid.
Will you take
Mrs. Vole inside
and explain the procedure?
Mr. Brogan-Moore
will lead the defense.
Oh?
You will not personally
defend Leonard?
Regrettably, not.
My health,
or rather the lack of it,
forbids me.
It is regrettable.
Mr. Mayhew described you
as the champion
of the hopeless cause.
Is it perhaps
that this cause
is too hopeless?
I shall have
a very serious talk
with Dr. Harrison.
It was a mistake
to let you come back here.
I should've taken you
directly to a rest home
or a resort.
Some place quiet,
far off, like Bermuda.
Shut up.
You just want to see me
in those nasty shorts.
Come, now, Sir Wilfrid.
You must not
think of it.
You must get ready
for sleep.
Think beautiful
thoughts.
Now, let's get undressed.
Put these on,
tops and the bottoms,
while I make your bed.
Now, after your rest,
we'll have a nice cup
of cocoa,
and then perhaps
we'll have a walk
around the square.
You know, I feel sorry
for that nice Mr. Vole.
And not just because
he was arrested,
but that wife of his,
she must be German.
I suppose that's
what happens
when we let our boys
cross the channel,
they go crazy.
Personally,
I think the government
should do something
about those foreign wives,
like an embargo.
How else can we take care
of our own surplus?
Don't you agree,
Sir Wilfrid?
All right, hop in.
Sir Wilfrid!
Come back!
Yes, of course I knew
that Leonard
had been seeing Mrs. French
quite frequently.
Go on, go on.
I knew it from the day
when he came home
with a pair of green socks
she had knitted for him.
Well, that's quite natural.
I'm sure the jury will find it
rather endearing.
Oh, Leonard can be
very endearing.
He hates that particular
shade of green
and the socks were two sizes
too large,
but he wore them
just the same,
just to give her pleasure.
Leonard has a way
with women.
I only hope he will have
an all-woman jury.
They will carry him
from the courtroom in triumph.
(CHUCKLING) A simple
acquittal will do.
Now, Mrs. Vole,
you know that Mrs. French
left your husband money?
Yes, a lot of money.
Of course, your husband
had no previous knowledge
of this bequest.
Is that what he told you?
Well, surely, Mrs. Vole,
you're not suggesting
anything different?
Oh, no. No.
I do not suggest anything.
Quite obviously, Mrs. French
had come to look
upon your husband
as a son or, perhaps,
a favorite nephew.
You think Mrs. French
looked upon Leonard
as a son or a nephew?
I do. An entirely natural
and understandable
relationship.
What hypocrites
you are in this country.
Pardon me,
Brogan-Moore.
Mrs. Vole, do you mind
if I ask you a question?
Go right ahead,
Sir Wilfrid.
Mrs. Vole, you realize
your husband's entire defense
rests on his word and yours.
I realize that.
And that the jury
will be quite skeptical
of the word of a man
accused of murder
when supported only
by the word of his wife?
I realize that, too.
Let us then at least
make sure that the two
are not in conflict.
CHRISTINE: By all means,
let's.
Mrs. Vole, I assume
you want to help
your husband?
Of course I want
to help Leonard,
I want to help
Mr. Brogan-Moore,
and I want to help you,
Sir Wilfrid.
There.
Isn't that more
comfortable for you?
Now, Mrs. Vole,
this is very important.
On the night of the murder,
your husband came home
before 9:30.
Is that correct?
CHRISTINE: Precisely.
Isn't that what
he wants me to say?
Isn't it the truth?
Of course.
But when I told it
to the police,
I do not think
they believed me.
Maybe I didn't say it well.
Maybe because
of my accent.
My dear Mrs. Vole,
in our courts
we will accept the evidence
of witnesses who speak
only Bulgarian
and who must have
an interpreter.
We will accept the evidence
of deaf-mutes who cannot
speak at all,
as long as they tell
the truth.
You're aware,
of course,
that when I put you
in the witness box,
you will be sworn
and you will testify
under oath?
Yes.
Leonard came home
at 9:26 precisely
and did not go out again.
The truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
Is that better?
Mrs. Vole, do you love
your husband?
Leonard thinks I do.
Well, do you?
Am I already under oath?
Mrs. Vole, whatever
your gambit may be,
do you know
that under British law
you cannot be called
to give testimony
damaging to your husband?
How very convenient.
We are dealing
with a capital crime.
The prosecution will try
to hang your husband.
He is not my husband.
Leonard and I went
through a form of marriage
in Hamburg,
but I had a husband
living at the time,
somewhere in East Germany
in the Russian zone.
Did you tell Leonard?
I did not.
It would have been stupid
to tell him.
He would not
have married me
and I would have
been left behind,
to starve in the rubble.
But he did marry you
and brought you safely
to this country.
Don't you think you should
be very grateful to him?
One can get very tired
of gratitude.
Your husband loves you
very much, does he not?
Leonard?
He worships the ground
I walk on.
And you?
You want to know
too much.
Auf Wiedersehen,
gentlemen.
Thank you for coming in,
Mrs. Vole.
Your visit has been
most reassuring.
Do not worry, Sir Wilfrid.
I will give him an alibi
and I shall be
very convincing.
There will be tears
in my eyes when I say,
"Leonard came home
at 9:26 precisely."
You're a very remarkable
woman, Mrs. Vole.
And you're satisfied,
I hope?
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm damned
if I'm satisfied.
Care to join me
in a whiff of those
smelling salts?
The woman's
up to something,
but what?
The prosecution
will break her
down in no time
when I put her
in the witness box.
You know,
defending this case
is going to be
rather like The Charge
Of The Light Brigade
or one of those Japanese
suicide pilots.
Quite one-sided,
with the odds
all on the other side.
I haven't got
much to go on,
have I?
The fact is,
I've got nothing.
Let me ask you something.
Do you believe
Leonard Vole is innocent?
Do you?
I'm not sure.
Oh, I'm sorry, Wilfrid.
Of course, I'll do my best.
It's all right,
Brogan-Moore.
I'll take it from here.
I have called
Dr. Harrison
and given him
a complete report
on your shocking behavior.
I can no longer...
Give me a match,
Miss Plimsoll.
Sir Wilfrid!
Did you hear me?
A match!
Hello, Mr. Mayhew.
Sir Wilfrid.
Mr. Mayhew tells me
that you are going
to represent me.
I'm very grateful.
I struck a bargain
with my doctors.
I let them exile me
to Bermuda
as soon as
we finish your case.
Thank you.
Let's hope
that we shall
both survive.
Get into these, will you.
We need a photograph.
What for?
Cause these were what
you were wearing
on the night
of the murder.
We want to circulate
a photograph
on the chance
that someone did see you
leaving Mrs. French
on your way home.
Over here
against the wall, please.
Now, hold it.
Now, one more
in profile, please.
I mean, after all,
do we really need this?
My wife knows
what time I came
home that night.
A disinterested witness
may be of more value.
Yes, of course.
Christine is an
interested witness.
I'll pick up
the negatives later,
thank you.
I don't understand it.
Why hasn't she come
to see me?
Won't they
let her see me?
I mean, it's been
two weeks now.
Mayhew, give me
the reports.
Have you been
talking to her?
Is there something
the matter with her?
I want to read you
a portion of the evidence
of Janet McKenzie,
the housekeeper.
"Mr. Vole helped Mrs. French
with her business affairs
"particularly
her income tax returns."
LEONARD: Oh, yes, I did.
Some of those forms
are very complicated.
There's also a hint
you may have helped her
draft her new will.
Oh, that's not true!
If Janet said that,
she's lying!
She was always against me.
I--I don't know why.
Well, it's quite obvious.
You threw an eggbeater
into the wheels
of her Victorian household.
Now, um, what about
this cut on your wrist?
You told the police
you cut yourself with a knife.
Well, that's true. I did.
I was cutting bread
and the knife slipped.
But that was two days
after the murder.
Christine was there.
She'll tell them
when she gives evidence.
Are you keeping
something from me?
Is she ill?
Was she shocked
by what happened to me?
All things considered,
I think she took it very well.
Of course, that may have
only been on the surface.
Wives are often
profoundly disturbed
at such a time.
Yes, it must
be hard on her.
We've never been
separated before
not since
our first meeting.
How did you meet
your wife, Mr. Vole?
In Germany, in 1945.
It's rather funny.
The very first time
I saw her,
the ceiling fell
right in on me.
LEONARD: I was stationed
outside Hamburg,
with an RAF
Maintenance unit.
I'd just installed
a shower in the
officers' billet,
so they gave me
a weekend pass.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN CHEERING)
CHRISTINE:
♫Come on, join the party
♫Have a hearty glass of rum
♫Don't ever think
about tomorrow
♫For tomorrow
may never come
♫When I find me a happy place
♫That's where I wanna stay
♫Time is nothing
♫As long as I'm living it
♫Up this way
♫I may
♫Never go home anymore
♫Dim the lights and
start locking the door
♫Give your arms to me
♫Give your charms to me
♫After all,
that's what sailors are for
♫I've got
♫Kisses and kisses galore
♫That have never
been tasted before
♫If you treat me right
♫This could be the night
♫I may never go home
CROWD: ♫I may never go home
♫I may never go home anymore
(CHEERING)
♫I may never go
home anymore ♫
Hey, Fraulein,
show us some legs!
(MEN LAUGHING)
They rob
you blind,
and then call you
a ruddy sailor.
(SHOUTING AGREEMENT)
Come on, let's see 'em!
CROWD: We want legs!
MAN: Throw out
the camouflage.
(LAUGHING)
All right,
Fraulein,
if you won't
show 'em, I will!
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(GLASS BREAKING)
Hey!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ALL HOLLERING)
All right.
All right,
outside everybody.
Come on, let's go!
(POLICEMAN SHOUTING)
POLICEMAN: All right,
come on.
Bring 'em round there,
on the front.
MAN: We'll be back, baby,
we'll be back.
LEONARD: Gesundheit.
What are you looking for?
My accordion.
Oh, let me help you.
(ACCORDION TRILL PLAYING)
I think I found it.
Step on it again,
it's still breathing.
(ACCORDION PLAYING)
I'm terribly sorry.
You'd better
get out of here.
We've had
trouble enough.
Actually,
it's your own fault.
That costume
in the picture outside
gave the boys ideas,
and then
those trousers of yours
let them down hard.
That costume went on
the first raid on Hamburg.
Then, raid by raid,
the rest of my dresses,
and now you've bombed
my trousers.
Cigarette? Gum?
You're burning
my nose.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's all right.
How about
a cup of coffee?
I've got a tin of coffee.
How much?
Well, I don't know.
What's the rate
of exchange?
Depends whether
it's fresh coffee
or powdered...
It's instant coffee.
Ooh.
Got any hot water
at your place?
Sometimes.
Let's take a chance.
Where do you live?
Nearby.
Come.
Sorry, it's the maid's
night off.
This is pretty
horrible,
in a gemutlich
sort of way.
Oh, it's fine now.
I used to have
a roommate.
A dancer. She had luck.
She married a Canadian.
She now
lives in Toronto.
She has
a Ford automobile.
You better make yourself
comfortable.
The stove is slow
these days.
Oh, that's all right.
I've got a weekend pass.
No, no,
not that chair.
It holds up the beam
and that holds up
half the ceiling.
You'd better sit down
on the cot.
The cot?
It's getting
more gemutlich
all the time.
Are you married?
Why?
Well, the, uh...
Oh, that.
No, no, I'm not married,
I just wear it
when I'm working.
It gives me
a little protection
with all the men.
Didn't work
too well tonight,
though, did it?
No. Tonight was bad.
But it's getting better.
Where's the coffee?
Ahh, coffee, jawohl.
The finest Brazilian blend.
The same brand
that Field Marshal
Montgomery drinks.
Is that a fair rate
of exchange?
Very fair.
Would, uh...
Would you be interested
in having the whole tin?
I would.
How're you fixed
for sugar?
I could use some.
Milk?
Sure.
Milk, sugar.
It is a pleasure
to do business with you.
Yeah.
I also carry, uh...
Biscuits, powdered eggs,
bacon, marmalade.
I don't know
if I can afford it.
Don't worry.
We'll work out
something like
an installment plan.
♫I may never
go home anymore ♫
(CRASHING)
Oh, I'm--
I'm terribly sorry.
Now you have no ceiling.
Well, maybe I can fix it.
I'm good at it.
Why fix it?
It's not raining.
Ooh.
Are you all right?
Yes, I think so.
My head aches a little.
Maybe I can fix it.
I'm good at it.
I had a weekend pass,
a month's pay
in my pocket...
And she already
had a wedding ring?
Yes, that's right.
So we got married,
and as soon as I got
out of the service,
I brought her to England.
Oh, it was wonderful.
I rented a little flat
on Edgware road.
The first time she saw it,
Christine was so happy
she broke down and cried.
Naturally,
she had a solid roof
over her head and
a British passport.
You don't
really know Christine,
and how she feels
about me,
but you will
when she gives
her evidence.
Mr. Vole,
I must tell you
I am not putting her
in the witness box.
You're not? Why not?
Well, for one thing,
she's a foreigner,
not too familiar
with the subtleties
of our language.
The prosecution
could easily
trip her up.
I hear it may be Mr. Myers
for the crown.
And we can't
take chances with him.
Quite. Well,
we'd better be going.
Miss Plimsoll
is waiting in the car
with her pills
and a thermos
of lukewarm cocoa.
Officer.
But Christine
must give evidence.
Mr. Vole, you must
learn to trust me.
If for no other
reason than that
I'm a mean,
ill-tempered old man
who hates to lose.
Let us
wish each other luck.
But I can't face
this without Christine.
I tell you,
I'm scared.
I need her.
Without her, I'm sunk.
Touching, isn't it?
The way he counts
on his wife.
Yes.
Like a drowning man
clutching at a razor blade.
CLERK: Leonard Stephen Vole,
you are charged
on indictment
for that you,
on the 14th day of October,
in the county
of London,
murdered
Emily Jane French.
How say you,
Leonard Stephen Vole?
Are you guilty
or not guilty?
Not guilty.
Members of the jury,
the prisoner
stands indicted
for that he
on the 14th day of October
murdered
Emily Jane French.
To this indictment
he has pleaded,
"Not guilty,"
and it is your
charge to say,
having heard
the evidence,
whether he be guilty
or not.
Members of the jury,
by the oath
which you have just taken,
you have sworn
to try this case
on the evidence.
You must shut out
from your minds
everything except
what will take
place in this court.
You may proceed
for the prosecution,
Mr. Myers.
May it please you,
my Lord.
Members of the jury,
I appear in this case
with my learned
friend, Mr. Barton,
for the prosecution.
And my learned friends,
Sir Wilfrid Robarts
and Mr. Brogan-Moore,
appear for the defense.
I trust we are not
to be deprived
of the learned
and stimulating presence
of Sir Wilfrid.
Ah, my Lord, may I assure
my learned friend
of the prosecution
that Sir Wilfrid is
in the Old Bailey.
He's slightly
incapacitated,
but he'll be
in his seat presently.
My Lord,
may I express my regret
that Sir Wilfrid
is even slightly
incapacitated?
You may, Mr. Myers.
You may also proceed
with the case
for the prosecution.
Thank you, my Lord.
Uh, the facts in this case
are simple
and to a point,
not in dispute.
You will hear
how the prisoner
made the acquaintance
of Mrs. Emily French,
a woman of 56.
How he was treated
by her with kindness
and even affection.
On the night of
October the 14th last,
between 9:30 and 10:00,
Mrs. French was murdered.
Medical testimony
will be introduced
to prove that
death was caused
by a blow from a blunt
and heavy instrument.
And it is the case
for the prosecution
that the blow was dealt
by the prisoner,
Leonard Vole.
That's not true.
I didn't do it!
(ALL MURMURING)
Among the
witnesses, you will hear
police evidence,
also, the evidence
of Mrs. French's housekeeper,
Janet McKenzie,
and from the medical
and laboratory experts,
and the evidence
of the murdered
woman's solicitor,
who drew her final will.
I will now call
Chief Inspector Hearne,
Criminal Investigation
Department,
New Scotland Yard.
USHER: Chief Inspector
Hearne.
POLICEMAN:
Chief Inspector Hearne.
(MURMURING)
This is ridiculous.
Just a bit
of nervous heartburn.
I always get it
the first day of a trial.
240 above 130?
You shouldn't
be here at all.
I should be
in the courtroom.
The trial's begun.
Syringe, please.
Be a good, brave boy,
Sir Wilfrid.
Miss Plimsoll,
it may interest you
to know
that I am descended
from a warrior family,
which traces
its brave past
back to Richard
the Lion-Hearted.
(GASPING)
You're to have
a calcium injection daily,
a tranquillizing pill
every hour.
I'll set
my wristwatch alarm.
In case of
a sudden pain or
shortness of breath,
pop one of these
nitroglycerine
tablets
from the black box
under your tongue.
Oh, and
I'll leave you some
drops for...
Yes, th-that's
enough, Doctor.
The judge will be asking
for a saliva test.
Carter!
I'd better take
that thermos
of cocoa with me.
Helps me
wash down the pills.
Now, let me see it,
please.
My learned patient
is not above substituting
brandy for cocoa.
(SNIFFING)
It is cocoa.
So sorry.
If you were a woman,
Miss Plimsoll,
I would strike you.
Take care of this,
Carter.
Now, Sir Wilfrid,
in the courtroom,
you must avoid
over-excitement.
Yes, Doctor, yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes.
DOCTOR: Watch your temper.
Keep both your voice
and your blood pressure down.
Thank you, doctor.
I shall be quite safe,
what with the pills
and the cocoa.
Come along, Carter.
From the body temperature
and other factors,
we placed the time of death
at between 9:30
and 10:00 p.m.
approximately 30 minutes
before Janet McKenzie,
the housekeeper,
returned home
and called us.
Death was instantaneous
caused by one blow
from a heavy
and blunt instrument.
MYERS:
Were there any signs
of a struggle?
HEARNE:
None. Just the one blow.
Would that indicate to you
that the murderer
had taken Mrs. French
by surprise?
My Lord, I must object.
My learned friend
refers to the assailant
as the murderer.
We have
not yet determined
whether the assailant
was a man or a woman.
It could quite conceivably
have been the murderess.
Mr. Myers, it seems that
Sir Wilfrid has joined us
just in time to catch you
on a point of grammar.
Please rephrase
your question.
Yes, my Lord.
Uh, Inspector,
is it your opinion
that the assailant
whether he, she or it
had taken Mrs. French
by surprise?
My Lord,
I am taken by surprise
that my learned friend
should attempt
to solicit
from the witness
an opinion
and not a fact.
Quite so. You'll have
to do better than that,
Mr. Myers.
My Lord, I withdraw
the question entirely.
Is that better?
That's much better.
(CROWD MURMURING)
USHER: Silence.
Silence!
(GAVEL BANGING)
MYERS: Very well, Inspector,
let us proceed
with the facts in the case.
After establishing the cause
and the time of death,
what did you then do?
A search was made,
photographs were taken,
and the premises
were fingerprinted.
What fingerprints
did you discover?
I found
the fingerprints
of Mrs. French,
those
of Janet McKenzie,
and some,
which later proved to be
those of Leonard Vole.
MYERS: No others?
No others.
Now, did you say
that the room
had the appearance
that a robbery
had been committed?
Yes.
Things were strewn about
and the window
had been broken
near the catch.
There was glass
on the floor
and fragments
were found outside.
The glass outside
was not consistent
with the window
having been forced
from the outside.
What you are saying
is that someone attempted
to make it look
as if the window
had been forced
from the outside,
isn't that so?
My Lord, I must object.
My learned friend
is putting words
in the witness' mouth.
After all,
if he insists on answering
his own questions,
the presence
of the witness
would seem superfluous.
Quite.
Don't you think so,
Mr. Myers?
MYERS: Yes, my Lord.
Inspector,
did you ascertain
if any of
the murdered woman's
property was missing?
According to the housekeeper,
nothing was missing.
In your experience,
Inspector,
when burglars
or burglaresses
break into a house,
do they leave
without taking anything?
No, sir.
Do you produce
a jacket, Inspector?
Yes, sir.
Is that the jacket?
That is exhibit P1,
my Lord.
Where did you
find this, Inspector?
That is the jacket
found in the prisoner's flat,
which I handed
to our lab to test
for bloodstains.
And did you find
any bloodstains?
Yes, though an attempt
had been made
to wash them out.
What tests
did the laboratory make?
First, to determine
if the stains were made
by human blood,
then to classify it
by group or type.
And was the blood
of a particular
group or type?
Yes, sir.
It is type O.
And did you subsequently test
the blood of the dead woman?
Yes, sir.
What type was that?
The same, type O.
MYERS:
Thank you, Inspector.
No further questions.
Inspector,
you say that
the only fingerprints
you found
were those
of Mrs. French,
Janet McKenzie
and the prisoner,
Leonard Vole.
In your experience,
when a burglar breaks in,
does he usually
leave fingerprints,
or does he
wear gloves?
He wears gloves.
So the absence
of fingerprints
in the case of robbery
would hardly
surprise you?
No, sir.
Can't we then surmise
that the burglar
might have entered
what was presumably
an empty house,
might have
suddenly encountered
Mrs. French and struck her,
then realizing
she was dead,
panicked and fled
without taking anything?
I submit, my Lord,
that it is entirely impossible
to guess what went on
in the mind
of some entirely
imaginary burglar,
uh, with or
without gloves.
Let us not surmise,
Sir Wilfrid,
but confine ourselves
to facts.
Inspector,
when you questioned
the prisoner
as to the stains
on his jacket,
did he not show you
a recently-healed scar
on his wrist,
and tell you that
he had cut himself
with a kitchen knife
while slicing bread?
Yes, sir,
that is what he said.
WILFRID: And were you not
told the same thing
by the prisoner's wife?
Yes, sir,
but afterwards...
Just a simple "yes"
or "no," please.
Did the prisoner's wife
show you a knife,
and tell you
that her husband
had cut his wrist
while slicing bread?
Yes, sir.
I will ask you to examine
this knife, Inspector.
Just test
the edge of it
with your finger.
Carefully!
You, uh, agree
that the point
and the cutting edge
are razor-sharp?
Yes, sir.
Now then,
if such a knife
were to slip,
might it not
inflict a cut
that would bleed
profusely?
Yes, sir, it might.
Now, Inspector,
you have stated
that the bloodstains
on the prisoner's jacket
were analyzed,
as was the blood
of Mrs. French,
and they were both found
to be of the same group,
group O?
That is correct.
However,
if the prisoner's blood
were also
of this same group,
then the stains
on his jacket
might very well
have resulted
from the household accident
he described to you.
Yes, sir.
Did you examine
the prisoner's blood,
Inspector?
No, sir.
I have here a certificate
stating that
Leonard Stephen Vole
is a blood donor
at the North London hospital
and that his blood is
group O.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Thank you, Inspector.
Inspector, granted that
the cut on the wrist
was caused
by that knife,
is there
anything to show
whether it was
an accident
or done deliberately
after the murder
to account for
the bloodstains?
Oh, really,
my Lord!
I withdraw
the question.
You may stand
down, Inspector.
MYERS: Call Janet McKenzie.
Janet McKenzie!
POLICEMAN 2:
I swear
by almighty God
(ALARM BUZZING)
that the evidence
that I shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
(WHISPERING)
Carter! Carter!
Pill! Pill!
MYERS: Your name
is Janet McKenzie?
JANET: Aye,
that's my name.
When did you
first come to London?
That was many years ago.
Twenty eight years ago.
Where do you live?
Now that Mrs. French,
poor soul, is dead,
I've moved in with my niece
at 19 Glenister Road.
Uh, you were
companion-housekeeper
to the late
Mrs. Emily French?
I was her housekeeper.
I've no opinion
of companions
poor, feckless bodies
afraid to do
a bit of honest
domestic work.
Quite.
What I meant was,
you were on
friendly terms
not altogether
those of a mistress
and a servant.
Aye.
Ten years I was with her
and looked after her.
She knew me and
she trusted me.
Ah, many's the time
I prevented her of doing
a foolish thing.
Please tell us,
in your own words,
about the events
of the evening
of October the 14.
It was a Friday
and my night out.
I was going round
to see my niece
at Glenister Road,
which is about
five minutes' walk.
I left the house
at half past seven.
I'd promised to take her
a dress pattern
that she admired.
(GASPING)
Oh, is this thing
necessary?
An excellent
question.
However,
it has been installed
at considerable expense
to the taxpayers,
so let us take
advantage of it.
Please continue.
Well, when I got
to my niece's,
I found I'd left
the pattern behind.
So after supper,
I slipped back to get it,
as it was no distance.
I got back to the house
at 25 past nine.
I let myself in
and I went upstairs
to my room.
As I passed
the sitting room,
I heard the prisoner
in there, talking
to Mrs. French.
No, it wasn't me.
It wasn't my voice!
(CROWD MURMURING)
Talking and laughing
they were,
but it was
no business of mine,
so I went upstairs and
I fetched my pattern.
Now, let us be
very exact as to the time.
You say that
you reentered the house
at 25 past nine?
JANET: Aye, the pattern
was on a shelf in my room
next to my clock,
so I saw the time.
And it was 25 past nine.
MYERS: Go on, please.
I went back
to my niece.
Oh! She was delighted
with her pattern. S...
(SIGHS)
Simply delighted.
I stayed there
until 20 to 11.
And then I said
good night to them
and I come home.
I went into
the sitting room then
to see if the mistress
wanted anything
before she went to bed,
and there she was...
Dead!
And everything tossed
hither and thither.
Did you really think
that a burglary
had been committed?
My Lord, I must protest.
I will not allow
that question
to be answered, Mr. Myers.
Miss McKenzie,
were you aware
that Leonard Vole
was a married man?
No, indeed.
And neither was
the mistress.
Janet!
My Lord, I must object.
What Mrs. French knew
or did not know
is pure conjecture
on Janet McKenzie's part.
Let me put it this way,
you formed the opinion
that Mrs. French
thought Leonard Vole
was a single man?
Have you any facts
to support that opinion?
Well, there were the books
that she ordered.
There was
The Life of Baroness
Burdett-Coutts,
and the one about
Disraeli and his wife
both of them about women
that married men
years younger
than themselves.
Oh, I knew
what she was thinking.
I'm afraid we cannot
admit that.
Why?
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Members of the jury,
it is possible
for a woman to read
The Life of Disraeli
without contemplating
marriage with a man
younger than herself.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Miss McKenzie,
were you aware
of what arrangements
Mrs. French had made
for the disposal
of her money?
She had
her old will revoked
and a new one drawn up.
I heard her
calling Mr. Stokes,
her solicitor.
He was there at the time.
The prisoner, I mean.
You heard Mrs. French
and the prisoner
discussing her new will?
Yes. He was to have
all her money,
she told him,
as she had
no near relations,
nor anybody
that meant to her
what he did.
MYERS: When did this
take place?
On October the 8th,
one week to the day
before she was murdered.
Thank you.
That concludes
my examination.
Ah, not just yet,
Miss McKenzie.
Would you?
Thank you.
Miss McKenzie,
you have given evidence
about two wills.
In the old will,
the will that was revoked,
were you
not to receive the bulk
of Mrs. French's estate?
Aye, that's so.
Whereas
in the new will,
except for a bequest
to you of a small annuity,
the principal beneficiary
is the prisoner,
Leonard Vole?
JANET: It will be
a wicked injustice
if he ever touches a penny
of that money.
It is entirely
understandable
that you are antagonistic
to the prisoner.
Oh, I'm not
antagonistic to him.
He's a shiftless,
scheming rascal,
but I'm not
antagonistic to him.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
I suggest that
you've formed
this opinion
because his friendship
with your mistress
cost you the bulk
of her estate.
I never liked him.
Your candor is refreshing.
Now, on the night
of October the 14th,
you say you heard
the prisoner and Mrs. French
talking together.
What did you
hear them say?
I didn't hear
what they actually said.
You mean you only
heard the voices?
The murmur of voices.
They were laughing.
What makes you say
the man's voice
was Leonard Vole's?
I know his voice
well enough.
WILFRID:
The door was closed,
was it not?
Aye, that's so.
You were no doubt
in a hurry
to get the pattern,
so you probably
walked quickly
past the closed door,
yet you are sure
you heard
Leonard Vole's voice?
I was there long enough
to hear what I heard.
Come, Miss McKenzie,
I'm sure you don't
wish to suggest
to the jury
that you were
eavesdropping.
I know it was him
in there with her.
Who else
could it have been?
Exactly. What you mean is
you wanted it to be him.
That's the way
your mind worked.
Now, tell me, did Mrs. French
sometimes watch television
in the evening?
JANET:
Yes, she was fond of a talk
or a good play.
Wasn't it possible
on the evening
when you returned home
and passed the door,
that what you really heard
was the television,
and a man and woman's
voices and laughter?
There was a play
called Lover's Leap
on the television
that night.
It was not the television.
Oh, why not?
Because the television
was away
being repaired that week.
That's why.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
(CHATTERING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
USHER: Silence.
Silence!
Odd.
It's not time yet.
If my learned friend
has no further questions,
I would like to...
I have not
quite finished.
You are registered,
are you not,
under the
National Health
Insurance act?
Aye, that's so.
Four and sixpence
I pay out every week.
Ach, that's
a terrible lot
of money
for a working woman
to pay.
WILFRID:
I am sure that many
agree with you.
Now then, Miss McKenzie,
did you recently apply to
the National Health Insurance
for...
A hearing aid?
F-f-f-for what?
My Lord, I must protest
against the manner
in which this question
is being put.
I will repeat
the question,
my Lord.
I asked you, in a normal
tone of voice,
audible to everyone
in open court
did you apply to
the National Health Insurance
for a hearing aid?
Yes, I did.
Did you get it?
No, not yet.
However, you state that
you walked past a door
which is four inches
of solid oak,
you heard voices
and you are willing to swear
that you could distinguish
the voice of...
(SPEAKING SOFTLY)
the prisoner,
Leonard Vole.
Wh-who? Wh...
(CROWD MURMURING)
No further questions.
JANET: Ach, maybe
you could help me,
your Lordship.
Six months ago, I applied
for my hearing aid
and I'm still
waiting for it!
My dear Miss McKenzie,
considering the rubbish
that is being talked
nowadays,
you are missing
very little.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
You may stand down now.
USHER: Silence!
MYERS: Call
Police Constable Jeffries.
JEFFRIES:
I swear by almighty God,
that the evidence I shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
JUDGE:
Mr. Myers, does that
conclude your case?
No, my Lord.
I now call
the final witness
for the prosecution,
Christine Helm.
USHER: Christine Helm.
POLICEMAN 1:
Christine Helm.
POLICEMAN 2:
Christine!
I swear by almighty God,
that the evidence I shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
My Lord, I have the most
serious objection
to this witness
being summoned
by the prosecution,
as she is the wife
of the prisoner,
Leonard Vole.
My Lord, I call
my learned friend's attention
to the fact that
I summoned not Mrs. Vole,
but Mrs. Helm.
Your name, in fact,
is Christine Helm?
Yes, Christine Helm.
And you have been
living as the wife
of the prisoner,
Leonard Vole?
CHRISTINE: Yes.
Are you actually
his wife?
No.
I went through
a marriage ceremony
with him in Hamburg,
but I already
had a husband.
He's still alive.
Christine, that's not true!
My Lord, there is proof
of a marriage
between the witness
and the prisoner.
But is there any proof
of a so-called
previous marriage?
My Lord, the so-called
previous marriage
is, in fact,
well documented.
Mrs. Helm,
is this a certificate
of marriage
between yourself and
one Otto Ludwig Helm?
The ceremony having
taken place in Breslau
on April 18, 1942?
Yes, that is the paper
of my marriage.
I don't see any reason
why this witness
should not be qualified
to give evidence.
Uh, Mrs. Helm, are you willing
to give evidence
against the man you've been
calling your husband?
Yes.
You stated to the police
that on the night
that Mrs. French was murdered,
Leonard Vole left the house
at 7:30
and returned at 9:25.
Did he, in fact,
return at 9:25?
No.
He returned at 10:10.
Christine,
what are you saying?
It's not true!
You know it's not true!
(CROWD MURMURING)
USHER: Silence!
I must have silence.
As your counsel
will tell you, Vole,
you will very shortly
have an opportunity
of speaking
in your own defense.
Leonard Vole returned,
you say, at 10:10.
And what happened next?
He was breathing hard,
very excited.
He threw off his coat
and examined the sleeves.
Then he told me
to wash the cuffs.
They had blood on them.
MYERS: Go on.
I said, "Leonard,
what have you done?"
And what did the prisoner
say to that?
He said, "I've killed her."
Christine, why are you lying?
Why are you saying
these things?
(CROWD MURMURING)
What an awful woman.
Oh, she's evil, that one.
I've known it all along.
(CROWD MURMURING)
If the defense so desires,
I will adjourn
for a short time
so that the prisoner
may gain control of himself.
My Lord is most gracious,
but pray let
the witness continue.
We are all of us caught up
in the suspense
of this horror fiction.
To have to hear it
in installments
might prove unendurable.
JUDGE: Proceed, Mr. Myers.
Uh, Mrs. Helm,
when the prisoner said,
"I have killed her,"
did you know
to whom he referred?
It was that woman
he had been going
to see so often.
Now then, when questioned
by the police,
you told them
that the prisoner
returned at 9:25?
Yes, because Leonard
asked me to say that.
MYERS: But you've changed
your story now. Why?
CHRISTINE:
I cannot go on lying
to save him.
I said to the police
what he wanted me to say
because I'm grateful to him.
He married me
and brought me
to this country.
What he has asked me to do,
I've always done
because I was grateful.
It was not because
he was your husband
and you loved him?
I never loved him.
MYERS: It was gratitude
to the prisoner, then,
that prompted you to give him
an alibi in your statement
to the police?
That is it, exactly.
But now you think
it was wrong to do so?
Because it is murder.
That woman,
she was a harmless old fool,
and he makes of me
an accomplice
to the murder.
I cannot come into court
and swear
that he was with me
at the time
when it was done.
I cannot do it!
Then this is the truth,
that Leonard Vole returned
that night at 10:10,
that he had blood
on the sleeves of his coat,
and that he said to you,
"I have killed her"?
That is the truth.
MYERS: That is the truth
before God?
That is the truth.
Thank you.
Mrs. Vole
or Mrs. Helm,
which do you prefer
to be called?
CHRISTINE: It does not matter.
Does it not?
In this country,
we are inclined
to take a rather more serious
view of marriage.
However, Frau Helm,
it would appear
that when you first met
the prisoner in Hamburg,
you lied to him
about your marital status?
I wanted to get out
of Germany, so...
WILFRID:
You lied, did you not?
Just yes or no, please.
Yes.
Thank you.
Then subsequently,
in arranging the marriage,
you lied to the authorities?
I, um, did not tell the truth
to the authorities.
You lied to them?
Yes.
And in the ceremony
of marriage itself,
when you swore
to love and to honor
and to cherish your husband,
that too was a lie?
CHRISTINE: Yes.
And when the police
questioned you
about this wretched man
who believes himself
married and loved,
you told them...
I told them what Leonard
wanted me to say.
You told them
that he was at home
with you at 9:25,
and now you say
that that was a lie?
Yes, a lie.
And when you said
that he had accidentally cut
his wrist, again you lied?
Yes!
(CHUCKLING)
And now today you've told us
a new story entirely.
The question is, Frau Helm,
were you lying then,
are you lying now?
Or are you not, in fact,
a chronic and habitual liar?
(CROWD MURMURING)
(COUGHING)
(WHISPERING) Carter. Carter.
The other pill,
under the tongue.
My Lord, is my learned friend
to be allowed
to bully and insult
the witness
in this fashion?
Mr. Myers,
this is a capital charge,
and within the bounds
of reason,
I should like the defense
to have every latitude.
My Lord, may I also remind
my learned friend
that his witness,
by her own admission,
has already violated
so many oaths,
that I am surprised
the testament did not leap
from her hand
when she was sworn here today!
I doubt if anything
is to be gained
by questioning you
any further.
That will be all, Frau Helm.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Mrs. Helm, I presume
you know the meaning
of the English word "perjury"?
In German,
the word is "Meineid."
Yes, Meineid.
It means to swear
falsely under oath.
And are you aware,
Mrs. Helm,
that the penalty
in this country for perjury
is a heavy term
of imprisonment?
CHRISTINE: Yes, I'm aware.
Mindful of this fact,
I ask you once more,
is the evidence
that you have given,
the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
So help me, God.
Then that, My Lord,
is the case
for the prosecution.
(CRYING)
Oh, want a tissue?
Yes, thanks.
It's the first murder trial
I've ever been to.
It's terrible.
USHER: Silence!
Sir Wilfrid, are you ready
for the defense?
My Lord,
members of the jury,
the prosecution has
very ably presented
against the prisoner,
Leonard Vole,
a case with the most
overwhelming
circumstantial evidence.
Among the witnesses,
you have heard
Chief Inspector Hearne,
who has given
his testimony in a fair
and impartial manner,
as he always does
in these cases.
He has evolved
and put before you
a clever theory of how
this crime was committed.
Whether it is theory
or actual fact, however,
you will decide
for yourselves.
And then you have heard
the evidence
of Janet McKenzie.
A worthy and devoted
housekeeper
who has suffered
two most grievous losses,
one, the death
of her beloved mistress
and second,
in being deprived
of an inheritance
of 80,000 pounds,
which she'd fully
expected to receive.
I will not comment further
on her evidence,
but will express only
my deepest sympathy for her
in both these mishaps.
And finally,
most damaging of all,
the prosecution has produced
a surprise witness,
one Christine Helm,
whom the prisoner married
and brought from the rubble
of her homeland
to the safety of this country,
giving her his love and
the protection of his name.
I objected to her testimony
because a wife cannot
give evidence
harmful to her husband.
But it has been proven
that her marriage
to Leonard Vole was fraudulent
and bigamous.
Therefore,
her evidence must be admitted
and you must consider it
for what it is worth.
Such is
the prosecution's case.
Now it is the turn
of the defense.
We could present,
on behalf of the prisoner,
a variety of witnesses
to his character,
his war record,
the lack of criminal
or evil association
in his past.
However,
only one witness
can shed new light
on this tragic riddle.
The prisoner himself.
Members of the jury,
I call Leonard Stephen Vole.
I swear by almighty God
that the evidence I shall give
will be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
No.
Is your name
Leonard Stephen Vole?
It is.
WILFRID: Where do you live?
620, Edgware road.
Leonard Stephen Vole,
did you or did you not,
on the night of
October the 14th last,
murder Emily Jane French?
I did not.
Thank you. That will be all.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Have you, in fact,
concluded your examination
of the prisoner, Sir Wilfrid?
My Lord, the prisoner
has endured three days
of the most profound
mental agony and shock.
The defense feels
that his faculties
should be spared
for the cross-examination
by my learned friend
for the prosecution.
This is not a plea
for any indulgence.
I am confident that no matter
how searching this may be,
the prisoner
will withstand it.
Mr. Vole, at the time
that you made the acquaintance
of Mrs. French,
were you employed?
No, sir.
How much money did you have?
Just a few pounds.
Did she ever give you
any money?
No, not a penny.
Did you expect to receive any?
No, sir.
And did you know
that in her new will,
you were the beneficiary
to the extent
of 80,000 pounds?
No, I didn't.
Now, Mr. Vole, when you went
to visit Mrs. French
for the last time,
did you wear a trench coat
and a brown hat?
Yes, I did.
Was it this coat and hat?
Yes, sir.
My Lord, the defense,
leaving no stone unturned
in its efforts to establish
an alibi for the prisoner,
circulated this photograph,
hoping to bring forth
a witness
who had seen him leaving
Mrs. French's house
or entering his own
at the times
that he has stated.
Apparently, this splendid
effort was without results.
However, the defense
will be pleased to learn
that at the last moment,
a witness has come forward,
and that the prisoner
had been seen
wearing this coat
and this hat.
Lamentably,
he had not been seen
on the night of the murder,
but exactly one week before.
On the afternoon
of October the eighth,
were you or were you not
in a travel agency
on Regent Street?
And did you or did you not
make inquiries
about prices and schedules
of foreign cruises?
Well, supposing I did?
That's not a crime, is it?
Not at all.
Many people go on a cruise
when they can afford
to pay for it.
But you couldn't pay for it,
could you, Mr. Vole?
Well, I--I was hard up.
I told you that.
And yet you came
to this particular
travel agency
with a clinging brunette.
"A clinging brunette,"
Mr. Myers?
(CROWD CHUCKLING)
My Lord, the young lady
was so described to me.
She was very affectionate
with the prisoner,
constantly clinging
to his arm.
Oh.
You then admit
that you made inquiries
about the most expensive
and luxurious cruises.
How did you expect
to pay for such a thing?
I don't know. It was...
If you don't know,
perhaps I can help you.
On the morning
of the very same day,
according to Mr. Stokes,
you heard Mrs. French
change her will, leaving you
the bulk of her money.
I didn't! I knew nothing
about the will!
And in the afternoon,
you started to make plans
to dispose of that money.
No! It was nothing
of the kind!
I was in a pub
and I met this girl.
I don't even remember
her name now.
And we had a couple of drinks
and walked out together.
And we passed
that display window
and saw those fancy posters,
all blue seas and palm trees,
Grecian isles
or some such place.
So we went in just for fun
and I started
asking for folders.
Well, the man gave me
a sort of a funny look,
because I did look
a bit shabby.
Well, anyway,
it irritated me,
so I kept asking
for the swankiest tours,
all de luxe and a cabin
on the boat deck,
but it was just
putting on an act.
An act?
You knew that
in a week you were going
to inherit 80,000 pounds.
No, it wasn't
that way at all!
It was make-believe
and childish, but...
It was fun
and I enjoyed it.
I never thought of
killing anyone
or of inheriting any money.
It was just
a remarkable coincidence
that Mrs. French
should be killed
only one week later?
I told you.
I didn't kill her!
Do you know any reason
why the witness,
Christine Helm,
should deliberately give
the evidence she has given
if it were not true?
No, I don't know
why my wife...
I don't even know why
I still call her my wife.
She must have been lying
or out of her mind.
She seemed remarkably sane
and self-possessed.
But insanity
is the only reason
that you can suggest?
I don't understand it.
Oh, God, what's happened?
What's changed her?
Very effective, I'm sure.
But in this court,
we deal with fact.
And the fact, Mr. Vole,
is that we have
only your word for it,
that you left
Mrs. French's house
at the time you say you did,
that you came home at 9:25,
and that you did not
go out again!
But somebody must have
seen me in the street
or going into the house.
One would
certainly think so.
But the only person
who did see you
come home that night
says that it was 10:10
and she says that
you had blood
on your hands.
I cut my wrist!
You cut your wrist
deliberately!
No, I didn't!
I didn't do anything,
but you make it sound
as though I did.
I can hear it myself.
MYERS: You came home
at 10:10?
No, I didn't.
You've got to believe me.
You've got to believe me!
You killed Emily French!
No, I didn't!
I didn't do it!
I didn't kill her!
I never killed anybody!
God, it's like a nightmare,
some ghastly, horrible dream.
Good evening, Sir Wilfrid.
How did it go today?
MAN: Oh, uh, Sir Wilfrid?
I'm from Hawks and Hill, sir,
and I brought
your bermuda shorts
for a fitting.
My what?
You better slip these on,
Sir Wilfrid,
if we're to have them
ready by tomorrow.
My dear man,
I'm in the middle
of a murder trial.
It'll all be over
by tomorrow afternoon
and the boat train
doesn't go until 9:40.
You two work it out.
You know my shape.
you've stabbed it
often enough.
Upstairs, Sir Wilfrid.
You need a lukewarm bath
and your calcium injection.
Oh, and there's a lot more
packing to be done still.
It's ridiculous having
those boat reservations.
How do we know?
The jury may be
out for days.
Not on this case,
I'm afraid.
It seems too open and shut.
(SIGHING)
I watched them when Frau Helm
was on the stand.
They didn't like her.
No, they didn't like her,
but they believed her.
They liked Leonard Vole,
but they didn't believe him.
And that travel agency
business doesn't help either.
Cigar, Wilfrid?
No.
Wilfrid, do you think
she lied?
Well, don't you?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
I am. She lied.
Whether she called it meineid
or perjury, she lied.
The only question
in my mind is, "Why?"
What's her game?
What is she up to?
What?
Sir Wilfrid, I hope that
in your final speech tomorrow,
you won't let yourself become
too emotionally involved.
You must think
of your physical condition.
He's right, you know.
I want to see you
save yourself.
This isn't going to be
your last case.
Yes, it is,
but until it's over,
I'm still a barrister.
And my client's life
is at stake.
That's all that matters.
His life.
He's entitled to the best
that I can do.
If I can't stand up to make
my final appeal for him,
I'll make it sitting down.
If I become short of breath,
I'll take a pill or two pills,
or all of them
and the box as well.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yes?
WOMAN: (IN COCKNEY ACCENT)
Is this
Sir Wilfrid Robarts' place?
Why, yes it is.
Let me talk
to the old geezer.
Who is this speaking,
please?
Never you mind.
Let me talk to him.
I'm afraid
that will be impossible.
Uh, what is the nature
of your business?
It's business all right.
I've got something
to sell him, I have.
CARTER:
Well, really, Madam.
And what I've got
to sell him, believe me,
he'll want to buy.
It's got to do
with that Leonard Vole.
CARTER: Leonard Vole?
It's about
that German wife.
I've got the goods on her
and it's for sale.
This is Wilfrid Robarts
speaking.
Now, what is this all about?
Well, hello, ducky.
What is this you said
about Mrs. Leonard Vole?
I'm not just saying.
I've got it
in black and white.
You've got what?
Listen to this carefully,
ducks.
I'm at the booth here
at Euston Station
at the far end of the bar.
And I'll be here
for just 30 minutes,
because that's
when me train leaves.
If you want the lowdown
on that German bag,
you get yourself over here.
What lowdown?
What do you know about her?
Uh-uh, not on the phone.
You better get on over here
and bring plenty of money.
Now, just a moment.
Hello! Hello!
That's bilge.
Some drunken crank.
You get those
in every murder trial.
Giving me an ultimatum,
Euston Station
in 30 minutes,
got the lowdown
on Mrs. Vole.
Balderdash.
I'm too old and too sick
to go on a wild goose chase.
Come on, Mayhew.
Where to, Sir Wilfrid?
Euston Station,
where do you think?
Now, sir?
Shortly.
Oh.
Cigar.
Sir Wilfrid,
where are you going?
Your bath, your massage,
your dinner, your injection.
Thank you, Miss Plimsoll.
(WOMAN ANNOUNCING
ON PA SYSTEM)
(STEAM ENGINE WHISTLING)
You wouldn't be Sir Wilfrid,
would you?
I would.
Didn't recognize you
without your wig.
Lovely you all look
in them wigs.
Two of you?
I'm not talking to two of you.
This is Mr. Mayhew,
Leonard Vole's solicitor.
Well, that's all right then,
isn't it?
And your name, please.
No need for names.
If I did give you a name,
it mightn't be the right one,
might it?
Have a drink, boys.
Two whiskeys
for me gentlemen friends.
Now, what is this information
you allegedly have?
You realize, of course,
that you are in duty bound
to come forward to give any
evidence that you might have
in your possession?
Oh, come off it.
Did you bring any money?
What is it you have, madam?
Letters.
Letters that German wife
of his wrote.
That's what I've got.
Letters written
by Christine Vole
to the prisoner?
To the prisoner?
Don't make me laugh.
Poor bleeder.
He's been took in
by her, all right,
and these letters prove it.
If we could see
these letters, madam,
we shall be able to advise you
as to how pertinent they are.
Well, I don't expect you...
(STEAM ENGINE WHISTLING)
Well, as I say,
I don't expect you
to buy without seeing,
but fair's fair.
If these letters
get the boy off,
well, it's 100 pounds
for me, right?
If these letters
contain information useful
to the defense,
I'm prepared
to offer you 10 pounds.
What? 10 bleeding pounds
for letters like these?
You can take that piece
of glass out of your eye.
Goodnight, gents.
If these should help to prove
my client's innocence,
20 pounds would, I think,
not be an unreasonable sum
for your expenses.
Fifty and it's a bargain.
That's if you're satisfied
with what's in them.
40 pounds.
All right, blast you.
Here, take them.
Nice little lot there.
How do we know these are
from Mrs. Vole?
Oh, she wrote them
all right.
It's all fair and square.
I hope they fix her
good and proper.
I've had messages
from Mrs. Vole.
It looks like her handwriting.
Good heavens,
look at this.
(STEAM ENGINE WHISTLING)
Juicy, ain't they?
There's one coming up
that's even better.
How did you get
hold of these?
What difference does it make,
so long as she gets
what's coming to her?
What have you
got against her?
Ha!
I'll give you something
to dream about, mister.
(GLASS BANGING)
Want to kiss me, ducky?
Ha! I didn't suppose
you would.
Christine Vole did that
to you?
Not her.
The chap I was going with.
He was a bit younger than me,
but I loved him.
And then she come along,
started seeing him
on the sly,
and then one day
he cleared out.
But I went after him
and I found them together.
I told him what
I thought of her and he cut
me face up proper.
Did you go to the police
about it?
Who, me? Not likely.
Besides,
it wasn't his fault,
not really. It was hers.
It was all hers.
Getting him away from me,
turning him against me.
But I waited me time
to pay her back.
And it's come now.
I'm deeply sorry,
deeply sorry.
We'll make it another 5 pounds
for the letters.
Holding out on me,
were you?
I knew I was being
too soft with you.
Cold-blooded vindictiveness.
Read this one.
Hmm?
Unbelievable.
We'd better have the full name
of the man to whom
these were addressed.
Miss, uh...Miss, um...
Where is she?
(TRAIN ENGINE CHUGGING)
On that train, I should think.
Just doesn't want
her other cheek slashed.
Can't blame her, can you?
Care for another, sir?
Hmm? Good idea.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
USHER: Silence!
Be upstanding in court.
All persons who have
anything further to do
before my lords,
the Queen's justices
of oyer and terminer
and general jail delivery
for the jurisdiction
of the Central Criminal Court
draw near and give
your attendance.
God save the Queen!
(BELLS CHIMING)
Since the defense
has called but one witness,
the prisoner,
it has the right
to be heard last.
Therefore, Mr. Myers,
if you are ready,
let us have the final address
for the prosecution.
My Lord,
members of the jury,
I will be brief
in my final speech
because I think that
the prosecution has proved
so obvious a case of murder
against the prisoner,
Leonard Vole,
that a verdict of guilty
must be the only
possible conclusion.
I will briefly summarize
these facts...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PANTING)
JUDGE: You'd better begin
again, Mr. Myers.
That is, if Sir Wilfrid
is at all interested
in our proceedings.
I am indeed, My Lord.
The speech for the Crown,
however, is premature.
I ask that the case
for the defense
be reopened,
and that a witness
be recalled.
My Lord,
I must strenuously object
to the case being reopened
at this final stage.
Evidence of the most startling
nature came into my possession
only last night.
My Lord, the course
my learned friend proposes
is quite unprecedented.
I have anticipated
my friend's objection
and am prepared to meet it
with ample precedent.
There is first the case
of the King against Stillman,
reported in
the Criminal Appeal Reports
of 1926 at page 463.
Also, the King against Porter,
in volume one of the
King's Bench Division Reports,
1942, at page 153.
And lastly, there is the case
of the King against Sullivan,
in which
this issue was raised,
which I am sure
Your Lordship will remember,
since your lordship appeared
for the prosecution.
JUDGE: I did?
Oh, yes,
before Mr. Justice Swindon.
Now, what is this new
evidence, Sir Wilfrid?
Letters, My Lord.
Letters written
by Christine Helm.
My Lord, the prosecution
continues its objection.
If my memory serves me well,
Your Lordship's
similar objection,
in the King against Sullivan,
was sustained.
Your memory, for once,
serves you ill, Mr. Myers.
My objection then
was overruled
by Mr. Justice Swindon,
as yours is now, by me.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Call Christine Helm.
USHER: Christine Helm.
POLICEMAN 1: Christine Helm.
POLICEMAN 2: Christine Helm.
If you still have any doubts
about Leonard Vole,
I wouldn't mind betting you
a very small box of cigars.
Mrs. Helm,
you appreciate
you are still under oath?
Yes.
WILFRID: Mrs. Helm,
do you know a man named Max?
I don't know what you mean.
It's a simple question.
Do you or do you not know
a man called Max?
Max?
Certainly not.
It's a fairly common name
and yet you mean
you've never known a man
with the name of Max?
CHRISTINE:
Oh, in Germany, perhaps,
but that was a long time ago.
I shall not ask you
to go back that far,
just a few weeks to, uh,
October the 20th last.
What have you got there?
WILFRID: A letter.
I suggest that
on October the 20th,
you wrote a certain letter...
I don't know what
you're talking about.
...addressed to a man
named Max.
I did nothing of the sort!
The letter was but
one of a series written
to the same man.
Lies! All lies!
You would seem
to have been on,
well, let us say,
on intimate terms
with this man.
How dare you
say a thing like that?
It isn't true!
I'm not concerned
with the general trend
of this correspondence,
only with
one particular letter.
"My beloved Max,
"An extraordinary thing
has happened.
"I believe
all our difficulties
may be ended..."
I will not stand here
and listen
to a pack of lies.
That letter's a forgery.
It isn't even
my letter paper.
WILFRID: It isn't?
No.
I write my letters
on small, blue paper
with my initials on it.
Like this?
(CROWD MURMURING)
This happens to be
a bill from my tailor
for a pair of extremely
becoming bermuda shorts.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Wilfrid the fox.
That's what we call him
and that's what he is.
Now, Mrs. Helm,
you've been kind enough
to identify your letter paper.
Now, if you like,
I can have an expert
identify your handwriting.
CHRISTINE: Damn you!
Damn you!
Leave her alone!
Mrs. Helm!
Let me go!
Let me get out of here!
Mrs. Helm!
Let me go!
Usher, get the witness
a chair.
(CHRISTINE SOBBING)
Sir Wilfrid,
would you now read
the letter in question
so that the jury may hear it?
"My beloved Max,
"an extraordinary thing
has happened.
"All our difficulties
may soon be solved.
"Leonard is suspected
of murdering the old lady
I told you about.
"His only hope of an alibi
depends on me,
"on me alone.
"Suppose I testify
"that he was not
at home with me
at the time of the murder,
"that he came home
with blood on his sleeves,
"and that he even admitted
to me that he'd killed her.
"Strange, isn't it?
He always said
"that he would never
let me leave him,
"But now, if this succeeds,
"he will be leaving me
because they will
take him away forever.
"And I shall be free,
and yours, my beloved.
"I count the hours
until we are together.
Christine."
Mrs. Helm, will you go
back to the witness box?
I now ask you again,
Christine Helm,
did you write
this letter?
Christine, tell him
that you didn't write it.
I know you didn't.
Please answer my question.
Did you write this letter?
Before answering, Mrs. Helm,
I wish to warn you that
the law regarding perjury
in this country
is very severe.
If you have already committed
perjury in this courtroom,
I strongly advise you
not to add to your crime.
But if this letter has not
been written by you,
then now is the time
to state this fact.
I wrote the letter.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Then that, My Lord,
is the case for the defense.
I keep asking myself,
Sir Wilfrid,
which is harder,
your head or your arteries?
You'd better stop
pressing your luck.
You're overdue now.
We're all packed
and ready, Doctor.
I hope the jury won't take
all the afternoon.
I concede.
Congratulations.
Here are your cigars.
Not yet.
Oh, come on, it's all over,
wrapped up neat and tidy.
Uh-uh?
Why, what's wrong?
It's a little too neat,
too tidy,
and altogether
too symmetrical.
That's what's
wrong with it.
The jury is just coming back.
You're not worried
about the verdict,
are you?
It's not their judgment
that worries me, it's mine.
Come along.
Where's my wig?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
The prisoner will stand up.
Members of the jury,
are you all agreed
upon your verdict?
We are.
Do you find
the prisoner at the bar,
Leonard Stephen Vole,
guilty or not guilty
of the murder
of Emily Jane French?
Not guilty, My Lord.
(CROWD CHEERING)
USHER: Silence!
Silence!
Leonard Stephen Vole,
you have been found
not guilty of the murder
of Emily Jane French,
on October the 14th.
You are hereby discharged
and are free
to leave the court.
USHER:
All persons who have
anything further to do
before my lords,
the Queen's justices
of oyer and terminer
and general jail delivery
for the jurisdiction of
the Central Criminal Court
may depart here.
(CROWD CHATTERING LOUDLY)
Thank you very much.
Yes, we'll talk later.
Thank you, Mr. Mayhew.
Thank you,
Mr. Brogan-Moore.
Carter.
Thank you, Sir Wilfrid.
Thank you for everything.
You were wonderful.
I'd say we were lucky
all around.
(CHUCKLING) Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
I have your belongings.
If you'll come with me,
Mr. Vole,
and sign the receipt,
we can release you.
"Mr. Vole."
They didn't call me Mister
when they charged me.
I'll go with you.
I brought
your hat and coat.
Yes, let's go quickly,
before they change their mind.
Very chipper, isn't he?
An hour ago, he had one foot
on the gallows and the other
on a banana peel.
You ought to be
very proud, Wilfrid.
Aren't you?
Not yet.
We've disposed of the gallows,
but there's still
that banana peel
somewhere under
somebody's foot.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
WOMAN: A liar,
that's what you are!
Every word you said
was a lie!
MAN 1: People like you
ought to be locked up.
MAN 2: Liar!
You'd better wait here
until we get rid
of that crowd, madam.
Thank you.
Ready, sir?
Miss Plimsoll will be waiting.
Let me finish
the last of the cocoa
while I'm still
beyond her jurisdiction.
Would you excuse me,
Brogan-Moore, Carter?
Thank you.
I never thought you British
could get so emotional,
especially in a public place.
I apologize
for my compatriots.
Oh, it's all right.
I don't mind
being called names
or pushed around,
or even kicked in the shin.
But now I have a ladder
in my last pair of nylons.
In case you are not familiar
with our prison regulations,
no silk stockings.
Prison? Will I go to prison?
You heard the learned judge.
You will quite certainly
be charged with perjury,
tried for it,
and to prison you shall go.
Well, it won't be
for life, will it?
If I were appearing
for the prosecution,
it would be.
You loathe me, don't you?
Like the people outside.
What a wicked woman I am,
and how brilliantly
you exposed me
and saved Leonard's life.
The great Sir Wilfrid Robarts
did it again.
Well, let me
tell you something.
You didn't do it alone.
You had help.
What are you driving at?
I'm not driving
at anything anymore.
Leonard is free,
and we did it.
We?
Remember?
When I came to see you
and you that said no jury
would believe an alibi
given by a loving wife,
no matter how much she swore
her husband was innocent?
That gave me the idea.
What idea?
The idea that I should be
a witness,
not for my husband,
but for the prosecution,
that I should swear
Leonard was guilty
and that you should expose me
as a vicious liar,
because only then
would they believe
Leonard was innocent.
So now you know
the whole story,
Sir Wilfrid.
(IN COCKNEY ACCENT)
I'll give you something
to dream about, mister.
Wanna kiss me, ducky?
I suspected something,
but not that.
Never that.
Thank you for the compliment.
It's been a long time
since I was an actress,
and I never before played
such an important role.
And all those blue letters?
It took me hours
to write them, to invent Max.
There never was a Max.
There's never been anyone
but Leonard, only Leonard.
My dear, could you not
have trusted me,
worked with me
truthfully and honorably?
We would have won!
I could not run that risk.
You see, you thought
he was innocent.
And you knew
he was innocent,
I understand.
No, Sir Wilfrid,
you do not understand at all.
I knew he was guilty.
That can't be true!
No!
Listen to me once and for all.
Leonard came home
a few minutes past 10:00.
He did have blood
on his sleeves,
he did tell me
he had killed the woman.
Only I could save him.
He pleaded with me.
And you saved him.
A murderer?
Again, you don't understand.
I love him.
I told you she was an actress
and a good one.
CHRISTINE: Leonard.
I knew she was going
to do something for me,
but I just didn't know
what or how.
Leonard! Leonard!
(SIGHING)
Fooled you completely,
didn't she?
It was you, Vole,
who fooled me.
Oh!
Easy, easy.
Now, we both got
out of this alive.
Let's stay this way.
Where are your pills?
Vole, you have made
a mockery of English law.
Who did?
You got me off,
and I can't be tried
again for this.
That's English law, too,
isn't it?
You can't touch him now.
Nobody can.
The scales of justice
may tip one way or another,
but ultimately
they balance out.
You'll pay for this.
Oh, ultimately's
a long way off.
I'd rather pay for it
as soon as possible
and in cash.
Suppose we double your fee.
There'll be plenty of money
as soon as the will
goes through.
I'm not cheap.
I want everybody to get
something out of this.
Now, there's Janet McKenzie.
We'll get her
that new hearing aid.
And we'll get you
a new one of these.
18 karat gold,
if they make them.
When they try you
for perjury,
there'll be 5,000 pounds
for the best defense
you can get.
I don't care, Leonard,
just so we'll be
together again.
You don't know
what I went through,
standing in the witness box,
having to face you
in the dock,
saying I never loved you.
What is it, Leonard?
Sir Wilfrid,
the luggage is in the car
and we've only 20 minutes
to catch the boat train.
This is a nice young lady
I met in the gallery
during the trial.
Len! Oh, Len!
Oh, Len, they've been
trying to keep me
away from you.
It's had me nearly crazy.
Leonard,
who is this girl?
I'm not "This girl."
I'm his girl.
Tell her, Len.
Leonard, is this the girl
who was with you
in the travel bureau?
The girl you said
you hardly knew,
didn't even know her name?
That's right.
That's who I am,
and I know all about you.
You're not his wife,
never have been.
You're years older than he is.
We've been going
together for months,
and we're going away
on one of those cruises,
just like they said in court.
Tell her yourself, Len.
Yes, Len.
Tell me yourself.
All right, Diana.
Come along.
You can't, Leonard.
Not after what I've done.
I won't let you.
Don't be silly.
I saved your life
getting you out of Germany.
You saved mine getting me
out of this mess.
So we're even.
It's all over now.
Don't, Leonard!
Don't leave me!
(SHUSHING)
Don't, Leonard, don't!
Pull yourself together.
They'll have you up here
for perjury.
Well, don't make it worse
or they'll try you
as an accessory.
And you know what that means.
CHRISTINE: I don't care.
Let them.
Let them try me for perjury
or an accessory or...
LEONARD: Ready?
Or better yet...
(PANTING)
Let them try me for...
(GRUNTS)
(DIANA SCREAMING)
(DIANA SOBBING)
Call a doctor.
It's no use.
No doctor can help now.
What happened?
She killed him.
Killed him?
She executed him.
Carter, what have you done
with the luggage?
I--I sent it on ahead
to the station
and I've got a cab
waiting outside.
A remarkable woman.
You can just barely
catch the boat train,
Sir Wilfrid.
Better bring
the luggage back
and you can dismiss the cab.
We are not going yet,
are we?
Thank you, Miss Plimsoll.
Get Brogan-Moore
to my chambers
and have Mayhew there, too.
We're appearing
for the defense in the trial
of Christine Vole.
Sir Wilfrid.
You've forgotten
your brandy.
MALE NARRATOR: The management
of this theater suggests
that for
the greater entertainment
of your friends who have
not yet seen the picture,
you will not divulge to anyone
the secret of the ending
of Witness for
the Prosecution.