[BEEPING]
[WATER DRIPPING]
[RASPY GRUMBLE]
[OWL HOOTS]
[LOW-PITCHED TONE]
[EXCITED GRUNT]
[EXCITED BREATHING]
Mmm? Oh.
Oh!
[GRUNTS]
[NERVOUS PANTING]
[GROWLS]
[LOW-PITCHED TONE]
[SCREECHES]
MAN: I think I see him![SCREECHING]
[SCREECHING]
This way!
[PANTING HEAVILY]
[ENGINES WHINING]
[CRYING OUT]
[MOANS SOFTLY]
[MOANING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[FAINT MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Five. Oh, great.
So you got an arrow
right in your chest.
You're out 10 mana points.
Oh, no. Don't worry
about it, Mike,
I got resurrection.
I'll bring you back.
I'm already one of
the undead, Greg.
I can still throw
death spells,
huh, Steve?
I'm just trying
to help you out, man,
don't be so cranky.
How about throwing a spell
over the pizza man?
Where's our pizza, man?
Get it? Huh?
Well, I'm ready to...
Now to play.
I'm ready
to play now,
you guys.
We're in the middle,
Elliott.
You can't just join
any universe
in the middle.
I got him!
What am
I asking for?
Papa Oom Mow. Okay.
Papa Oom Mow Mow.
Yeah? Mike?
GREG: I know,
it's not for us,
it's for his mother.
Mike?
You have to ask Steve.
He's game master.
He has
absolute power.
Steve?
GREG: [MOCKINGLY]
Steve, can I play now?
Go wait for
the pizza first.
Then I'm in?Yeah, you're in.
Figure out your strategy,
'cause you're playing
after Greg.
Plenty of sausage
and pepperonis.
Everything
but the little fishies.
[DOG BARKING]
ELLIOTT: Oops!
[FAINTLY ON RADIO]
♪ ...Papa oom
mow mow
♪ 'A papa oom
mow mow mow
♪ Papa oom
mow mow... ♪
[GARBAGE CAN RATTLES]
Harvey?
Harvey,
is that you, boy?
[PAPA OOM MOW MOW
CONTINUING ON RADIO]
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
Over here,
you guys.
Stop it.
Sorry.
[RATTLING]
Harvey?
TYLER: All's you can get
is those 40-year-olds.
How do you win
this game, anyway?
There's no winning.
It's like life.
You don't win at life.
Money helps.
Mom! Mom! There's
something out...
Where's the pizza?
Mom! Mom, there's
something out there!
It's in the tool shed.
It threw
the ball at me. [BOYS MOCKING]
Quiet!
[WHISPERING]
Nobody go out there.
[ALL LAUGHING]
MARY: Stop!
Now, you guys
stay right here.
[IN A DEEP VOICE]
You stay here, Mom.
We'll check it out.
And put those
knives back!
It's okay, Elliott.
Let's go
get the flashlights.
Hold it.
Wait a minute.
MICHAEL: Ooh, creep...
Creepy.
What exactly
did you see?
In there. [HUMMING  TWILIGHT ZONE]
[BOYS LAUGHING]
GREG: It's scary.
Boo!
MARY: There's
nothing in here.
The gate's open.
Look at these.
Coyote's come
back again, Mom.
Okay, party's over.
Everybody
back inside now.
Get out.
Hurry up.
Quick. Hurry up.
Tyler, give me
that knife.
Oh, great.
Nice one, Elliott.
It was an accident.
A pizza?
Who said you guys
could order a pizza?
Uh... Him.But...
Huh? In the house.
You geek, man. Good going.
But, Mom,
it was real,
I swear!
Douche bag. No douche bag talk
in my house.
[RASPY BREATHING]
[RATTLING]
[WHISTLES]
ELLIOTT: Elliott,
you're crazy.
[E.T. GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS]
[RUSTLING]
[SCREECHING]
[SCREAMING]
Ahh!
[WHISTLES]
Hello?
[WHISTLING]
[KEYS JANGLING]
[RASPY BREATHING]
What are you going as
for Halloween?
I'm not going
to stupid Halloween.
Why don't you
go as a goblin?
Shut up.
It's not
that we don't
believe you, honey.
It was real,
I swear!
What are you
going as, Gert?
I'm going
as a cowgirl.
ELLIOTT: So, what else is new?
Maybe it was
an iguana.
It was no iguana.Maybe a...
You know how they say
there are alligators
in the sewers?
Alligators
in the sewers.
All we're
trying to say is,
maybe you just
probably imagined it.
I couldn't have
imagined it!
Maybe it was a pervert,
or a deformed kid,
or something. A deformed kid.
Maybe an elf
or leprechaun.
It was nothing
like that, penis-breath!
Elliott!
[CHUCKLING] Sit down.
MARY: Ahem!
Dad would believe me.
Maybe you ought
to call your father
and tell him about it.
I can't.
He's in Mexico
with Sally.
Wh... Where's Mexico?
Excuse me.
I'm going
to kill you.
If you ever
see it again,
whatever it is,
don't touch it.
Just call me.
And we'll have
somebody come
and take it away.
Like the dogcatcher?
They'll give it
a lobotomy
or do experiments on it
or something.
MARY: It's your turn
to do the dishes, fellas.
I set and cleared.
I set and cleared. I did breakfast.
I did breakfast. [DISH CLATTERS]
What's the matter, Mom?
[SIGHING]
He hates Mexico.
Damn it, why don't
you grow up?
Think how other people
feel for a change.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[FOOTSTEPS CONTINUING]
[GRUNTS]
Mo...
[WEAKLY] Mom.
Mom. Michael.
Michael. Mom.
[MUNCHING]
[PURRING SOFTLY]
[GRUNTING]
[RATTLING]
[SQUEAKING]
Wow.
[CHUCKLES]
[PURRS]
[YAWNING]
[E.T. SNORING]
[BEEPING]
[MUNCHING]
Okay, you're hot.
I'll be back.
MICHAEL: Mary, can I
back the car out?
MARY: Not one foot
past the driveway.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING
RAPIDLY]
[SCRAPING]
You were outside
last night waiting
for that thing
to come back,
weren't you?
Going to live
if I go to work?
Okay.
No TV.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Come on.
Mommy, look
what Michael did.
This and...
I see them, Gert,
and when I catch him,
I'll catch him.
Come on.
Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
Come on.
[FOOTSTEPS]
Do you talk?
You know, talk?
Me human.
Boy.Hmm.
Elliott.
[ENUNCIATING CLEARLY]
Elliott. [SNIFFING]
Elliott.
Coke. See,
we drink it.
It's, uh...
It's a drink.
You know, food?
These are toys.
These are little men.
This is Greedo.
And then this
is Hammerhead.
See, this is Walrus Man.
And then this
is Snaggletooth.
And this is
Lando Calrissian.
See?
And this
is Boba Fett.
Look, they can
even have wars.
Look at this.
[IMITATES LASER BLASTS]
[MOCK GROANING]
And look, fish.
The fish eat
the fish food,
and the shark
eats the fish.
But nobody
eats a shark.
See, this is Pez. Candy.
You see, you eat it.
You put the candy in here,
and then when you
lift up the head,
the candy comes out
and you can eat it.
You want some?
This is a peanut.
You eat it.
But you can't
eat this one
'cause this is fake.
This is money.
You see?
We put the money
in the peanut.
You see? Bank.
You see?
And then...
This is a car.
This is what
we get around in.
See? Car.
Hey! [CRUNCHING]
Hey, wait a second.
No, you don't
eat them.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
Stay.
I'll be right here.
[PURRING] Okay? I'll be
right here.
Harv![SCREECHING]
[BARKING] No biting!
[SCREECHING]
[BARKING] Come on, Harvey.
He'll like this.
This.
[CRIES OUT] [GRUNTING]
Are you okay?
[MOANING]
Too much
excitement, huh?
Want a Coke?
♪ Accidents will happen
♪ But it's only
Hit-and-run
♪ There are
So many people to see
♪ So many people
You can check upon
♪ And add
To your collection
♪ But they
Keep you hanging on
♪ Nothin' but health shit
♪ And add
To your collection
♪ But they
Keep you hanging on
♪ Accidents will happen
♪ But it's only
Hit-and-run
♪ You'll be
A victim of... ♪
Mike, come in.
How you feeling, faker?
I'm feeling fine.
Look, I've got something
really important...
Tyler said he got 69,000
on Asteroids yesterday,
but he pulled the plug.
Look, remember
the goblin?
You're so lame,
Elliott.
Come on, Michael.
He came back.
He came back?
Oh, my God!
ELLIOTT: One thing.
I have absolute power.
Say it.
Say it!
What have you got?
Is it the coyote?
No. Look...
Okay, now, swear it.
The most excellent
promise you can make.
Swear as my only brother,
on our lives.
Don't get so heavy.
I swear.
Okay, stand over there.
And you'd better take off
your shoulder pads. What?
You might scare him.
And close your eyes.
Don't push it, Elliott.
ELLIOTT: I'm not
coming out there until
your eyes are closed.
Okay, they're closed.
Mom is going
to kill you.
[MOCK GROANING]
Okay, swear it
one more time.
I have absolute... [MIMICKING YODA] You have
absolute power. Yes!
[MIMICS YODA'S LAUGH]
[GRUNTS]
GERTIE: Elliott!
Look what I made for you!
[SNORTS]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREECHING]Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Ahh!
[MUFFLED MOANING]
MARY: Kids, I'm home!
Guys? ELLIOTT: In the closet, fast.
MARY: Anybody
up there? Kids?
Ahh!
[GRUNTING]
MARY: Anybody home?
Hi, honey,
how you fee...
What happened
in here?
Oh, you mean my room.
This is no room.
This is an accident.
I was, um...
Reorganizing.
MARY: I can see that.
Put those shelves
back on the wall.
Let's get the toys
off the floor. [GRUNTING]
Make your bed,
since you're not using it.
Well, you're feeling
better, I see.
You guys keep an eye
on Gertie for me
while I take a shower?
Absolutely.
Bye, Mom.
Whew!
[GROANS SOFTLY]
Elliott.
I'm keeping him.
[GRUNTING]
What is it?
He won't hurt you,
Gertie.
We're not going
to hurt you.
Is he a boy or a girl?
ELLIOTT: He's a boy.
Was he wearing
any clothes?
No.
But, look...
You can't tell.
Not even mom.
Why not?
Because, um...
Grownups can't see him.
Only little kids
can see him.
Give me a break.
[MIMICS DRACULA]
Do you know what's
going to happen
if you do tell?
Do it, Mike.
We have to.
[GIRL'S VOICE]
Oh, no, please!
Don't hurt me,
please!
Gertie, help me!
No, please!
Give it!
Promise? Yes.
Do you promise?
[GRUNTS]
[PURRS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[SHUTTER CLICKING]
[HARVEY WHIMPERING]
What are you
doing, Gert?
I'm going to play
in Elliott's room.
Okay, don't let him
torture you.
I won't, Mary.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
MARY: Hello?
Jer... Jerry!
[KNOCKING]
Come on, come on.
Hurry up.
Don't be pushy,
pushy.
A plant for you.
MICHAEL: Maybe
he's some animal that
wasn't supposed to live.
Like those rabbits
we saw that time. GERTIE: I brought clay.
ELLIOTT: Don't be lame.Green, orange, red.
MICHAEL: Could be
a monkey or orangutan.
ELLIOTT: A bald monkey?
Is he a pig?
He sure eats like one.
You could make faces
and make them mean.
And happy,
and make them
get sharp teeth...
We are here.
We're here. No, use this.
You could do
all sorts of things.
Okay, we're here.
We are here.
Where are you from?
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
I don't like his feet.
They're only feet,
you little twerp.
He's trying
to tell us something.
Earth.
Home.
[GRUNTING]
What's he doing?
What's happening?
[RATTLING]
Elliott.
Oh, no.
[CRIES OUT]
[FAINT BEEPING]
Elliott, what is it?
I don't know.
Something scary.
[BEEPING]
MAN 1: Got a pulse?MAN 2: No, boss.
Hold it.
We got it right here.
MAN 1: Follow him.
MAN 2: Okay.
MAN 1: You check this house?
Hmm.
Mmm.
MICHAEL: Did you
explain school to him?
ELLIOTT: How do you
explain school
to higher intelligence?
MICHAEL: Maybe
he's not that smart.
Maybe he's only a worker bee,
who only knows
how to push buttons...
ELLIOTT: He is too smart.
MICHAEL: Okay, I just hope
we don't wake up on Mars
or something,
surrounded by millions
of these little squashy guys.
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
Hi, Elliott.
Hey, Elliott,
where's your goblin?
Shut up. Did he come back?
Well, did he?
Yeah, he came back.
But he's
not a goblin.
He's a spaceman. [MOCKING]
As in extraterrestrial.
Where's he from?
Uranus?
Get it? Your anus?
He doesn't get it, Ty.
Get it? Your anus? He doesn't get it.
You're so immature.
And you're such
a cintus suprimus.
Zero charisma. Cintus suprimus.
Shut up, Greg! Cintus suprimus.
Zero charisma! Hi, Elliott.
You wimp.
Let's go.
Come on,
get in the car.
We're gonna be late.
[SHUFFLING]
[SIGHS]
Okay, boys and girls,
today we will be doing
the actual frog dissection
for which
we've been preparing.
And you will find
many similarities...
As you get
into the dissection,
you will discover
that the anatomy...
[GROWLING]
[WHINES]
TEACHER: The scalpel
is very sharp.
Use discretion
when you are cutting.
There will be
very little blood.
There may be
a few body fluids.
[E.T. SNIFFING]
E.T.: Ugh!
[CAN POPS OPEN]
[BARKING]
TEACHER: As we
get started with...[BELCHES]
...the dissection... KIDS: Ugh!
TEACHER: Remember
that the things
you are writing down...
[BELCHES]
TEACHER: One thing that
you should be looking for
during the dissection
is to locate
the heart,
and notice that
it is still beating.
I'm going to once more
emphasize the similarities
of those things
which we see in the...
[MOANS]
TEACHER: Similarities
with human anatomy.
First of all,
of course, the heart.
which you will see beating.
The intestines
will be going
through their
peristaltic action.
TOY:  X-W-V-U.
A-F-P.
That is incorrect.
The correct spelling
of nuisance
is N-U-I...
S-A-N-C-E.
[HOWLS]
They're
pulling us up.
Class, these are
the cotton balls
with the chloroform.
As soon as I get
them all in,
be sure and put
the lid on right away.
Ugh! TEACHER: That's it.
That will start them
going to sleep.
They won't feel anything.
They won't be hurt.
Sick. This is gross.
TEACHER: It'll take
a little while.
If you don't want
to watch them,
you don't have to.
[KIDS WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Say hi.
Can you talk?
Can you say hi?
E.T.: Oh!
[BELCHES]
Mmm...
WOMAN ON TV:  Hello? MAN ON TV:  Hi!
Uncle Ralph!
It's Uncle Ralph,
long distance
from California!
Ooh, I'll talk fast.
This call must
be expensive.
Oh, no, no. I call
anytime on Saturday
without an operator,
I can talk for five minutes
for 85 cents plus tax.
If I talk less,
I pay less.
Let me talk to that
little fella, huh?
WOMAN:  Lou, it's Uncle Ralph.
Hello, Uncle Ralph.
[WHISPERING]
Save him.
Run for your life!
Back to the river!
Back to the forest!
Run! I want to save you!
Let's get out of here!
Get out!
I got to let him go!
You've got to save him!
[CHAOTIC TUMULT]
TEACHER: Let me handle this!
Class, let me handle this!
I can handle this.
Let me get this.
Ahh!
[TV PLAYING
IN THE BACKGROUND]
WOMAN:  Stanford,
what's wrong?
STANFORD:  I'm afraid
Betsy Sue isn't going
to run tomorrow.
WOMAN:  Oh, no.
Is it anything serious?
MARY: Harvey, I'm home.
Come here, boy.
Here he is.
Here's who?
The man from the moon,
but I think you've
killed him already.
Honey, just as soon as
I unload the stuff, okay?
Mmm.
Med-bugs.
I want you
to meet somebody.
This stuff has
gone up so much
in one week.
I want you
to meet somebody.
Okay, honey, as soon as
I get finished putting
this stuff away, all right?
Stupid Ragu. I knew
it wouldn't come out.
B. B.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]I'm stuck with this...
Hello.
Yeah, this is she.
Basket.
Bandit.
Ball.
Basket, bandit, ball.
MARY: ...he was feeling
a little ill yesterday. Books.
Bananas.
Intoxicated?
[SNIFFING]
You sure you have
the right Elliott?
B. B.
Biscuits. B.
B.
TELEVISION:  ...is for
baseball and bat.
Y... You said "B."
B.
You said "B." Good!
Good...
Okay, I'll be right down.
Thank you.
Gertie, I have to go
pick up Elliott.
Will you be...
Mommy, he can talk.
Of course he can talk.
I'll be right back
in 10 minutes.
Stay there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
little Grover here
will demonstrate
by chinning himself
two times.
GROVER:  Two times?  Two times, okay.
GROVER:  Should I start?
Okay. Go ahead, Grover.
Okay, here we go.
Phone.
E.T.: Phone...
[SLOWLY] Phone.
You want
to call somebody?
MARY: I am not
paying for frogs.
GERTIE: Be good. Be good.
Stay here. Stay.
And don't tell anybody.
No... Nobody.
Be good. Be good.
Move.
Oh, God!
Elliott.
What?
E.T.: Elliott.
[REPEATING]
Elliott...
I taught him
how to talk now.
He can talk now.
Look what he brought
up here all by himself.
What's he need
this stuff for?
E.T.: Elliott.
"E.T.," can you say that?
Can you say, "E.T.?"
E-T.
[SLOWLY] E.T.
[LAUGHS]
E.T., E.T., E.T.
Be good.
I taught him that, too.
You should give
him his dignity.
This is the most
ridiculous thing
I've ever seen!
E.T.: Phone.
Phone?
He said "phone"?
Can't you
understand English?
He said "phone."
E.T.: Home.
You're right.
That's E.T.'s home.
E... T...
Home... Phone.
E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home!
He wants
to call somebody.
What's all this shit?
E.T.: E.T. phone home.
Oh, my God,
he's talking now.
Home...
E.T. phone home?
E.T. phone home.
[WHISPERS] And they'll come?
Come...
Home...
ELLIOTT: [OVER RADIO]
Come on, I promise, Mom.
GIRL 1:  What book? GIRL 2:  Any one you want...
Spider-Man...
MARY:  We'll just put
a smile on our face
and try to get
through the evening.
That's all I want.
We can't ask Cathy
to go trick-or-treating
in the same sheet
she wore last year.
ELLIOTT:
Now I wish I would've
listened in science.
Think, Michael.
Just grab anything
it looks like he could
make a machine out of.
What would make a radar?
How the hell do I know?
You're the genius here.
You have absolute
power, remember?
[MIMICKING] "I found him.
He belongs to me."
You know, Elliott,
he doesn't look
too good anymore.
Don't say that!
We're fine!
What's all this
"we" stuff?
You say "we"
all the time now.
Really, Elly, I think
he might be getting sick.
Look, he's fine,
Michael!
MICHAEL:  Okay, okay!
Forget I mentioned it.
Grab that Fuzzbuster.
Dad's shirt.
Yeah.
Remember when he
used to take us out
to the ball games
and take us
to the movies
and we'd have
popcorn fights?
We'll do that again,
Elliott.
ELLIOTT:  Sure.
[SNIFFS]
Old Spice.
Sea Breeze.
[BEEPING]
"Peter says,
'The redskins
were defeated?
"'Wendy and the boys
captured by the pirates?
"'I'll rescue her.
I'll rescue her.'
"He leaps
first at his dagger,
"and then at his grindstone
to sharpen it.
"Tink alights near the ship
and rings out a warning cry.
"'Oh, that is
just my medicine.'
"She says, 'Poisoned?
"'Who could've
poisoned it?'
"'I promised Wendy
to take it,
"'and I will, as soon
as I have sharpened
my dagger.'
"Tink, who sees
its red color
"and remembers the red
in the pirate's eye,
"nobly swallows
the draft
"as Peter's hand
is reaching for it.
"'Why, Tink, you have
drunk my medicine.'
"She flutters strangely
about the room,
"answering him
in a very faint tinkle..."
Ouch!
Ouch.
MARY:
"'She says...
"'She says she thinks
she could get well again
"'if children
believed in fairies.'
"Do you believe in fairies?
Say quick that
you believe."
I do, I do, I do.
"If you believe,
clap your hands.
"Many clap, some don't,
a few hiss..."
[GROANS]
Mmm.
MARY: "But Tink is saved.
'Thank you.
"'Oh, thank you,
thank you,
thank you.
"'And now
to rescue Wendy.'"
GERTIE:
Can you read it
to me again?
[MARY SIGHS]
[PURRING]
MARY:
"Peter says..."
[ENGINE IDLING]
ELLIOTT:
He's putting it
together now.
I told you
he was smart.
[WHISPERING] I'm worried,
Elliott.
He could blow up
the whole house.
ELLIOTT: He knows
what he's doing.
MICHAEL: Listen to how
he's breathing.
[RASPY WHEEZING]
ELLIOTT: It's going to work.
MICHAEL: What's he
feeling now?
ELLIOTT: He's feeling
everything.
Now, you're going
as a ghost.
You promised.
GERTIE: I'm only pretending
I'm going as a cowgirl.
Okay now, you know
the plans by heart,
don't you?
Meet you
at the lookout.
At the lookout.
I'm not stupid,
you know.
MARY: Listen, buster,
you won't get four blocks
in this neighborhood
dressed like that!
MICHAEL: [PLEADING] Please. No, and that is final.
You are not
going as a terrorist!
MICHAEL: But all
the guys are!
I'm not stupid,
you know.
Ready?
Ready.
MICHAEL:
No, wait, Mom.
Don't look.
Oh, okay.
Okay, Mom.
You can look now.
[SQUEALS]
[LAUGHS]
Oh, that's great.
Stay here.
E.T.: Ooh.
Oh.
Ouch.
[WHISPERING]
Stop that!
No! Don't!
Ouch.
No, it's a fake knife.
It's a fake!
Ouch. MARY: Okay.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
Okay.
Oh, you look great!
Thank you. Thank you.
E.T.: Thank you.
[E.T. EXCLAIMS]
[E.T. COUGHS]
Be back one hour
after sundown.
No later.
E.T.: Oh.
Bye.
[E.T. WAILING]
Gertie, come here.
Come on.
Trick or treat.
[E.T. GRUNTS]
Home. Home.
Home. Home. Home.
MICHAEL: Be back one hour
after sunset.
No later.
I'll try as fast
as I can, Mike.
You got to cover me.
Well, come on.
Help me.
We'll be waiting
for you, Elliott,
so come back for sure.
It's too bumpy.
We'll have
to walk from here!
[YELLS] E.T.!
Not so high!
[WHOOPING]
Don't crash, please.
[GRUNTS]
[E.T. PURRING]
[RUSTLING]
[COYOTES HOWLING]
I really can't believe
you did this.
[MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Next time you want a pizza,
see who's going to pay...
Your father's gonna
hear about this one.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Mexico.
[VARIOUS TONES PLAY]
ELLIOTT: E.T., it's work...
It's working!
Home.
You did it!
It's working! Home.
Home.
[SHOUTING] E.T., it's working!
[GEIGER COUNTER BEEPING]
MAN:
There's a residual trace.
ELLIOTT: We have to
go now, E.T.
We're so late
already.
[COUGHS]
We have to go
home now, E.T.
E.T.: Hmm?
You should
give them some time.
Ouch.
You could
be happy here.
I could
take care of you.
I wouldn't let
anybody hurt you.
We could grow up
together, E.T.
Home.
[GRUNTS]
[COUGHS]
E.T.?
Uh, how was he
dressed when
last seen?
He was
dressed as a...
Hunchback.
Is there anything
to indicate
that he might
have run away?
Any family problems
or recent arguments?
Um... My husband and I
just separated recently,
and it hasn't been easy
on the children, but...
My father's
in Mexico.
But run away? I...
Where would he
have gone?
MICHAEL: Elliott.
[SOBS] Oh, Elliott!
Don't ever do this
again, Elliott!
Oh, my.
You're so hot.
Run up and draw him
a bath. Quick, Gert.
Sorry I yelled at you.
Um... Thanks very much
for all your trouble.
Is he here?
You've got
to find him, Mike.
Where is he?
In the forest.
At the bald spot.
You've got
to find him.
E.T.!
[THUNDERCLAP]
[GROANING]
No!
[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING]
[KEYS JANGLING]
Mom, would you
come with me?
What is it?
Mary,
just come with me.
Michael, what?
Mom, remember
the goblin?
Michael, what are you
talking about?
Just swear the most
excellent promise
you can make.
Michael.
That's terrific.
Mom.
We're sick.
I think we're dying.
[WHISPERS] Michael.Mom, it's okay.
[GROANS]
Downstairs.
He's not going
to hurt you, Mom.
to hurt you.
Michael,
get her downstairs!
It's the man
from the moon.
The man
from the moon!
You don't know him!
[CRYING]
We can't
leave him alone.
[E.T. CONTINUES CRYING]
[HEAVY BREATHING]
[SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
This is my home!
[WHEEZING]
[HEAVY BREATHING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Home.
MAN: [OVER RADIO]
Check north perimeter.
Does everything
check okay?
MAN:
The collagen unit,
report to the blue level
immediately.
MAN: [OVER RADIO]
Regulate oxygen level
on countdown.
DOCTOR: Does he sleep
at night?
I don't know.
What's the matter
with Elliott?
Have you noticed
any surface sweating?
No.
Has it lost any hair?
He never
had any hair.
Are the children
all right?
Did it ever build anything,
or write anything down?
Uh, no.
You say it
has the ability
to manipulate
its own environment?
He's smart.
He communicates
through Elliott.
Elliott thinks
its thoughts.
No. Elliott...
Elliott feels
his feelings.
WOMAN: [OVER PA]
The dermal sample shows
crystalline refractive index.
Gauge is crystalline.
Repeat, crystalline.
MAN 1: I want an ultrasound.
MAN 2: Do a test area,
damn it.
WOMAN: Run ultrasound, please.
[WOMAN CHATTERING OVER PA]
[BEEPING]
ELLIOTT:
You have no right
to do this.
You're scaring him.
You're scaring him!
MAN 1: What is it? A heart?
Do you think
he's changing color?
WOMAN 1: I don't know.
Are there any other changes?
WOMAN 2: His temperature
has dropped from
20 to 17 centigrade.
Leave him alone.
WOMAN 3: His skin is
cool and clammy.
ELLIOTT: Leave him alone.
I can take care of him.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
DOCTOR: Make up
a saline solution
in the same proportion.
[KEYS JANGLE]
Elliott.
I've been
to the forest.
MAJOR: He shouldn't
talk now.
Well, he has
to talk now, Major.
Elliott,
that machine...
What does it do?
[WEAKLY] The communicator?
Is it still working?
It's doing something.
What?
I really
shouldn't tell.
He came to me.
Elliott,
he came to me, too.
I've been
wishing for this
since I was
10 years old.
I don't want him
to die.
What can we do that
we're not already doing?
He needs to go home.
He's calling
his people...
And I don't know
where they are.
He needs to go home.
Elliott, I don't think
that he was left here
intentionally.
But his being here
is a miracle, Elliott.
It's a miracle,
and you did the best
that anybody could do.
I'm glad
he met you first.
He's got DNA.
[EXCITED CHATTERING]
Positive.
He's got DNA.
Temperature 20 degrees
centigrade.
WOMAN 1: There's a drop
in the creature's
blood pressure
down from 100/70
to 84/64.
E.T.!The boy's condition
is stabilizing.
His blood pressure's
coming back up.
E.T.
Elliott.
WOMAN 2: He's speaking. WOMAN 3: He's talking.
E.T.
Stay with me.
Please.
Stay...
ELLIOTT:
Together.
I'll be right here.
Stay...
Elliott.
[WHISPERING] Stay.
Stay.
WOMAN 1: Creature's pressure
is bottoming out.
His complexes are slow
and widening.
WOMAN 2: How's the boy?
He's converting back
to normal sinus rhythm.
MAN: They're separating. WOMAN 2: Yes.
Boy and creature
are separating.
What does
that mean?
WOMAN 2: The boy's
coming back. We're losing E.T.
E.T., answer me, please.
WOMAN 2: Everything's
going to be fine.Please.
WOMAN 2: Just relax.
No!
E.T., don't go! [ALARM RINGING]
WOMAN: No blood pressure! He's got no pulse
or respiration!
We can't get a pulse
or blood pressure
on the creature!
It doesn't look
like he's breathing.
You can't break
a sterile field like that!
Stand back! [EKG FLATLINING]
ELLIOTT:
Leave him alone!
You're killing him!
MAN: Move it!
Get the boy out
of here.
Stop it!
You're killing him!
Let's go.
Move it out.
You're killing him!
He came to me!
DOCTOR: Let's ventilate him.
Any pulses?
Let's begin CPR.He came to me!
How many compressions?
60 per minute,
please.
WOMAN: Minimal breath sounds.
Calm down.
Calm down. Calm down.
Let's try some
bretyllium.
Can we have
some bretyllium, please?
Getting a pulse? MAN: Five milligrams.
Compressed air.
Compressed air's fine.
Thank you.
IV push.
He's not ventilating.
His pupils are fixed
and dilated.
More drugs!Quiet!
Defibrillate him.
Losing him.
We're losing him.
Let's go. Everybody stand clear.
Clear.
MAN: We're losing him. WOMAN: One more time.
[DEFIBRILLATOR BEEPING]
Quiet!
It's still V. Fib.
DOCTOR: Okay, let's go.
Let's go.
Elliott?
Mom.
WOMAN: He needs calcium
in his body.
MAN: Let's continue CPR,
please.
Would you people
stand back?
Something's
happening.
Ooh, they're
going to die.
Shut up, Greg.
Something is
definitely happening.
Anybody have
any ideas?
MAN 1: EEG's flat. MAN 2: EKG's flat.
Okay, I'm going
to call it.
I think he's dead. No, I don't know.
DOCTOR: All right.
I'm calling it.
What time do you have?
WOMAN: 15:36.
DOCTOR: Fifteen hours,
36 minutes.
Okay, let's
pack him in ice.
Let's leave.
Is he dead, Mama?
I think so,
sweetheart.
Can we wish
for him to come back?
[WHISPERS] Yeah.
I wish.
I wish, too.
Come on, Gert.
We'll wait for Elliott
in the front room.
MAN: Cardiac arrest
was terminated
at 1500 hours
and 36 minutes.
He received
intravenous
lidocaine,
epinephrine
on a lidocaine drip,
2.7% sodium-chloride
solution,
catheters
from the A line,
and the intravenous line
should be sent for culture.
He was monitored with a EEG
and an EKG,
he was
defibrillated...
They're going to have
to take him away now.
They're just going
to cut him all up.
Would you like
to spend some time
alone with him?
[MURMURING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: Could we all step out
for a minute, please?
Look at what
they've done to you.
I'm so sorry.
You must be dead
because...
I don't know
how to feel.
I can't feel
anything anymore.
You've gone
someplace else now.
I'll believe in you
all my life.
Every day.
E.T.,
I love you.
Oh, my God.
E.T. phone home.
[WHOOPING]
Phone home.
Does this mean
they're coming?
Yes.
[YELLING]
E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home...
Stay.
[SHUSHING] Shut up.
Phone.
Phone home.
Quiet!
Phone! Phone!
Phone!
Would you shut up?
Phone home.
E.T. phone home.
Elliott.
Stay. Stay.
[CRYING]
Elliott,
why don't you
come with me?
No.
Elliott, why don't you
come with me?
No. No. No.
It's all right. No!
Would you like
the flower?
[WAILING]
He's alive!
All right!
It's glowing
right here.
Hey! Come here!
Listen! Listen!
[SPEAKING INAUDIBLY]
Are they gone, Mama?
Who's gone, honey?
The boys.
What boys?
I'm supposed to give you
this note when they're gone.
Give it to me now,
Gertie.
[SIGHS] Oh, my God.
Give me
a hand with this.
[EXCLAIMS]
Where's your mask? It's back here.
Well, get it on!I'm trying!
Hey, who are you?
I'm driving.
Open the door,
son.
There's a guy out here.
[YELLS] What do I do?
Well, what are you
waiting for? Let's go!
Well, let's get
out of here, Michael!
I've never driven
forward before!
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[HONKING]
Get the bikes!
Meet us at the playground
at the top
of the hill.
GREG: Let's do it! Here, take my hand.
Come on, Michael! Go!
We're all gonna die,
and they're never going
to give me my license.
Where's
the playground?
It's near the preschool!
Where's that?
I don't know streets!
Mom always drives me.
Son of a bitch.
MAN:
Hey, stop!
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
Where are you going?
To the spaceship.
MARY: Shh! Spaceship?
To the spaceship
to the moon.
Quiet!
Oh, my God.
MAN: Stop the van!
Don't pull them off!
Kid!
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Okay, he's a man
from outer space,
and we're taking him
to his spaceship.
Well, can't he
just beam up?
This is reality,
Greg.
Keep her back! MARY: No!
Hold her back!
MARY: No guns!
MARY: They're children!
No! No! No! No!
MAN: Where are they?
There's nobody here.
[RASPY GRUMBLING]
Where are we going?
To the forest!
[SIREN WAILING]
Follow me!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
We got them
at the bottom
of the hill.
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
This is unit 302.
We've cut the kids off
at the bottom of the hill.
Send backup.
[GRUNTS]
Let's split up.
Okay!
Hang on!
[GRUNTS]
We made it!
Oh, shit!
[GRUNTS]
Whoa! Whoa!
Tell me when it's over!
[GASPS]
Home.
GERTIE:
Stop the car, Mom!
They're over there!
I just wanted
to say goodbye.
He doesn't know
goodbye.
Be good.
Yes.
[SIGHS]
Thank
you.
You're welcome.
Come.
Stay.
[GROANS]
Ouch.
[PURRING]
I'll be
right here.
Bye.