CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
[LA MARSEILLAISE PLAYING]
Narrator: WITH THE COMING
OF THE SECOND WORLD WAR,
MANY EYES
IN IMPRISONED EUROPE
TURNED HOPEFULLY
OR DESPERATELY
TOWARD THE FREEDOM
OF THE AMERICAS.
LISBON BECAME
THE GREAT EMBARKATION POINT,
BUT NOT EVERYBODY COULD GET
TO LISBON DIRECTLY.
AND SO A TORTUOUS ROUNDABOUT
REFUGEE TRAIL
SPRANG UP--
PARIS TO MARSEILLES...
ACROSS THE MEDITERRANEAN
TO ORAN...
THEN BY TRAIN
OR AUTO OR FOOT
ACROSS THE RIM OF AFRICA
TO CASABLANCA
IN FRENCH MOROCCO.
HERE THE FORTUNATE ONES,
THROUGH MONEY
OR INFLUENCE OR LUCK,
MIGHT OBTAIN EXIT VISAS
AND SCURRY TO LISBON
AND FROM LISBON
TO THE NEW WORLD.
BUT THE OTHERS WAIT
IN CASABLANCA...
AND WAIT...
AND WAIT.
"TO ALL OFFICERS--
"TWO GERMAN COURIERS
"CARRYING IMPORTANT
OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
"MURDERED ON TRAIN
FROM ORAN.
"MURDERER AND POSSIBLE
ACCOMPLICES
"HEADED FOR CASABLANCA.
"ROUND UP ALL
SUSPICIOUS CHARACTERS
AND SEARCH THEM
FOR STOLEN DOCUMENT. IMPORTANT."
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
[SHOUTING
IN FRENCH]
[SIREN]
MAY WE SEE
YOUR PAPERS?
I DON'T THINK
I HAVE THEM ON ME.
IN THAT CASE WE'LL HAVE
TO ASK YOU COME ALONG.
WAIT. IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT I...
YES, HERE THEY ARE.
THESE PAPERS EXPIRED
3 WEEKS AGO.
YOU'LL HAVE
TO COME ALONG.
HALT!
[GUNSHOT]
WHAT ON EARTH'S
GOING ON THERE?
I DON'T KNOW,
MY DEAR.
PARDON, MONSIEUR.
PARDON, MADAME.
HAVE YOU NOT HEARD?
WE HEAR VERY LITTLE.
WE UNDERSTAND EVEN LESS.
TWO GERMAN COURIERS
WERE FOUND MURDERED
IN THE UNOCCUPIED
DESERT.
THIS IS THE CUSTOMARY
ROUNDUP OF REFUGEES, LIBERALS,
AND, OF COURSE,
BEAUTIFUL YOUNG GIRLS
FOR MONSIEUR RENAULT,
THE PREFECT OF POLICE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
ALONG WITH THESE
UNHAPPY REFUGEES,
THE SCUM OF EUROPE
HAS GRAVITATED
TO CASABLANCA.
SOME HAVE BEEN WAITING
YEARS FOR A VISA.
I BEG OF YOU, MONSIEUR,
WATCH YOURSELF.
BE ON GUARD. THIS PLACE
IS FULL OF VULTURES,
VULTURES EVERYWHERE.
EVERYWHERE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOT AT ALL. AU REVOIR,
MONSIEUR, MADAME.
AU REVOIR.
AMUSING LITTLE FELLOW.
WAITER!
OH, HOW SILLY OF ME.
WHAT, DEAR?
I'VE LEFT MY WALLET
IN THE HOTEL. I...
[AIRPLANE ENGINES]
PERHAPS TOMORROW
WE'LL BE ON THE PLANE.
GARDE-A-VOUS!
HEIL HITLER.
IT'S VERY GOOD TO SEE YOU
AGAIN, MAJOR STRASSER.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
MAY I PRESENT
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
POLICE PREFECT
OF CASABLANCA?
MAJOR STRASSER.
UNOCCUPIED FRANCE
WELCOMES YOU
TO CASABLANCA.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
IT'S VERY GOOD TO BE HERE.
MAJOR STRASSER, MY AIDE
LIEUTENANT CASSELLE.
CAPTAIN TONELLI,
ITALIAN SERVICE,
AT YOUR COMMAND.
THAT IS KIND OF YOU.
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
YOU MAY FIND
THE CLIMATE
OF CASABLANCA
A TRIFLE WARM.
WE GERMANS MUST GET USED
TO ALL CLIMATES,
FROM RUSSIA TO THE SAHARA,
BUT PERHAPS YOU WERE NOT
REFERRING TO THE WEATHER.
WHAT ELSE,
MY DEAR MAJOR?
THE MURDER OF THE COURIERS--
WHAT HAS BEEN DONE?
REALIZING THE IMPORTANCE
OF THE CASE,
WE'RE ROUNDING UP TWICE THE
USUAL NUMBER OF SUSPECTS.
WE KNOW WHO
THE MURDERER IS.
GOOD.
IS HE IN CUSTODY?
OH, THERE'S NO HURRY.
TONIGHT HE'LL BE AT RICK'S.
EVERYBODY COMES TO RICK'S.
I'VE ALREADY HEARD ABOUT THIS
CAFE, AND ALSO ABOUT MR. RICK.
♪ IT HAD TO BE YOU ♪
♪ I WANDERED AROUND ♪
♪ AND FINALLY FOUND
THE SOMEBODY WHO ♪
♪ COULD MAKE ME BE TRUE ♪
♪ COULD MAKE ME BE BLUE ♪
♪ AND EVEN BE GLAD ♪
♪ JUST TO BE SAD
THINKING OF YOU ♪
♪ SOME OTHERS I'VE SEEN ♪
♪ MIGHT NEVER BE MEAN ♪
♪ MIGHT NEVER BE CROSS ♪
♪ OR TRY TO BE BOSS ♪
♪ BUT THEY WOULDN'T DO ♪
♪ FOR NOBODY ELSE
GAVE ME A THRILL ♪
♪ HONEY,
WITH ALL YOUR FAULTS ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU STILL ♪
♪ IT HAD TO BE YOU ♪
♪ WONDERFUL YOU ♪
♪ HAD TO BE YOU ♪
♪ 'CAUSE ♪
♪ MY HAIR IS CURLY ♪
♪ MY TEETH ARE PEARLY... ♪
WAITING,
WAITING, WAITING.
I'LL NEVER
GET OUT OF HERE.
I'LL DIE
IN CASABLANCA.
CAN'T YOU MAKE IT JUST
A LITTLE MORE? PLEASE?
SORRY, MADAME, BUT DIAMONDS
ARE A DRAG ON THE MARKET.
EVERYBODY SELLS DIAMONDS.
THERE ARE DIAMONDS
EVERYWHERE. 2,400.
ALL RIGHT.
THE TRUCKS ARE READY.
THE MEN ARE WAITING.
EVERYTHING IS--
[MEN SPEAKING GERMAN]
IT'S THE FISHING SMACK
SANTIAGO.
IT LEAVES AT 1:00
TOMORROW NIGHT
HERE FROM THE END OF
LA MEDINA. THIRD BOAT.
THANK YOU.
BRING 15,000 FRANCS
IN CASH.
REMEMBER, IN CASH.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
CHEERIO.
OPEN UP, ABDUL.
YES, HERR PROFESSOR.
GRAZIE, SIGNORE.
RED FOR MADAME.
BLACK FOR MONSIEUR.
UM...WAITER.
YES, MADAME?
WILL YOU ASK RICK IF HE'LL
HAVE A DRINK WITH US?
MADAME, HE NEVER DRINKS
WITH CUSTOMERS. NEVER.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN IT.
WHAT MAKES SALOON KEEPERS
SO SNOBBISH?
PERHAPS
IF YOU TOLD HIM
I RAN THE SECOND LARGEST
BANKING HOUSE IN AMSTERDAM.
SECOND LARGEST?
THAT WOULDN'T
IMPRESS RICK.
THE LEADING BANKER
IN AMSTERDAM
IS NOW THE PASTRY
CHEF IN OUR KITCHEN.
WE HAVE SOMETHING
TO LOOK FORWARD TO.
AND HIS FATHER
IS THE BELLBOY.
Waiter:
FOR MADAME.
MONSIEUR.
Waiter:
FOR MONSIEUR.
EXCUSE ME.
SORRY, SIR.
THIS IS A PRIVATE ROOM.
OF ALL THE NERVE!
WHO DO YOU--
I KNOW THERE'S
GAMBLING IN THERE.
THERE IS NO SECRET.
YOU DARE NOT
KEEP ME OUT OF HERE.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE?
I'VE BEEN IN EVERY
GAMBLING ROOM
BETWEEN HONOLULU
AND BERLIN.
IF YOU THINK I'LL BE
KEPT OUT OF A SALOON
LIKE THIS, YOU ARE
VERY MUCH MISTAKEN.
EXCUSE ME.
HELLO, RICK.
YOUR CASH IS GOOD
AT THE BAR.
WHAT? DO YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
I DO. YOU'RE LUCKY
THE BAR'S OPEN TO YOU.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS! I SHALL
REPORT IT TO THE ANGRIFF.
RICK, WATCHING YOU
WITH THE DEUTSCHE BANK,
ONE WOULD THINK YOU'VE BEEN
DOING THIS ALL YOUR LIFE.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I HAVEN'T?
NOTHING, BUT WHEN
YOU FIRST CAME
TO CASABLANCA,
I THOUGHT--
YOU THOUGHT WHAT?
WHAT RIGHT DO I
HAVE TO THINK?
MAY I?
TOO BAD ABOUT THOSE
2 GERMAN COURIERS.
THEY GOT A LUCKY BREAK.
YESTERDAY THEY WERE
JUST TWO GERMAN CLERKS.
TODAY THEY'RE
THE HONORED DEAD.
YOU ARE A VERY
CYNICAL PERSON.
FORGIVE ME
FOR SAYING SO.
I FORGIVE YOU.
WILL YOU HAVE
A DRINK WITH ME?
NO.
I FORGOT. YOU NEVER
DRINK WITH ANYONE.
I'LL HAVE ANOTHER,
PLEASE.
YOU DESPISE ME,
DON'T YOU?
IF I GAVE YOU ANY THOUGHT,
I PROBABLY WOULD.
WHY? YOU OBJECT
TO THE KIND OF
BUSINESS I DO, HUH?
THINK OF ALL THOSE
POOR REFUGEES
WHO'D ROT HERE IF I
DIDN'T HELP THEM.
THAT'S NOT SO BAD.
THROUGH WAYS
OF MY OWN,
I PROVIDE THEM
WITH EXIT VISAS.
FOR A PRICE, UGARTE,
FOR A PRICE.
BUT THINK OF
ALL THE POOR DEVILS
WHO CAN'T MEET
RENAULT'S PRICE.
I GET IT
FOR THEM FOR HALF.
IS THAT SO PARASITIC?
I DON'T MIND A PARASITE.
I OBJECT TO A CUT-RATE ONE.
WELL, AFTER TONIGHT,
I'LL BE THROUGH WITH
THE WHOLE BUSINESS.
I'M LEAVING, FINALLY,
THIS CASABLANCA.
WHO'D YOU BRIBE
FOR YOUR VISA,
RENAULT OR YOURSELF?
MYSELF. I FOUND MYSELF
MUCH MORE REASONABLE.
LOOK, RICK.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS?
SOMETHING THAT EVEN YOU
HAVE NEVER SEEN.
LETTERS OF TRANSIT
SIGNED BY GENERAL DE GAULLE.
CANNOT BE RESCINDED,
NOT EVEN QUESTIONED.
ONE MOMENT.
TONIGHT I'LL BE
SELLING THOSE
FOR MORE MONEY THAN EVEN
I'VE EVER DREAMED OF,
AND THEN ADDIO,
CASABLANCA.
YOU KNOW, RICK,
I HAVE MANY FRIENDS,
BUT SOMEHOW, BECAUSE
YOU DESPISE ME,
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
I TRUST.
WILL YOU KEEP THESE
FOR ME?
FOR HOW LONG?
PERHAPS AN HOUR. PERHAPS
A LITTLE LONGER.
I DON'T WANT THEM HERE
OVERNIGHT.
DON'T BE AFRAID
OF THAT.
PLEASE KEEP THEM
FOR ME.
THANK YOU. I KNEW
I COULD TRUST YOU.
OH, WAITER. I'M
EXPECTING SOME PEOPLE.
IF ANYBODY ASKS FOR ME,
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
YES, MONSIEUR.
RICK, I HOPE YOU'RE MORE
IMPRESSED WITH ME NOW.
IF YOU'LL FORGIVE ME,
I'LL SHARE MY GOOD LUCK
WITH YOUR
ROULETTE WHEEL.
JUST A MOMENT.
I HEARD A RUMOR
THOSE 2 GERMAN COURIERS
WERE CARRYING
LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
HUH?
OH. I'VE HEARD
THAT RUMOR, TOO.
POOR DEVILS.
YOU'RE RIGHT, UGARTE.
I AM A LITTLE MORE
IMPRESSED WITH YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
♪ SAY, WHO'S
GOT TROUBLE? ♪
♪ WE GOT TROUBLE ♪
♪ HOW MUCH TROUBLE? ♪
♪ TOO MUCH TROUBLE ♪
♪ WELL, NOW,
DON'T YOU FROWN ♪
♪ JUST KNUCKLE DOWN
AND KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♪ WHO'S UNHAPPY? ♪
♪ WE'RE UNHAPPY ♪
♪ HOW UNHAPPY? ♪
♪ TOO UNHAPPY ♪
♪ UH-OH,
THAT WON'T DO ♪
♪ WHEN YOU ARE BLUE,
JUST KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♪ WHO'S UNLUCKY? ♪
♪ WE'RE UNLUCKY ♪
♪ HOW UNLUCKY? ♪
♪ TOO UNLUCKY ♪
♪ BUT YOUR LUCK'LL
CHANGE ♪
♪ IF YOU'LL ARRANGE
TO KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♪ WHO'S GOT NOTHIN'? ♪
♪ WE GOT NOTHIN' ♪
♪ HOW MUCH NOTHIN'? ♪
♪ TOO MUCH NOTHIN' ♪
♪ SAY, NOTHIN'S NOT
AN AWFUL LOT ♪
♪ BUT KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♪ NOW WHO'S HAPPY? ♪
♪ WE'RE HAPPY ♪
♪ JUST HOW HAPPY? ♪
♪ VERY HAPPY ♪
♪ THAT'S THE WAY
WE'RE GONNA STAY ♪
♪ SO KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
[KNOCK KNOCK KNOCK]
♪ NOW WHO'S LUCKY? ♪
♪ WE'RE ALL LUCKY ♪
♪ JUST HOW LUCKY? ♪
♪ VERY LUCKY ♪
♪ WELL, SMILE UP, THEN ♪
♪ AND ONCE AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S KNOCK ON WOOD ♪
HELLO, RICK.
HELLO, FERRARI.
HOW'S BUSINESS
AT THE BLUE PARROT?
FINE, BUT I'D LIKE
TO BUY YOUR CAFE.
IT'S NOT FOR SALE.
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
MY OFFER.
IT'S NOT FOR SALE
AT ANY PRICE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FOR SAM?
I DON'T BUY OR SELL
HUMAN BEINGS.
TOO BAD. THAT'S CASABLANCA'S
LEADING COMMODITY.
IN REFUGEES ALONE,
WE COULD MAKE A FORTUNE.
YOU COULD WORK WITH ME
THROUGH THE BLACK MARKET.
SUPPOSE YOU RUN
YOUR BUSINESS,
AND LET ME RUN MINE.
SUPPOSE WE ASK SAM.
MAYBE HE'D LIKE A CHANGE.
SUPPOSE WE DO.
WHEN WILL YOU REALIZE
THAT IN THIS WORLD TODAY,
ISOLATIONISM IS NO LONGER
A PRACTICAL POLICY?
SAM, FERRARI WANTS YOU
TO WORK FOR HIM.
I LIKE IT FINE HERE.
HE'LL DOUBLE
WHAT I PAY YOU.
YEAH,
BUT I AIN'T GOT TIME
TO SPEND THE MONEY
I MAKE HERE.
SORRY.
BOSS' PRIVATE STOCK...
BECAUSE, YVONNE,
I LOVE YOU.
OH, SHUT UP.
ALL RIGHT. FOR YOU,
I SHUT UP...
BECAUSE, YVONNE,
I LOVE YOU.
UH-OH.
SOME GERMANS
GAVE THIS CHECK.
IS IT ALL RIGHT?
WHERE WERE YOU
LAST NIGHT?
THAT'S SO LONG AGO,
I DON'T REMEMBER.
WILL I SEE YOU
TONIGHT?
I NEVER MAKE PLANS
THAT FAR AHEAD.
GIVE ME ANOTHER.
SACHA,
SHE'S HAD ENOUGH.
DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
FILL IT UP.
YVONNE, I LOVE YOU,
BUT HE PAYS ME.
RICK, I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF HAVING YOU--
SACHA, CALL A CAB.
LET'S GET YOUR COAT.
YOU'RE GOING HOME.
YOU'VE HAD A LITTLE
TOO MUCH TO DRINK.
HEY, TAXI.
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU
ARE, PUSHING ME AROUND?
I WAS A FOOL TO FALL
FOR A MAN LIKE YOU.
MAKE SURE SHE GETS HOME...
AND COME RIGHT BACK.
YES, BOSS.
HELLO, RICK.
HELLO, LOUIS.
HOW EXTRAVAGANT YOU ARE,
THROWING AWAY WOMEN LIKE THAT.
SOMEDAY THEY MAY
BE SCARCE.
I THINK I'LL CALL ON YVONNE,
MAYBE GET HER ON THE REBOUND.
WHEN IT COMES TO WOMEN,
YOU'RE A TRUE DEMOCRAT.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
IF HE GETS A WORD IN,
IT'LL BE A MAJOR
ITALIAN VICTORY.
THE PLANE TO LISBON.
YOU WOULD LIKE
TO BE ON IT.
WHY?
WHAT'S IN LISBON?
THE CLIPPER TO AMERICA.
I'VE OFTEN SPECULATED
ON WHY YOU DON'T RETURN.
DID YOU ABSCOND
WITH THE CHURCH FUNDS?
DID YOU RUN OFF WITH
A SENATOR'S WIFE?
I'D LIKE TO THINK
THAT YOU KILLED A MAN.
IT'S THE ROMANTIC
IN ME.
IT'S A COMBINATION
OF ALL 3.
WHAT IN HEAVEN'S NAME
BROUGHT YOU TO CASABLANCA?
MY HEALTH.
I CAME TO CASABLANCA
FOR THE WATERS.
THE WATERS? WHAT WATERS?
WE'RE IN THE DESERT.
I WAS MISINFORMED.
EXCUSE ME,
MONSIEUR RICK.
A GENTLEMAN INSIDE
HAS WON 20,000 FRANCS,
AND THE CASHIER
WOULD LIKE SOME MONEY.
I'LL GET IT
FROM THE SAFE.
I'M SO UPSET, MONSIEUR RICK.
FORGET IT, EMIL.
THINGS LIKE THAT
HAPPEN ALL THE TIME.
I'M AWFULLY SORRY.
[PLAYING BABY FACE]
THERE'S GOING TO BE
SOME EXCITEMENT TONIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
AN ARREST IN YOUR CAFE.
WHAT, AGAIN?
THIS IS
NO ORDINARY ARREST.
A MURDERER, NO LESS.
IF YOU'RE THINKING
OF WARNING HIM,
DON'T
PUT YOURSELF OUT.
HE CANNOT POSSIBLY
ESCAPE.
I STICK MY NECK OUT
FOR NOBODY.
A WISE FOREIGN POLICY.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
WE COULD'VE
MADE THIS ARREST
EARLIER THIS EVENING
AT THE BLUE PARROT.
OUT OF MY REGARD FOR YOU,
WE'RE STAGING IT HERE.
IT WILL AMUSE
YOUR CUSTOMERS.
OUR ENTERTAINMENT'S
ENOUGH.
WE'LL HAVE AN IMPORTANT
GUEST HERE TONIGHT,
MAJOR STRASSER
OF THE THIRD REICH, NO LESS.
WE WANT HIM TO BE HERE
WHEN WE MAKE THE ARREST.
A LITTLE DEMONSTRATION
OF THE EFFICIENCY
OF MY ADMINISTRATION.
WHAT'S STRASSER
DOING HERE?
HE CERTAINLY DIDN'T
COME TO CASABLANCA
TO WITNESS
A DEMONSTRATION
OF YOUR EFFICIENCY.
PERHAPS NOT.
IT SHALL NOT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LOUIS, SOMETHING'S
ON YOUR MIND.
WHY DON'T YOU
SPILL IT?
HOW OBSERVANT YOU ARE.
I WANTED TO GIVE YOU
A WORD OF ADVICE.
YEAH?
HAVE A BRANDY?
THANK YOU.
THERE ARE MANY EXIT VISAS
SOLD IN THIS CAFE,
BUT WE KNOW
YOU'VE NEVER SOLD ONE.
THAT IS THE REASON
WE PERMIT YOU TO REMAIN OPEN.
I THOUGHT IT WAS BECAUSE
I LET YOU WIN AT ROULETTE.
THAT IS ANOTHER REASON.
A MAN ARRIVED IN CASABLANCA
ON HIS WAY TO AMERICA.
HE'LL OFFER A FORTUNE
TO ANYONE
WHO WILL FURNISH HIM
WITH AN EXIT VISA.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
VICTOR LASZLO.
VICTOR LASZLO?
THAT IS THE FIRST TIME I'VE
EVER SEEN YOU SO IMPRESSED.
WELL, HE'S IMPRESSED
HALF THE WORLD.
IT'S MY DUTY TO SEE HE DOESN'T
IMPRESS THE OTHER HALF.
RICK, LASZLO MUST NEVER
REACH AMERICA.
HE STAYS IN CASABLANCA.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING
TO SEE HOW HE MANAGES.
MANAGES WHAT?
HIS ESCAPE.
BUT I TOLD YOU--
STOP IT. SINCE HIS ESCAPE
FROM A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
THE NAZIS HAVE CHASED HIM
ALL OVER EUROPE.
THIS IS THE END
OF THE CHASE.
20,000 FRANCS
SAYS IT ISN'T.
IS THAT
A SERIOUS OFFER?
I JUST PAID OUT 20.
I'D LIKE IT BACK.
MAKE IT 10.
I'M ONLY A POOR,
CORRUPT OFFICIAL.
OK.
DONE. NO MATTER
HOW CLEVER HE IS,
HE STILL NEEDS
AN EXIT VISA.
I SHOULD SAY 2.
WHY 2?
HE'S TRAVELING
WITH A LADY.
HE'LL TAKE ONE.
I THINK NOT.
I'VE SEEN THE LADY.
IF HE DIDN'T LEAVE
HER IN MARSEILLES,
HE CERTAINLY WON'T
LEAVE HER IN CASABLANCA.
MAYBE HE'S NOT QUITE
AS ROMANTIC AS YOU ARE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THERE'S NO EXIT VISA
FOR HIM.
WHATEVER GAVE YOU
THE IMPRESSION
THAT I'D BE INTERESTED
IN HELPING LASZLO ESCAPE?
BECAUSE I SUSPECT THAT
UNDER THAT CYNICAL SHELL,
YOU'RE AT HEART
A SENTIMENTALIST.
LAUGH IF YOU WILL,
BUT I'M FAMILIAR
WITH YOUR RECORD.
LET ME POINT OUT
JUST 2 ITEMS.
IN 1935, YOU RAN GUNS
TO ETHIOPIA.
IN 1936,
YOU FOUGHT IN SPAIN
ON THE LOYALIST SIDE.
I GOT WELL PAID FOR IT
ON BOTH OCCASIONS.
THE WINNING SIDE
WOULD HAVE PAID YOU
MUCH BETTER.
MAYBE.
IT SEEMS YOU'RE DETERMINED
TO KEEP LASZLO HERE.
I HAVE MY ORDERS.
I SEE. GESTAPO SPANK.
YOU OVERESTIMATE
THE INFLUENCE
OF THE GESTAPO.
I DON'T INTERFERE
WITH THEM.
THEY DON'T
INTERFERE WITH ME.
IN CASABLANCA, I'M
MASTER OF MY FATE.
MAJOR STRASSER'S
HERE, SIR.
YOU WERE SAYING.
EXCUSE ME.
CARL, SEE THAT MAJOR STRASSER
GETS A GOOD TABLE.
ONE CLOSE TO THE LADIES.
I'VE ALREADY
GIVEN HIM THE BEST,
KNOWING HE'S GERMAN
AND WOULD TAKE IT
ANYWAY.
TAKE HIM QUIETLY.
2 GUARDS AT EVERY DOOR.
YES, SIR.
EVERYTHING
IS READY, SIR.
GO AHEAD.
GOOD EVENING,
GENTLEMEN.
GOOD EVENING, CAPTAIN.
WON'T YOU JOIN US?
THANK YOU.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO HAVE YOU HERE, MAJOR.
CHAMPAGNE
AND CAVIAR.
MAY I RECOMMEND
VEUVE CLIQUOT '26?
A GOOD FRENCH WINE.
VERY WELL, SIR.
VERY INTERESTING CLUB.
ESPECIALLY SO
TONIGHT, MAJOR.
IN A FEW MINUTES
YOU'LL SEE THE ARREST
OF THE MAN WHO MURDERED
YOUR COURIERS.
I EXPECTED NO LESS,
CAPTAIN.
MONSIEUR UGARTE.
OH.
YES?
WILL YOU PLEASE
COME WITH US?
CERTAINLY.
MAY I FIRST PLEASE
CASH MY CHIPS?
[SPEAKING
FRENCH]
PRETTY LUCKY, HUH?
2,000, PLEASE.
2,000.
THANK YOU.
[GUNSHOTS]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
RICK! RICK, HELP ME.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
YOU CAN'T GET AWAY.
HIDE ME. DO SOMETHING.
YOU MUST HELP ME!
DO SOMETHING!
RICK!
EXCELLENT, CAPTAIN.
WHEN THEY COME
TO GET ME, RICK,
I HOPE YOU'RE
MORE OF A HELP.
I STICK MY NECK OUT
FOR NOBODY.
I'M SORRY THERE WAS
A DISTURBANCE, FOLKS,
BUT IT'S ALL OVER NOW.
EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST SIT DOWN
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
ENJOY YOURSELVES.
ALL RIGHT, SAM.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
RICK.
RICK, THIS IS MAJOR
HEINRICH STRASSER
OF THE THIRD REICH.
HOW DO YOU DO?
YOU ALREADY KNOW
HERR HEINZE.
PLEASE JOIN US,
MR. RICK.
WE ARE HONORED
TONIGHT, RICK.
MAJOR STRASSER
IS ONE REASON
THE THIRD REICH
ENJOYS
THE REPUTATION
IT HAS TODAY.
YOU REPEAT
THIRD REICH
AS THOUGH YOU EXPECTED
THERE TO BE OTHERS.
PERSONALLY, MAJOR
I'LL TAKE WHAT COMES.
MAY I ASK A FEW QUESTIONS--
UNOFFICIALLY, OF COURSE?
MAKE IT OFFICIAL
IF YOU LIKE.
WHAT IS YOUR
NATIONALITY?
I'M A DRUNKARD.
THAT MAKES RICK
A CITIZEN OF THE WORLD.
I WAS BORN IN NEW YORK CITY
IF THAT'LL HELP YOU ANY.
YOU CAME HERE FROM PARIS
DURING THE OCCUPATION?
THERE'S NO SECRET
ABOUT THAT.
ARE YOU ONE
OF THOSE PEOPLE
WHO CANNOT
IMAGINE GERMANS
IN THEIR BELOVED PARIS?
IT'S NOT PARTICULARLY
MY BELOVED PARIS.
CAN YOU IMAGINE US
IN LONDON?
WHEN YOU GET THERE,
ASK ME.
DIPLOMATIST.
HOW ABOUT NEW YORK?
THERE ARE CERTAIN SECTIONS
OF NEW YORK, MAJOR,
THAT I WOULDN'T ADVISE YOU
TO TRY TO INVADE.
WHO DO YOU THINK
WILL WIN THE WAR?
I HAVEN'T
THE SLIGHTEST IDEA.
RICK IS NEUTRAL
ABOUT EVERYTHING.
THAT INCLUDES
WOMEN, TOO.
YOU WERE NOT ALWAYS
SO NEUTRAL.
WE HAVE A COMPLETE
DOSSIER ON YOU.
"RICHARD BLAINE,
AMERICAN, 37.
CANNOT RETURN
TO HIS COUNTRY."
THE REASON
IS A LITTLE VAGUE.
WE ALSO KNOW WHAT
YOU DID IN PARIS
AND WHY YOU LEFT PARIS.
DON'T WORRY. WE AREN'T
GOING TO BROADCAST IT.
ARE MY EYES
REALLY BROWN?
FORGIVE MY CURIOSITY.
THE POINT IS,
AN ENEMY OF THE REICH
HAS COME TO CASABLANCA,
AND WE ARE CHECKING UP
ON ANYBODY WHO CAN HELP.
MY INTEREST IN WHETHER
VICTOR LASZLO STAYS OR GOES
IS PURELY A SPORTING ONE.
IN THIS CASE, YOU HAVE
NO SYMPATHY FOR THE FOX?
NOT PARTICULARLY.
I UNDERSTAND THE HOUND'S
POINT OF VIEW, TOO.
VICTOR LASZLO PUBLISHED
THE FOULEST LIES
IN THE PRAGUE NEWSPAPERS
UNTIL WE MARCHED IN.
EVEN AFTER THAT,
HE PRINTED SCANDAL
SHEETS IN A CELLAR.
ONE MUST ADMIT
HE HAS GREAT
COURAGE.
I ADMIT
HE'S VERY CLEVER.
3 TIMES HE SLIPPED
THROUGH OUR FINGERS.
IN PARIS HE CONTINUED
HIS ACTIVITIES.
WE INTEND NOT
TO LET IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
EXCUSE ME, GENTLEMEN.
YOUR BUSINESS IS POLITICS,
MINE IS RUNNING
A SALOON.
GOOD EVENING,
MR. BLAINE.
YOU SEE, MAJOR,
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT RICK.
PERHAPS.
YES, MONSIEUR?
I RESERVED A TABLE.
VICTOR LASZLO.
YES, MONSIEUR LASZLO.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
TWO COINTREAUS, PLEASE.
OUI, MONSIEUR.
I SAW NO ONE OF UGARTE'S
DESCRIPTION.
VICTOR, I FEEL SOMEHOW
WE SHOULDN'T STAY HERE.
IF WE WOULD
WALK OUT SO SOON,
IT WOULD ONLY CALL
ATTENTION TO US.
PERHAPS UGARTE'S IN SOME
OTHER PART OF THE CAFE.
EXCUSE ME, BUT YOU
LOOK LIKE A COUPLE
WHO ARE ON THEIR WAY
TO AMERICA.
YOU'LL FIND A MARKET
THERE FOR THIS RING.
I'M FORCED
TO SELL IT.
THANK YOU, BUT I--
PERHAPS FOR THE LADY.
THE RING'S QUITE UNIQUE.
OH, YES, I'M
VERY INTERESTED.
GOOD.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
BERGER. NORWEGIAN.
AT YOUR SERVICE.
VICTOR.
I'LL MEET YOU IN A FEW
MINUTES AT THE BAR.
NO, WE DON'T WANT
TO BUY THE RING,
BUT THANK YOU FOR
SHOWING IT TO US.
THAT'S
YOUR DECISION?
I'M SORRY. IT IS.
MONSIEUR LASZLO,
IS IT NOT?
YES.
I AM CAPTAIN RENAULT,
PREFECT OF POLICE.
YES. WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT?
MERELY TO WELCOME YOU
TO CASABLANCA
AND TO WISH YOU
A PLEASANT STAY.
IT ISN'T OFTEN WE HAVE
SO DISTINGUISHED A VISITOR.
THANK YOU.
FORGIVE ME, CAPTAIN.
THE PRESENT FRENCH
ADMINISTRATION
HASN'T ALWAYS BEEN
SO CORDIAL.
MAY I PRESENT
MISS ILSA LUND?
I WAS INFORMED YOU WERE
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
EVER TO VISIT CASABLANCA.
THAT WAS A GROSS
UNDERSTATEMENT.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
WON'T YOU JOIN US?
IF YOU WILL PERMIT ME.
NO, EMIL, PLEASE,
A BOTTLE OF CHAMPAGNE.
PUT IT ON MY BILL.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE.
PLEASE. IT'S A LITTLE
GAME WE PLAY.
THEY PUT IT ON THE BILL,
I TEAR UP THE BILL.
IT IS VERY CONVENIENT.
CAPTAIN, THE BOY WHO'S
PLAYING THE PIANO--
SOMEWHERE I'VE SEEN HIM.
SAM? HE CAME FROM PARIS
WITH RICK.
RICK? WHO'S HE?
MADEMOISELLE, YOU'RE IN
RICK'S, AND RICK IS, UH...
WELL, HE'S THE KIND OF MAN
THAT IF I WERE A WOMAN,
AND I WERE NOT AROUND,
I SHOULD BE IN LOVE WITH RICK.
WHAT A FOOL I AM,
TALKING TO A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
ABOUT ANOTHER MAN.
EXCUSE ME.
AH, MAJOR.
MADEMOISELLE LUND
AND MONSIEUR LASZLO,
MAY I PRESENT
MAJOR HEINRICH STRASSER.
THIS IS A PLEASURE
I'VE LONG LOOKED FORWARD TO.
EXCUSE ME
IF I'M NOT GRACIOUS,
BUT, YOU SEE,
I'M A CZECHOSLOVAKIAN.
YOU WERE
A CZECHOSLOVAKIAN.
NOW YOU'RE A SUBJECT
OF THE GERMAN REICH.
I'VE NEVER ACCEPTED
THAT PRIVILEGE,
AND I'M NOW
ON FRENCH SOIL.
I SHOULD LIKE TO DISCUSS
SOME MATTERS ARISING
FROM YOUR PRESENCE
ON FRENCH SOIL.
THIS IS HARDLY
THE TIME OR PLACE.
THEN WE'LL STATE
ANOTHER TIME AND PLACE.
TOMORROW AT 10:00
IN THE PREFECT'S OFFICE...
WITH MADEMOISELLE.
CAPTAIN, I'M UNDER
YOUR AUTHORITY.
IS IT YOUR ORDER
THAT WE COME
TO YOUR OFFICE?
LET'S SAY
IT IS MY REQUEST--
THAT'S A MORE
PLEASANT WORD.
VERY WELL.
MADEMOISELLE.
A VERY CLEVER
TACTICAL RETREAT, MAJOR.
THIS TIME THEY REALLY
MEAN TO STOP ME.
VICTOR, I'M
AFRAID FOR YOU.
WE'VE BEEN IN DIFFICULT PLACES
BEFORE, HAVEN'T WE?
[APPLAUSE]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
I MUST FIND OUT
WHAT BERGER KNOWS.
BE CAREFUL.
I WILL.
DON'T WORRY.
MONSIEUR BERGER, THE RING,
COULD I SEE IT AGAIN?
YES.
CHAMPAGNE COCKTAIL,
PLEASE.
I RECOGNIZE YOU FROM
THE NEWS PHOTOGRAPHS.
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
ONE IS APT TO LOSE WEIGHT.
WE READ 5 TIMES
YOU WERE KILLED
IN 5 DIFFERENT
PLACES.
AS YOU SEE, IT WAS TRUE
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
THANK HEAVEN
I FOUND YOU, BERGER.
I'M LOOKING FOR
A MAN NAMED UGARTE.
HE'S SUPPOSED
TO HELP ME.
UGARTE CANNOT EVEN
HELP HIMSELF.
HE'S UNDER ARREST
FOR MURDER.
HE WAS ARRESTED
HERE TONIGHT.
I SEE.
BUT WE
WHO ARE STILL FREE
WILL DO WHAT WE CAN.
WE ARE ORGANIZED,
MONSIEUR...
UNDERGROUND LIKE
EVERYWHERE ELSE.
TOMORROW NIGHT
THERE'S A MEETING.
IF YOU'LL COME--
Bartender: MONSIEUR.
BRAVO!
WILL YOU ASK
THE PIANO PLAYER
TO COME OVER HERE,
PLEASE?
VERY WELL,
MADEMOISELLE.
HOW'S THE JEWELRY
BUSINESS, BERGER?
NOT SO GOOD.
CHECK, PLEASE.
TOO BAD YOU WEREN'T HERE
EARLIER, MONSIEUR LASZLO.
WE HAD QUITE A BIT
OF EXCITEMENT,
DIDN'T WE, BERGER?
YES.
EXCUSE ME.
MY BILL.
NO. TWO CHAMPAGNE
COCKTAILS. PLEASE.
HELLO, SAM.
HELLO, MISS ILSA.
I NEVER EXPECTED
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME.
YES, MA'AM.
A LOT OF WATER
UNDER THE BRIDGE.
SOME OF THE OLD
SONGS, SAM.
YES, MA'AM.
[PLAYS PIANO]
WHERE IS RICK?
I DON'T KNOW.
I AIN'T SEEN HIM ALL NIGHT.
WHEN WILL HE
BE BACK?
NOT TONIGHT.
HE AIN'T COMIN'.
HE WENT HOME.
DOES HE ALWAYS
LEAVE SO EARLY?
OH, HE NEVER--
HE'S GOT A GIRL
UP TO THE BLUE PARROT.
GOES UP THERE
ALL THE TIME.
YOU USED TO BE
A MUCH BETTER LIAR.
LEAVE HIM ALONE,
MISS ILSA.
YOU'RE BAD LUCK
TO HIM.
PLAY IT ONCE, SAM,
FOR OLD TIMES' SAKE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN, MISS ILSA.
PLAY IT, SAM.
PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY.
I CAN'T REMEMBER IT.
I'M A LITTLE RUSTY ON IT.
I'LL HUM IT FOR YOU.
♪ DA DI DA DI DA DUM ♪
♪ DA DI DEE DEE DEE DUM ♪
SING IT, SAM.
♪ YOU MUST REMEMBER THIS ♪
♪ A KISS IS JUST A KISS ♪
♪ A SIGH IS JUST A SIGH ♪
♪ THE FUNDAMENTAL
THINGS APPLY ♪
♪ AS TIME GOES BY ♪
♪ AND WHEN
TWO LOVERS WOO ♪
♪ THEY STILL SAY
I LOVE YOU ♪
♪ ON THAT YOU CAN RELY ♪
♪ NO MATTER
WHAT THE FUTURE BRINGS ♪
♪ AS TIME GOES BY ♪
SAM, I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
NEVER TO PLAY--
YOU WERE ASKING
ABOUT RICK. HERE HE IS.
MADEMOISELLE,
MAY I PRESENT--
HELLO, ILSA.
HELLO, RICK.
YOU'VE ALREADY MET RICK,
MADEMOISELLE.
THEN PERHAPS YOU ALSO--
THIS IS
MR. LASZLO.
HOW DO YOU DO?
ONE HEARS A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT RICK IN CASABLANCA.
AND ABOUT VICTOR LASZLO
EVERYWHERE.
WON'T YOU JOIN US
FOR A DRINK?
OH, NO. RICK NEVER--
THANKS. I WILL.
WELL...A PRECEDENT
IS BEING BROKEN. EMIL.
THIS IS A VERY
INTERESTING CAFE.
I CONGRATULATE YOU.
I CONGRATULATE YOU
FOR YOUR WORK.
THANK YOU. I TRY.
WE ALL TRY.
YOU SUCCEED.
I CAN'T GET OVER
YOU TWO.
SHE WAS ASKING
ABOUT YOU EARLIER
IN A WAY THAT MADE ME
EXTREMELY JEALOUS.
I WASN'T SURE
YOU WERE THE SAME.
THE LAST TIME WE MET--
IT WAS LA BELLE AURORE.
HOW NICE. YOU REMEMBERED.
THAT WAS THE DAY THE GERMANS
MARCHED INTO PARIS.
NOT AN EASY DAY
TO FORGET.
I REMEMBER
EVERY DETAIL.
THE GERMANS WORE GRAY.
YOU WORE BLUE.
YES. I PUT
THAT DRESS AWAY.
WHEN THE GERMANS MARCH
OUT, I'LL WEAR IT AGAIN.
RICKY, YOU'RE BECOMING
QUITE HUMAN.
I SUPPOSE WE HAVE
TO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
ILSA,
IT'S LATE.
SO IT IS, AND WE HAVE
A CURFEW HERE IN CASABLANCA.
IT WOULD NEVER DO
FOR THE CHIEF OF POLICE
TO BE FOUND
DRINKING AFTER HOURS
AND HAVE TO FINE HIMSELF.
I HOPE WE DIDN'T
OVERSTAY OUR WELCOME.
YOUR CHECK, SIR.
OH, IT'S MY PARTY.
ANOTHER PRECEDENT
GONE.
THIS HAS BEEN
A VERY INTERESTING EVENING.
I'LL CALL YOU A CAB.
GASOLINE RATIONING.
WE'LL
COME AGAIN.
ANY TIME.
SAY GOOD NIGHT
TO SAM FOR ME.
I WILL.
THERE'S STILL
NOBODY IN THE WORLD
WHO CAN PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY LIKE SAM.
HE HASN'T PLAYED IT
IN A LONG TIME.
GOOD NIGHT.
PUZZLING FELLOW, THIS RICK.
WHAT SORT IS HE?
I REALLY CAN'T SAY,
THOUGH I SAW HIM
QUITE OFTEN IN PARIS.
TOMORROW AT 10:00
AT THE PREFECT'S OFFICE.
WE'LL BE THERE.
GOOD NIGHT.
BOSS?
BOSS.
YEAH?
AIN'T YOU
GOING TO BED?
NOT RIGHT NOW.
AIN'T YOU PLANNING ON GOING
TO BED IN THE NEAR FUTURE?
NO!
YOU EVER GOING
TO BED?NO!
WELL, I AIN'T SLEEPY
EITHER.
GOOD.
THEN HAVE A DRINK.
NO, NOT ME, BOSS.
THEN DON'T
HAVE A DRINK.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
NO, SAM.
I'M WAITING FOR A LADY.
PLEASE, LET'S GO.
AIN'T NOTHING BUT TROUBLE
FOR YOU HERE.
SHE'S COMING BACK.
I KNOW SHE'S COMING BACK.
WE'LL DRIVE ALL NIGHT.
WE'LL GET DRUNK.
WE'LL GO FISHING AND STAY
AWAY TILL SHE'S GONE.
SHUT UP AND GO HOME.
NO, SIR.
I'M STAYING RIGHT HERE.
THEY GRAB UGARTE,
THEN SHE WALKS IN.
WELL, THAT'S
THE WAY IT GOES.
ONE IN, ONE OUT.
SAM.
YES, BOSS.
IF IT'S DECEMBER 1941
IN CASABLANCA,
WHAT TIME IS IT
IN NEW YORK?
WHAT?
MY WATCH STOPPED.
I BET THEY'RE ASLEEP
IN NEW YORK.
ALL OVER AMERICA.
OF ALL THE GIN JOINTS
IN ALL THE TOWNS
IN ALL THE WORLD,
SHE WALKS INTO MINE.
WHAT'S THAT
YOU'RE PLAYING?
JUST A LITTLE
SOMETHING OF MY OWN.
WELL, STOP IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I WANT TO HEAR.
NO, I DON'T.
YOU PLAYED IT FOR HER,
YOU CAN PLAY IT FOR ME.
I DON'T THINK
I CAN REMEMBER--
IF SHE CAN STAND IT,
I CAN!
PLAY IT.
YES, BOSS.
[PLAYS AS TIME GOES BY]
OH.
[POP]
WHO ARE YOU REALLY?
WHAT WERE YOU BEFORE?
WHAT DID YOU DO,
AND WHAT DID YOU THINK?
WE SAID NO QUESTIONS.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
A FRANC
FOR YOUR THOUGHTS.
IN AMERICA,
THEY'D BRING ONLY A PENNY.
I GUESS THAT'S ABOUT ALL
THEY'RE WORTH.
WELL, I'M WILLING
TO BE OVERCHARGED.
TELL ME.
WELL, I WAS WONDERING.
YES?
WHY I'M SO LUCKY.
WHY I SHOULD FIND YOU
WAITING FOR ME TO COME ALONG.
WHY THERE IS NO OTHER
MAN IN MY LIFE?
UH-HUH.
THAT'S EASY.
THERE WAS.
HE'S DEAD.
I'M SORRY
FOR ASKING.
I FORGOT.
WE SAID NO QUESTIONS.
WELL,
ONLY ONE ANSWER
CAN TAKE CARE OF
ALL OUR QUESTIONS.
[SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
Man on loudspeaker:
ICI, STUTTGART, ALLEMAGNE,
FRANCAIS, PARISIENS,
LES TROUPES FRANCAISES
ONT ABANDONNE LEURS POSITIONS.
LES ALLEMANDS SERONT DEMAIN
DANS LA CAPITALE.
NOTHING
CAN STOP THEM NOW.
THURSDAY AT THE LATEST,
THEY'LL BE IN PARIS.
IF THEY FIND OUT
YOUR RECORD,
IT WON'T BE SAFE
FOR YOU HERE.
I'M ON THEIR
BLACKLIST ALREADY.
THEIR ROLL OF HONOR.
♪ MOONLIGHT AND LOVE SONGS ♪
♪ NEVER OUT OF DATE ♪
♪ HEARTS FULL OF PASSION ♪
♪ JEALOUSY AND HATE ♪
♪ WOMAN NEEDS MAN ♪
♪ AND MAN
MUST HAVE HIS MATE ♪
♪ THAT NO ONE CAN DENY ♪
♪ IT'S STILL
THE SAME OLD STORY ♪
♪ A FIGHT
FOR LOVE AND GLORY ♪
♪ A CASE OF DO OR DIE ♪
♪ THE WORLD WILL
ALWAYS WELCOME LOVERS ♪
♪ AS TIME GOES BY ♪
HENRI WANTS US TO FINISH
THIS BOTTLE AND THEN 3 MORE.
SAYS HE'LL WATER
HIS GARDEN WITH CHAMPAGNE
BEFORE HE'LL LET
THE GERMANS DRINK IT.
THIS OUGHT TO TAKE THE STING
OUT OF BEING OCCUPIED.
YOU SAID IT.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
[MAN SPEAKING GERMAN
OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
MY GERMAN'S
A LITTLE RUSTY.
IT'S THE GESTAPO.
THEY SAY THEY EXPECT
TO BE IN PARIS TOMORROW.
THEY'RE TELLING US
HOW TO ACT
WHEN THEY COME MARCHING IN.
WITH THE WHOLE
WORLD CRUMBLING,
WE PICK THIS TIME
TO FALL IN LOVE.
YEAH, IT'S PRETTY
BAD TIMING.
WHERE WERE YOU, SAY,
10 YEARS AGO?
10 YEARS AGO.
LET'S SEE. I WAS HAVING
A BRACE PUT ON MY TEETH.
WHERE WERE YOU?
LOOKING FOR A JOB.
[DISTANT ARTILLERY]
WAS THAT CANNON FIRE,
OR IS IT
MY HEART POUNDING?
IT'S THE NEW
GERMAN 77.
JUDGING
BY THE SOUND,
ONLY ABOUT
35 MILES AWAY.
[ARTILLERY FIRE]
AND GETTING CLOSER
EVERY MINUTE.
HERE, HERE,
DRINK UP.
OR WE'LL NEVER FINISH
THE OTHER 3.
GERMANS WILL BE HERE
PRETTY SOON NOW.
THEY'LL COME
LOOKING FOR YOU.
REMEMBER THERE'S A PRICE
ON YOUR HEAD.
I LEFT A NOTE
IN MY APARTMENT.
THEY'LL KNOW WHERE
TO FIND ME.
STRANGE.
I KNOW SO VERY
LITTLE ABOUT YOU.
AND I KNOW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT YOU--
JUST THE FACT THAT YOU HAD
YOUR TEETH STRAIGHTENED.
BE SERIOUS,
YOU ARE IN DANGER.
YOU MUST
LEAVE PARIS.
NO, NO.
WE MUST LEAVE.
YES, OF COURSE, WE.
THE TRAIN FOR MARSEILLES
LEAVES AT 5:00.
I'LL PICK YOU UP
AT YOUR HOTEL AT 4:30.
NO. NOT AT MY HOTEL.
I HAVE THINGS
TO DO IN THE CITY
BEFORE I LEAVE.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT THE STATION.
ALL RIGHT, AT 4:45.
WHY DON'T WE GET MARRIED
IN MARSEILLES?
HA HA HA!
TH-THAT'S TOO FAR
AHEAD TO PLAN.
YES. IT IS A LITTLE
TOO FAR AHEAD.
WHAT ABOUT THE ENGINEER?
WHY CAN'T HE MARRY US
ON THE TRAIN?
OH, DARLING...
WHY NOT?
THE CAPTAIN ON A SHIP CAN.
IT DOESN'T SEEM FAIR--
HEY. HEY,
WHAT'S WRONG, KID?
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH...
AND I HATE THIS WAR
SO MUCH.
OH, IT'S
A CRAZY WORLD.
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN.
IF YOU
SHOULDN'T GET AWAY,
I MEAN, IF SOMETHING
SHOULD KEEP US APART,
WHEREVER THEY PUT YOU
AND WHEREVER I'LL BE,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I--
[ARTILLERY FIRE]
KISS ME.
KISS ME AS IF
IT WERE THE LAST TIME.
EN VOITURE!
ALLONS, ATTENTION!
ALL ABOARD! THE LAST TRAIN
LEAVING IN 20 MINUTES!
ALLEZ-EN!
EN VOITURE!
LE DERNIER TRAIN!
THE LAST TRAIN!
WHERE IS SHE?
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
NO, I CAN'T FIND HER.
SHE CHECKED OUT OF THE HOTEL.
BUT THIS NOTE CAME
AFTER YOU LEFT.
[WHISTLE]
THAT'S THE LAST CALL,
MR. RICHARD.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
COME ON. LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
COME ON.
[WHISTLE]
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
RICK, I HAVE TO
TALK TO YOU.
I SAVED MY FIRST DRINK
TO HAVE WITH YOU.
HERE.
NO. NO, RICK,
NOT TONIGHT.
ESPECIALLY TONIGHT.
WHY DID YOU HAVE TO
COME TO CASABLANCA?
THERE ARE OTHER PLACES.
I WOULDN'T HAVE COME
IF I'D KNOWN
THAT YOU WERE HERE.
BELIEVE ME. IT'S
TRUE. I DIDN'T KNOW.
YOUR VOICE HASN'T CHANGED.
I CAN STILL HEAR IT.
"RICHARD, DEAR,
I'LL GO WITH YOU ANYPLACE."
PLEASE, DON'T.
DON'T, RICK!
I CAN UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU'RE FEELING.
YOU UNDERSTAND
HOW I FEEL.
HOW LONG WAS IT
WE HAD, HONEY?
I DIDN'T
COUNT THE DAYS.
WELL, I DID.
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
MOSTLY I REMEMBER THE LAST ONE,
THE WOW FINISH,
A GUY STANDING ON A STATION
PLATFORM IN THE RAIN
WITH A COMICAL LOOK
ON HIS FACE
BECAUSE HIS INSIDES
HAD BEEN KICKED OUT.
CAN I TELL YOU
A STORY, RICK?
HAS IT GOT
A WOW FINISH?
I DON'T KNOW
THE FINISH YET.
GO ON, TELL IT.
MAYBE ONE'LL COME TO YOU
AS YOU GO ALONG.
IT'S ABOUT A GIRL
WHO HAD JUST
COME TO PARIS
FROM HER HOME IN OSLO.
AT THE HOUSE OF SOME
FRIENDS, SHE MET A MAN
ABOUT WHOM SHE HAD HEARD
HER WHOLE LIFE,
A VERY GREAT
AND COURAGEOUS MAN.
HE OPENED UP FOR HER
A WHOLE BEAUTIFUL WORLD
FULL OF KNOWLEDGE
AND THOUGHTS AND IDEALS.
EVERYTHING SHE KNEW
OR EVER BECAME
WAS BECAUSE OF HIM.
SHE LOOKED UP TO HIM
AND WORSHIPPED HIM
WITH A FEELING
SHE SUPPOSED WAS LOVE.
YES. IT'S VERY PRETTY.
I HEARD A STORY ONCE.
I'VE HEARD A LOT OF STORIES
IN MY TIME.
THEY WENT ALONG WITH THE SOUND
OF A TINNY PIANO
PLAYING IN THE PARLOR
DOWNSTAIRS.
"MISTER, I MET A MAN ONCE
WHEN I WAS A KID,"
IT ALWAYS BEGINS.
OH, I GUESS NEITHER ONE
OF OUR STORIES IS VERY FUNNY.
TELL ME, WHO WAS IT
YOU LEFT ME FOR?
WAS IT LASZLO, OR WERE THERE
OTHERS IN BETWEEN--
OR AREN'T YOU
THE KIND THAT TELLS?
[DOOR CLOSES]
I STRONGLY SUSPECT
THAT UGARTE LEFT THE LETTERS
OF TRANSIT WITH MR. BLAINE.
I SUGGEST YOU SEARCH THE CAFE
IMMEDIATELY AND THOROUGHLY.
IF RICK HAS THE LETTERS,
HE'S MUCH TOO SMART TO
LET YOU FIND THEM THERE.
YOU GIVE HIM CREDIT
FOR TOO MUCH CLEVERNESS.
HE'S JUST ANOTHER
BLUNDERING AMERICAN.
WE MUSTN'T UNDERESTIMATE
AMERICAN BLUNDERING.
I WAS WITH THEM
WHEN THEY BLUNDERED
INTO BERLIN IN 1918.
AS TO LASZLO,
WE WANT HIM WATCHED
24 HOURS A DAY.
AT THIS VERY MOMENT,
HE'S ON HIS WAY HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO.
I'M DELIGHTED
TO SEE YOU BOTH.
DID YOU HAVE
A GOOD NIGHT'S REST?
I SLEPT VERY WELL.
THAT'S STRANGE.
NOBODY'S SUPPOSED
TO SLEEP WELL
IN CASABLANCA.
MAY WE PROCEED
TO THE BUSINESS?
WITH PLEASURE.
WON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
VERY WELL.
LET'S NOT MINCE WORDS.
YOU ARE AN ESCAPED
PRISONER OF THE REICH.
SO FAR YOU HAVE
ELUDED US.
YOU HAVE REACHED
CASABLANCA.
IT'S MY DUTY TO SEE THAT
YOU STAY IN CASABLANCA.
WHETHER OR NOT YOU SUCCEED
IS PROBLEMATIC.
CAPTAIN RENAULT'S
SIGNATURE
IS NECESSARY
ON EVERY EXIT VISA.
WILL HERR LASZLO
RECEIVE A VISA?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
MY REGRETS, MONSIEUR.
PERHAPS I SHALL LIKE IT
IN CASABLANCA.
AND
MADEMOISELLE?
YOU NEEDN'T BE
CONCERNED ABOUT ME.
IS THAT ALL
YOU WISH TO TELL US?
DON'T BE
IN SUCH A HURRY.
YOU HAVE ALL THE TIME
IN THE WORLD.
YOU MAY BE IN CASABLANCA
INDEFINITELY,
OR YOU MAY LEAVE
FOR LISBON TOMORROW
ON ONE CONDITION.
AND THAT IS?
YOU KNOW THE LEADER
OF THE UNDERGROUND
MOVEMENT IN PARIS,
IN PRAGUE, IN BRUSSELS,
IN AMSTERDAM,
IN OSLO, IN BELGRADE,
AND ATHENS.
EVEN BERLIN.
YES, EVEN IN BERLIN.
IF YOU'LL FURNISH ME WITH
THEIR NAMES AND WHEREABOUTS,
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR VISA
IN THE MORNING.
AND THE HONOR OF HAVING
SERVED THE THIRD REICH.
I WAS IN A GERMAN
CONCENTRATION CAMP FOR A YEAR.
THAT'S HONOR ENOUGH
FOR A LIFETIME.
YOU'LL GIVE US
THE NAMES?
IF I DIDN'T GIVE THEM TO YOU
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP,
WHERE YOU HAD
MORE PERSUASIVE METHODS
AT YOUR DISPOSAL,
I CERTAINLY WON'T
GIVE THEM TO YOU NOW.
WHAT IF YOU KILL THESE MEN?
WHAT IF YOU
MURDERED ALL OF US?
FROM EVERY CORNER
OF EUROPE, HUNDREDS,
THOUSANDS WOULD RISE
TO TAKE OUR PLACES.
EVEN NAZIS CAN'T
KILL THAT FAST.
YOU HAVE A REPUTATION
FOR ELOQUENCE
WHICH I NOW UNDERSTAND.
BUT IN ONE RESPECT
YOU ARE MISTAKEN.
YOU SAID THE REICH'S ENEMIES
COULD BE REPLACED.
THERE'S ONE EXCEPTION.
NO ONE COULD REPLACE YOU
IF ANYTHING UNFORTUNATE
SHOULD OCCUR TO YOU
WHILE YOU WERE
TRYING TO ESCAPE.
YOU WON'T DARE
TO INTERFERE WITH ME HERE.
THIS IS STILL
UNOCCUPIED FRANCE.
ANY VIOLATION OF NEUTRALITY
WOULD REFLECT ON RENAULT.
INSOFAR AS IT IS
IN MY POWER.
THANK YOU.
LAST NIGHT, YOU EVINCED
INTEREST IN SIGNOR UGARTE.
YES.
YOU HAVE
A MESSAGE FOR HIM.
NOTHING IMPORTANT,
BUT MAY I SPEAK TO HIM NOW?
YOU WOULD FIND
THE CONVERSATION
A TRIFLE ONE-SIDED.
SIGNOR UGARTE'S DEAD.
I'M MAKING OUT
THE REPORT NOW.
WE HAVEN'T QUITE DECIDED
WHETHER HE COMMITTED SUICIDE
OR DIED
TRYING TO ESCAPE.
ARE YOU FINISHED WITH US?
FOR THE TIME
BEING.
GOOD DAY.
UNDOUBTEDLY THEIR NEXT STEP
WILL BE TO THE BLACK MARKET.
ANOTHER VISA PROBLEM
HAS COME UP.
SHOW HER IN.
YES, SIR.
SORRY. WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO HANDLE THE POLICE.
THIS IS A JOB
FOR SIGNOR FERRARI.
IT CAN BE MOST HELPFUL
TO KNOW HIM.
HE HAS A MONOPOLY
ON THE BLACK MARKET.
YOU'LL FIND HIM
AT THE BLUE PARROT.
THANKS.
DON'T BE TOO
DOWNHEARTED.
PERHAPS YOU CAN
COME TO TERMS
WITH CAPTAIN RENAULT.
HELLO, FERRARI.
GOOD MORNING,
RICK.
I SEE THE BUS IS IN.
I'LL TAKE
MY SHIPMENT WITH ME.
NO HURRY. I'LL HAVE IT
SENT OVER. HAVE A DRINK.
EVERY TIME YOU SEND
MY SHIPMENT OVER,
IT'S ALWAYS
A LITTLE SHORT.
CARRYING CHARGES,
MY BOY.
HERE, SIT DOWN.
THERE'S SOMETHING I WANT
TO TALK OVER WITH YOU.
THE BOURBON.
THE NEWS ABOUT UGARTE
UPSETS ME.
YOU'RE A FAT HYPOCRITE.
YOU DON'T FEEL ANY SORRIER
FOR UGARTE THAN I DO.
OF COURSE NOT.
WHAT UPSETS ME
IS THAT UGARTE'S DEAD,
AND NO ONE KNOWS WHERE THOSE
LETTERS OF TRANSIT ARE.
PRACTICALLY NO ONE.
IF I COULD
LAY MY HANDS ON THEM,
I COULD MAKE A FORTUNE.
SO COULD I, AND I'M
A POOR BUSINESSMAN.
I HAVE A PROPOSITION
FOR WHOEVER HAS
THOSE LETTERS.
I'LL HANDLE
THE ENTIRE TRANSACTION,
TAKE ALL THE RISK,
FOR A SMALL PERCENTAGE.
AND THE CARRYING
CHARGES?
NATURALLY THERE WILL BE
A FEW INCIDENTAL EXPENSES.
THAT'S THE PROPOSITION
I HAVE
FOR WHOEVER
HAS THOSE LETTERS.
I'LL TELL HIM
WHEN HE COMES IN.
I THINK YOU KNOW
WHERE THOSE LETTERS ARE.
YOU'RE IN GOOD COMPANY.
RENAULT AND STRASSER
PROBABLY THINK SO, TOO.
THAT'S WHY
I CAME OVER HERE,
TO GIVE THEM A CHANCE
TO RANSACK MY PLACE.
DON'T BE A FOOL. TAKE ME
INTO YOUR CONFIDENCE.
YOU NEED A PARTNER.
EXCUSE ME.
I'LL BE GETTING BACK.
GOOD MORNING.
SIGNOR FERRARI'S
THE FAT GENT AT THE TABLE.
YOU WILL NOT FIND A TREASURE
LIKE THIS IN ALL MOROCCO.
ONLY 700 FRANCS.
YOU'RE BEING CHEATED.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THANK YOU.
THE LADY'S A FRIEND
OF RICK'S.
FOR FRIENDS OF RICK'S,
WE HAVE A SMALL DISCOUNT.
DID I SAY 700?
YOU CAN HAVE IT
FOR 200.
I'M SORRY I WAS
IN NO CONDITION
TO RECEIVE YOU
LAST NIGHT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
FOR SPECIAL FRIENDS
OF RICK'S,
A SPECIAL DISCOUNT--
100 FRANCS.
YOUR STORY HAD ME
A LITTLE CONFUSED.
MAYBE IT WAS THE BOURBON.
I HAVE SOME TABLECLOTHS,
SOME NAPKINS.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT INTERESTED.
PLEASE, ONE MINUTE.
WHY DID YOU COME BACK,
TO TELL ME WHY
YOU RAN OUT ON ME
AT THE RAILWAY STATION.
YES.
YOU CAN TELL ME NOW.
I'M REASONABLY SOBER.
I DON'T THINK I WILL.
WHY NOT? I GOT STUCK
WITH THE RAILWAY TICKET.
I THINK I'M ENTITLED
TO KNOW.
LAST NIGHT, I SAW WHAT
HAS HAPPENED TO YOU.
THE RICK I KNEW
IN PARIS,
I COULD TELL HIM.
HE WOULD UNDERSTAND.
THE ONE WHO LOOKED AT ME
WITH SUCH HATRED...
I'LL BE LEAVING
CASABLANCA SOON.
WE'LL NEVER SEE
EACH OTHER AGAIN.
WE KNEW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT EACH OTHER
WHEN WE WERE IN LOVE
IN PARIS.
IF WE LEAVE IT THAT WAY,
MAYBE WE'LL REMEMBER
THOSE DAYS
AND NOT CASABLANCA.
NOT LAST NIGHT.
DID YOU RUN OUT ON ME
BECAUSE YOU
COULDN'T TAKE IT--
HIDING FROM THE POLICE,
RUNNING AWAY ALL THIS TIME?
YOU CAN BELIEVE THAT
IF YOU WANT TO.
I'M NOT
RUNNING AWAY ANYMORE.
I'M SETTLED NOW--
ABOVE A SALOON, IT'S TRUE,
BUT WALK UP A FLIGHT.
I'LL BE EXPECTING YOU.
ALL THE SAME, SOMEDAY
YOU'LL LIE TO LASZLO.
YOU'LL BE THERE.
NO, RICK.
NO. YOU SEE,
VICTOR LASZLO'S
MY HUSBAND.
AND WAS, EVEN WHEN
I KNEW YOU IN PARIS.
I WAS JUST TELLING
MONSIEUR LASZLO
THAT UNFORTUNATELY
I'M NOT ABLE
TO HELP HIM.
THE WORD
HAS GONE AROUND.
AS LEADER OF ALL
ILLEGAL ACTIVITIES
IN CASABLANCA,
I'M AN INFLUENTIAL
AND RESPECTED MAN.
IT WOULDN'T BE WORTH
MY LIFE
TO DO ANYTHING
MONSIEUR LASZLO.
YOU, HOWEVER, ARE
A DIFFERENT MATTER.
SIGNOR FERRARI THINKS
IT MIGHT JUST BE POSSIBLE
TO GET AN EXIT VISA
FOR YOU.
YOU MEAN FOR ME
TO GO ON ALONE?
Ferrari:
AND ONLY ALONE.
I'LL STAY HERE
AND KEEP ON TRYING.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
BE FRANK.
IT WOULD TAKE
A MIRACLE
TO GET YOU OUT
OF CASABLANCA,
AND THE GERMANS
OUTLAWED MIRACLES.
WE ARE ONLY INTERESTED
IN 2 VISAS.
PLEASE, ILSA,
DON'T BE HASTY.
YOU TWO WILL WANT
TO DISCUSS THIS.
EXCUSE ME.
I'LL BE AT THE BAR.
I WON'T LET YOU
STAY HERE.
YOU MUST GET TO AMERICA.
SOMEHOW I'LL JOIN YOU.
IF THE SITUATION
WERE DIFFERENT.
IF I HAD TO STAY
AND THERE WERE
ONLY VISA FOR ONE,
WOULD YOU TAKE IT?
YES, I WOULD.
YES, I SEE.
WHEN I HAD TROUBLE
GETTING OUT OF LILLES,
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LEAVE ME THERE?
WHEN I WAS SICK
IN MARSEILLES
AND HELD YOU UP
FOR 2 WEEKS,
AND YOU WERE IN
DANGER EVERY MINUTE,
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LEAVE ME THEN?
I MEANT TO, BUT SOMETHING
ALWAYS HELD ME UP.
I LOVE YOU
VERY MUCH, ILSA.
YOUR SECRET WILL BE
SAFE WITH ME.
FERRARI'S WAITING
FOR OUR ANSWER.
NOT MORE THAN
50 FRANCS, THOUGH.
WE HAVE DECIDED,
SIGNOR FERRARI.
FOR THE PRESENT, WE'RE ONLY
LOOKING FOR 2 EXIT VISAS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD LUCK, BUT BE CAREFUL.
YOU KNOW THAT
YOU'RE BEING SHADOWED?
OF COURSE.
IT BECOMES AN INSTINCT.
IN ONE RESPECT, YOU ARE
A VERY FORTUNATE MAN, MONSIEUR.
I MOVE TO MAKE ONE MORE
SUGGESTION. WHY, I DON'T KNOW,
BECAUSE IT CANNOT
POSSIBLY PROFIT ME.
HAVE YOU HEARD
ABOUT SIGNOR UGARTE
AND THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
YES. SOMETHING.
THEY WEREN'T ON UGARTE
WHEN THEY ARRESTED HIM.
WHERE ARE THEY?
NOT FOR SURE.
I'LL VENTURE TO GUESS
THAT UGARTE LEFT THEM
WITH MONSIEUR RICK.
RICK?
ONE NEVER KNOWS
WHAT RICK WILL DO OR WHY,
BUT IT IS WORTH A CHANCE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD DAY.
GOODBYE. THANK YOU
FOR YOUR COFFEE.
I SHALL MISS THAT
WHEN WE LEAVE
CASABLANCA.
GRACIOUS OF YOU TO SHARE IT
WITH ME. GOOD DAY.
GOOD DAY.
[PIANO PLAYING]
HERE'S TO YOU, SIR.
GOOD LUCK.
I'D BETTER BE GOING.
MY CHECK, PLEASE.
I HAVE TO WARN YOU.
THIS IS A DANGEROUS PLACE
FULL OF VULTURES.
VULTURES EVERYWHERE.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
GOODBYE, SIR.
A PLEASURE TO MEET YOU.
I'M SORRY.
MONSIEUR RICK, YOU ARE GETTING
TO BE YOUR BEST CUSTOMER.
DRINKING? NOW YOU'RE BEGINNING
TO LIVE LIKE A FRENCHMAN.
THAT'S SOME GOING-OVER
YOUR MEN GAVE MY PLACE.
WE BARELY GOT CLEANED UP
IN TIME TO OPEN.
I TOLD STRASSER
THE LETTERS WEREN'T HERE,
BUT I TOLD MY MEN TO BE
ESPECIALLY DESTRUCTIVE.
YOU KNOW HOW THAT
IMPRESSES GERMANS.
RICK, HAVE YOU GOT
THOSE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
ARE YOU PRO-VICHY
OR FREE FRENCH?
SERVES ME RIGHT FOR ASKING
A DIRECT QUESTION.
THE SUBJECT IS CLOSED.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE
A LITTLE LATE.
HA HA HA!
SO YVONNE'S GONE OVER
TO THE ENEMY?
WHO KNOWS?
IN HER OWN WAY,
SHE MAY CONSTITUTE
AN ENTIRE SECOND FRONT.
IT'S TIME FOR ME TO FLATTER
MAJOR STRASSER A LITTLE.
SACHA!
FRENCH 75s.
WE'LL HAVE
A WHOLE ROW, SACHA,
STARTING HERE
AND ENDING HERE!
WE WILL BEGIN
WITH 2.
VOUS N'ETES PAS
FRANCAISE VOUS,
D'ALLER AVEC
LES BOCHES COMME CA!
DE QUOI
VOUS MELEZ-VOUS?
NO, NO, NO.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
WOULD YOU KINDLY REPEAT IT?
IT'S NONE
OF YOUR BUSINESS!
I'LL MAKE IT
MY BUSINESS.
ARRETEZ,
JE VOUS EN PRIE!
JE VOUS EN PRIE,
ARRETEZ!
I DON'T LIKE
DISTURBANCES HERE.
EITHER LAY OFF POLITICS
OR GET OUT!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
YOU SEE, CAPTAIN,
THE SITUATION IS NOT AS MUCH
UNDER CONTROL
AS YOU BELIEVE.
WE'RE TRYING TO COOPERATE
WITH YOUR GOVERNMENT.
WE CANNOT REGULATE
OUR PEOPLE'S FEELINGS.
ARE YOU CERTAIN
WHICH SIDE YOU ARE ON?
I HAVE NO CONVICTION.
I BLOW WITH THE WIND.
THE PREVAILING WIND
HAPPENS TO BE FROM VICHY.
AND IF IT SHOULD
CHANGE?
SURELY THE REICH DOESN'T
ADMIT THAT POSSIBILITY.
WE'RE CONCERNED ABOUT
MORE THAN CASABLANCA.
WE KNOW EVERY FRENCH
PROVINCE IN AFRICA
IS HONEYCOMBED
WITH TRAITORS
WAITING FOR THEIR CHANCE,
PERHAPS FOR A LEADER.
A LEADER? LIKE LASZLO?
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS
IF YOU LET HIM GO.
IT MAY BE TOO DANGEROUS
IF YOU LET HIM STAY.
I SEE WHAT YOU MEAN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
THANK YOU, CARL.
CARL, SIT DOWN.
HAVE A BRANDY WITH US.
TO CELEBRATE OUR LEAVING
FOR AMERICA TOMORROW.
THANK YOU. I THOUGHT
YOU WOULD ASK ME,
SO I BROUGHT THE GOOD BRANDY...
AND...A THIRD GLASS.
AT LAST,
THE DAY IS CAME!
WE ARE SPEAKING
NOTHING BUT ENGLISH NOW.
SO WE SHOULD FEEL
AT HOME IN AMERICA.
VERY NICE IDEA.
HA HA.
TO AMERICA.
LIEBCHEN, SWEETNESS,
WHAT WATCH?
10:00 WATCH.
SUCH MUCH?
YOU WILL GET ALONG
BEAUTIFULLY IN AMERICA.
HOW'S LADY LUCK
TREATING YOU?
OH, TOO BAD.
YOU'LL FIND HIM
OVER THERE.
MONSIEUR RICK?
YES.
COULD I SPEAK
TO YOU, PLEASE?
HOW DID YOU GET IN HERE?
YOU'RE UNDERAGE.
I CAME WITH
CAPTAIN RENAULT.
OH, I SHOULD HAVE
KNOWN.
MY HUSBAND
IS WITH ME, TOO.
HE IS? CAPTAIN RENAULT'S
GETTING BROAD-MINDED.
WILL YOU HAVE A DRINK?
OF COURSE NOT.
DO YOU MIND IF I DO?
WHAT KIND OF A MAN
IS CAPTAIN RENAULT?
LIKE ANY OTHER,
ONLY MORE SO.
NO, I MEAN, IS HE TRUSTWORTHY?
IS HIS WORD--
WAIT. WHO TOLD YOU
TO ASK ME THAT?
HE DID.
CAPTAIN RENAULT DID.
I THOUGHT SO.
WHERE'S YOUR HUSBAND?
AT THE ROULETTE TABLE,
TRYING TO WIN ENOUGH
FOR OUR EXIT VISAS.
OF COURSE HE'S LOSING.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN MARRIED?
8 WEEKS.
WE COME FROM BULGARIA.
THINGS ARE VERY
BAD THERE.
THE DEVIL HAS THE PEOPLE
BY THE THROAT.
JAN AND I, WE DO NOT
WANT OUR CHILDREN
TO GROW UP
IN SUCH A COUNTRY.
SO YOU DECIDED
TO GO TO AMERICA.
YES, BUT WE HAVEN'T
MUCH MONEY.
TRAVELING IS SO EXPENSIVE
AND DIFFICULT.
IT WAS MUCH MORE
THAN WE THOUGHT TO GET HERE.
THEN CAPTAIN RENAULT
SEES US.
HE IS SO KIND.
HE WANTS TO HELP US.
YES. I'LL BET.
HE SAYS HE CAN GIVE US
AN EXIT VISA,
BUT WE HAVE NO MONEY.
HE KNOWS THAT, AND
HE'S STILL WILLING
TO GIVE YOU A VISA?
YES.
YOU WANT TO KNOW...
WILL HE KEEP HIS WORD?
HE ALWAYS HAS.
OH.
MONSIEUR,
YOU ARE A MAN.
IF SOMEONE LOVED YOU
VERY MUCH,
SO THAT YOUR HAPPINESS WAS
THE ONLY THING THAT SHE WANTED,
BUT SHE DID A BAD THING
TO MAKE CERTAIN OF IT,
COULD YOU FORGIVE HER?
NOBODY EVER LOVED ME
THAT MUCH.
AND HE NEVER KNEW.
AND THE GIRL KEPT THIS BAD
THING LOCKED IN HER HEART.
THAT WOULD BE ALL RIGHT,
WOULDN'T IT?
YOU WANT MY ADVICE?
YES, PLEASE.
GO BACK TO BULGARIA.
OH, BUT IF YOU KNEW
WHAT IT MEANS TO US
TO LEAVE EUROPE,
TO GET TO AMERICA!
OH, BUT IF JAN
SHOULD FIND OUT...
HE'S SUCH A BOY.
IN MANY WAYS, I'M SO MUCH
OLDER THAN HE IS.
YES, WELL, EVERYBODY IN
CASABLANCA HAS PROBLEMS.
YOURS MAY WORK OUT.
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU, MONSIEUR.
GOOD EVENING. YOU SEE,
HERE WE ARE AGAIN.
I TAKE THAT AS A GREAT
COMPLIMENT TO SAM.
I SUPPOSE HE MEANS PARIS
OF, WELL, HAPPIER DAYS.
HE DOES.
COULD WE HAVE A
TABLE NEAR HIM?
AND AS FAR FROM MAJOR
STRASSER AS POSSIBLE?
THE GEOGRAPHY MAY BE
DIFFICULT TO ARRANGE.
PAUL, TABLE 30.
RIGHT THIS WAY,
IF YOU PLEASE.
I'LL HAVE SAM PLAY
AS TIME GOES BY.
I BELIEVE THAT'S
YOUR FAVORITE TUNE.
THANK YOU.
[PLAYS AS TIME GOES BY]
TWO COGNAC, PLEASE.
COGNAC.
MARQUONS LES JEUX,
MESDAMES ET MESSIEURS.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
MESDAMES ET MESSIEURS,
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
DO YOU WISH TO PLACE
ANOTHER BET, SIR?
NO. NO. I GUESS NOT.
HAVE YOU TRIED
22 TONIGHT?
I SAID 22.
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
FINIS.
VINGT-DEUX!
VINGT-DEUX.
LEAVE IT THERE.
MARQUONS LES JEUX.
LES JEUX SONT FAITS.
LA PARTIE CONTINUE.
FINIS.
VINGT-DEUX!
CASH IT IN,
AND DON'T COME BACK.
FINIS.
ARE YOU SURE
THIS PLACE IS HONEST?
HONEST? AS HONEST
AS THE DAY IS LONG!
HOW ARE WE
DOING TONIGHT?
A COUPLE
OF THOUSAND LESS
THAN I THOUGHT
THERE WOULD BE.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MONSIEUR RICK...I...
I...OH!
JUST A LUCKY GUY.
MONSIEUR RICK, MAY I
GET YOU A CUP OF COFFEE?
NO, THANKS, CARL.
MONSIEUR RICK...
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
MAY I GIVE YOU--
NOT HERE, PLEASE.
COME TO MY OFFICE
IN THE MORNING.
WE'LL DO EVERYTHING
BUSINESSLIKE.
WE'LL BE THERE AT 6:00.
I'LL BE THERE
AT 10:00.
I'M HAPPY
FOR BOTH YOU.
IT'S VERY STRANGE
THAT YOU WON.
MAYBE NOT SO STRANGE.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
THANK YOU,
CAPTAIN RENAULT.
NO! IS IT TRUE?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
BOSS, YOU'VE DONE
A BEAUTIFUL THING!
GO AWAY,
YOU CRAZY RUSSIAN.
AS I SUSPECTED,
YOU'RE A RANK SENTIMENTALIST.
YEAH. WHY?
WHY DO YOU INTERFERE
WITH MY LITTLE ROMANCES?
PUT IT DOWN
AS A GESTURE TO LOVE.
I'LL FORGIVE YOU
THIS TIME,
BUT I'LL BE IN TOMORROW
WITH A BREATHTAKING BLONDE,
AND IT'LL MAKE ME
VERY HAPPY IF SHE LOSES.
MONSIEUR BLAINE, I WONDER
IF I COULD TALK TO YOU.
GO AHEAD.
WELL, ISN'T THERE
SOME OTHER PLACE?
IT'S RATHER CONFIDENTIAL,
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY.
IN MY OFFICE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
I GET OUT OF CASABLANCA.
I AM ONE OF THE LEADERS
OF A GREAT MOVEMENT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT MEANS
TO THE LIVES OF
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
THAT I REACH AMERICA
AND CONTINUE MY WORK.
THE PROBLEMS OF THE WORLD
AREN'T IN MY DEPARTMENT.
I'M A SALOON KEEPER.
MY FRIENDS
IN THE UNDERGROUND
TELL ME YOU'VE
QUITE A RECORD.
YOU RAN GUNS
TO ETHIOPIA,
YOU FOUGHT
FASCISTS IN SPAIN.
WHAT OF IT?
ISN'T IT STRANGE
THAT YOU'RE ALWAYS
FIGHTING ON THE SIDE
OF THE UNDERDOG?
YES. I FOUND THAT
AN EXPENSIVE HOBBY, TOO,
BUT I NEVER WAS
MUCH OF A BUSINESSMAN.
WOULD YOU APPRECIATE AN
OFFER OF 100,000 FRANCS?
YES, I'D APPRECIATE IT,
BUT I DON'T ACCEPT IT.
200,000.
YOU COULD MAKE IT
A MILLION OR 3.
MY ANSWER WOULD BE
THE SAME.
THERE MUST BE
SOME REASON
WHY YOU WON'T
LET ME HAVE THEM.
THERE IS. I SUGGEST
YOU ASK YOUR WIFE.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
I SAID ASK YOUR WIFE.
MY WIFE?
YES.
[SINGING
DIE WACHT AM RHEIN]
PLAY LA MARSEILLAISE.
PLAY IT.
♪ ALLONS,
ENFANTS DE LA PATRIE ♪
♪ LE JOUR DE GLOIRE
EST ARRIVE ♪
♪ CONTRE NOUS
DE LA TYRANNIE ♪
♪ L'ETENDARD SANGLANT
EST LEVE ♪
♪ L'ETENDARD
SANGLANT EST LEVE ♪
♪ ENTENDEZ-VOUS,
DANS LES CAMPAGNES ♪
♪ MUGIR
CES FEROCES SOLDATS? ♪
♪ ILS VIENNENT
JUSQUE DANS NOS BRAS ♪
♪ EGORGER NOS FILS
ET NOS COMPAGNES ♪
♪ AUX ARMES, CITOYENS! ♪
♪ FORMEZ VOS BATAILLONS! ♪
♪ MARCHONS! ♪
♪ QU'UN SANG IMPUR ♪
♪ ABREUVE NOS SILLONS! ♪
VIVE LA FRANCE!
VIVE LA DEMOCRATIE!
[CHEERING]
VIVE LA FRANCE!
VIVE LA DEMOCRATIE!
IF LASZLO'S PRESENCE
IN A CAFE CAN INSPIRE
THIS UNFORTUNATE
DEMONSTRATION,
WHAT MORE WILL HIS PRESENCE
IN CASABLANCA BRING ON?
I ADVISE THAT THIS PLACE
BE SHUT UP AT ONCE.
BUT EVERYBODY'S HAVING
SUCH A GOOD TIME.
YES, MUCH TOO GOOD.
CLOSE THE PLACE.
BUT I HAVE NO EXCUSE
TO CLOSE IT.
FIND ONE.
SANTE.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
EVERYBODY IS TO
LEAVE IMMEDIATELY!
THIS CAFE IS CLOSED
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE!
CLEAR THE ROOM AT ONCE!
HOW CAN HE CLOSE ME UP?
ON WHAT GROUNDS?
I'M SHOCKED TO FIND
GAMBLING GOING ON HERE!
YOUR WINNINGS, SIR.
OH, THANK YOU.
EVERYBODY OUT!
MADEMOISELLE, AFTER
THIS DISTURBANCE,
IT ISN'T SAFE FOR LASZLO
TO STAY IN CASABLANCA.
THIS MORNING YOU IMPLIED
IT WASN'T SAFE
FOR HIM TO LEAVE.
TRUE, EXCEPT
FOR ONE DESTINATION.
TO RETURN
TO OCCUPIED FRANCE--
OCCUPIED FRANCE?
UNDER A SAFE
CONDUCT FROM ME.
WHAT VALUE IS THAT?
YOU MAY RECALL
WHAT GERMAN GUARANTEES
HAVE BEEN WORTH IN THE PAST.
THERE ARE ONLY
2 ALTERNATIVES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
IT IS POSSIBLE
THE FRENCH AUTHORITIES
COULD PUT HIM IN
A CONCENTRATION CAMP.
THE OTHER ALTERNATIVE?
MY DEAR MADEMOISELLE,
PERHAPS YOU HAVE
ALREADY OBSERVED
THAT IN CASABLANCA
HUMAN LIFE IS CHEAP.
GOOD NIGHT,
MADEMOISELLE.
GARCON?
WHAT HAPPENED
WITH RICK?
WE'LL DISCUSS IT
LATER.
OUR FAITHFUL FRIEND
IS STILL THERE.
VICTOR,
PLEASE DON'T GO
TO THE UNDERGROUND
MEETING TONIGHT.
I MUST. BESIDES,
IT ISN'T OFTEN
A MAN CAN DISPLAY HEROICS
BEFORE HIS WIFE.
DON'T JOKE.
AFTER MAJOR STRASSER'S
WARNING TONIGHT,
I AM FRIGHTENED.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I'M FRIGHTENED, TOO.
SHALL I REMAIN HERE
IN A HOTEL ROOM, HIDING,
OR SHALL I CARRY ON
THE BEST I CAN?
WHATEVER I'D SAY,
YOU'D CARRY ON.
TELL ME ABOUT RICK.
WHAT DID YOU FIND OUT?
APPARENTLY
HE HAS THE LETTERS.
YES?
BUT NO INTENTION
OF SELLING THEM.
ONE WOULD THINK IF SENTIMENT
WOULDN'T PERSUADE HIM,
MONEY WOULD.
DID HE GIVE YOU
ANY REASON?
HE SUGGESTED
I ASK YOU.
ASK ME?
YES, HE SAID,
"ASK YOUR WIFE."
I DON'T KNOW
WHY HE SAID THAT.
OUR FRIEND OUTSIDE WILL THINK
WE HAVE RETIRED BY NOW.
I'LL BE GOING
IN A FEW MINUTES.
ILSA, I--
YES?
WHEN I WAS IN
THE CONCENTRATION CAMP,
WERE YOU LONELY
IN PARIS?
YES, VICTOR, I WAS.
I KNOW HOW IT IS
TO BE LONELY.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WISH TO TELL ME?
NO, VICTOR,
THERE ISN'T.
I LOVE YOU VERY MUCH,
MY DEAR.
YES.
YES, I KNOW.
VICTOR, WHATEVER I DO,
WILL YOU BELIEVE
THAT I--THAT--
YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE
TO SAY IT. I'LL BELIEVE.
GOOD NIGHT, DEAR.
GOOD NIGHT.
VICTOR.
YES, DEAR?
BE CAREFUL.
OF COURSE
I'LL BE CAREFUL.
WELL, YOU ARE IN PRETTY
GOOD SHAPE, HERR RICK.
HOW LONG CAN I
AFFORD TO STAY CLOSED?
2 WEEKS, MAYBE 3.
MAYBE I WON'T HAVE TO.
A BRIBE HAS WORKED BEFORE.
IN THE MEANTIME, EVERYBODY
STAYS ON SALARY.
THANK YOU.
SACHA WILL BE HAPPY.
I OWE HIM MONEY.
FINISH LOCKING UP,
WILL YOU, CARL?
YES. THEN I AM GOING
TO THE MEETING OF--
DON'T TELL ME
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
I WON'T.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, MR. RICK.
HOW DID YOU GET IN?
THE STAIRS
FROM THE STREET.
I TOLD YOU THIS MORNING
YOU'D COME AROUND,
BUT THIS IS AHEAD
OF SCHEDULE. SIT DOWN.
RICHARD, I HAD TO
SEE YOU.
OH, IT'S RICHARD AGAIN.
WE'RE BACK IN PARIS.
IS YOUR VISIT ISN'T CONNECTED
WITH THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT?
AS LONG AS I HAVE THOSE,
I'LL NEVER BE LONELY.
ASK ANY PRICE, BUT I
MUST HAVE THOSE LETTERS.
I WENT THROUGH THAT
WITH YOUR HUSBAND. NO DEAL.
I'M ASKING YOU TO
PUT YOUR FEELINGS ASIDE
FOR SOMETHING
MORE IMPORTANT.
DO I HAVE TO
HEAR AGAIN
WHAT A GREAT MAN
YOUR HUSBAND IS,
WHAT AN IMPORTANT CAUSE
HE'S FIGHTING FOR?
IT WAS YOUR CAUSE,
TOO. IN YOUR WAY,
YOU WERE FIGHTING
FOR THE SAME THING.
I'M NOT FIGHTING FOR ANYTHING
ANYMORE EXCEPT MYSELF.
I'M THE ONLY CAUSE
I'M INTERESTED IN.
RICHARD, WE LOVED
EACH OTHER ONCE.
IF THOSE DAYS MEANT
ANYTHING AT ALL TO YOU--
I WOULDN'T BRING UP PARIS.
IT'S POOR SALESMANSHIP.
PLEASE LISTEN TO ME.
IF YOU ONLY
KNEW THE TRUTH.
I WOULDN'T BELIEVE YOU,
NO MATTER WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU'D SAY ANYTHING
TO GET WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU WANT TO FEEL SORRY
FOR YOURSELF, DON'T YOU?
THERE'S SO MUCH
AT STAKE.
ALL YOU THINK OF
IS YOUR OWN FEELING.
ONE WOMAN HAS HURT YOU,
AND YOU TAKE YOUR REVENGE
ON THE WHOLE WORLD.
YOU'RE A COWARD
AND A WEAKLING.
NO. NO, RICHARD.
I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY, BUT YOU
ARE OUR LAST HOPE.
IF YOU DON'T HELP US,
VICTOR LASZLO
WILL DIE IN CASABLANCA.
WHAT OF IT? I'M GOING
TO DIE IN CASABLANCA.
IT'S A GOOD SPOT FOR IT.
NOW, IF YOU--
ALL RIGHT, I TRIED
TO REASON WITH YOU.
I TRIED EVERYTHING.
NOW I WANT
THOSE LETTERS.
GET THEM FOR ME.
I DON'T HAVE TO.
I GOT THEM RIGHT HERE.
PUT THEM ON THE TABLE.
NO.
FOR THE LAST TIME,
PUT THEM ON THE TABLE.
IF LASZLO AND THE CAUSE
MEAN SO MUCH,
YOU WON'T STOP AT ANYTHING.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL
MAKE IT EASIER FOR YOU.
GO AHEAD AND SHOOT.
YOU'LL BE
DOING ME A FAVOR.
RICHARD.
I TRIED TO STAY AWAY.
I THOUGHT I WOULD
NEVER SEE YOU AGAIN,
THAT YOU WERE
OUT OF MY LIFE.
THE DAY
YOU LEFT PARIS...
IF YOU KNEW WHAT
I WENT THROUGH.
IF YOU KNEW HOW MUCH
I LOVED YOU.
HOW MUCH
I STILL LOVE YOU.
AND THEN?
IT WASN'T LONG
AFTER WE WERE MARRIED
THAT VICTOR WENT BACK
TO CZECHOSLOVAKIA.
THEY NEEDED HIM
IN PRAGUE,
BUT THERE THE GESTAPO
WERE WAITING FOR HIM.
JUST A 2-LINE ITEM
IN THE PAPER,
"VICTOR LASZLO
APPREHENDED.
SENT TO
CONCENTRATION CAMP."
I WAS FRANTIC.
FOR MONTHS
I TRIED TO GET WORD.
THEN IT CAME.
HE WAS DEAD--
SHOT TRYING TO ESCAPE.
I WAS LONELY.
I HAD NOTHING--
NOT EVEN HOPE.
THEN I MET YOU.
WHY WEREN'T YOU
HONEST WITH ME?
WHY DID YOU KEEP
YOUR MARRIAGE A SECRET?
IT WASN'T MY SECRET.
VICTOR WANTED IT
THAT WAY.
OUR CLOSEST FRIENDS
DIDN'T KNOW.
HE WANTED TO PROTECT ME.
I KNEW ABOUT HIS WORK.
IF THE GESTAPO KNEW
I WAS HIS WIFE,
IT WOULD BE DANGEROUS
FOR ME
AND FOR THOSE
WORKING WITH US.
WHEN DID YOU FIRST
FIND OUT HE WAS ALIVE?
JUST BEFORE YOU AND I
WERE TO
LEAVE PARIS TOGETHER.
A FRIEND TOLD ME
VICTOR WAS ALIVE.
THEY WERE HIDING HIM
IN A FREIGHT CAR
ON THE OUTSKIRTS
OF PARIS.
HE WAS SICK.
HE NEEDED ME.
I WANTED TO TELL YOU,
BUT I DIDN'T DARE.
I KNEW YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE LEFT PARIS
AND THE GESTAPO
WOULD HAVE CAUGHT YOU.
SO I...WELL,
YOU KNOW THE REST.
WELL, IT'S STILL
A STORY WITHOUT AN ENDING.
WHAT ABOUT NOW?
NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
I KNOW THAT I'LL NEVER
HAVE THE STRENGTH
TO LEAVE YOU AGAIN.
AND LASZLO?
YOU'LL HELP HIM,
WON'T YOU?
YOU'LL SEE
THAT HE GETS OUT.
THEN HE'LL HAVE
HIS WORK--
ALL THAT HE'S
BEEN LIVING FOR.
ALL EXCEPT ONE.
HE WON'T HAVE YOU.
I CAN'T FIGHT IT
ANYMORE.
I RAN AWAY
FROM YOU ONCE.
I CAN'T DO IT AGAIN.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S RIGHT ANY LONGER.
YOU HAVE TO THINK
FOR BOTH OF US,
FOR ALL OF US.
ALL RIGHT.
I WILL.
HERE'S LOOKING
AT YOU, KID.
I WISH I DIDN'T
LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
I THINK
WE LOST THEM.
YES. I'M AFRAID THEY CAUGHT
SOME OF THE OTHERS.
COME INSIDE.
COME.
COME, MR. LASZLO.
I WILL HELP YOU...
IMMEDIATELY.
THANK YOU.
[VOICES]
CARL, WHAT HAPPENED?
THE POLICE BREAK UP
OUR MEETING, HERR RICK.
WE ESCAPED
IN THE LAST MOMENT.
COME UP HERE.
TURN OUT THE LIGHT
IN THE REAR ENTRANCE.
IT MIGHT
ATTRACT THE POLICE.
SACHA ALWAYS
PUTS IT OUT.
TONIGHT HE FORGOT.
I WILL DO IT.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE MISS LUND HOME.
YES, SIR.
IT'S NOTHING.
JUST A LITTLE CUT.
WE HAD TO GET
THROUGH A WINDOW.
THIS MIGHT
COME IN HANDY.
THANK YOU.
HAD A CLOSE ONE, EH?
YES, RATHER.
DON'T YOU SOMETIMES WONDER
IF IT'S WORTH ALL THIS?
I MEAN, WHAT
YOU'RE FIGHTING FOR.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL QUESTION
WHY WE BREATHE.
IF WE STOP BREATHING,
WE'LL DIE.
IF WE STOP FIGHTING OUR
ENEMIES, THE WORLD WILL DIE.
WHAT OF IT? IT'LL BE
OUT OF ITS MISERY.
YOU KNOW HOW YOU SOUND?
LIKE A MAN TRYING TO CONVINCE
HIMSELF OF SOMETHING
HE DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN HIS HEART.
EACH OF US HAS A DESTINY--
FOR GOOD OR EVIL.
I GET THE POINT.
I WONDER IF YOU DO.
DO YOU KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO ESCAPE FROM YOURSELF?
YOU'LL NEVER SUCCEED.
YOU SEEM TO KNOW
ALL ABOUT MY DESTINY.
I KNOW A GOOD DEAL MORE
ABOUT YOU THAN YOU SUSPECT.
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
IN LOVE WITH A WOMAN.
IT'S PERHAPS
A STRANGE CIRCUMSTANCE
THAT WE BOTH SHOULD BE
IN LOVE WITH THE SAME WOMAN.
THE FIRST EVENING
I CAME TO THIS CAFE,
I KNEW THERE WAS SOMETHING
BETWEEN YOU AND ILSA.
SINCE NO ONE'S TO BLAME,
I DEMAND NO EXPLANATION.
I ASK ONLY ONE THING.
YOU WON'T GIVE ME
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
ALL RIGHT, BUT I
WANT MY WIFE TO BE SAFE.
I ASK YOU TO USE THE LETTERS
TO TAKE HER AWAY.
YOU LOVE HER
THAT MUCH?
YOU THINK OF ME
ONLY AS A LEADER OF A CAUSE.
I'M ALSO A HUMAN BEING.
YES, I LOVE HER THAT MUCH.
MONSIEUR LASZLO?
YES?
COME WITH US. WE HAVE
A WARRANT FOR YOUR ARREST.
ON WHAT CHARGE?
CAPTAIN RENAULT WILL
DISCUSS THAT WITH YOU LATER.
IT SEEMS THAT DESTINY
HAS TAKEN A HAND.
YOU KNOW YOU HAVEN'T
ANY ACTUAL PROOF.
THIS ISN'T GERMANY
OR OCCUPIED FRANCE.
YOU CAN ONLY FINE HIM
AND GIVE HIM 30 DAYS.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
LET HIM GO NOW.
I'D ADVISE YOU NOT TO BE
TOO INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO LASZLO.
IF YOU HELPED HIM
ESCAPE--
WHY WOULD I STICK
MY NECK OUT FOR LASZLO?
1--YOU BET 10,000 FRANCS
HE'D ESCAPE.
2--YOU'VE GOT
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
DON'T BOTHER TO DENY IT.
AND YOU MIGHT DO IT
BECAUSE YOU DON'T LIKE
STRASSER'S LOOKS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I DON'T LIKE THEM,
EITHER.
THEY'RE ALL
EXCELLENT REASONS.
DON'T COUNT TOO MUCH
ON MY FRIENDSHIP.
IN THIS MATTER,
I'M POWERLESS.
BESIDES, I MIGHT LOSE
THE 10,000 FRANCS.
YOU'RE NOT VERY SUBTLE,
BUT YOU ARE EFFECTIVE.
I GET THE POINT.
YES, I HAVE THE LETTERS.
I INTEND USING THEM MYSELF.
I'M LEAVING CASABLANCA
ON THE LAST PLANE TONIGHT.
I'M TAKING A FRIEND--
ONE YOU'LL APPRECIATE.
WHAT FRIEND?
ILSA LUND.
THAT SHOULD PUT YOUR MIND
TO REST ABOUT LASZLO--
THE LAST MAN I WANT
TO SEE IN AMERICA.
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TELL ME THIS.
YOU HAVE THE LETTERS
OF TRANSIT.
YOU CAN LEAVE
ANYTIME YOU PLEASE.
WHY ARE YOU STILL
INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO LASZLO?
I'M NOT.
BUT I AM INTERESTED
IN WHAT HAPPENS
TO ILSA AND ME.
WE HAVE A LEGAL RIGHT
TO GO, THAT'S TRUE,
BUT PEOPLE HAVE BEEN HELD
IN SPITE OF THEIR RIGHTS.
WHY SHOULD
WE HOLD YOU?
ILSA'S LASZLO'S WIFE.
SHE PROBABLY KNOWS THINGS
STRASSER WOULD LIKE TO KNOW.
I'LL MAKE A DEAL.
INSTEAD OF THIS PETTY CHARGE,
GET SOMETHING BIG
THAT WOULD CHUCK HIM IN
A CONCENTRATION CAMP FOR YEARS.
IT'D BE QUITE A FEATHER
IN YOUR CAP, WOULDN'T IT?
IT CERTAINLY WOULD.
GERMANY--VICHY
WOULD BE VERY GRATEFUL.
THEN RELEASE HIM.
BE AT MY PLACE A HALF HOUR
BEFORE THE PLANE LEAVES.
I'LL HAVE LASZLO COME THERE
TO PICK UP
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT--
THAT'LL GIVE YOU THE CRIMINAL
GROUNDS FOR ARREST.
YOU GET HIM,
AND WE GET AWAY.
TO THE GERMANS, THAT LAST ONE
WILL BE JUST A MINOR ANNOYANCE.
THERE'S STILL SOMETHING
I DON'T QUITE UNDERSTAND.
MISS LUND--SHE'S
VERY BEAUTIFUL, YES,
BUT YOU WERE NEVER
INTERESTED IN ANY WOMAN.
SHE ISN'T
JUST ANY WOMAN.
I SEE. HOW DO I KNOW
YOU'LL KEEP YOUR WORD?
I'LL MAKE THE ARRANGEMENTS
RIGHT NOW WITH LASZLO
IN THE VISITORS' PEN.
RICKY,
I'LL MISS YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
IN CASABLANCA
WHO HAS EVEN LESS
SCRUPLES THAN I.
THANKS.
GO AHEAD, RICKY.
CALL OFF YOUR WATCHDOGS
WHEN YOU LET HIM GO.
I DON'T WANT THEM AROUND
THIS AFTERNOON.
I'M TAKING NO CHANCES,
NOT EVEN WITH YOU.
SHALL WE
DRAW UP PAPERS,
OR IS A HANDSHAKE
GOOD ENOUGH?
CERTAINLY
NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
BUT SINCE I'M IN A
HURRY, IT'LL HAVE TO DO.
AH, TO LEAVE CASABLANCA
AND GO TO AMERICA--
YOU'RE A LUCKY MAN.
BY THE WAY,
MY AGREEMENT WITH SAM
IS THAT HE GETS
25% OF THE PROFITS.
I HAPPEN TO KNOW IT'S 10%,
BUT HE'S WORTH 25.
ABDUL, CARL, AND SACHA
STAY, OR I DON'T SELL.
OF COURSE. RICK'S WOULDN'T
BE RICK'S WITHOUT THEM.
WELL, SO LONG.
DON'T FORGET,
YOU OWE RICK'S
100 CARTONS OF
AMERICAN CIGARETTES.
I SHALL REMEMBER
TO PAY IT TO MYSELF.
[BANGING ON DOOR]
YOU'RE LATE.
I WAS INFORMED
JUST AS LASZLO WAS
LEAVING THE HOTEL,
SO I KNEW
I'D BE ON TIME.
I ASKED YOU TO TIE UP
YOUR WATCHDOGS.
HE WON'T BE
FOLLOWED HERE.
THIS PLACE WON'T BE
THE SAME WITHOUT YOU.
I KNOW, BUT I'VE ALREADY
SPOKEN TO FERRARI.
YOU'LL STILL
WIN AT ROULETTE.
IS EVERYTHING READY?
I HAVE
THE LETTERS.
WHEN WE SEARCHED THE PLACE,
WHERE WERE THEY?
SAM'S PIANO.
SERVES ME RIGHT
FOR NOT BEING MUSICAL.
[BRAKES SQUEAL]
HERE THEY ARE.
YOU'D BETTER
WAIT IN MY OFFICE.
HERE.
RICHARD, VICTOR THINKS
I'M LEAVING WITH HIM.
HAVEN'T YOU TOLD HIM?
NO, NOT YET.
IT'S ALL RIGHT?
YOU ARRANGED EVERYTHING?
YES. WE'LL TELL HIM
AT THE AIRPORT.
THE LESS TIME TO THINK,
THE EASIER FOR ALL OF US.
PLEASE TRUST ME.
YES, I WILL.
MONSIEUR BLAINE, I DON'T
KNOW HOW TO THANK YOU.
SAVE IT. WE'VE LOTS
OF THINGS TO DO.
I BROUGHT
THE MONEY.
KEEP IT. YOU'LL
NEED IT IN AMERICA.
BUT WE
MADE A DEAL.
NEVER MIND. WILL YOU
HAVE TROUBLE IN LISBON?
NO. IT'S ALL ARRANGED.
GOOD. THE LETTERS ARE
ALL MADE OUT IN BLANK.
JUST FILL IN
THE SIGNATURES.
VICTOR LASZLO?
VICTOR LASZLO,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST...
ON THE CHARGE
OF ACCESSORY
TO THE MURDER
OF THE COURIERS
FROM WHOM THESE LETTERS
WERE STOLEN.
YOU'RE SURPRISED
ABOUT MY FRIEND RICKY?
THE EXPLANATION
IS QUITE SIMPLE.
LOVE, IT SEEMS, HAS
TRIUMPHED OVER VIRTUE.
NOT SO FAST, LOUIS.
NOBODY IS GOING
TO BE ARRESTED,
NOT FOR A WHILE YET.
HAVE YOU TAKEN LEAVE
OF YOUR SENSES?
I HAVE.
SIT DOWN.
I WOULDN'T LIKE
TO SHOOT YOU,
BUT I WILL IF YOU
TAKE ONE MORE STEP.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I WILL SIT DOWN.
KEEP YOUR HANDS
ON THE TABLE.
I WONDER IF YOU REALIZE
WHAT THIS MEANS.
I DO. WE'LL DISCUSS
THAT LATER.
"CALL OFF YOUR
WATCHDOGS," YOU SAID.
CALL THE AIRPORT. LET
ME HEAR YOU TELL THEM.
THIS GUN'S POINTED
RIGHT AT YOUR HEART.
THAT IS MY
LEAST VULNERABLE SPOT.
HELLO?
IS THAT THE AIRPORT?
EH?
CAPTAIN RENAULT SPEAKING.
THERE'LL BE 2 LETTERS OF TRANSIT
FOR THE LISBON PLANE.
THERE'S TO BE NO TROUBLE
ABOUT THEM.
GOOD.
HELLO? HELLO?
[BUZZER]
MY CAR, QUICKLY.
JAWOHL, MAJOR.
THIS IS MAJOR STRASSER.
HAVE A SQUAD OF POLICE
MEET ME AT THE AIRPORT
AT ONCE, DO YOU HEAR?
HELLO, HELLO,
RADIO TOWER?
LISBON PLANE TAKING OFF
IN 10 MINUTES. EAST RUNWAY.
VISIBILITY,
1 1/2 MILES.
LIGHT GROUND FOG.
DEPTH OF FOG,
APPROXIMATELY 500.
CEILING UNLIMITED.
THANK YOU.
LOUIS, HAVE YOUR MAN
GO WITH MR. LASZLO.
TAKE CARE
OF HIS LUGGAGE.
ANYTHING YOU SAY.
PUT MR. LASZLO'S LUGGAGE
ON THE PLANE.
YES, SIR.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
YOU FILL IN THE NAMES.
THAT'LL MAKE IT
EVEN MORE OFFICIAL.
YOU THINK OF EVERYTHING,
DON'T YOU?
THE NAMES ARE MR.
AND MRS. VICTOR LASZLO.
WHY MY NAME,
RICHARD?
BECAUSE YOU'RE
GETTING ON THAT PLANE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I'M STAYING HERE
WITH HIM
TILL THE PLANE
GETS SAFELY AWAY.
NO, RICHARD.
LAST NIGHT--
LAST NIGHT WE SAID
A GREAT MANY THINGS.
YOU SAID I SHOULD
THINK FOR BOTH OF US.
WELL, I HAVE.
IT ALL ADDS UP TO ONE THING.
YOU'RE GETTING
ON THAT PLANE.
RICHARD, NO. I--
YOU'VE GOT LISTEN TO ME.
9 CHANCES OUT OF 10,
IF YOU STAYED,
WE'D PROBABLY BOTH WIND UP
IN A CONCENTRATION CAMP.
ISN'T THAT TRUE, LOUIS?
I'M AFRAID MAJOR STRASSER
WOULD INSIST.
YOU'RE SAYING THIS
ONLY TO MAKE ME GO.
I'M SAYING IT
BECAUSE IT'S TRUE.
INSIDE, WE BOTH KNOW
YOU BELONG WITH VICTOR.
YOU'RE PART OF HIS WORK,
THE THING THAT KEEPS HIM GOING.
IF THAT PLANE LEAVES THE GROUND
AND YOU'RE NOT WITH HIM,
YOU'LL REGRET IT.
MAYBE NOT TODAY,
MAYBE NOT TOMORROW,
BUT SOON, AND FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE.
BUT WHAT ABOUT US?
WE'LL ALWAYS HAVE PARIS.
WE DIDN'T HAVE IT.
WE'D LOST IT UNTIL YOU CAME
TO CASABLANCA.
WE GOT IT BACK
LAST NIGHT.
WHEN I SAID I
WOULD NEVER LEAVE YOU.
AND YOU NEVER WILL,
BUT I'VE GOT A JOB
TO DO, TOO.
WHERE I'M GOING,
YOU CAN'T FOLLOW.
WHAT I'VE GOT TO DO,
YOU CAN'T BE PART OF.
I'M NO GOOD
AT BEING NOBLE,
BUT IT DOESN'T
TAKE MUCH TO SEE
THAT THE PROBLEMS
OF THREE LITTLE PEOPLE
DON'T AMOUNT TO A HILL OF BEANS
IN THIS CRAZY WORLD.
SOMEDAY YOU'LL
UNDERSTAND THAT.
NOW, NOW.
HERE'S LOOKING AT YOU, KID.
[HONKS HORN]
EVERYTHING
IS IN ORDER.
ALL EXCEPT
ONE THING.
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD KNOW
BEFORE YOU LEAVE.
I DON'T ASK YOU
TO EXPLAIN ANYTHING.
I'M GOING TO ANYWAY.
BECAUSE IT MAY MAKE
A DIFFERENCE LATER ON.
YOU SAID YOU KNEW
YES.ABOUT ILSA AND ME.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS
AT MY PLACE LAST NIGHT.
SHE CAME THERE FOR
THE LETTERS OF TRANSIT.
ISN'T THAT TRUE?
YES.
SHE TRIED EVERYTHING,
AND NOTHING WORKED.
SHE DID HER BEST
TO CONVINCE ME
THAT SHE WAS STILL
IN LOVE WITH ME.
THAT WAS OVER LONG AGO.
FOR YOUR SAKE,
SHE PRETENDED IT WASN'T,
AND I LET HER PRETEND.
I UNDERSTAND.
HERE IT IS.
THANKS.
I APPRECIATE IT.
WELCOME BACK TO THE FIGHT.
THIS TIME I KNOW
OUR SIDE WILL WIN.
ARE YOU READY, ILSA?
YES, I'M READY.
GOODBYE, RICK.
GOD BLESS YOU.
YOU'D BETTER HURRY
OR YOU'LL MISS THAT PLANE.
WELL, I WAS RIGHT.
YOU ARE A SENTIMENTALIST.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WHAT YOU JUST DID
FOR LASZLO.
THAT FAIRY TALE
YOU INVENTED.
I KNOW A LITTLE
ABOUT WOMEN.
SHE WENT, BUT SHE KNEW
YOU WERE LYING.
ANYWAY, THANKS
FOR HELPING ME OUT.
I SUPPOSE YOU KNOW
THIS WON'T BE PLEASANT
FOR EITHER OF US--
ESPECIALLY FOR YOU.
I'LL HAVE TO ARREST YOU.
AS SOON AS THE PLANE GOES.
WHAT WAS THE MEANING
OF THAT PHONE CALL?
VICTOR LASZLO
IS ON THAT PLANE.
WHY DO YOU STAND HERE?
WHY DON'T YOU STOP HIM?
ASK MONSIEUR RICK.
GET AWAY
FROM THAT PHONE.
I WOULD ADVISE YOU
NOT TO INTERFERE.
I WAS WILLING TO SHOOT
CAPTAIN RENAULT,
AND I'M WILLING
TO SHOOT YOU.
HELLO.
PUT THAT PHONE DOWN.
GET ME THE RADIO TOWER.
PUT IT DOWN.
MON CAPITAINE.
MAJOR STRASSER
HAS BEEN SHOT.
ROUND UP
THE USUAL SUSPECTS.
OUI,
MON CAPITAINE.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
WELL, RICK, YOU'RE
NOT ONLY A SENTIMENTALIST,
BUT YOU'VE
BECOME A PATRIOT.
IT SEEMED LIKE
A GOOD TIME TO START.
I THINK
PERHAPS YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT MIGHT
BE A GOOD IDEA
FOR YOU TO DISAPPEAR
FROM CASABLANCA
FOR A WHILE.
THERE'S A FREE
FRENCH GARRISON
OVER AT BRAZZAVILLE.
I COULD BE INDUCED TO
ARRANGE YOUR PASSAGE.
MY LETTER OF TRANSIT?
I COULD USE A TRIP,
BUT IT DOESN'T
AFFECT OUR BET.
YOU STILL
OWE ME 10,000 FRANCS.
AND THAT 10,000 FRANCS
SHOULD PAY OUR EXPENSES.
OUR EXPENSES?
MM-HMM.
LOUIS, I THINK
THIS IS THE BEGINNING
OF A BEAUTIFUL
FRIENDSHIP.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.