Universal definitely has
an intense commitment
to preservation and
restoration of its film library.
The restoration of Jaws is
a tremendous responsibility.
Centennial Project is
Universal Pictures' 100th anniversary.
We are releasing 100 of our titles.
Thirteen of our classic titles are
being fully restored on a film level.
In the case of Jaws,
this is history, culture.
Whoa. Hold on.
What's exciting about this digital age
where we're able to restore these movies,
we can bring these classic movies
back to life in a way that makes them
more vivid than even we remember them
when we went to the cinema to see them.
The restoration of Jaws
began with, literally,
going through our records,
our vault inventory,
and understanding what
elements were at our disposal.
Universal has
always had a strong commitment
to preservation, restoration
in their film heritage.
In the library,
in the vaults we have here,
we've got over
a million pieces of material.
Around the world, we've got over
three million pieces of material.
In Jaws, there's about
2,700 pieces of this altogether.
When we started on the Jaws project
we determined that luckily, we
were able to use the original negative
and that was our primary source.
Working with a negative is always
gonna get you a better resolution.
But passes on the element add up.
The negative of Jaws was
pretty crummy, was pretty bad.
The first thing we want
to do when we have that element,
we wanna make sure
that all the perforations are
correct, we don't have any tears.
Many sections had vertical scratches
running through significant
portions of the film.
Come on in the water!
We felt the best result
was to do a wet gate scan.
There is a special liquid
that will take all the scratches
and basically erase them.
As the film is on the scanner,
it's literally passed
through this liquid bath
so that those scratches are not visible
to the light that's
passing through that film.
With Jaws the colorists need to have
as much information to
work with as possible.
We're checking to make sure that
the full range of the image is there.
That's really what the
scanning process is about.
Once we had the digital scans,
we went ahead and dealt with
issues such as film movement and dirt.
We have very high-end
graphics and editing systems.
These tools enable us
to take the digital data
that results from the film scans
and manipulate those pixels
in many different ways.
With Jaws, each damage was different.
Just would have to
look at it and see if you
could take a frame after the
damage or a frame before.
Part of a good frame here,
a good frame there.
Composite it together
and digitally clean it out.
You could spend three to
four hours on one frame.
Chief Brody!
When you're working with
an original negative,
across some of the cuts, you
see tremendous differences
in color, brightness, contrast.
Our colorists do a great job
at matching all those shots.
We had a particular
issue inside the cabin.
Those windows didn't match cut-to-cut.
I had to balance out the view
from the inside which changed.
The viewer should not be distracted
because the levels of light are changing.
Nothing materially
was changed about the film.
But the image on a really, really
good hi-def TV screen looks better
than the film looked when
first projected in 1975.
See that?
I got the crème de la crème.
Right there.
Mary Ellen Moffit.
She broke my heart.
The audio side on Jaws,
our project was
to build a 7.1 up mix.
It's an iconic film.
We're very sensitive to the
integrity of the original mix.
At that time, it was an analogue process.
They recorded on 35 mm mag.
We're taking all that sound information
and adding additional channels to it.
That process consists
of taking the original dialogue,
music and effects mono-tracks
and realizing that we're now
gonna place it in a 7.1 audio codec.
To do that, you're gonna have to go
and get backgrounds and sound effects
that can get you to move
left to right on the screen.
Once you've got all those elements
picked out, then you've got the music.
There's certainly a number
of things about Jaws that are unique.
A lot of that on
the audio side goes back to
those first two notes
in John Williams' score.
They set the tone for the shark.
Oh, God, help!
Throughout the film, you
don't necessarily see the shark,
but you hear those notes, and
so the sound really drives that film.
In some places you don't hear anything.
You're underwater and
there's nothing but score.
That is what lets you know that
something is about to happen.
Hey. He's taking it.
Go!
Boys, I think he's come back
for his noon feeding.
The sound is better than
we've ever heard it before.
Our whole intent is to be able to fulfill
the audio experience
in that 7.1 remix.
They put kind of a dinosaur sound
when the shark is sinking
at the end of the film
and you can hear it better.
It doesn't overpower anything, it's just
gonna be a little more
audible to the ear now.
The outputs of this
process are both film and digital.
We're restoring high
resolution digital files,
as well as recording a new negative.
We do both because digital files,
while they are convenient to work with
and they allow us a wide range of options,
for an archival means, we still
want a piece of film to put away.
This is our cultural heritage.
It's very important to
preserve the physical film,
the 35 mm film and the negative.
Film is a known commodity.
We can put that on a shelf and
store it in the proper conditions
and that thing will last 100 years plus.
It's the movie the people remember.
It's just really crystal
clear and very vivid.
I, quite honestly, have
never seen this level of commitment.
We're very passionate about Jaws
and using the tools that we have
it allows us to get the best
possible restoration.
There's something else out there.
What is it?
It was a shark.
Originally in the theater,
you might have seen
film movement as the print wore out.
Or you might have seen dirt
as the print got dirtier.
But today, with a digital file cleaned up
it looks like that
on play one and play 1,000.
The new Jaws is still the Jaws Jaws.
It's enhanced by
the HD Blu-ray experience.
People are gonna like what they see.
It looks amazing.
This shark, swallow you whole.
But I'll catch him and kill him.
For that, you get the head,
the tail, the whole damn thing.
You're going to need a bigger boat.
The wonderful thing about this restoration
is what you get is something
that for both sight and sound,
is something that I didn't even
get when I made the movie.