(FOOTSTEPS SHUFFLING)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(BREATHING AND MUMBLING)
(AIR HISSING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(GROWLING)
(OWL HOOTS)
(RINGING)
(RINGING STOPS)
(GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(GRUNTS)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(MOANING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUMBLES)
(RINGING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(SCREAMING)
AGENT: I think I see him!
(SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
(SPACESHIP WHIRS)
(MEN PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
AGENT: This way!
(PANTING)
(WHIRRING INTENSIFIES)
(SCREECHING)
(MOANS)
(WHIMPERING)
(DISTANT POLICE SIREN)
(DISTANT DOGS BARKING)
(FOOTSTEPS SHUFFLING)
STEVE: Five.
(SARCASTICALLY)
MIKE: Oh, great.
So you got an arrow right in
your chest. And you're out
10 melee rounds.
Oh, no.
GREG: Don't worry about it, Mike.
I got resurrection.
I'm already one of the
undead. I can still
throw death spells.
GREG: I'm just trying to
help you out, man.
Don't be so cranky.
How about throwing a spell
over the pizza man?
Where's our pizza, man?
Well, I'm ready now to play.
I'm ready to play now,
you guys.
We're in the middle, Elliott.
You can't just join any
universe in the middle.
I got him! I got him!
What am I asking for?
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
GREG: Yeah.
ELLIOTT: Mike?
GREG: I know. It's not for us,
it's for his mother.
Mike?
Papa-oom-mow-mow.
You have to ask Steve.
He's game master.
He has absolute power.
Steve?
TYLER: (MOCKINGLY) Steve,
can I play now?
Go wait for the pizza first.
Then I'm in?
Yeah, you're in.
Figure out your strategy.
You're playing after Greg.
Plenty of sausage
and pepperonis.
Everything but
the little fishies.
(DOG BARKING)
(CLATTERING SOUND)
Harvey?
Harvey, is that you, boy?
(ROCK AND ROLL
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(HUMMING)
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
TYLER: Over here, you guys.
MIKE: Stop it.
TYLER: Sorry.
(CLATTERING SOUND)
Harvey?
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
TYLER: All's you can get
is those 40-year-olds.
MARY: How do you win
this game anyway?
STEVE: There's no winning.
It's like life.
You don't win at life.
GREG: Money helps.
ELLIOTT: Mom! Mom! There's
something out...
MIKE: Where's the pizza?
Mom! Mom! There's
something out there!
It's in the tool shed.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(PANTING)
It threw the ball at me.
Quiet!
(WHISPERING)
Nobody go out there.
(ALL LAUGHING)
MARY: Stop. Now, you guys
stay right here.
MIKE: You stay here, Mom.
We'll check it out.
And put those knives back!
ELLIOTT: Come on, Mom!
(BOYS LAUGHING)
MARY: It's okay, Elliott.
MARY: Let's go
get the flashlight.
Hold it. Wait a minute.
TYLER: Creeps. Creepy.
MARY: What exactly
did you see?
STEVE: It's dark out here.
ELLIOTT: In there.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
STEVE: It's scary.
GREG: Psst.
MARY: There's nothing in here.
MIKE: The gate's open.
Look at these.
Coyote's come back again, Mom.
MARY: Okay, party's over.
Everybody, back inside now.
Get out. Hurry up.
Quick. Hurry up. Come on.
Tyler, give me that knife.
Oh, great. Nice one, Elliott.
(OTHER BOYS SIGHING)
It was an accident.
MARY: A pizza?
Who said you guys
could order a pizza?
Him.
(STAMMERING)
MARY: In the house.
MIKE: You geek, man.
ELLIOTT: But Mom,
it was real. I swear.
TYLER: Douche bag.
MARY: No douche-bag
talk in my house.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(RASPY BREATHING)
(CLATTERING SOUNDS)
(HARVEY GRUMBLES)
(HARVEY WHINES)
(ELLIOTT WHISTLES)
ELLIOTT: Elliott,
you're crazy.
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(BREATHING NERVOUSLY)
(RUSTLING)
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(RASPY BREATHING)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
(E.T. SCREECHING)
(SWING SET CREAKING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(ELLIOTT WHISTLING)
Hello.
Hello?
(KEYS JANGLING)
(GASPS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
GERTIE: What are you
going as for Halloween?
ELLIOTT: I'm not going
to stupid Halloween.
Why don't you go
as a goblin?
Shut up.
(CHUCKLES)
It's not that we don't
believe you, honey.
Well, it was real.
I swear.
What are you going as, Gert?
I'm going as a cowgirl.
ELLIOTT: So what else is new?
Maybe it was
an iguana.
ELLIOTT: It was no iguana.
MIKE: Maybe a...
A...
You know how they say
there are alligators
in the sewers?
Alligators in the sewers.
All we're trying to say
is, maybe you just
probably imagined it.
I couldn't have
imagined it.
Maybe it was a pervert
or a deformed kid
or something.
A deformed kid.
Maybe an elf
or a leprechaun.
It was nothing like that,
penis breath!
Elliott!
Sit down.
(MARY CLEARS THROAT)
Dad would believe me.
(SIGHS)
Maybe you ought to call
your father and tell
him about it.
I can't. He's in
Mexico with Sally.
Where's Mexico?
Excuse me.
(WHISPERING) I'm
going to kill you.
MARY: (SHAKILY) If you ever see
it again, whatever it is,
don't touch it.
Just call me.
And we'll have somebody
come and take it away.
Like the dogcatcher?
They'll give it a lobotomy
or do experiments
on it or something.
MARY: It's your turn to
do the dishes, fellas.
I set and cleared.
MIKE: I did breakfast.
I did breakfast.
(MARY SLAMS DOWN DISHES)
(MARY SIGHS)
What's the matter, Mom?
He hates Mexico.
Damn it! Why don't you
grow up? Think how other
people feel for a change.
(WATER RUNNING)
(FOOTSTEPS SHUFFLING)
(MOANING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS) Mom.
(WHISPERING) Mom. Mom!
Michael.
(GRUNTING)
(WHISPERING)
Michael. Mom.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(PURRING)
(PURRS)
(GOBBLING)
(PURRING)
(MURMURS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(CRASHING)
(BLEATING)
(PANTING)
(WHISPERS) Wow.
(PURRS)
(LAUGHS)
(YAWNS)
(PURRS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(CRUNCHING)
Okay, you're hot.
I'll be back.
MIKE: Mary, can I
back the car out?
MARY: Not one foot
past the driveway.
(CRUNCHING)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
You were outside last night
waiting for that thing to
come back, weren't you?
MARY: Are you going to
live if I go to work?
Okay. No TV.
(PANTING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
MARY: Come on.
Mommy, look what Michael did.
This and that...
I see them, Gert.
And when I catch him,
I'll catch him.
Come on. Don't be afraid.
It's all right. Come on.
Come on.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(PURRS)
Do you talk?
You know, talk?
Me, human.
Boy.
Elliott.
(SNIFFING)
ELLIOTT: Elliott.
Coke. See, we drink it.
It's a drink. You know, food?
These are toys.
These are little men.
This is Greedo.
And then, this is Hammerhead.
You see, this is Walrus Man.
And then this is Snaggletooth.
And this is Lando
Calrissian. See?
And this is Boba Fett.
Look. They can even
have wars. Look at this.
(MAKING LASER SOUNDS)
And look. Fish.
The fish eat the fish food
and the shark eats the fish,
but nobody eats a shark.
See, this is Pez. Candy.
You see, you eat it.
You put the candy in here
and then when you lift up
the head, the candy comes
out and you can eat it.
You want some?
This is a peanut.
You eat it.
But you can't eat this one
because this is fake.
This is money. You see?
We put the money
in the peanut.
You see? Bank.
You see? And then,
this is a car.
This is what we get around in.
See? A car.
(CRUNCHING SOUNDS)
Hey! Hey! Wait a second.
No. You don't eat them.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
Stay.
Stay. I'll be right here.
(E.T. MOANS)
Okay? I'll be right here.
Harv!
(E.T. SHRIEKS)
He won't bite.
(E.T. SHRIEKING)
Come on, Harvey.
(E.T. MOANS)
He'll like this.
This.
(SHRIEKS)
(E.T. SHRIEKS)
(ELLIOTT PANTING)
(E.T. WHIMPERING)
Are you okay?
Too much excitement, huh?
Want a Coke?
(MIKE SINGING)
There are so many
people to see
So many people you can
check up on and add
to your collection
But they keep you hanging on
Nothing but health shit.
Add to your collection
But they keep you hanging on
(MIKE CONTINUES SINGING)
ELLIOTT: Mike, Mike, come in.
How you feeling, faker?
I'm feeling fine.
Look, I got something
really important...
Tyler said he got 69,000
on Asteroids yesterday.
But he pulled the plug.
Look, remember the goblin?
You're so lame, Elliott.
Come on, Michael.
He came back.
He came back?
Oh, my God!
(SCREAMS)
ELLIOTT: One thing.
I have absolute power.
Say it.
Say it!
What have you got?
Is it the coyote?
No. Look...
Okay. Now, swear it.
The most excellent
promise you can make.
Swear as my only
brother on our lives.
Okay, don't get so
heavy. I swear.
(SIGHS) Okay.
Stand over there.
And you'd better take off
your shoulder pads.
What?
You might scare him.
And close your eyes.
Don't push it, Elliott.
ELLIOTT: I'm not coming
out there until your
eyes are closed.
Okay. They're closed.
(MUTTERING)
Mom is going
to kill you.
(EXCLAIMING)
Okay. Swear it
one more time.
I have absolute power.
(IMITATING YODA)
You have absolute power. Yes.
(LAUGHS)
(E.T. MOANS)
GERTIE: Elliott! Look
what I made for you!
(E.T. GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(SHRIEKS)
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
MARY: Kids, I'm home!
Guys?
ELLIOTT: In the closet, fast.
MARY: Anybody up there, kids?
(GERTIE SCREAMS)
(E.T. SHRIEKS)
MARY: Anybody home?
Hi, honey, how are you feel...
What happened in here?
Oh, you mean my room.
This is no room.
This is an accident.
I was reorganizing.
(E.T. BREATHING)
MARY: I can see that.
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
MARY: Put those shelves
back on the wall, dear.
Let's get the toys
off the floor.
Make your bed since
you are not using it.
Well, you're feeling
better, I see.
Will you guys keep an eye
on Gertie for me while
I take a shower?
Absolutely.
(SIGHS)
Bye, Mom.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(E.T. BREATHING)
(E.T. MOANS)
Elliott...
I'm keeping him.
What is it?
He won't hurt you, Gertie.
ELLIOTT: He won't
hurt you, Gertie.
We're not going to hurt you.
Is he a boy or a girl?
ELLIOTT: He's a boy.
Was he wearing
any clothes?
(SIGHS)
No.
But, look,
you can't tell.
Not even Mom.
Why not?
Because grownups
can't see him.
Only little kids
can see him.
Give me a break.
(IMITATING COUNT DRACULA)
Well, do you know
what's going to happen
if you do tell?
Do it, Mike. We have to.
MIKE AS
THE DOLL:
No, please!
No! I'll do
anything, please!
(GERTIE CRYING)
MIKE AS THE DOLL:
Gertie, help me!
No, please!
GERTIE: Give it!
ELLIOTT: Promise?
GERTIE: Yes.
Do you promise?
(MOANS)
(E.T. PURRS)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(HARVEY WHINING)
What are you doing, Gert?
I'm going to play
in Elliott's room.
MARY: Okay. Don't
let him torture you.
I won't, Mary.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
MARY: Hello?
Jerry! Jerry!
(KNOCKING)
MIKE: Come on,
come on. Hurry up.
GERTIE: Don't be pushy, pushy.
A plant for you.
MIKE: Maybe he's some animal
that wasn't supposed to live.
You know, like those
rabbits we saw that time.
ELLIOTT: Don't be lame.
GERTIE: Green, orange, red.
MIKE: Could be a monkey
or an orangutan...
ELLIOTT: A bald monkey?
Is he a pig? He
sure eats like one.
GERTIE: You could make faces.
And make them mean and happy
and make them get sharp teeth.
We are here.
ELLIOTT: We're here.
MIKE: No, use this.
GERTIE: You could make
all sorts of things.
Okay. We're here.
We are here.
ELLIOTT: Where are you from?
(E.T. MOANS)
I don't like his feet.
They're only feet,
you little twerp.
He's trying to
tell us something.
ELLIOTT: Earth.
Home.
ELLIOTT: Home.
(E.T. MURMURS)
What's he doing?
What's happening?
(RATTLING)
Elliott.
Oh, no.
(SHRIEKS)
Elliott, what is it?
I don't know. Something scary.
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(INDISTINCT MEN'S VOICES)
(KEYS JANGLING)
BOSS: Got a pulse?
MAN: No, boss.
Hold it. We got it right here.
BOSS: Follow him.
MAN: You think this house?
(E.T. MOANING)
MIKE: Did you explain
school to him?
ELLIOTT: How do you
explain school to
higher intelligence?
MIKE: Maybe he's not
that smart. Maybe
he's a worker bee
who only knows
how to push buttons.
ELLIOTT: He's too smart.
MIKE: Okay, I just hope
we don't wake up
on Mars or something,
surrounded by
millions of little
squashy guys.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
GIRL: Hi, Elliott.
Hey, Elliott, where's
your goblin?
Shut up.
Did he come back?
Well, did he?
Yeah, he came back.
But he's not a goblin.
He's a spaceman.
(ALL EXCLAIMING SARCASTICALLY)
As in extraterrestrial.
Where's he from? Uranus?
Get it? Your anus?
(SCHOOL BUS HONKING HORN)
He doesn't get it, Ty.
Get it? Your anus?
He doesn't get it.
You're so immature.
And you're a sine supremus.
Zero charisma.
Sine supremus.
Shut up, Greg!
GREG: Sine supremus.
Zero charisma!
You wimp.
(ALL SHOUTING)
MARY: Let's go.
(SIGHS)
Come on. Get in the car.
We're gonna be late.
(THUMP FROM UPSTAIRS)
(EXHALES)
(E.T. SIGHS)
TEACHER: Okay, boys and girls,
today we will be doing
the actual frog dissection
for which we've
been preparing.
And you will find
many similarities.
As you get into the
dissection, you will
discover that the anatomy...
(HARVEY GROWLS)
(HARVEY WHINES)
TEACHER: The scalpel
is very sharp.
Use discretion when
you are cutting.
There will be very little
blood. There may be
a few body fluids.
(E.T. SNIFFING)
E.T.: Ugh.
(OPENS CAN)
TEACHER: As we get started
with the dissection...
(BELCHES)
ALL: Ew!
...remember that the things
that you are writing down...
(BELCHES)
TEACHER: One thing that you
should be looking for
during the dissection
is to locate the heart
and notice that
it is still beating.
(E.T. EXCLAIMS)
TEACHER: I'm going to
once more emphasize
the similarities
of those things which
we see in the...
(GRUNTS)
TEACHER: Similarities
with human anatomy...
(GRUNTS)
First of all,
here's the heart...
(CHUCKLES DRUNKENLY)
The intestines will be
going through their
peristaltic action.
ELECTRONIC TOY: X-W-V-U.
A-F-P.
That is incorrect.
The correct spelling
of nuisance is
N-U-I-S-A-N-C-E.
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
They're pulling us up.
TEACHER: Class, these are
the cotton balls with
the chloroform.
And as soon as I get them
all in, be sure and put
the lid on right away.
ALL: Ew!
That's it.
That will start them
going to sleep.
And they won't feel anything.
They won't be hurt.
It'll take a little while.
If you don't want
to watch them,
you don't have to.
(FROGS CROAK)
Say hi.
Can you talk?
Can you say hi?
(YAWNING)
(BURPS)
GIRL ON TV: Hello.
Uncle Ralph!
It's Uncle Ralph,
long distance from California!
I'll talk fast. This call
must be expensive.
RALPH: No, no, no, no. If
I call anytime on Saturday
without an operator,
I can talk for five minutes
for 85 cents plus tax.
If I talk less, I pay less.
Let me talk to
that little fella.
GIRL: Lou, it's Uncle Ralph.
LOU: Hello, Uncle Ralph.
(SIGHS)
Hmm.
Save him.
Run for your life!
Back to the river!
Back to the forest!
ELLIOTT: Run!
I want to save you!
Let's get out of here!
Get out!
I got to let him go!
(STRAINING)
You've got to save him!
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
TEACHER: Let me handle this!
Class. Let me handle this!
I can handle this.
Let me get this.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(SCREAMS)
(WIND HOWLING)
GIRL ON TV: Grandpa,
what's wrong?
GRANDPA: I'm afraid Betsy Sue
isn't going to run tomorrow.
GIRL: Oh, no. Is it
anything serious?
MARY: Harvey, I'm home.
Come here, boy.
(E.T. GROANING)
GERTIE: Here he is.
MARY: Here's who?
GERTIE: The man from
the moon, but I think
you've killed him already.
Honey, just as soon
as I unload the stuff, okay?
Med-bugs.
GERTIE: I want you
to meet somebody.
MARY: This stuff has gone up
so much in one week.
GERTIE: I want you
to meet somebody.
MARY: Okay, honey, as soon
as I finish putting all
this stuff away, all right?
(SIGHS)
Oh!
(E.T. MUMBLING)
Stupid ragù. I knew it
wouldn't come out.
WOMAN ON TV: "B."
GERTIE: "B."
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
MARY: What's with this?
Hello.
Yeah, this is she.
GERTIE: "Basket."
"Bandit."
"Ball."
"Basket. Bandit. Ball."
"Bugs."
"Bananas."
Intoxicated?
(SNIFFS)
You sure you have
the right Elliott?
"B. B."
GERTIE: "Biscuits."
E.T.: B.
MAN ON TV:
But "B" is for boy...
E.T.: B.
...with a baseball and bat.
You said "B."
E.T.: B.
You said "B." Good.
B.
Good.
Okay, I'll be
right down. Thank you.
Ooh...
Gertie, I have to
go pick up Elliott.
Will you be a good girl...
Mommy, he can talk.
Of course he can talk.
I'll be right back in
10 minutes. Stay there.
BIG BIRD: Ladies and
gentlemen, little Grover
here will demonstrate
by chinning himself two times.
GROVER: Two times?
BIG BIRD: Two times.
GROVER: Can I start?
BIG BIRD: Okay. Go ahead.
GROVER: Okay. Here we go.
Phone.
E.T.: Phone.
You want to call somebody?
MARY: I am not
paying for frogs.
GERTIE: Be good. Be good.
Stay here. Stay.
And don't tell
anybody. Nobody.
Be good. Be good.
ELLIOTT: Move.
Oh, God!
Elliott.
What?
E.T.: Elliott.
Elliott.
I taught him how to talk now.
He can talk now.
E.T.: Elliott!
GERTIE: Look what he brought
up here all by himself.
E.T.: Elliott.
GERTIE: What's he
need this stuff for?
E.T.: Elliott. Elliott.
E.T. Can you say that?
Can you say E.T.?
E.T.
(LAUGHS)
E.T. E.T. E.T.
Be good.
GERTIE: "Be good."
I taught him that, too.
ELLIOTT: You should
give him his dignity.
This is the most ridiculous
thing I've ever seen!
E.T.: Phone.
Phone?
He said "phone"?
Can't you understand English?
He said "phone."
Home.
You're right.
That's E.T.'s home.
E.T.
Home, phone.
E.T. phone home.
He wants to call somebody.
(LAUGHS)
What's all this shit?
E.T.: E.T. phone home.
Oh, my God, he's talking now.
Home.
E.T. phone home?
E.T.: E.T. phone home.
And they'll come?
Come.
Home.
CHILD: Come on.
I promise, Mom.
SIBLING: What book?
CHILD: Any one you want.
SIBLING: Spiderman...
MOTHER: I'm fine. We'll just
put a smile on our face
and try to get
through the evening.
That's all I want to do.
WOMAN: We can't ask Cathy
to go trick-or-treating
in the same old sheet
she wore last year.
ELLIOTT: Now I wish I would've
listened in science.
Think, Michael.
MIKE: I guess we should
just grab anything that
looks like he could make
a machine out of.
ELLIOTT: What would
make a radar?
MIKE: How the hell do I know?
You're the genius here.
You have absolute
power, remember?
"I found him.
He belongs to me."
You know, Elliott,
he doesn't look too
good anymore.
Don't say that! We're fine!
What's all this "we" stuff?
MIKE: You say "we"
all the time now.
Really, Elliott, I think
he may be getting sick.
ELLIOTT: Look, he's fine.
MIKE: Okay, okay.
Forget I mentioned it.
MIKE: Grab that Fuzzbuster.
Dad's shirt.
(CHUCKLES)
Remember when he used to
take us out to the ball games
and take us to the movies,
and we'd have popcorn fights?
MIKE: We'll do that
again, Elliott.
ELLIOTT: Sure.
(SNIFFS)
Old Spice.
Sea Breeze.
MARY: "Peter says,
'The redskins were defeated?
"'Wendy and the boys
captured by the pirates?
"'I'll rescue her.
I'll rescue her.'
"He leaps, first
at his dagger...
(E.T. BREATHING)
"...then at his grindstone
to sharpen it.
"Tink alights near the shell,
and rings out a warning cry.
"'Oh, that is
just my medicine.'
"She says, 'Poisoned?
"'Who could've poisoned it?'
"'I promised Wendy to take it
and I will, as soon as I have
sharpened my dagger.'
"Tink, who sees its red color
"and remembers the red
of the pirate's eye
"nobly swallows the draft
as Peter's hand is
reaching for it.
"'Why, Tink, you have
drunk my medicine.'
"She flutters strangely about
the room, answering him now
in a very thin tinkle."
Ouch.
E.T.: Ouch.
MARY: "She says she thinks
she could get well again
"if children believed
in fairies.
"Do you believe in fairies?
Say quick that you believe."
GERTIE: I do! I do! I do!
MARY: "If you believe,
clap your hands.
"Many clap, some
don't, a few hiss.
(E.T. MOANS)
MARY: "But Tink
is saved. 'Thank you.
"'Oh, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
"'And now to rescue Wendy."'
GERTIE: Can you read it
to me again?
(E.T. PURRING)
MARY: "Peter says..."
ELLIOTT: He's putting it
together now.
I told you he was smart.
MIKE: I'm worried, Elliott.
MIKE: He could blow up
the whole house.
ELLIOTT: He knows
what he's doing.
MIKE: Listen to how
he's breathing.
(STRAINED BREATHING)
ELLIOTT: It's going to work.
MIKE: What's he feeling now?
ELLIOTT: He's feeling
everything.
ELLIOTT: Now, you're going
as a ghost. You promised.
GERTIE: I'm only pretending
I'm going as a cowgirl.
ELLIOTT: Okay. Now, you know
the plans by heart, don't you?
Meet you at the lookout.
At the lookout. I'm not
stupid, you know.
MARY: Listen, buster.
You won't get four blocks
in this neighborhood
dressed like that.
MIKE: Please.
MARY: No, and that is final.
You are not going
as a terrorist.
MIKE: But all the guys are!
I'm not stupid, you know.
ELLIOTT: Ready?
E.T.: Ready.
MIKE: Wait, Mom.
Don't look.
MARY: Okay.
Okay, Mom. You can look now.
(SHRIEKING)
(LAUGHING)
MARY: Oh, that's great!
(E.T. GRUMBLING)
(MARY LAUGHING)
Stay here.
E.T.: Oh...
E.T.: Ouch.
MIKE: (WHISPERING)
Stop that! No! Don't!
E.T.: Ouch. Ouch.
MIKE: No. It's a fake knife.
It's a fake.
E.T.: Ouch.
MARY: Okay.
All right.
You look great!
MIKE: Thank you.
ELLIOTT: Thank you.
E.T.: Thank you.
(E.T. GASPS)
(E.T. COUGHS)
Be back one hour after
sundown. No later.
E.T.: Ohhh!
MARY: Bye.
(MARY LAUGHS)
(E.T. CRIES OUT)
MIKE: Gertie,
come here. Come on.
KID: Trick or treat?
E.T.: Home. Home.
Home. Home. Home.
MIKE: Be back one hour
after sunset. No later.
ELLIOTT: I'll try as
fast as I can, Mike.
You got to cover me.
ELLIOTT: Well, come on.
Help me.
MIKE: We'll be waiting
for you, Elliott.
So come back for sure.
It's too bumpy. We'll have
to walk from here!
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
E.T.!
(SHOUTING)
Not so high! Not so high!
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
Ha! Ha!
Don't crash, please.
(E.T. GRUNTS)
(ELLIOTT GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
(ELLIOTT GASPS)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
I really can't believe
you did this.
(MARY MUTTERING)
Your father's going to
hear about this one.
(SIGHS)
Mexico.
(KEYS JANGLING)
(E.T. SIGHS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
ELLIOTT: E.T., it's working.
It's working!
Home.
You did it!
It's working!
Home.
(SHOUTING JOYFULLY)
ELLIOTT: E.T., it's working!
(KEYS JANGLING)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Check the door on the left.
ELLIOTT: We have to
go now, E.T.
We're so late already.
(COUGHS)
We have to go home now, E.T.
(E.T. MOANS)
You should give
them some time.
Ouch.
You could be happy here.
I could take care of you.
ELLIOTT: I wouldn't let
anybody hurt you.
We could grow up
together, E.T.
Home.
(COUGHS)
(WHISPERS) E.T.?
E.T.?
COP: How was he dressed
when last seen?
He was dressed as a
hunchback.
COP: Hunchback.
Is there anything
to indicate that he
might have run away?
Any family problems
or recent arguments?
My husband and I just
separated recently
and it hasn't been easy
on the children, but...
GERTIE: My father's in Mexico.
But run away, I...
Where would he
have gone? (SOBS)
MIKE: Elliott.
MARY: (SOBBING) Oh, Elliott!
(YELLING) Don't ever do
this again, Elliott!
Oh, my. You're so hot.
Run up and draw him
a bath. Quick, Gert.
(WHISPERING)
MARY: Sorry I yelled at you.
(TEARFULLY) Thanks very much
for all your trouble.
Is he here?
(SOBBING) You've
got to find him, Mike.
MIKE: Where is he?
In the forest.
At the bald spot.
You've got to find him.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(SHOUTING) E.T.!
E.T.!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(E.T. MOANS)
No!
(RACCOON CHITTERING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
Mom, would you come with me?
MARY: What is it?
Mary, just come with me.
Michael, what?
Mom, remember the goblin?
Michael, what are you
talking about?
Just swear the most excellent
promise you can make.
Michael.
(LAUGHS)
That's terrific.
Mom.
We're sick.
I think we're dying.
(GASPS)
MARY: Michael.
MIKE: Mom, it's okay.
(E.T. GROANS)
Downstairs.
He's not going to
hurt you, Mom.
He's not gonna hurt you.
MARY: Michael,
get her downstairs.
It's the man from the moon.
The man from the moon!
ELLIOTT: You don't know
him! You don't know him!
(E.T. CRYING OUT)
We can't leave him alone.
(E.T. CRYING)
(PRESSURIZED BREATHING)
(YELLS)
(MARY SCREAMS)
(PRESSURIZED BREATHING)
(MARY GASPS)
(TOY TRAIN WHISTLES)
MARY: This is my home!
(STRAINED BREATHING)
(PRESSURIZED BREATHING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Home.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(KEYS JANGLING)
MAN ON INTERCOM: The collagen
unit, report to the blue level
immediately.
(KEYS JANGLING)
DOCTOR 1: Does he
sleep at night?
MARY: I don't know.
I don't know.
What's the matter
with Elliott?
DOCTOR 2: Have you noticed
any surface sweating?
MARY: No.
Has it lost any hair?
GERTIE: He never had any hair.
DOCTOR 1: Are the children
all right?
MARY: Yes.
PSYCHIATRIST: Did it ever
build anything or
write anything down?
MIKE: Uh... No.
Would you say it has the ability
to manipulate its
own environment?
He's smart. He
communicates
through Elliott.
Elliott thinks
its thoughts.
No. Elliott feels
his feelings.
SCIENTIST 1: We've identified
his primary carrier protein by
electrophoresis.
It's definitely not albumin.
SCIENTIST 2: Testing shows no
deficit. Some F&F. HTS test...
SCIENTIST 3: EEG analysis
shows complete coherence
and synchronization of
brainwave activity between
both subjects.
DOCTOR 1: Skin biopsy reveals
9 millimeters of...
WOMAN ON INTERCOM:
Read isotonic.
Nitrates.
255 million equivalent.
DOCTOR 2: Better do IV
and oral contrast.
If there's no response,
let's move to
hypertonic saline.
DOCTOR 3: We have
meta-starch available.
DOCTOR 2: Cut five per kilo.
DOCTOR 3: CVP line could help.
DOCTOR 2: I think you
get more information
with this one gain.
ELLIOTT: You have no right to
do this. You're scaring him.
You're scaring him!
DOCTOR 2:
Respiratory rate, 12.
DOCTOR 4: Good air entry but
decreased tidal volume
on the boy.
Put him on O2 five liters by
nasal cannula and draw blood
gas in 20 minutes.
DOCTOR 2: Temperature's
dropped from 20 to 17 degrees
centigrade.
DOCTOR 3: Get a
hypothermia blanket...
ELLIOTT: Please
leave him alone.
Can you leave him alone?
I can take care of him.
DOCTOR 2: Get a Doppler-scope
in here and set me up for
a 2D cardiac echo.
DOCTOR 1: Skin is cool
and diaphoretic.
DOCTOR 2: He's not refusing
at all. He needs inotropic
support.
DOCTOR 4: PH is down to 7.03.
He's got metabolic acidosis.
It could be sepsis.
DOCTOR 3: We've drawn two sets
of blood cultures.
DOCTOR 2: He needs
broad-spectrum coverage.
How about amp, gen, flagyl?
(TAPPING ON GLASS)
KEYS: Elliott.
I've been to the forest.
MILITARY DOCTOR:
He shouldn't talk now.
Well, he has to
talk now, Major.
Elliott, that machine,
what does it do?
(VERY WEAKLY)
The communicator?
Is it still working?
KEYS: It's doing something.
What?
I really shouldn't tell.
(BREATHLESSLY)
He came to me.
Elliott, he came to me, too.
I've been wishing for this
since I was 10 years old.
I don't want him to die.
What can we do that
we're not already doing?
He needs to go home.
He's calling his people
and I don't know
where they are.
He needs to go home.
Elliott, I don't think
that he was left
here intentionally.
But his being here
is a miracle, Elliott.
It's a miracle.
And you did the best
that anybody could do.
I'm glad he met you first.
DOCTOR 1: He's got DNA.
Incredible.
ALL: What?
DOCTOR 1: He doesn't have
four nucleotides like we do.
He has six.
DOCTOR 2: I've got
de-synchronization of the two
brainwave activities.
DOCTOR 3: What are they?
E.T.!
NURSE 1: The boy's condition
is stabilizing. His blood
pressure's coming back up.
E.T.
E.T. (HOARSELY): Elliott.
DOCTOR 4: He's speaking.
NURSE 2: He's talking.
E.T., stay with me.
Please.
E.T.: Stay.
ELLIOTT: Together.
(GASPING FOR BREATH)
I'll be right here.
E.T.: Stay.
Elliott.
Stay.
The creature's pressure is
bottoming out. His complexes
are slow and widening.
DOCTOR 4: How's the boy?
He's converting back to
normal sinus rhythm.
DOCTOR 2: They're separating.
DOCTOR 4: Yes, definitely
separating.
DOCTOR 3: Boy and creature
are separating.
KEYS: What does that mean?
NURSE 1: The boy's coming back.
We're losing E.T.
E.T., answer me, please.
DOCTOR 4: Everything is
going to be fine.
Please.
DOCTOR 4: Just relax.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
No!
E.T., don't go!
(ALARM RINGING)
No blood pressure.
He's got no pulse
or respiration.
DOCTOR 1: We can't get a pulse
or blood pressure on
the creature.
NURSE: It doesn't look like
he's breathing.
(E.T. GROANS)
ELLIOTT: Leave him alone!
You're killing him!
Leave him alone!
DOCTOR 2: Let's move it!
DOCTOR 1: Get the boy
out of here. Get him away.
(ELLIOTT SHOUTING)
Stop it! You're killing him!
You're killing him!
He came to me!
DOCTOR 1: Any pulses?
Any pulses?
DOCTOR 2: Okay, let's go.
He came to me!
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
NURSE: Minimal breath sounds.
Calm down. Calm down. Calm...
Let's try some bretylium.
Can we have some
bretylium, please?
Getting a pulse?
DOCTOR 3: Compressed air.
Compressed air's fine.
DOCTOR 2: Thank you.
All IV push.
He's not ventilating.
His pupils are fixed
and dilated.
How about some
more drugs?
Quiet.
Defibrillate him.
DOCTOR 4: Everybody,
stand clear.
DOCTOR 1: Clear.
DOCTOR 2:
We're losing him.
DOCTOR 1: One more time.
Quiet.
DOCTOR 4: It's still v-fib.
DOCTOR 1: Okay, let's go.
Okay. Let's go. Let's go.
DOCTOR 3: Quiet.
MARY: Elliott?
Mom.
DOCTOR 3: Try calcium.
DOCTOR 1: He needs some
calcium in his body.
DOCTOR 2: Let's continue
CPR, please.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
COP: Would you people
stand back?
Something's happening.
Ooh, they're going to die.
Shut up, Greg.
Something is
definitely happening.
DOCTOR 2: Anybody have
any ideas?
DOCTOR 1: EKG's flat.
MILITARY DOCTOR: Okay, I'm
going to call it.
DOCTOR 1: I think he's dead.
DOCTOR 2: No. I don't know.
MILITARY DOCTOR: All right.
I'm calling it.
What time do you have?
NURSE: 1536.
MILITARY DOCTOR:
15 hours, 36 minutes.
Okay.
Let's pack him in ice.
Let's leave.
Is he dead, Mama?
I think so, sweetheart.
Can we wish for him
to come back?
Yeah.
I wish.
I wish, too.
MARY: Come on, Gert.
We'll wait for Elliott
in the front room.
DOCTOR: Cardiac arrest was
terminated at 1500 hours
and 36 minutes.
He received intravenous
lidocaine, intravenous
epinephrine, a lidocaine drip,
2.7% sodium-chloride solution,
catheters from the "A" line.
And the intravenous line
should be sent for culture.
He was monitored with
an EEG and an EKG.
He was defibrillated...
KEYS: They're going to have
to take him away now.
They're just gonna
cut him all up.
Would you like
to spend some time
alone with him?
(DOCTOR CONTINUING
HIS REPORT)
DOCTOR: Could we all
step out for a minute, please?
Look at what they've
done to you.
I'm so sorry.
You must be dead
because I don't know
how to feel.
I can't feel anything anymore.
You've gone some place
else now.
I'll believe in you
all my life.
Every day.
E.T.,
I love you.
Oh, my God.
E.T. phone home.
(EXCLAIMS JOYFULLY)
E.T.: Home. Phone home.
Phone home.
Does this mean they're coming?
Yes.
(EXCLAIMS IN SHOCK)
E.T.: E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home.
(WHISPERING)
ELLIOTT: Stay.
Shut up.
E.T.: Phone.
E.T.: Phone home.
ELLIOTT: Quiet!
Phone! Phone! Phone!
Would you shut up?
Phone home. E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home.
(MUFFLED)
Phone home.
Phone home. Elliott.
Elliott. Elliott. Elliott.
Elliott?
(PRETENDING TO CRY)
No.
Elliott, why don't you
come with me?
No. No.
It's all right.
No, no.
KEYS: It'll be all right.
(ELLIOTT PRETENDING TO CRY)
KEYS: Would you like
the flowers?
(CONTINUES FAKE CRYING)
He's alive! He's alive!
(EXCLAIMS IN EXCITEMENT)
(BANGS HEAD)
(INAUDIBLE)
Are they gone, Mama?
MARY: Who's gone, honey?
GERTIE: The boys.
What boys?
I'm supposed to give you
this note when they're gone.
Give it to me
now, Gertie.
Oh, my God.
Give me a hand
with this.
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
Where's your mask?
It's back here.
Well, get it on!
I'm trying!
Hey, who are you?
I'm driving.
Open the door, son.
There's a guy out here.
What do I do?
What are you waiting
for? Let's go!
ELLIOTT: Well, let's get
out of here, Michael!
I've never driven
forward before!
(STARTS ENGINE)
(HORN HONKING)
Get the bikes. Meet us
at the playground at
the top of the hill.
GREG: Let's do it!
ELLIOTT: Come on, Michael!
Go, go, go!
We're all gonna die,
and they're never gonna
give me my license.
(BOTH EXCLAIMING IN SURPRISE)
MIKE: Where's the playground?
It's near the preschool!
Where's that?
I don't know streets.
Mom always drives me.
Son of a bitch.
(BOTH EXCLAIMING FRANTICALLY)
Where are you going?
To the spaceship.
Spaceship?
To the spaceship to the moon.
MARY: Quiet!
Oh, my God.
MAN: Stop the van!
MAN: Don't pull them off!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
MAN: That did it!
(RINGING)
Okay. He's a man from outer
space and we're taking him
to his spaceship.
Well, can't he just beam up?
This is reality, Greg.
AGENT: Keep her back!
MARY: No!
AGENT: Hold her back!
MARY: No guns!
They're children!
MARY: No! No! No!
AGENT: Where are they?
MARY: No!
AGENT: There's nobody here.
(E.T. GROANING)
Where are we going?
To the forest!
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Follow me!
(CAR TIRES SQUEALING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
We got them,
at the bottom of the hill.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
This is Unit 302.
We've cut the kids off
at the bottom of the hill.
Send backup units.
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(E.T. EXCLAIMING)
Let's split up.
Okay!
Hang on!
We made it! Oh, shit!
Whoa!
Tell me when it's over!
(GASPS)
(RINGING)
Ah.
Home.
(SPACESHIP ENGINE
SLOWING DOWN)
GERTIE: (SHOUTING)
Stop the car, Mama!
They're over there!
I just wanted
to say goodbye.
MIKE: He doesn't
know goodbye.
E.T.: Be good.
Yes.
(KISSES)
Ah.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Come.
Stay.
(E.T. SIGHS)
Ouch.
(CRYING)
(E.T. PURRING)
I'll be right here.
Bye.
(SPACESHIP ENGINE WHIRRING)