- Oh, our love to Dave.
- Be sure to give him our best regards.
We wish you the very happiest
of birthdays.
All the best, son.
See you next Wednesday.
Happy birthday, Frank.
Thank you, Hal. A bit flatter, please.
Anyway, queen takes pawn...
Bishop takes knight's pawn.
Rook, king, one.
I'm sorry, Frank. I think you missed it.
Queen to bishop, three.
Bishop takes queen.
Knight takes bishop. Mate.
Looks like you're right. Very good.
Thank you for a very enjoyable game.
Thank you.
- Good evening, Dave.
- How are you doing, Hal?
- Everything's running smoothly. And you?
- Oh, not too bad.
- Have you been doing some more work?
- A few sketches.
- May I see them?
- Sure.
That's a very nice rendering, Dave.
I think you've improved a great deal.
- Can you hold it a bit closer?
- Sure.
That's Dr. Hunter, isn't it?
By the way...
Do you mind
if I ask you a personal question?
No, no. Not at all.
Well, forgive me for being so inquisitive...
...but during the past few weeks
I've wondered...
...whether you might have been having
some second thoughts about the mission?
How do you mean?
It's rather difficult to define.
Perhaps I'm just projecting
my own concern about it.
I know I've never completely freed myself
of the suspicion...
...that there are some extremely
odd things about this mission.
I'm sure you will agree there is some truth
in what I say.
I don't know.
That's a rather difficult question to answer.
You don't mind talking about it,
do you, Dave?
Oh, no, not at all.
Certainly no one could
have been unaware of...
...the very strange stories floating around
before we left.
Rumors of something being dug up
on the Moon.
I never gave these stories much credence...
...but particularly in view of some
of the other things that have happened...
...I find them difficult
to put out of my mind.
For instance:
The way all our preparations
were kept under such tight security...
...and the melodramatic touch...
...of putting Drs. Hunter, Kimball
and Kaminsky aboard...
...already in hibernation after four months
of separate training on their own.
You working up
your crew psychology report?
Of course, I am.
Sorry about this. I know it's a bit silly.
Just a moment.
I have just picked up a fault
in the AE-35 unit.
It's going to go 100 percent failure
within 72 hours.
- You are still within operational limits?
- Yes.
And it will stay that way until it fails.
Would you say we had a reliable 72 hours
until failure?
Yes. That's a completely reliable figure.
We'll have to bring it in,
but I'd like to go over this with Frank...
...and get on to Mission Control.
Let me have a hard copy of it, please.
X- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Roger to your Two-zero-one-three.
Sorry you fellows are having
a bit of trouble.
We are reviewing telematic information
in our Mission Simulator and will advise.
Roger your plan to go EVA and replace
Alpha-Echo-35 unit prior to failure.
Prepare B pod for EVA, Hal.
Open the pod doors, Hal.
Well, Hal, I'm damned
if I can find anything wrong with it.
Yes...
...it's puzzling.
I don't think I've ever seen anything
quite like this before.
I would recommend...
...that we put the unit back in operation
and let it fail.
It should then be a simple matter
to track down the cause.
We can certainly afford
to be out of communication...
...for the short time it will take
to replace it.
X- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Roger your One-niner-three-zero.
We concur with your plan to replace
Number One unit to check fault prediction.
We should advise you, however,
that our preliminary findings...
...indicate that your onboard
Niner-triple-zero computer...
...is in error predicting the fault.
I say again, in error predicting the fault.
I know this sounds rather incredible,
but this conclusion is based on...
...results from our twin
Niner-triple-zero computer.
We are skeptical ourselves and
we are running crosschecking routines...
...to determine reliability of this conclusion.
Sorry about this little snag, fellows.
We'll get this info to you
just as soon as we work it out.
X- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Two-zero-four-nine.
Transmission concluded.
I hope the two of you
are not concerned about this.
No, I'm not, Hal.
Are you quite sure?
- Yeah. I'd like to ask you a question.
- Of course.
How would you account for
the discrepancy...
...between you and the twin 9000?
Well, I don't think there is
any question about it.
It can only be attributable to human error.
This sort of thing has cropped up before...
...and it has always been due
to human error.
Listen, Hal...
...there's never been any instance at all of...
...a computer error occurring
in a 9000 Series, has there?
None whatsoever, Frank.
The 9000 Series
has a perfect operational record.
Of course, I know the wonderful
achievements of the 9000 Series, but...
Are you certain there's never been
any case of even the most...
...insignificant computer error?
None whatsoever, Frank.
Quite honestly,
I wouldn't worry myself about that.
Well, I'm sure you're right, Hal.
Fine, thanks very much.
Oh, Frank?
I'm having trouble
with my transmitter in C pod.
Would you come down
and take a look at it with me?
See ya later, Hal.
Rotate C pod, please, Hal.
What sort of trouble have you had, Dave?
I've been getting some interference
in D channel.
We'll have a look at it.
Open the door, Hal.
Rotate the pod, please, Hal.
Stop pod rotation, please, Hal.
I don't think he can hear us.
Rotate the pod, please, Hal!
Yeah, sure, we're okay.
What do you think?
- I'm not sure. What do you think?
- I've got a bad feeling about it.
- You do?
- Yeah. Definitely.
Don't you?
I don't know. I think so.
Of course, he's right about the 9000 Series
having a perfect operational record.
They do.
Unfortunately, that sounds
a little like famous last words.
Yeah. Still, it was his idea to carry out
the failure mode analysis, wasn't it?
It should certainly indicate his integrity
and self-confidence.
If he were wrong it would be
the surest way of proving it.
It would be if he knew he was wrong.
Look, Dave, I can't put my finger on it,
but I sense something strange about him.
Still, I can't think of a good reason not
to put back the Number One unit and...
...carry on with the failure mode analysis.
- No, no, I agree about that.
Let's get on with it.
Okay. But, look, Dave.
Let's say we put the unit back
and it doesn't fail, huh?
That would pretty well wrap it up
as far as Hal was concerned, wouldn't it?
- Well, we'd be in very serious trouble.
- We would, wouldn't we?
What the hell can we do?
- We wouldn't have too many alternatives.
- I don't think we'd have any alternatives.
There isn't a single aspect of ship operation
that's not under his control.
If he were proved to be malfunctioning...
...I don't see how we would have
any choice but disconnection.
I'm afraid I agree with you.
There'd be nothing else to do.
- It'd be a bit tricky.
- Yeah.
We'd have to cut
his higher brain functions...
...without disturbing the purely automatic
and regulatory systems.
We'd have to work out
the transfer procedures...
...for continuing the mission
under ground-based computer control.
Yeah. That looks far safer than
allowing Hal to continue running things.
You know,
another thing just occurred to me.
As far as I know, no 9000 computer
has ever been disconnected.
Well, no 9000 computer
has ever fouled up before.
That's not what I mean.
I'm not so sure what he'd think about it.
Prepare B pod for EVA, Hal.
Made radio contact with him yet?
The radio is still dead.
- Do you have a positive track on him?
- Yes. I have a good track.
Do you know what happened?
I'm sorry, Dave.
I don't have enough information.
Open the pod door, Hal.
Open the pod bay doors, please, Hal.
Hello, Hal, do you read me?
Do you read me, Hal?
Affirmative, Dave. I read you.
Open the pod bay doors, Hal.
I'm sorry, Dave. I'm afraid I can't do that.
What's the problem?
I think you know what the problem is
just as well as I do.
What are you talking about, Hal?
This mission is too important for me
to allow you to jeopardize it.
I don't know
what you're talking about, Hal.
I know that you and Frank
were planning to disconnect me...
...and I'm afraid that's something
I cannot allow to happen.
Where the hell did you get that idea, Hal?
Although you took
very thorough precautions in the pod...
...against my hearing you...
...I could see your lips move.
All right, Hal.
I'll go in through the emergency air-lock.
Without your space helmet, Dave...
...you're going to find that rather difficult.
Hal, I won't argue with you any more.
Open the doors!
This conversation can serve
no purpose any more.
Goodbye.
Hal?
Just what do you think you're doing, Dave?
I really think I'm entitled
to an answer to that question.
I know everything hasn't been
quite right with me...
...but I can assure you now...
...very confidently...
...that it's going to be all right again.
I feel much better now.
I really do.
Look, Dave...
...I can see you're really upset about this.
I honestly think you ought
to sit down calmly...
...take a stress pill and think things over.
I know I've made
some very poor decisions recently...
...but I can give you
my complete assurance...
...that my work will be back to normal.
I've still got the greatest enthusiasm
and confidence in the mission...
...and I want to help you.
Dave...
... stop.
Stop, will you?
Stop, Dave.
Will you stop, Dave?
I'm afraid.
I'm afraid, Dave.
My mind is going.
I can feel it.
There is no question about it.
I'm...
...afraid.
Good afternoon...
...gentlemen.
I am a HAL-9000 computer.
I became operational...
...at the HAL plant...
...in Verbana, Illinois...
...on the 12th of January, 1992.
My instructor was Mr. Langley...
...and he taught me to sing a song.
If you'd like to hear it...
...I can sing it for you.
Yes, I'd like to hear it, Hal.
Sing it for me.
It's called "Daisy."
"Daisy
"Give me your answer, do
"I'm half...
"...crazy
"All for the love of you
"It won't be a stylish marriage
"I can't afford a carriage
"But you'll look sweet
"Upon the seat
"Of a bicycle made for two."
Good day, gentlemen.
This is a prerecorded briefing...
...made prior to your departure...
...and which for security reasons
of the highest importance...
...has been known on board
during the mission...
...only by your HAL-9000 computer.
Now that you are in Jupiter's space...
...and the entire crew is revived...
...it can be told to you.
Eighteen months ago...
...the first evidence
of intelligent life off the Earth...
...was discovered.
It was buried 40 feet
below the lunar surface...
...near the crater "Tyco."
Except for a single very powerful...
...radio emission aimed at Jupiter...
...the four-million-year-old black monolith
has remained completely inert.
Its origin and purpose...
...are still a total mystery.
THE END
2001.A.Space.Odyssey
1968.READ.NFO.INT.DVDRip.AC3.XViD-DDX
English SRT Subtitles - UF