Slave in the Magic Mirror,
come from the farthest space.
Through wind and darkness,
I summon thee.
Speak!
Let me see thy face.
What wouldst thou know, my Queen?
Magic Mirror on the wall,
who is the fairest one of all?
Famed is thy beauty, Majesty.
But hold, a lovely maid I see.
Rags cannot hide her gentle grace.
Alas, she is more fair than thee.
Alas for her! Reveal her name.
Lips red as the rose.
Hair black as ebony.
Skin white as snow.
Snow White!
Want to know a secret?
Promise not to tell?
We are standing
by a wishing well
Make a wish into the well
That's all you have to do
And if you hear it echoing
Your wish will soon come true
- I'm wishing
For the one I love
- To find me
- Today
- I'm hoping
And I'm dreaming of
- The nice things
- He'll say
- I'm wishing
For the one I love
- To find me
- Today
- Oh!
- Hello.
- Oh.
- Did I frighten you?
Wait! Wait, please.
Don't run away.
Now that I've found you
Hear what I have to say
One song
I have but one song
One song only for you
One heart tenderly beating
Ever entreating
Constant and true
One love
That has possessed me
Thrilling me through
One song
My heart keeps singing
Of one love
Only for you
Take her far into the forest.
Find some secluded glade
where she can pick wildflowers.
Yes, Your Majesty.
And there, my faithful Huntsman,
you will kill her!
But, Your Majesty, the little Princess!
Silence!
You know the penalty if you fail.
Yes, Your Majesty.
But to make doubly sure
you do not fail,
bring back her heart in this.
One song,
I have but one song
Hello there.
What's the matter?
Where's your mama and papa?
Why, I believe you're lost.
Oh, please don't cry.
Come on, perk up.
Won't you smile for me?
That's better.
Your mama and papa can't be far.
There they are!
Can you fly?
Good-bye. Good-bye!
I can't, I can't do it.
Forgive me.
I beg of Your Highness, forgive me.
I don't understand!
She's mad, jealous of you!
She'll stop at nothing!
- But, but who?
- The Queen.
- The Queen?
- Now, quick, child, run.
Run away, hide!
In the woods! Anywhere!
Never come back!
Now, go. Go! Go!
Run! Run! Hide!
Oh!
Please don't run away.
I won't hurt you.
I'm awfully sorry.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
But you don't know
what I've been through.
And all because I was afraid.
I'm so ashamed of the fuss I've made.
What do you do
when things go wrong?
Oh! You sing a song!
With a smile and a song
Life is just like a bright, sunny day
Your cares fade away
And your heart is young
With a smile and a song
All the world seems to waken anew
Rejoicing with you
As the song is sung
There's no use in grumbling
When raindrops come tumbling
Remember you're the one
Who can fill the world with sunshine
When you smile and you sing
Everything is in tune and it's spring
And life flows along
With a smile and a song
I really feel quite happy now.
I'm sure I'll get along somehow.
Everything's going to be all right.
But I do need a place to sleep at night.
I can't sleep
in the ground like you
or in a tree the way you do.
And I'm sure no nest would possibly
be big enough for me.
Maybe you know where I can stay.
In the woods somewhere?
You do?
Will you take me there?
Oh, it's adorable!
Just like a doll's house.
I like it here.
Ooh, it's dark inside.
Guess there's no one home.
Hello?
May I come in?
Shh!
Oh!
What a cute little chair!
Why, there's seven little chairs!
Must be seven little children.
And from the look of this table,
seven untidy little children.
A pickaxe. A stocking, too!
And a shoe!
And just look at that fireplace.
It's covered with dust.
And look, cobwebs everywhere!
My, my, my!
What a pile of dirty dishes!
And just look at that broom!
Why, they've never swept this room.
You'd think their mother would…
Maybe they have no mother.
Then they're orphans.
That's too bad.
I know!
We'll clean the house
and surprise them.
Then maybe they'll let me stay.
Now, you wash the dishes.
You tidy up the room.
You clean the fireplace.
And I will use the broom.
Just whistle while you work
And cheerfully together
we can tidy up the place
So hum a merry tune
It won't take long when there's a song
to help you set the pace
And as you sweep the room
Imagine that the broom
Is someone that you love and soon
you'll find you're dancing to the tune
Oh, no, no, no, no! Put them in the tub.
When hearts are high the time will fly
So whistle while you work
Uh-uh, uh-uh!
Not under the rug.
So whistle while you work
We dig, dig, dig,
dig, dig, dig, dig
In our mine the whole day through
To dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig
is what we like to do
It ain't no trick to get rich quick
If ya dig, dig, dig
with a shovel or a pick
- In a mine
- Where a million diamonds
- Shine
We dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig, dig
From early morn 'til night
up everything in sight
We dig up diamonds by the score
A thousand rubies
Sometimes more
Though we don't know
what we dig 'em for
We dig, dig, dig-a-dig, dig
Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho, hum
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho…
Let's see what's upstairs.
Oh, what adorable little beds!
And look,
they have their names carved on them.
Doc, Happy,
Sneezy, Dopey…
What funny names
for children!
Grumpy, Bashful and Sleepy.
I'm a little sleepy myself.
Oh! Oh!
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho! Heigh-ho
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's home from work we go
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho, heigh…
Look!
Our house! The lit's light…
Uh, the light's lit.
Jiminy Crickets!
- The door is open.
- The chimney's smoking.
- Something's in there.
- Maybe a ghost.
- Or a goblin.
- A demon.
Or a dragon.
Mark my words,
there's trouble a-brewin'.
Felt it coming all day. My corns hurt.
- Gosh!
- That's a bad sign.
- What'll we do?
- Let's sneak up on it.
Yes.
We'll, uh, squeak up… Sneak up.
Come on, hen… Uh, men. Follow me.
Psst!
Shh!
Careful, men.
Search every cook and nanny…
Hook and granny…
Crooked fan…
Search everywhere.
Shh!
Quiet.
Look! The floor, it's been swept!
Hah!
Chair's been dusted!
Our window's been washed.
Gosh, our cobwebs are missing.
Why, why, why, why,
the whole place is clean!
There's dirty work afoot.
Sink's empty.
Hey, someone stole our dishes!
They ain't stole.
They're hid in the cupboard.
My cup's been washed.
Sugar's gone.
Something's cooking.
Smells good!
Don't touch it, you fools!
Might be poison.
See? It's witches' brew.
Look what's happened
to our stable… Uh, table.
Flowers!
- Huh?
- Look, goldenrod.
Don't do it. Take them away.
My nose! My hay fever!
You know I can't stand it.
I can't… I can't… I… Oh.
Ah…
Ahhh…
Thanks!
Hey!
Shh!
Ya crazy fool!
Fine time you picked to sneeze!
I couldn't help it. I can't tell.
When you gotta, you gotta.
I… I… I gotta.
It's coming.
- Don't let him.
- Stop him.
Oh! Ah… Ah… Ah!
- No, tie it tight.
- Don't let go.
- Hold him tight.
- I'll tie it.
Make a hard knot.
There, that will hold him.
- Thanks!
- Shh!
Quiet, you fool!
You want to get us all killed?
- What's that?
- That's it.
- Sounded close.
- It's in this room right now.
- It's up there.
- Yeah. In the bedroom.
One of us has gotta go down
and chase it up.
Up. Down.
Here, take it.
Don't be nervous.
Don't be afraid. We're right behind you.
Yes! Right behind ya.
Here it comes!
- It's after us.
- Don't let it out.
Hold it shut.
- Here it comes.
- Now's our chance.
Get it now!
- Quick!
- Give it to it!
Don't let it get away!
Hold on there. It's only Dopey.
- Did you see it?
- How big is it?
- Was it a dragon?
- Has it got horns?
- Was it breathing fire?
- Was it droolin'?
What was it doin'?
He says it's a,
a monster asleep in our beds!
- Let's attack.
- While it's sleeping.
Yeah, while it's sleeping.
- Hurry, men. It's now or never!
- Off with its head.
- Break its bones.
- Chop it to pieces.
We'll kill it dead.
- Jiminy Crickets!
- Gosh!
- Gee!
- What a monster!
It covers three beds.
Let's kill it before it wakes up.
- Which end do we kill?
- Shh!
Shh!
Well, eh, ah…
- What is it?
- Why, it… It's a girl!
She's mighty purdy.
She's beautiful, just like a angel.
Angel, hah! She's a female!
And all females is poison!
They're full of wicked wiles.
What are wicked wiles?
I don't know. But I'm agin 'em.
Shh!
Not so loud. You'll wake her up.
Aw, let her wake up!
She don't belong here nohow.
- Look out.
- She's movin'.
- She's wakin' up.
- What'll we do?
Hide.
Oh, dear.
I wonder if the children are…
Oh!
Why, why, you're little men!
How do you do?
- I said, how do you do?
- How do you do what?
Oh, you can talk! I'm so glad!
Now, don't tell me who you are.
Let me guess.
I know, you're Doc.
Why, why, why, yes.
Yes! That's true.
And you're, you're Bashful.
Oh, gosh!
And you, you're Sleepy.
How'd you guess?
And you?
And you're Sneezy.
- Yes, and you must be…
- Happy, ma'am. That's me.
And this is Dopey. He don't talk none.
You mean he can't talk?
He don't know. He never tried.
Oh, that's too bad.
Oh!
You must be Grumpy.
Oh, yes! Yes!
Hah! We know who we are.
Ask her who she is
and what she's a-doin' here.
Hmph! Yeah!
What are you and who are you doin'?
What are you… Who are you, my dear?
Oh, how silly of me. I'm Snow White.
- Snow White?
- The Princess?
Yes.
Well… Well, my,
my dear Quincess… Uh, Princess.
We're, uh, we're honored.
Yes, we're, uh, we're…
- Mad as hornets!
- Mad as hornets! No, no, we're not.
We're bad as cornets…
No, no, as bad as… What was I sayin'?
Nothing! Just standin' there
sputterin' like a doodlebug!
Who, who, who,
who's butterin' like a spoodledug?
- Who's… Uh, gutter…
- Aw, shut up and tell her to get out!
Please don't send me away!
- If you do, she'll kill me.
- Kill you?
- Who will?
- Yes, who?
- My stepmother, the Queen.
- The Queen?
- She's wicked!
- She's bad!
- She's mighty mean!
- She's an old witch!
I'm warnin' ya.
If the Queen finds her here,
she'll swoop down
and wreak her vengeance on us!
But she doesn't know where I am!
She don't, eh? She knows everything.
She's full of black magic.
She can even make herself invisible.
Pfft!
Might be in this room right now.
Oh, she'll never find me here.
And if you let me stay,
I'll keep house for you.
I'll wash and sew
and sweep and cook and…
Cook?
Can you make dapple lumpkins…
Uh, lumple dapplins?
- Apple dumplings!
- Eh, yes!
Crapple dumpkins.
Yes, and plum pudding
and gooseberry pie…
Gooseberry pie?
Hooray! She stays!
Ah!
Soup!
Hooray!
Uh-uh, uh-uh!
Just a minute.
Supper's not quite ready.
You'll just have time to wash.
Wash? Wash?
- Wash? Wash? Wash?
- Hah! Knew there was a catch to it.
- Why wash?
- What for? We ain't goin' nowhere.
'Tain't New Year's.
Oh, perhaps you have washed.
Perhaps we…
- Yes! Perhaps we have.
- But when?
When? When. Uh, you said whe…
Why, last week.
Why, recently!
Yes, recently!
Oh, recently!
Let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands!
Why, Doc, I'm surprised!
Come on, let's see them.
Oh, Bashful, my, my, my!
And you?
Worse than I thought!
Oh!
How shocking!
Goodness me, this will never do.
March straight outside and wash,
or you'll not get a bite to eat.
Hah!
Well, aren't you going to wash?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Oh! Did you hurt yourself?
Hah, women!
Courage, men, courage.
Don't be nervous.
Gosh, it's wet!
It's cold, too!
We ain't gonna do it, are we?
Well, it'll please the Princess.
I'll take a chance for her!
Me, too!
Hah! Her wiles are beginnin' to work.
But I'm warnin' ya,
you give 'em an inch,
and they'll walk all over ya!
Don't listen to that old warthog.
Come on now, men.
- How hard do ya scrub?
- Will our whiskers shrink?
Do ya get in the tub?
Do ya have to wash
where it doesn't show?
Now, now, now, don't get excited.
Here we go.
Step up to the tub
'Tain't no disgrace
Just pull up your sleeves
and get 'em in place
Then scoop up the water
and rub it on your face and go…
Pick up the soap
Now don't try to bluff
Work up a lather
And when you got enough
Get your hands full of water
and you snort and you snuff and go…
You douse and you souse
Rub and you scrub
You sputter and splash
all over the tub
You may be cold
and wet when you're done
But you gotta admit
it's good and clean fun
So splash all you like
'Tain't any trick
As soon as you're through
You'll feel mighty slick
Bunch of old nanny goats.
Ya make me sick going…
Hah! Next thing ya know
she'll be tyin' your beards up
in pink ribbons
and smellin' ya up with
that stuff called "perfoom."
Hah!
A fine bunch of water lilies
you turned out to be.
I'd like to see anybody
make me wash if I didn't wanna.
Get him!
Hey, let go of me!
Get him over to the tub.
Let me loose, you fools! Let me loose!
Get him up on the tub. Get him up!
Hang on to him! Bang him! Pound him!
Get him up on the tub! On the tub.
That's the tub. That's the tub.
Don't, don't, don't, don't get excited!
Don't get… Don't get up… Don't get…
Get the soap!
- Hey, steady, men.
- We'll get him there. We'll get him.
Never say die. Never say die.
You don't…
Now, scrub good and hard
It can't be denied
That he'll look mighty cute
as soon as he's dried
Well, it's good for the soul
And it's good for the hide to go…
Ain't he sweet?
Smells like a petunia.
He sure is cute!
You'll pay dearly for this!
Supper!
- Supper!
- Food. Hooray!
Hah!
Magic Mirror on the wall,
who now is the fairest one of all?
Over the seven jeweled hills
beyond the seventh fall,
in the cottage of the seven dwarfs
dwells Snow White, fairest one of all.
Snow White lies dead in the forest.
The Huntsman has brought me proof.
Behold her heart.
Snow White still lives,
the fairest in the land.
'Tis the heart of a pig
you hold in your hand.
The heart of a pig!
Then I've been tricked!
The blundering fool!
I'll go myself to the dwarfs' cottage
in a disguise so complete
no one will ever suspect.
Now, a formula to transform
my beauty into ugliness,
change my queenly raiment
to a peddler's cloak.
Mummy Dust to make me old.
To shroud my clothes,
the black of night.
To age my voice, an old hag's cackle.
To whiten my hair, a scream of fright.
A blast of wind
to fan my hate!
A thunderbolt
to mix it well.
Now,
begin thy magic spell.
Look!
My hands!
My voice!
My voice.
A perfect disguise.
And now…
A special sort of death
for one so fair.
What shall it be?
Ah!
A poisoned apple!
Sleeping Death.
I'd like to dance
and tap my feet
But they won't keep in rhythm
You see, I washed 'em both today
and I can't do nothin' with 'em
Ho-hum, the tune is dumb
The words don't mean a thing
Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing?
I…
Oh, gosh!
I chased a polecat up a tree
Way out upon a limb
And when he got the best of me
I got the worst of him
Ho-hum, the tune is dumb
The words don't mean a thing
Isn't this a silly song
for anyone to sing?
Watch out. Be ca… Watch… Watch…
Watch… Watch…
Thanks.
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hooray!
That was fun!
Now you do something.
Well, what shall I do?
- Tell us a story.
- Yes, tell us a story.
- A true story.
- A love story.
Well, once there was a princess.
Was the princess you?
- And she fell in love.
- Was it hard to do?
Oh, it was very easy.
Anyone could see that the Prince
was charming.
The only one for me.
Was he strong and handsome?
Was he big and tall?
There's nobody like him
anywhere at all.
Did he say he loved ya?
Did he steal a kiss?
He was so romantic
I could not resist
Some day my prince will come
Some day we'll meet again
And away to his castle we'll go
To be happy forever
I know
Hah! Mush!
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true
Oh, my goodness!
It's past bedtime.
Go right upstairs to bed.
Wait! Hold on there, men!
The, uh, Princess will sleep
in our beds upstairs.
But where will you sleep?
Oh, we'll be quite comfortable
down here in… in…
In a pig's eye!
In a pig's eye… Sty. No, no! I mean…
We'll be comfortable, won't we, men?
Oh, yes. Mighty comfortable.
Now don't you worry about us.
- We'll be all right, ma'am.
- Go right on up now, my dear.
Well, if you insist.
Good night.
Good night, Princess.
You're sure you'll be comfortable?
Oh, yes. Very comfortable.
Well, pleasant dreams.
Pleasant dreams.
Let go!
- I saw it first!
- Now, men, don't get excited.
Remember, share.
It's share and share alike.
Look out, it'll rip. It'll rip!
Bless the seven little
men who have been so kind to me.
And… And may my dreams come true.
Amen.
Oh, yes!
And please make Grumpy like me.
Hah! Women!
A fine kettle of fish!
Dip the apple in the brew.
Let the Sleeping Death seep through!
Look! On the skin!
The symbol of what lies within.
Now, turn red to tempt Snow White.
To make her hunger for a bite.
Have a bite?
It's not for you.
It's for Snow White.
When she breaks the tender peel
to taste the apple in my hand,
her breath will still, her blood congeal.
Then I'll be fairest in the land!
But wait!
There may be an antidote.
Nothing must be overlooked.
Oh, here it is!
"Love's First Kiss."
Bah!
No fear of that.
The dwarfs will think she's dead.
She'll be buried alive!
Buried alive!
Thirsty?
Have a drink!
Now, don't forget, my dear.
The… The old Queen's a sly one,
full of witchcraft.
So beware of strangers.
Don't worry. I'll be all right.
See you tonight.
Uh, yes. We… Well, c'mon, men.
Be awful careful
'cause if anything'd happen to you, I, I…
- Good-bye.
- Oh, gosh!
Hah! Disgustin'!
And be sure to watch out…
To wa… To wa…
To wa…
Watch out.
Thanks.
Well… All right.
But that's the last… Wha…
Oh, go on. Run along.
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
Heigh-ho
Good-bye! Good-bye!
Now I'm warnin' ya.
Don't let nobody or nothin' in the house.
Why, Grumpy, you do care.
Hah!
Good-bye, Grumpy!
The little men will be away
and she'll be all alone
with a harmless old peddler woman.
A harmless old peddler woman!
Some day
my prince will come
Some day we'll meet again
And away to his castle we'll go
To be happy forever I know
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true
All alone, my pet?
Why, why, yes, I am. But…
The, the little men are not here?
No, they're not, but…
Mmm-hmm.
Making pies?
Yes, gooseberry pies.
It's apple pies
that make the menfolks' mouths water.
Pies made from apples like these.
- Oh, they do look delicious.
- Yes!
But wait 'til you taste one, dearie.
Like to try one?
Hmm?
Go on. Go on, have a bite.
Stop it! Stop it! Go away! Go away!
Shame on you,
frightening a poor old lady.
Oh, I thought I'd lost it.
There, there. I'm sorry.
Oh! My heart!
Oh, my… My poor heart.
Take me into the house and let me rest.
A drink of water, please.
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
Hey, look!
- Stop that!
- Get away, boy. Get away! Go on, shoo!
Go on! Get outta here!
What ails these crazy birds?
They've gone plumb daffy.
Yeah, they've…
And because you've been
so good to poor old Granny,
I'll share a secret with you.
This is no ordinary apple.
It's a magic wishing apple.
A wishing apple?
Yes!
One bite and all your dreams
will come true.
- Really?
- Yes, girlie.
Now, make a wish
and take a bite.
- Go on, get!
- These pesky critters won't stop.
- 'Tain't natural.
- There's something wrong.
They ain't actin' this way for nothin'.
Maybe the old Queen's
got Snow White.
- The Queen!
- Snow White!
The Queen'll kill her!
We gotta save her!
Yes! Yes! We, we, we gotta save her!
- She'll kill her!
- What'll we do?
Yes, yes, what'll we do?
Come on! Giddap!
Wait for me! Wait for…
There must be something
your little heart desires.
Perhaps there's someone you love.
Well, there is someone.
I thought so. I thought so!
Old Granny knows a young girl's heart.
Now, take the apple, dearie,
and make a wish.
I wish… I wish…
That's it, go on! Go on.
And that he will carry me away
to his castle
where we will live happily ever after.
Fine! Fine! Now take a bite.
Don't let the wish grow cold!
Oh, I feel strange.
- Her breath will still.
- Oh. Oh.
- Her blood congeal.
- Oh.
Now I'll be fairest in the land!
Hurry, hurry.
There she goes!
After her!
I'm trapped! What will I do?
The meddling little fools!
I'll fix ya. I'll fix ya.
I'll fix ya! I'll crush your bones!
Look out!
One song
I have but one song
- One song
- Only for you
- For you
One heart
Tenderly beating
Ever entreating
- Constant and true
- So true
- One love
That has possessed me
- Thrilling me through
- So true
- One song
- My heart keeps singing
- Keeps singing
- Of one love
- One love
Only for you…
And away
to his castle you'll go
To be happy forever we know
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Grumpy.
Oh, Dopey.
Good-bye!
Some day when spring is here
We'll find our love anew
And the birds will sing
And wedding bells will ring
Some day when my dreams
Come true!