- ( heavy breathing )
Oh. Oh.
( keys jangle )
( shriek )
( shouting )
- ( shriek )
- This way!
( sirens )
- Five. - Oh, great.
- You got an arrow right in your chest,
and you're out 10 rounds. - Oh, no.
- Don't worry about it, Mike.
I got resurrection. I'll bring you back.
- I'm already one of the undead, Greg.
I can still throw death spells, huh, Steve?
- I'm just trying to help you out, man.
Don't be so cranky.
- How about throwing a spell over the pizza man?
Where's our pizza, man? Get it? Huh?
- Well, I'm ready now to play.
- You know you're a thief.
- I'm ready to play now, you guys.
- We're in the middle, Elliott.
Can't just join any universe in the middle.
- I got him! I got him!
Hey, what am I asking him for now?
- Papa Oom Mow Mow. - Okay. Papa Oom Mow Mow.
Yeah. - Mike?
- I know. It's not for us. It's for his mother.
- Mike?
- Papa Oom Mow Mow.
- You have to ask Steve. He's gamemaster.
He has absolute power.
- Steve. - Thanks a lot. Bye.
- Go wait for the pizza first.
- Then I'm in? - Yeah, you're in.
Figure out your strategy,
'cause you playing after Greg.
- With plenty of sausage and pepperonis.
- Everything but the little fishies.
( dog barks )
( clanging )
- Harvey?
Harvey, is that you, boy?
- Oh, this is great time. I destroyed the dungeon.
- Is this the one I asked for?
- Yeah, that's the one you asked for.
( overlapping voices )
- Stop it. - All right.
- Harvey?
( clanging )
- All's you can get is those 40-year-olds.
- So how do you win this game anyway?
- There's no winning.
It's like life. You don't win at life.
- Money helps. - Yeah, but--
- Mom! Mom! There's something out--
- Where's the pizza?
- Mom, Mom, there's something out there!
It's in the toolshed!
- Calm down. Calm down.
- It threw the ball at me.
- Quiet!
Nobody go out there.
( all laugh )
- Stop. Now you guys stay right here.
- You stay here, Mom. We'll check it out.
- And put those knives back!
- Come on, Mom.
- Okay, Elliott.
Hold it. Wait a minute. Come on.
- You little creep.
- What exactly did you see? - It's dark out here.
- ( hums Twilight Zone theme )
( all laugh )
- It's scary.
- There's nothing in here.
- The gate's open.
- Look at these.
Coyote's come back again, Mom.
- Okay, party's over. Everybody back inside.
Hurry up. Quick, hurry up.
Tyler, give me that knife.
- Oh, great. Nice one, Elliott.
- It was an accident.
- A pizza. - Yeah, accident.
- Who said you guys could order a pizza, huh?
- Uh, him. - Huh?
- In the house. - You geek, man.
- But, Mom, it was real. I swear.
- Douche bag, Elliott.
- No douche bag talk in my house.
( heavy breathing )
( dog whimpers )
( whistles )
- Elliott, you're crazy.
- ( grunts )
( heavy breathing )
( shrieks )
- Aah!
( screaming and shrieking )
( whistles )
- Hello?
Hello?
( keys jangle )
( heavy breathing )
- What are you going as for Halloween?
- I'm not going to stupid Halloween.
- Why don't you go as a goblin?
- Shut up.
- It's not that we don't believe you, honey.
- Well, it was real. I swear.
- What are you going as, Gert?
- I'm going as a cowgirl.
- So what else is new?
- Maybe it was an iguana.
- It was no iguana.
- Maybe a... you know how they say
there are alligators in the sewers?
- Alligators in the sewers.
- All we're trying to say
is maybe you just probably imagined it.
- I couldn't have imagined it.
- Maybe it was a pervert or a deformed kid or something.
- A deformed kid.
- Maybe an elf or a leprechaun.
- It was nothing like that, penis breath.
- Elliott. ( laughs )
Sit down.
( clears throat )
- Dad would believe me.
- Maybe you ought to call your father
and tell him about it.
- I can't. He's in Mexico with Sally.
- Where's Mexico?
- Excuse me.
- I'm gonna kill you.
- If you ever see it again, whatever it is,
don't touch it.
Just call me
and we'll have somebody come and take it away.
- Like the dog catcher?
- But they'll give it a lobotomy
or do experiments on it or something.
- It's your turn to do the dishes, fellas.
- I set and cleared.
- I did breakfast.
- What's the matter, Mom?
- ( sighs )
He hates Mexico.
- Damn it. Why don't you grow up?
Think how other people feel for a change.
- ( whines )
- Mom. Mom. Michael.
Michael. Mom.
- ( grunts )
( coos )
( crash )
- Wow.
- ( coos )
- ( chuckles )
( keys jangle )
- Okay, you're hot.
I'll be back.
- Mary, can I back the car out?
- Not one foot past the driveway.
( clunk )
You were outside last night
waiting for that thing to come back, weren't you?
You gonna live if I go to work?
Okay.
No TV.
Come on.
- Mommy, look what Michael did.
This and that and--
- I see it, Gert.
and when I catch him, I'll catch him.
- Come on.
It's all right.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
- ( heavy breathing )
- Do you talk?
You know, talk?
Me human.
Boy.
Elliott.
Coke, see? We drink it.
It's a drink. You know, food.
These are toys.
These are little men.
This is Guido and then this is Hammerhead.
See? This is Walrus Man,
and then this is Snaggletooth.
And this is Lando Calrissian, see?
And this is Boba Fett.
And look, they can even have wars.
Look at this.
( imitates gunshots )
And look. Fish.
The fish eat the fish food
and the shark eats the fish,
but nobody eats the shark.
See? This is Pez. Candy.
See? You eat it.
You put the candy in here.
Then when you lift up the head, the candy comes out
and you can eat it.
You want some?
This is a peanut. You eat it.
But you can't eat this one, 'cause this is fake.
This is money, see?
We put the money in the peanut, you see?
Bank. See?
Then this is a car.
This is what we get around in.
See? Car.
Hey!
Hey, wait a second.
No. You don't eat 'em.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
Stay.
Stay. I'll be right here, okay?
I'll be right here.
Harv!
- ( shrieks )
( barks ) - No bite! No bite!
Come on, Harvey.
- I like this.
This.
Aah! - ( shrieks )
- ( sighs )
Are you okay?
- ( whimpers )
- Too much excitement, huh?
Want a Coke?
- ♪ There are so many people to see ♪
♪ So many people you can check on ♪
♪ And add to your collection ♪
♪ But they keep you hanging on ♪
♪ Nothing but hell, shit
♪ Add to your collection
♪ But they keep you hanging on ♪
♪ Accidents will happen
♪ But it's only hit and run ♪
♪ You'll be a victim of...
- Mike, Mike, come in.
- How you feeling, faker?
- I'm feeling fine.
Look, I got something really important to tell you--
- You know, Tyler said he got 69,000 on Asteroids yesterday,
but he pulled the plug.
- Remember the goblin?
- You're so lame, Elliott.
- Come on, Michael. He came back.
- He came back?
He came back? Oh, my God!
- One thing.
I have absolute power.
Say it. Say it.
- What have you got? Is it the coyote?
- No. Look.
Okay, now swear it.
The most excellent promise you can make.
Swear as my only brother on our lives.
- Elliott, don't get so heavy. I swear.
- Okay, stand over there.
And you better take off your shoulder pads.
- What? - You might scare him.
And close your eyes.
- Don't push it, Elliott.
- I'm not coming out there until your eyes are closed.
- Okay, they're closed.
Mom's gonna kill you. Ugh...
- Okay, swear it one more time.
I have absolute--
- You have absolute power. Yes.
- ( grunt )
- Elliott, look what I made for you.
- ( groans )
- Aah!
- ( shriek ) - Stop!
Stop!
- ( shriek )
- Aah!
- Kids, I'm home.
Guys?
- In the closet! Fast!
- ( grunt )
- Aah!
- ( shriek )
- Anybody home?
Hi, honey. How you feel--
What happened in here?
- Oh, you mean, my room?
- This is no room.
This is an accident.
- I was, um, reorganizing.
- I can see that.
Put those shelves back on the wall, Elliott.
- ( muffled scream )
- Let's get the toys off the floor.
Make your bed, since you are not using it.
Well, you're feeling better, I see.
Guys, keep an eye on Gertie for me while I take a shower.
- Absolutely.
Bye, Mom.
( sighs )
- ( groan )
- Elliott?
- I'm keeping him.
- ( coos )
- What is it?
- He won't hurt you, Gertie.
He won't hurt you, Gertie.
We're not gonna hurt you.
- Is he a boy or a girl?
- He's a boy.
- Was he wearing any clothes?
- No, but look.
You can't tell.
Not even Mom.
- Why not?
- 'Cause, uh, grownups can't see him.
Only little kids can see him.
- Give me a break.
- Well, do you know what's going to happen
if you do tell?
Do it, Mike. We have to.
- Oh, no! Please, no!
Don't do anything, please!
Gertie, help me. Help me.
- Promise?
- Yes.
- Do you promise?
- ( groans )
( keys jangle )
- What are you doing, Gert?
- I'm going to play in Elliott's room.
- Okay. Don't let him torture you.
- I won't, Mary.
- Come on. Come on, hurry up.
- Don't be pushy, pushy.
That's for you.
- Maybe he's some animal that wasn't supposed to live.
You know, like those rabbits we saw that time.
- Red, green, orange, red--
- Don't be lame.
- Could be a monkey or an orangutan or something.
- A bald monkey?
- Is he a pig? He sure eats like one.
You can make faces
and make them mean and happy
and make them get sharp teeth--
- We are here.
- And you can make 'em have their head cut off.
- We're here. - No, use this.
- Okay, we're here.
We are here. Where are you from?
- ( gurgles )
- I don't like his feet.
- They're only feet, you little twerp.
He's trying to tell us something.
Earth.
Home.
- ( grunts )
- What's he doing?
- What's happening?
( rumbling )
- Elliott.
- Oh, wow.
Aah!
- Elliott, what is it?
- I don't know. Something scary.
( keys jangle )
( voices )
- ( coos )
- Did you explain school to him?
- How do you explain school to higher intelligence?
- Maybe he's not that smart.
Maybe he's like a worker bee
who only knows how to push buttons or something.
- He's smart.
- Okay. I just hope we don't wake up on Mars or something
surrounded by millions of little squashy guys.
- Hey, Elliott.
- Hey, Elliott. Where's your goblin?
- Shut up. - Did he come back?
Well, did he?
- Yeah, he came back, but he's not a goblin.
He's a spaceman.
- Ooh!
- As in extraterrestrial.
- Where's he from, Uranus?
Get it? Your anus?
- He doesn't get it, Ty. - Get it? Your anus?
- He doesn't get it. - You're so immature.
- You're such a cintus supremus.
- Zero charisma. - Cintus supremus.
- Shut up, Greg.
- Cintus supremus. - Zero charisma.
- You wimp!
( shouting and laughing )
- Let's go.
Come on. Get in the car. We're gonna be late.
( scraping )
- ( sighs )
- Okay, boys and girls.
Today we will be doing the actual frog dissection
for which we've been preparing,
and you will find many similarities...
As you get into the dissection,
you will discover that the anatomy...
( growls )
- The scalpel is very sharp.
Use discretion when you are cutting.
There will be very little blood.
There may be a few body fluids.
- ( sniffs )
( sneezes )
- Blech!
( barks )
- As we get started with the dissection...
- ( belch )
- Eew.
- Remember that the things that you are writing down...
- ( belch )
- One thing that you should be looking for
during the dissection is to locate the heart
and notice that it is still beating.
- ( groans )
- I need to once more emphasize
the similarities of those things which we see in the...
Similarities to the human anatomy.
First of all, here's the heart, which is beating.
The intestines will be going through
their peristaltic action.
- Computer voice: S-W-V-U-A-F-P.
That is incorrect.
The correct spelling of nuisance is N-U-I-S-A-N-C-E.
- They're pulling us up.
- Now, class, these are the cotton balls
with the chloroform,
and as soon as I get them all in,
be sure and put the lid on right away.
That's it.
That will start them going to sleep.
They won't feel anything. They won't be hurt.
It'll take a little while.
If you don't want to watch them, you don't have to.
- Say hi.
Can you talk?
Can you say hi?
- ( groans )
( belches )
- Hello? Uncle Ralph.
It's Uncle Ralph long distance from California.
Ooh, I'll talk fast. This call is expensive.
- Oh, no, no, no.
If I call anytime on Saturday without an operator,
I can go for five minutes for 85 cents plus tax.
If I talk less, I pay less.
Let me talk to that little fella, huh?
- Say hello to your Uncle Ralph.
- Hello, Uncle Ralph.
- ( grunts )
- Save him.
Run for your life.
Down to the river. Down to the forest. Run!
I wanna save you.
Let's get out of here.
Get out. I gotta let him go.
You gotta save him.
- Let me handle this.
I can handle this. I can handle this.
I can get this.
- Aah!
( TV plays )
- Francis, what's wrong?
- I'm afraid Betsy Sue isn't going to run tomorrow.
- Oh, no. Is it anything serious?
- Harvey, I'm home. Come here, boy.
- ( muttering )
- Here he is. - Here's who?
- The man from the moon.
But I think you killed him already.
- Honey, just as soon as I unload this stuff, okay?
- Med-bugs.
- I want you to meet somebody.
- This stuff has gone up so much in one week.
- Okay, honey. As soon as I get finished
putting all this stuff away, all right?
Stupid Ragu. I knew it wouldn't come out.
- B. - B is for basket.
( telephone rings ) - What's up with this mess?
( ring )
- Hello?
Yeah, this is she.
- Basket, bandit, ball.
Basket, bandit, ball.
- He was feeling a little ill yesterday.
- Bananas.
- Intoxicated?
( sniffs )
You sure you have the right Elliott?
- B. B. Biscuits.
- B.
B.
- But B is for boy with a baseball and bat.
- You said B.
- B.
- You said B. Good.
Good.
- Okay, I'll be right down. Thank you.
Gertie, I have to go pick up Elliott.
Will you be a good girl and--
- Mommy, he can talk.
- Of course he can talk.
I'll be right back in 10 minutes.
Stay there.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
Little Grover here
will demonstrate by chinning himself two times.
- Two times? - Two times. Okay--
- Can I start? - Okay, go ahead, Grover.
- Okay, here we go.
- Phone.
- Phone?
- You wanna call somebody?
- I am not paying for frogs.
- Be good. Be good.
Stay here. Stay.
And don't tell anybody. Nobody.
Be good. Be good.
- Oh, God.
- Elliott?
- What?
- Elliott. Elliott.
- I taught him how to talk.
Now he can talk now.
- Elliott.
- Look what he brought up here all by himself.
- Elliott, Elliott.
- What's he need this stuff for?
- Elliott.
- E.T. Can you say that?
Can you say E.T.? E.T.
- E.T.
- ( laughs )
- E.T., E.T., E.T. Be good.
- Be good. I taught him that, too.
- You should give him his dignity.
This is the most ridiculous thing I've ever seen.
- Phone.
- Phone? He said phone?
He said phone?
- Can't you understand English?
He said phone.
- Home?
- You're right. That's E.T.'s home.
- E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home.
- He wants to call somebody.
- ( chuckles )
Elliott, what's all this shit?
- E.T. phone home.
- Oh, my God, he's talking now.
- Home.
- E.T. phone home?
- E.T. phone home.
- And they'll come?
- Come home.
Home.
- Come on. I promise, Mom. - What book?
- Any one you want. Spiderman--
- Football.
- Fine. We'll just put a smile on our faces
and try to get through the evening.
That's all I want to do.
- Okay. Make some of your garlic bread.
That's all I'm asking.
- I can't ask Kathy to go trick or treating
in the same old sheet she wore last year.
- Now I wish I would have listened in science.
Think, Michael.
- I guess we could just grab anything
that looks like he can make a machine out of.
- What would make a radar?
- How the hell do I know? You're the genius here.
You have absolute power, remember?
"I found him. He belongs to me."
You know, Elliott,
he doesn't look too good anymore.
- Don't say that. We're fine.
- What's all this "we" stuff?
You say "we" all the time now.
Really, Elliott, I think he might be getting kind of sick.
- Look, he's fine, Michael.
- Okay, okay. Forget I mentioned it.
Grab that fuzz buster.
- Dad's shirt.
- Yeah.
- Remember when he used to take us out to the ball games
and take us to the movies?
We'd have popcorn fights.
- We'll do that again, Elliott.
- Sure.
( sniffs )
- ( sniffs )
Old Spice.
- Sea Breeze.
- "Peter says, The redskins were defeated?
"Wendy and the boys captured by the pirates?
"I'll rescue her. I'll rescue her.
"He leaps first at his dagger,
"and then at his grindstone to sharpen it.
"But Tink alights near the shed
"and rings out a warning cry.
"Oh, that is just my medicine.
"She says, poisoned? Who could have poisoned it?
"I promised Wendy I'd take it,
"and I will as soon as I have sharpened my dagger.
"Tink, who sees its red color
"and remembers the red in the pirate's eye,
"nobly swallows the draft
"as Peter's hand is reaching for it.
"Why, Tink, you have drunk my medicine.
"She flutters strangely about the room,
answering him now in a very faint tinkle."
- Ouch. Ouch.
- "It was poison and you drank it to save my life?
Tink, dear Tink!"
- Ouch.
- "She says...
"She say she thinks she could get well again
if children believed in fairies."
Do you believe in fairies? Say quick that you believe.
- I do, I do, I do.
- If you believe, clap your hands.
"Some clap, some don't. A few hiss.
And then perhaps a rush of Nanas to the nurseries..."
"But Tink is saved. Thank you.
"Oh, thank you, thank you, thank you.
And now to rescue Wendy."
- Can you read it to me again?
- ( snoring )
- "Peter says...
- He's putting it together now.
I told you he was smart.
- I'm worried, Elliott.
He could blow up the whole house.
- He knows what he's doing.
- Listen to how he's breathing.
- ( labored breathing )
- It's going to work.
- What's he feeling now?
- He's feeling everything.
- Now, you're going as a ghost. You promised.
- I'm only pretending I'm going as a cowgirl.
- Okay. Now you know the plans by heart, don't you?
- Meet you at the lookout.
At the lookout. I'm not stupid, you know.
- Listen, buster, you won't get four blocks
in this neighborhood dressed like that.
- Please? - No, and that is final.
You are not going as a terrorist.
- But all the guys are.
- I'm not stupid, you know.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- No, wait, Mom. Don't look.
- Okay.
- Okay, Mom, you can look now.
- ( screams and laughs )
Oh, that's great.
- ( grunts )
- Yes.
( laughs )
- ( grunts ) Ooh.
Ouch...
- Stop that. No, don't.
- Ouch, ouch, ouch.
- It's a fake knife. It's fake.
- Ouch.
- Okay.
Oh, you look great.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Thank you.
( gasp )
- Be back one hour after sundown, no later.
- Oh.
- Bye.
- ( squeals ) - Gertie?
Come here. Come on.
- Home. Home. Home.
Home. Home. Home.
- Be back one hour after sunset, no later.
- I'll try as fast as I can, Mike.
You gotta cover me.
- ( grunts )
- Well? Come on, help me.
- We'll be waiting for you, Elliott.
Just come back for sure.
- It's too bumpy. We'll have to walk from here!
E.T.!
Not so high! Not so high!
( laughs )
Don't crash, please?
- ( grunts )
- Whoa!
( howling )
- I really can't believe you did this.
( muttering )
Your father's gonna hear about this one.
( sighs ) Mexico.
( keys jangle )
- ( sighs )
- E.T., it's working.
- ( grunts )
- It's working!
- Home.
- You did it.
It's working.
- Home?
- E.T., it's working!
( beeping )
- We have to go now, E.T.
We're so late already.
( coughs )
We have to go home now, E.T.
- ( grunts )
- You should give 'em some time.
- Ouch.
- You could be happy here.
I could take care of you.
I wouldn't let anybody hurt you.
We could grow up together, E.T.
- Home.
Home.
( moans )
- E.T.?
E.T.?
- How was he dressed when last seen?
- He was dressed as a hunchback.
- Hunchback.
Is there anything to indicate
that he might have run away?
Any family problems or recent arguments?
- Um, my husband and I just separated recently,
and it hasn't been easy on the children, but--
- My father's in Mexico.
- But run away?
Where would he have gone? ( crying )
- Elliott!
- Oh, Elliott!
Don't ever do this again, Elliott!
Oh, my, you're so hot.
Run up and draw him a bath quick, Gert.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
Thanks very much for all your trouble.
- Is he here?
You've got to find him, Mike.
- Where is he?
- In the forest in the bald spot.
You've got to find him.
- E.T.!
E.T.!
( thunder )
No!
- ( groans )
( keys jangle )
- Mom? Would you come with me?
- What is it?
- Mary, just come with me.
- Michael, what?
- Mom, remember the goblin?
- Michael, what are you talking about?
- Just swear the most excellent promise you can make.
- Michael.
That's terrific.
- Mom.
- We're sick.
I think we're dying.
- Michael...
- Mom, it's okay.
- ( groans )
- Go downstairs.
- He's not gonna hurt you, Mom.
- He's not gonna hurt you.
- Michael, get her downstairs.
- It's the man from the moon.
It's the man from the moon.
- ( groans )
- You don't know him.
You don't know him.
- ( cries )
- We can't leave him alone.
- Aah!
( train whistle blows )
- This is my home!
- ( shallow breathing )
( footsteps )
- Home.
Home.
( police radio )
( keys jangle )
- I don't know. - Does he sleep at night?
- I don't know.
What's the matter with Elliott?
- Have you noticed any surface swelling?
- No.
- Has it lost any hair?
- He never had any hair.
- Are the children all right?
- Did it ever build anything or write anything down?
- Uh, no.
- You say it has the ability
to manipulate its own environment?
- He's smart. He communicates through Elliott.
- Elliott thinks its thoughts?
- No. Elliott feels his feelings.
- We've identified the primary carrier.
It's definitely not recognizable.
- Testing shows no deficits on FNF
and HPS testing.
EEG analysis shows complete coherent and synchronization
of brainwave activity from both subjects.
- Isotonic.
Nitrates, 255 mili-equivalents.
- We have medi-starts available.
- Step five for helo.
- CVC line can help.
- I think we'd get more information with a Swan-Ganz.
- Fine, but let's do another thorax.
- Oxygen saturation is 82% on room air.
- You're scaring him.
You're scaring him!
- Good air entry, but decreased tidal volume on the boy.
Put him on .025 liters by nasal cannula
and draw a blood gas in 20 minutes.
- Get a hypothermia blanket and some--
- Leave him alone.
Leave him alone. I can take care of him.
- Get a Doppler scope in here.
and set me up for a two deep cardiac echo.
- I'm seeing diaphoretic.
We should consider all shock ideology.
- He's not profusing at all.
He needs anatropic support.
pH is down to 7.03.
He's got a metabolic acidosis.
It could be sepsis.
- We've drawn two sets of blood cultures.
- He needs broad specular coverage.
- Elliott?
I've been to the forest.
- He shouldn't talk now.
- Well, he has to talk now, Major.
Elliott, that machine, what does it do?
- The communicator?
Is it still working?
- It's doing something. What?
- I really shouldn't tell.
He came to me.
- Elliott, he came to me, too.
I've been wishing for this since I was 10 years old.
I don't want him to die.
What can we do that we're not already doing?
- He needs to go home.
He's calling his people.
I don't know where they are.
He needs to go home.
- Elliott, I don't think
that he was left here intentionally,
but his being here is a miracle, Elliott.
It's a miracle.
And you did the best that anybody could do.
I'm glad he met you first.
- He's got DNA.
- Incredible.
- He doesn't have four nucleotides like we do.
He has six.
- I've got desynchronization
of the two brainwave activity.
- E.T.!
- The boy's condition is stabilizing.
His blood pressure's coming back up.
- E.T.?
- Elliott?
- He's speaking!
- He's talking!
- E.T., stay with me.
Please.
- Stay together.
- I'll be right here.
I'll be right here.
- Stay, Elliott.
Stay.
- The creature's pressure is bottoming out.
His complexes are slow and widening.
- How's the boy?
- He's converting back to normal sinus rhythm.
- They're separating.
- Yes, definitely separating.
- Boy and creature are completely separated.
- What does that mean? - The boy's coming back.
We're losing E.T.
- E.T., answer me, please.
- Everything's going to be fine.
- Please. - Just relax.
- No!
- E.T., don't go!
( alarm sounds ) - No blood pressure!
- He's got no pulse or respiration.
We can't get a pulse or blood pressure on the creature.
- It doesn't look like he's breathing.
- We gotta get in there.
- You can't break a sterile field.
- Get back.
- Leave him alone!
- How's he doing? - You're killing him!
Leave him alone.
- Get him moving.
- Okay, let's get the boy out of here. Get him moving.
- Stop it! You're killing him!
You're killing him!
- Move the gurney over here. Let's go.
- You're killing him!
You're killing him! You're killing him!
He came to me.
- Let's ventilate him. Any pulses?
- No femoral pulse. - Any pulses?
- He came to me!
( overlapping voices )
- Let's try some bretylium.
May we have some bretylium, please?
- Getting a pulse?
- Compressed air. Compressed air is fine.
- He's not ventilating!
His pupils are fixed and dilated.
- Quiet! Quiet!
- Everybody stand clear.
- Clear!
- We're losing him.
- Quiet!
- It's still defib.
- Okay, let's go.
- Elliott?
- Mom!
- Would you people stand back?
- Something's happening.
- Ooh, they're gonna die.
- Shut up, Greg.
- Something is definitely happening.
- Anybody have any ideas?
- EEG's flat. EKG's flat.
- Okay, I'm gonna call it.
- I think he's dead.
- I don't know. - All right, I'm calling it.
What time do you have?
- 15:36.
- 15 hours, 36 minutes. Okay.
Let's pack him in ice.
Let's leave.
( keys jangle )
- Is he dead, Mama?
- I think so, sweetheart.
- Can we wish for him to come back?
- Yeah.
- I wish.
- I wish, too.
- Come on, Gert.
We'll wait for Elliott in the front room.
- Cardiac arrest was terminated at 15 hours and 36 minutes.
He received intravenous lidocaine,
intravenous epinephrine, a lidocaine drip,
2.7% sodium chloride solution.
Catheters from the A-line
and the intravenous lines should be sent for culture.
He was monitored with a EEG and EKG
to be interpolated with--
- They're gonna have to take him away now.
- They're just gonna cut him all up.
- Would you like to spend some time alone with him?
- Hey, can we be alone here a minute, please?
- Could we all step out for a minute, please?
- Look at what they've done to you.
I'm so sorry.
You must be dead...
'cause I don't know how to feel.
I can't feel anything anymore.
You're going someplace else now.
I'll believe in you all my life.
Every day.
E.T.,
I love you.
Oh, my God.
- E.T. phone home.
- ( laughs )
- Home, home, home.
Phone home.
- Does this mean they're coming?
- Yes.
- Aah!
- E.T. phone home. E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home.
- Stay. Shut up.
- Home. Phone home.
- Quiet!
- Phone home. Phone home.
- Would you shut up.
- Phone home. E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home. E.T. phone home.
Elliott! Elliott!
Elliott!
- ( crying loudly )
- Elliott, come with me.
- No!
- Elliott, why don't you come with me?
- No, no.
No! - It's all right.
- No!
( crying ) - It's all right.
- Would you like the flowers? - (crying )
- He's alive! He's alive!
- All right!
- Are they gone, Mama? - Who's gone, honey?
- He'll be the same, honestly, eight days to two weeks.
- The boys. - What boys?
- I'm supposed to give you this note when they're gone.
- Give it to me now, Gertie.
( sighs ) Oh, my God.
- Give me a hand with this.
- ( gasps )
- Where's your mask? - It's back here.
- Well, get it on. - I'm trying.
( knock knock knock ) - Hey, who are you?
- I'm driving.
- Open the door, son.
- There's a guy out here. What do I do?
- Well, what are you waiting for? Let's go.
Well, let's get out of here, Michael.
- I've never driven forward before.
Get the bikes.
Meet us at the playground at the top of the hill.
- Let's do it!
- Here, take my hand.
- We're all gonna die,
and they're never gonna give me my license.
- Where's the playground?
- It's near the preschool.
- Where's that?
- I don't know streets.
Mom always drives me.
- Son of a bitch.
- Where are you going?
- To the spaceship. - Spaceship?
- To the spaceship to the moon.
- Quiet.
- Oh, my God.
- Okay, he's a man from outer space,
and we're taking him to his spaceship.
- Well, can't he just beam up?
- This is reality, Greg.
- Keep her back. - No!
- Hold her back.
- No guns. They're children.
No, no, no.
- Where are they?
- There's nobody here.
- ( grunts )
- Where we going?
- To the forest.
( siren )
Follow me!
- We got 'em at the bottom of the hill.
This is Unit 302.
We cut the kids off at the bottom of the hill.
Send back-up unit.
- ( gasps )
- ( grunts )
- Let's split up. - Okay.
- Hang on.
- ( grunts )
- We made it!
Oh, shit!
- Whoa.
- Whoa! - Whoa!
- Tell me when it's over.
- Home.
- Stop the car, Mama.
They're over there! They're over there!
( crying )
I just wanted to say goodbye.
- He doesn't know "goodbye."
- Be good.
- Yes.
- ( coos )
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Come.
- Stay.
- ( sighs )
- Ouch.
- I'll be right here.
- Bye.