Ready?
Ready.
Wait, Mom. Don't look.
Okay.
Okay, Mom. You can look now.
That's great.
Stay here.
Ouch.
Stop that! No! Don't!
It's a fake knife. It's a fake.
Ouch.
Okay.
All right.
You look great!
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Be back one hour after sundown. No later.
'Bye.
Gertie, come here. Come on.
Trick or treat?
Home. Home.
Home.
Be back one hour after sunset. No later.
I'll try as fast as I can, Mike.
You got to cover me.
Well, come on. Help me.
We'll be waiting for you, Elliott.
So come back for sure.
It's too bumpy. We'll have to walk from here!
E.T!
Not so high! Not so high!
Don't crash, please.
I really can't believe you did this.
Your father's going to hear
about this one.
Mexico.
Boo!
Trick or treat?
Bull's-eye.
Good shot.
Where's Elliott?
I'm asking you a question.
Anyways, why would Elliott go to the forest?
Why would he do such a thing?
Get in the car.
Get in the car, now.
E.T., it's working.
It's working!
Home.
You did it!
It's working!
Home.
E.T., it's working!
We have to go now, E.T.
We're so late already.
We have to go home now, E.T.
You should give them some time.
Ouch.
You could be happy here.
I could take care of you.
I wouldn't let anybody hurt you.
We could grow up together, E.T.
Home.
E.T?
How was he dressed when last seen?
He was dressed as a...
...hunchback.
Hunchback.
Is there anything to indicate
that he might have run away?
Any family problems or recent arguments?
My husband and I just separated recently...
...and it hasn't been easy on the children,
but...
My father's in Mexico.
But run away, I...
Where would he have gone?
Elliott.
Oh, Elliott!
Don't ever do this again, Elliott!
Oh, my. You're so hot.
Run up and draw him a bath. Quick, Gert.
Sorry I yelled at you.
Thanks very much for all your trouble.
Is he here?
You've got to find him.
Where is he?
In the forest.
At the bald spot.
You've got to find him.
E.T!
No!
Mom, would you come with me?
What is it?
Mary, just come with me.
Michael, what?
- Mom, remember the goblin?
- What are you talking about?
Swear the most excellent promise
you can make.
Michael.
That's terrific.
Mom.
We're sick.
I think we're dying.
Michael.
Mom, it's okay.
Downstairs.
He's not going to hurt you, Mom.
He won't hurt you.
Michael, get her downstairs.
It's the man from the moon.
The man from the moon!
You don't know him! You don't know him!
We can't leave him alone.
This is my home!
Home.
The Collagen Unit,
report to the Blue Level immediately.
Does he sleep?
I don't know.
What's the matter with Elliott?
Have you noticed any sweating?
No.
Has it lost hair?
He never had any hair.
Are the children all right?
Did it build or write anything?
No.
You say it has the ability
to manipulate its own environment?
He's smart.
He communicates through Elliott.
Elliott thinks its thoughts.
No. Elliott feels his feelings.
We've identified
his primary carrier protein.
It's definitely not albumin.
The testing shows no deficits
on FNF and HTS testing.
EEG analysis shows complete coherence
and synchronization of brainwave activity...
...between subjects.
There's no response at 20 per kilo.
Let's move to hypertonic saline.
Cut five per kilo.
You have no right to do this.
You're scaring him.
You're scaring him!
Respiratory rate: 12.
Good air entry
but decreased tidal volume on the boy.
Put him on 025 liters by nasal cannula
and draw blood gas in 20 minutes.
Temperature's dropped
from 20 to 17 degrees.
Get a hypothermia blanket
and some rags.
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone. I can take care of him.
...and set me up for a 2D cardiac echo.
Skin is cool and diaphoretic.
He's not refusing at all.
He needs anatropic support.
PH is down to 7.03.
He's got a metabolic acidosis. It could be sepsis.
We've drawn two sets of blood cultures.
He needs broad spectrum coverage.
Elliott.
I've been to the forest.
He shouldn't talk now.
Well, he has to talk now, Major.
Elliott, that machine...
...what does it do?
The communicator?
Is it still working?
It's doing something.
What?
I really shouldn't tell.
He came to me.
Elliott, he came to me, too.
I've been wishing for this
since I was 10 years old.
I don't want him to die.
What can we do that we're not already doing?
He needs to go home.
He's calling his people...
...and I don't know where they are.
He needs to go home.
Elliott, I don't think
that he was left here intentionally.
But his being here is a miracle, Elliott.
It's a miracle...
...and you did the best that anybody could do.
I'm glad he met you first.
He's got DNA.
DNA?
He doesn't have four nucleotides like
we do. He has six.
I've got de-synchronization
of the two brain wave activities.
E.T!
The boy's condition is stabilizing.
Blood pressure's back up.
E.T.
Elliott.
He's speaking.
He's talking.
E. T...
...stay with me.
Please.
Stay.
Together.
I'll be right here.
Stay...
...Elliott.
Stay.
The creature's pressure is bottoming out.
His complexes are slow.
How's the boy?
He's converting back to normal sinus rhythm.
They're separating.
Boy and creature are separating.
What does that mean?
Boy's coming back. We're losing E.T.
E.T., answer me, please.
Please.
Just relax.
No!
E.T., don't go!
- No blood pressure.
- He's got no pulse or respiration.
We can't get a pulse or blood pressure.
He's not breathing.
Leave him alone! You're killing him!
Leave him alone!
Let's move it!
Get the boy out.
Stop it! You're killing him!
You're killing him!
You're killing him! You're killing him!
You're killing him! He came to me!
Any pulses?
He came to me!
Minimal breath sounds.
Calm down. Calm.
Let's try some bretylium.
Can we have some bretylium?
Getting a pulse?
Compressed air. Compressed air's fine.
His pupils are fixed and dilated.
Defibrillate him.
Everybody, stand clear.
Clear.
We're losing him.
Quiet.
It's still defib.
Okay, let's go.
Let's go. Let's go.
Elliott?
Mom.
Let's continue CPR, please.
Would you people stand back?
Something's happening.
- They're going to die.
- Shut up, Greg.
Something is definitely happening.
Anybody have any ideas?
EKG's flat.
I'm going to call it.
- I think he's dead.
- No. I don't know.
I'm calling it. What time do you have?
15:36.
15 hours, 36 minutes.
Okay.
Let's pack him in ice.
Let's leave.
Is he dead, Mama?
I think so, sweetheart.
Can we wish for him to come back?
Yeah.
I wish.
I wish, too.
Come on, Gert.
We'll wait for Elliott in the front room.
Cardiac arrest was terminated
at 1500 hours and 36 minutes.
He received intravenous lidocaine...
...intravenous epinephrine, a lidocaine drip...
...2.7 percent sodium-chloride solution...
...catheters from the "A" line.
The intravenous line should be sent for culture.
He was monitored with a...
...EEG and an EKG, he was defibrillated...
They're going to have to take him away now.
They'll just cut him all up.
Would you like
to spend some time alone with him?
Could we all step out for a minute,
please?
Look at what they've done to you.
I'm so sorry.
You must be dead...
...because...
...I don't know how to feel.
I can't feel anything anymore.
You've gone someplace else now.
I'll believe in you all my life.
Every day.
E. T...
...I love you.
Oh, my God.
E.T. Phone home.
Phone home.
Does this mean they're coming?
Yes.
E.T. Phone home. E.T. Phone home.
Stay.
Shut up.
Phone.
- Phone home.
- Quiet!
Phone! Phone!
Would you shut up?
Phone home. E.T. Phone home.
E.T. Phone home.
Phone home.
Elliott.
Stay.
Elliott, why don't you come with me?
No.
It's all right.
Would you like the flowers?
He's alive! He's alive!
He's glowing right here.
Are they gone, Mama?
- Who's gone, honey?
- The boys.
What boys?
I'm supposed to give you
this note when they're gone.
Give it to me now, Gertie.
Oh, my God.
Give me a hand with this.
- Where's your mask?
- Back here.
Well, get it on!
I'm trying!
Who are you?
I'm driving.
Open the door, son.
- There's a guy out here. What do I do?
- What are you waiting for? Let's go!
Let's get out of here!
I've never driven forward before!
Get the bikes. Meet us at the playground
at the top of the hill.
Let's do it!
Come on, Michael!
We'll all die, and they'll never give me my license.
Where's the playground?
It's near the preschool!
- Where's that?
- I don't know streets.
Mom always drives me.
Son of a bitch.
- Where are you going?
- To the spaceship.
To the spaceship to the moon.
Quiet!
Oh, my God.
Stop the van!
Don't pull them off!
That did it!
Okay. He's a man from outer space...
...and we're taking him to his spaceship.
Well, can't he just beam up?
This is reality, Greg.
Keep her back!
No!
Hold her back!
Where are they?
There's nobody here.
Where are we going?
To the forest!
Follow me!
We got them at the bottom of the hill.
This is Unit 302.
We've cut the kids off at the bottom of the hill.
Let's split up.
Okay!
Hang on!
We made it! Oh, shit!
Tell me when it's over!
Home.
Stop the car, Mama!
They're over there!
I just wanted to say goodbye.
He doesn't know goodbye.
Be good.
Yes.
Thank...
...you.
You're welcome.
Come.
Stay.
Ouch.
I'll be...
...right here.
'Bye.