We're off the east coast of America,
on the ferry from Cape Cod
to Martha's Vineyard.
Martha's Vineyard is a tiny island
which achieved an international fame
five years ago this summer
when senator Edward Kennedy
drove his car off the bridge and
into the river at Chappaquiddick.
It's a tiny island, the holiday preserve
of the rich from New York and from Boston.
But this summer it's the location
for one of America's
biggest motion pictures,
Jaws.
Based on the novel by Peter Benchley.
It's a best seller in England right now.
It's the story of how a killer shark
marauds and threatens the lives
and the livelihood of a small
New England beach community.
Making a feature film on dry
land is a complex enough process.
There seem to be at least
three people for every job.
Making a feature film at sea
stops just short of a nightmare.
It's the second day of
American shooting on Jaws.
They've already been to Australia
for the underwater shots of the shark.
Turn on the walkie-talkie please, Freddy.
I don't think Freddy can lift his anchor.
I need to talk to you, Fred.
Turn on the walkie-talkie.
Stand up, we're not shooting.
All the usual panoply of
assistant directors with megaphones
continuity girls, barks, and chippies
are obliged to float round the action.
They're still in the process of learning
which side is port and which is starboard.
Guys we can't shoot right now, hold on.
Have that boat go out and pull the
anchor up and reset it out there, okay?
Film stars, Roy Scheider
of The French Connection
and Richard Dreyfuss of American Graffiti.
Director faced the head of the studio
and he said, "I can't do it in time."
But in the age of "director as superstar"
the movie will probably be sold
on the latest American
star behind the camera,
Steven Spielberg.
Jaws is one of the hottest
properties in the film world this year.
The book was an instant hit in America
and the film rights
were commensurately costly.
To shoot for 13 weeks
at a budget of over a million pounds
is something of a rarity these days.
So the producers, Richard
Zanuck and David Brown
must have a lot of faith in their property
and even more in their
director Mr. Spielberg
who is only 26 years old.
In America he's already provided them
with a financial and critical success in
Sugar land Express, which he directed.
He won the award for best
screenplay at the recent Cannes festival.
Age never seems to have
daunted Mr. Spielberg.
At 20, he was directing
episodes of Columbo in Hollywood.
At 22, he made Duel. A story of
a motorist being chased by a lorry.
Which got rave reviews when
it was eventually released here.
And now Jaws.
It's lunchtime and the afternoon
dialog is being doctored a little.
No, because he'll be so energetic.
He'll be screaming and yelling,
"It's a great white!
I knew it all along."
And there's only room in there for
one quick, expository line about...
The mate.
...the mate.
The mate is dead.
Where's the body?
Why is the boat torn to pieces?
Because it's a great white shark.
And then all we have
to do is, uh, cut out.
Where are they feeding him?
I don't know.
There have been
known attacks...
There's a theory
called the bumping theory.
And it's not a theory anymore,
it's a proven fact that sharks will
nudge and bump a, uh, boat
or an intended victim before they attack.
Uh, uh, not so much in a playful manner
but in a way of testing its, uh, defenses.
To see if it's going to bump back
and when it doesn't,
it comes in for the kill.
Kosher salami!
Spielberg himself had
the idea for Sugar land Express.
He found it in a newspaper.
It had to do with, uh,
the loss of their baby
and it had to do with,
um, this media event.
Where it sort of
sprang up all of a sudden.
In Texas, there's a posse theory.
When a fellow officer is in trouble
everybody jumps into their
automobiles, all the fellow officers
they fall in behind to try to help
the guy out. The posse theory
sort of is the backdrop
issue for Sugar land Express.
I was able to, within
the budget of my picture,
afford 40 police cars
and in real life 90
police cars were involved
in a bumper-to-bumper pursuit.
That was strung out over,
uh, about 150 miles.
I had seen Goldie in Butterflies are Free.
And there was one scene she
had with Eileen Heckart in the car
that I felt was, uh, really heart turning.
Uh, I knew there was
serious actress somewhere
underneath that Laugh-In facade.
She was anxious to break out of
that mold and do something dramatic
and do something very serious,
and that's why she
became a part of the company
and that's why I hired her.
You seem to get very strong performances
and naturalistic performances from
your actors. What's your technique?
I don't know if it's so much of
a technique. I asked the actor
For the most part to give me too much.
So I can then take it down to
a level that I feel is believable.
I don't like casting actors who are
low-key people.
I like people with energy.
So in the initial casting,
I think that half of
what a director does
is cast his picture well.
The other half is, uh, the
control of the people within that.
But I think half of the secret
when you do see a good
picture and you like the people,
it's in the casting.
Uh, I like people who are
outspoken and who are very large
so I can bring them down to life level.
You know in King Kong, when
they run into the jungle, all talking?
There's 40 extras and
everybody had three things to say.
All through the picture,
they're ad-libbing.
"It's big! Do you see it coming
there? Look out Charlie! Fire now!
"Throw the grenade! Duck!"
Everybody had three lines to
say, they all overlapped. Terrific.
They haven't made a movie
like that since King Kong.
A lot of, "What's the
matter? "What's wrong with it?
"Looks like it's broken."
Right.
"That rear cleat's all torn up."
The scene they're taking
is one early in the film.
Where a fisherman has gone
out to try and catch the shark
but it's holed his boat and
it's sunk and it's killed him.
The two men, the sheriff, Brody,
and Hooper, the shark expert
come upon his body.
Roll sound.
It's taken pretty
well all day to get this shot.
Marker.
Time and tides still refuse
to obey the director.
One of the actors has to climb
from the rescue craft
into the half-sunk boat.
An easy enough task, you might think.
Whoa!
Forget it. Don't
roll. CREW MEMBER: Save it.
Over half an hour is wasted
for dry clothes and new make-up.
By then the light is wrong and the shot
is put off till the following day.
it seemed to me almost
fanciful in the book that a shark
could actually threaten
people on a large boat.
But nevertheless, this is the case, is it?
Sharks have... Here's
an interesting example,
when we were shooting
the Australian sequences
of the great white sharks
one of the great white sharks
jumped into the cage boat
and sank the cage boat and sank the cages.
The shark grabbed between its jaws,
which can close and squeeze
at 21 tons per square inch,
grabbed and twisted a cage
and then sounded with the cage.
When we recovered the cage it
was torn up, completely torn up.
It's not very big,
it'll never hold that boat.
It will hold something.
This is my second day at sea
and I have 54 more days to go
and if I survive this, uh,
I will have learned a lot.
Right now, all I can tell you is
it's twice as slow shooting at
sea as it is shooting on land.
Because when you set
your camera for a shot
invariably the boat which began here
is over here when you're ready to shoot.
Uh, with tide and wind,
uh, there are a lot
of factors to take into consideration.
You really can't, uh, uh,
hold composition, hold frame.
You have to do a lot of pot-shotting
and shooting loose at open sea.
Pull the anchor up and reset it.
It doesn't come easily.
I don't even think about it.
If I thought about
multi-million dollar pictures
and all the equipment and all the
responsibility I'd probably go bananas.