What's your
name again?
Chrissie.
Where are we going?
Swimming.
Slow up. Slow down.
I'm not drunk!
Slow down!
Wait. I'm coming.
I'm coming.
I'm definitely coming.
Whoa.
Hold on. Whoa!
I can swim.
I just can't walk
or undress myself.
Come on in the water!
Take it easy.
Oh, God, help!
Please help me!
I'm coming.
It hurts!
...local
fishing reported good.
Amity Boat Rental Yard's
opening early
to prepare for
the annual seasonal rush.
This is WISS...
How come the sun
didn't use to shine
in here?
We bought
the house in the fall,
and this is summer.
Somebody feed the dogs.
Right.
Do you see the kids?
They must be
in the back yard.
In Amity you say "yard."
They're in the "yard,"
not too "far"
from the "car."
How's that?
Like you're
from New York.
Mum, I got cut.
I got hit by a vampire.
You were playing
on those swings,
weren't you?
Those swings
are dangerous.
Stay off there.
I haven't fixed them yet.
I think you're
going to live.
It's not the prettiest
thing I've ever seen.
Hello.
Yes.
Can I go swimming?
Yeah, but let me clean
this thing off first.
What do they usually do?
Wash up, or float up,
or what?
Oh, no.
Keep them there.
I'll be out in about
15, 20 minutes.
All right?
Dry you off.
Okay.
Go on,
get a Band-Aid.
Got to go.
Missing person.
Season hasn't started.
Nobody's even here yet.
Listen, Chief...
be careful, will you?
In this town?
Hi, Dad.
Wait a minute.
Let me get on.
I want my cup back!
You'll get it.
Wave goodbye. Bye.
Nobody saw her
go into the water?
Somebody could've.
I was sort of passed out.
You mean,
she ran out on you?
No, sir.
She must've drowned.
Look, I reported it
to you, didn't I?
You live here?
No. Hartford.
I go to Trinity.
My folks live
in Greenwich.
Your folks were
born here, right?
Yeah, I'm an Islander.
They moved off
when my dad retired.
You an Islander?
No. New York City.
You here for the summer?
Come on.
Hold it.
Oh, Jesus.
Well, you're up awful early.
Is the Chief in there?
Chief, what have
you got on?
If this new filing system
is to work,
you must keep
outdated stuff
off my desk.
Just the pending,
all right?
Yes, Chief.
We got a bunch of calls
about that karate school.
It seems that the 9-year-olds
from the school have been
karate-ing
the picket fences.
Chief Brody's office.
The medical inspector.
The Fire Chief
wants you to go over
the Fourth of July...
Polly, I want a list
of the water activities
that the city fathers
are planning for today.
Right away.
Hendricks!
Where do we keep
the "Beach Closed" signs?
We never had any.
No?
There's a dead truck
with New Hampshire plates
in front of my store.
Just have him
fill out the form.
Just fill it out.
Look what
the kids did to my fence.
8 and 9-year-olds...
Glasses?
Yeah, glasses.
I'll call you later
in the afternoon.
I promise.
This stuff ain't going
to help me in August.
The summer ginks
come down here in June.
You haven't got
one thing on here
I ordered.
Not a beach umbrella,
not a sun lounger,
no beach balls.
If I can't get service...
Chief, Polly sent me
to tell you
that there's a bunch
of Boy Scouts
out in Avril Bay
doing the mile swim
for their merit badges.
I couldn't call them in,
there's no phones out there.
Okay. Come on,
get out of there.
Take this stuff
back to the office
and get to work
on those signs.
"Beaches Closed. No Swimming.
By order of the Amity P.D."
Let Polly
do the printing.
What's the matter
with my printing?
Let Polly
do the printing.
Chief Brody!
What have you got there?
Listen, we had
a shark attack
at South Beach
this morning, Mayor.
Fatal. I have to
batten down the beach.
Albert,
come on, you kook.
Keep your arms up.
Charlie, take me out
to those kids, will you?
Martin, you're going
to shut down the beaches
on your own authority?
What other authority
do I need?
Technically, you need
a civic ordinance
or a resolution
by a board of...
That's just going
by the book.
We're really
a little anxious
that you're rushing into
something serious here.
This is your first
summer, you know.
What does that mean?
I'm only trying
to say that Amity
is a summer town.
We need summer dollars.
If they can't
swim here
they'll be glad to
swim at the beaches
of Cape Cod,
the Hamptons,
Long Island.
That doesn't mean
we serve them
a smorgasbord.
But we've never had
that kind of trouble
in these waters.
What else could've
done that to that girl?
A boat propeller?
I think possibly,
yes, a boating accident.
That's not
what you told me
on the phone.
I was wrong.
We'll have to
amend our reports.
And you'll
stand by that?
I'll stand by that.
Martin, a summer girl
goes swimming,
swims out a little far.
She tires,
fishing boat
comes along...
It's happened before.
I don't think
you appreciate
the gut reaction
people have
to these things.
Larry, I appreciate it.
I'm just reacting
to what I was told.
Martin,
it's all psychological.
You yell, "Barracuda!"
and everybody says,
"Huh? What?"
You yell, "Shark!"...
we've got
a panic on our hands
on the Fourth of July.
Okay. You can
take us back now.
Here's mommy, here.
I'm going to get my raft
and go back out in the water.
Let me see
your fingers.
Alex Kintner,
they're beginning
to prune.
Just let me go out
a little longer.
Just 10 more minutes.
Thanks.
There are no Islanders.
None of them are
from the island.
It's just a big bother.
They're bringing in...
All I want to know...
I just want to
know one simple thing.
When do I get to
become an Islander?
Ellen, never.
You're not born here,
you're not an Islander.
That's it.
Nantucket Ferries...
...to Amity,
Martha's Vineyard
and Nantucket islands.
Monday to Thursday,
8:40, 1:15, 5:45
and 6:00 p.m.
Starting July 1,
8:30 p.m....
Come back here.
- But don't
bother him. Come right back.
- Okay. I won't.
Martin, I know you got
a lot of problems downtown
but I've got
problems at the house
I wish you'd take care of.
One, I've got
some cats parking
in front of the house,
I can't get...
And that garbage truck
next to the office,
that's terrible.
What I need is a red zone.
It's a simple thing
you can take care of.
You've done it before.
Come here a minute,
please.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Listen, if the kids
going in the water
is worrying you
they can play out here
on the beach.
It's all right.
Let them go.
It's cold.
We know all
about you, Chief.
You don't go in the water
at all, do you?
That's some
bad hat, Harry.
Chief Brody,
you are uptight.
Come on. That's it.
Oh, do you know
the muffin man
The muffin man
Tippet!
Did you see that?
Blood!
Everybody out!
Get them out!
Michael,
get out of the water!
Alex?
We don't even know
if there's a shark
around here.
I can't argue with you.
I can't talk to you.
I have to talk
to Mrs. Kintner.
Because this is
turning into a contest.
It's not just the Gazette.
She's advertising in
out-of-town papers.
I suggest we move back
to council chambers where
we'll have more room.
I'm responsible for
public safety here.
Then go out tomorrow
and see that
no one gets hurt.
It's a small story.
I'll bury it as deep
as I can.
The ad will run on the back
along with the grocery ads.
Right in here, please.
Move on in, please.
Why do you insist
on playing the heavy?
I have a point of view
and I think it speaks for
many of the people here.
Not only me,
because I have the motel.
How do you feel about it?
Let's have
some order.
Let's have order,
please.
Any special questions?
Is that $3,000
bounty on the shark
in cash or check?
I don't think
that's funny.
that's funny at all.
All right.
That's private business
between you fishermen
and Mrs. Kintner.
Martin,
would you please...
Chief Brody.
I just want to tell you
what we're planning so far.
What about
the beaches, Chief?
We're going to put on
the extra summer deputies
as soon as possible.
And then we're going to try
and use shark spotters
on the beach.
Are you going to
close the beaches?
Yes, we are.
We also plan to
bring in experts
from the Oceanographic
Institute on the mainland.
Only 24 hours.
I didn't agree to that.
Twenty-four hours
is like three weeks!
You all know me.
Know how I earn a living.
I'll catch this bird
for you.
It ain't going to
be easy. Bad fish.
Not like going
down to the pond
and chasing bluegills
or tommy cods.
This shark,
swallow you whole.
Shaking, tenderizing.
Down you go.
And we got to
do it quick.
Got to bring back
the tourists
that'll put
all your businesses
on a paying basis.
But it's not
going to be pleasant.
I value my neck
a lot more than
$3,000, Chief.
I'll find him for $3,000,
but I'll catch him and
kill him for $10,000.
You got to
make up your minds.
Gonna stay alive
and ante up,
gonna play it cheap
and be on welfare
the whole winter.
I don't want no volunteers.
I don't want no mates.
There's too many captains
on this island.
$10,000 for me,
by myself.
For that,
you get the head, the tail,
the whole damn thing.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Quint.
We'll take it
under advisement.
Mr. Mayor, Chief,
ladies and gentlemen.
Oh, God, you scared me.
Oh.
You know, Ellen,
people don't even know
how old sharks are.
I mean, if they live
2,000, 3,000 years...
They don't know.
Enough.
You're not going to
even be able to go
to sleep tonight.
Here. Come on.
Thanks.
Oh.
Want to get drunk
and fool around?
Oh, yeah.
Mikey really
loves his present.
Where is he?
Sitting in it.
Good God.
All right, Michael,
out of the boat!
Tied up to the jetties,
sitting in the boat.
I'm helping Michael.
Get out of that boat!
Hi, Dad. Just a little
longer. Please?
It's his birthday.
I don't want him
on the ocean!
He's not on the ocean,
he is in a boat.
He won't go
in the water.
I don't think he'll
go in the water again,
after what happened yesterday.
All right,
now don't say that.
I don't want that
to happen,
you know that.
I want him to read
the boating regulations,
the rules, before he
goes out on his own.
Michael,
did you hear your father?
Out of the water now!
Now!
I'm tired.
Let's stop before
someone reports us.
Don't worry.
The Chief lives on the other
side of the island.
Am I coming in straight?
Don't worry about it.
Just keep rowing.
We better
catch something,
this is my wife's
holiday roast.
Don't worry about it.
$3,000 buys
an awful lot of roast.
Come and get it.
The tide's
taking it right out.
Can't we go home?
He's taking it.
Go!
Charlie,
take my word for it,
don't look back!
Swim, Charlie!
Come on! To me, boy!
Come on, Charlie! Swim!
Come on, Charlie,
keep coming.
Keep swimming.
Come on, a little more.
Atta boy.
I can't get up.
Give me your hand,
Charlie.
Help me!
Get your feet
out of the water!
Can we go home now?
So then Denherder and Charlie
sat there trying to
catch their breath
and figure out how
to tell Charlie's wife
what happened to her
freezer full of meat.
That's not funny.
That's not funny at all.
Mrs. Kintner
must've put her ad
in Field & Stream.
Looks more like
The National Enquirer.
All right, hold it.
Hold everything.
I said, hold it!
Hello.
Hello back, young fellow.
How are you?
Say, I hope
you're not going out
with those nuts, are you?
The Weetock boats
gotta move out first.
You have to move out
or he can't get out
at all.
Don't raise sail,
you're going to luff it.
You got a paddle?
I got a paddle.
Scull it out of here.
Officer, wait a second.
How many guys
are you going to
put aboard that boat?
Whatever's safe,
right?
Yeah,
well that ain't safe.
Watch it,
that's dynamite.
What are you doing
with that?
Where are you going
I'm going on the boat.
Please, help me
get those guys out
of the boat, will you?
Sure.
Come on.
Gentlemen, the officer
asked me to tell you
that you're
overloading that boat!
Go on, get out of here.
You ain't going.
What do you care?
Can you tell me if there's
a good restaurant or hotel
on the island?
Yeah, you walk
straight ahead.
They're all
going to die.
Listen to me.
We've got some road
block signs outside.
You've got to get
somebody to help us.
Yeah,
get those road block signs
out on the highway.
Because we've got
more people down here
than we can handle.
What're you doing there?
These are your people.
Go talk to them.
They aren't my people.
They're from all over.
You see all
the license plates?
Connecticut,
Rhode Island, New Jersey.
I'm all by myself out there.
What happened to
the extra help...
It's not until
the Fourth of July.
Till then,
it's you and me.
You know those guys
in the fan-tail launch?
None of them are getting
out of the harbor alive.
That's what I'm saying.
You know their names.
Talk to those clowns.
Everyone's having
a good time today.
Tell me about it.
Polly, I'll get
back to you.
Could you tell me
how I could find
Chief Brody?
Who are you?
Matt Hooper. I'm from
the Oceanographic Institute.
Oh, for Christ's sakes.
You're the guy we called.
I'm Brody.
Oh. I'm glad
to meet you.
Me, too.
I know you got
a lot on your hands.
What can we do
for you?
The best thing to do
is to see the remains
of the first victim,
the girl on the beach.
Okay, fine.
Just bear with me,
will you?
Sure.
Wait till we get
them silly bastards
down in that rock pile.
There'll be some fun.
They'll wish
their fathers hadn't
met their mothers
when they start
digging the bottoms out
and slamming into
them rocks, boy.
Get away from there,
you goddamn fool!
What's the matter
with you?
You want to swamp us,
you crazy son of a bitch?
What are
these guys doing out here?
What are they
doing back there?
They're chumming
right now.
What the hell
is that?
They're tracking
the shark.
$3,000 divided
four ways is what?
Watch your starboard. Jesus!
Let's show Mr. Hooper
our accident.
"Victim identified
as Christine Watkins,
female Caucasian."
And here's the way
we have it.
"Probable
boating accident."
The height and weight
of the victim
can only be estimated
from the partial remains.
The torso has been
severed in mid-thorax.
There are no major
organs remaining.
May I have a glass
of water?
The right arm
has been severed
above the elbow
with massive tissue loss
in the upper musculature.
Thank you very much.
Partially
denuded bone remaining.
This was no boat accident.
Did you notify
the Coast Guard about this?
No. It was only
local jurisdiction.
The left arm, head,
the shoulders, sternum
and portions of
the rib cage are intact.
Do not smoke in here.
Thank you very much.
This is what happens.
Indicates
the non-frenzy feeding
of a large squalus
possibly longimanus
or Isurus glaucus.
The enormous amount
of tissue loss prevents
any detailed analysis
however,
the attacking squalus
must be considerably larger
than any normal squalus
found in these waters.
Didn't you get out a boat
and check these waters?
No.
Well, this is
not a boat accident.
And it wasn't any propeller.
It wasn't any coral reef.
And it wasn't
Jack the Ripper.
It was a shark.
I wanna go AP and UPI.
I want to get on
the state wire services.
See if Boston
will pick it up
and go national.
Call Dave Axelrod
in New York
and tell him
he owes me a favor.
This is the shot I want
with everybody
and the fish in it.
Guys, could we
please get organized?
I want to get
a picture for the paper.
Now, can we
just have the...
Ben Gardner get this?
No, we caught it.
That's swell.
It's a beauty.
Guys, please,
I need a picture
for the paper.
Clear out of the way,
please.
Just the guys
that caught the fish.
Open it up a little bit.
I want to get a picture
of the guy with the fish.
Come on.
I need a picture
for the paper.
Could we get the sign,
please?
Kneel down,
just like in high school.
One row kneeling,
one row standing.
Come on,
just get out of the way.
Young fellow,
could you step out
of the picture?
Take your rake
with you.
We're ready.
Thank you.
Can you get that,
please.
How's that?
Larry, you won't
believe it.
What kind of
a shark is that?
I don't know.
I think it's a mako.
It's got a deep throat,
Frank.
Yeah, but what kind?
What kind of shark?
Tiger shark.
A what?
We can start
breathing again.
Is Ben getting
plenty of pictures?
Oh, you bet he is.
What is this
bite radius crap?
That is a big mouth.
You stuff
your frigging head
in there, man,
and find out if
it's a man-eater.
All I'm saying is
that it may not be
the shark.
It's just a slight...
I want you to meet Matt.
This is Larry Vaughn,
our mayor.
Matt's from
the Oceanographic Institute.
Nice to meet you.
Terrific, huh, Mayor?
There are all kinds of
sharks in the waters.
Hammerheads,
white tips,
blues, makos.
And the chances
that these bozos
got the exact shark...
There are no other
sharks like this here.
It's 100-to-1.
I'm not saying that
this is not the shark.
It probably is, Martin.
It's a man-eater.
It's extremely rare
for these waters.
But the fact is,
the bite radius
on this animal
is different
than the wounds
on the victim.
I want to be sure.
You want to be sure.
We all want to
be sure, okay?
What I want to do
is very simple.
The digestive system
of this animal
is very slow.
Let's cut it open.
Whatever it's eaten
in the last 24 hours
is bound to
still be in there.
And then we'll be sure.
It may be the only way
to confirm it.
Look, fellows,
let's be reasonable.
This is not
the time or the place
to perform some kind
of a half-assed autopsy
on a fish.
And I am not
going to stand here
and see that thing cut open
and see that
little Kintner boy
spill out all over the dock.
Chief Brody?
Yes?
I just found out
that a girl got
killed here last week.
And you knew it.
You knew there was
a shark out there.
You knew
it was dangerous.
But you let people
go swimming anyway.
You knew all those things,
but still my boy
is dead now.
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
My boy is dead.
I wanted you
to know that.
I'm sorry, Martin.
She's wrong.
No, she's not.
All right, fellows
let's cut this ugly
son of a bitch down
before it stinks up
the whole island.
Harve, you and Carl
take it out tomorrow
and dump it in the drink.
Come here.
Give us a kiss.
Why?
Because I need it.
Get out of here.
Can I help you?
The door was open.
Mind if I come in?
I'm Matt Hooper.
Oh, hi. Ellen Brody.
Your husband's home?
Yes.
I'd really like
to talk to him.
Yes, so would I.
Come in.
Can I get you
some coffee?
No. Nothing, thank you.
Oh, wine. How nice.
How was your day?
Swell.
I got red and white.
I didn't know what
you'd be serving.
Oh, that's nice.
Is anyone eating this?
No.
My husband tells me
you're in sharks.
Excuse me. Yes.
I've never heard it
quite put that way.
But yes, I am.
I love sharks.
You love sharks?
Yeah, I love them.
When I was 12 years old,
my father got me a boat
and I went fishing
off of Cape Cod.
I hooked a scup and
as I was reeling it in
I hooked a 4.5 foot
baby thresher shark
who proceeded
to eat my boat.
He ate my oar, hooks,
and my seat cushions.
He turned an inboard
into an outboard
scared me to death,
and I swam back to shore.
When I was on the beach,
I turned around
and actually saw
my boat being
taken apart.
Ever since then,
I have been
studying sharks
and that's why I know
that I'm going to go
to the Institute tomorrow
and tell them
that you still have
a shark problem here.
Why do you have
to tell them that?
Sorry.
I'm sorry,
I thought that...
You told me
the shark was caught.
I heard it on the news.
I heard it on
the Cape station.
They caught a shark,
not the shark.
Not the shark that
killed Chrissie Watkins.
And probably not the shark
that killed the little boy.
Which I wanted
to prove today by
cutting the shark open...
You may want to let
that breathe... Nothing.
You know, you'll be
the only rational man
left on this island
after I leave tomorrow.
Where are you going?
I am going
on the Aurora.
The Aurora?
What is that?
It's a floating asylum
for shark addicts.
It's pure research,
18 months at sea.
Martin hates boats.
Martin hates water.
Martin sits in his car
when we go on the ferry
to the mainland.
I guess it's
a childhood thing.
There's a clinical name
for it, isn't there?
Drowning.
Is it true that most
people get attacked
by sharks in
three feet of water
about 10 feet
from the beach?
Yeah.
And that before
people started to swim
for recreation...
I mean, before sharks
knew what they were missing
that a lot
of these attacks
weren't reported?
That's right.
Now this shark
that swims alone
what's it called?
Rogue.
Rogue, yeah.
This guy,
he keeps swimming around
in a place where
the feeding is good
until the food
supply is gone, right?
That's called
territoriality.
It's just a theory that
I happen to agree with.
Then why don't we
have one more drink
and go down
and cut that shark open?
Martin?
Can you do that?
I can do anything.
I'm the Chief of Police.
We start in
the alimentary canal
and open
the digestive tract.
Just like I thought.
What?
Came up in the Gulf Stream,
from southern waters.
He didn't eat a car,
did he?
No.
Tiger shark's
like a garbage can.
It'll eat anything.
Somebody probably
threw that in the river.
That's it.
I've got to
close the beach,
call the Mayor.
You got a bigger
problem than that,
Martin.
You still got a hell
of a fish out there
with a mouth
about this big.
How do we confirm that
by morning?
If he is a rogue,
and there's any truth
to territoriality at all
we got a good chance
of spotting him
between Cape Scott
and South Beach.
Where are you going?
To find him.
He's a night feeder.
On the water?
We're not gonna
find him on the land.
I'm not drunk enough
to go on a boat.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can.
I'm telling you,
the crime rate in
New York will kill you.
There's so many problems,
you never feel like you're
accomplishing anything.
Violence,
rip-offs, muggings.
The kids can't
leave the house.
You've got to
walk them to school.
But in Amity,
one man can
make a difference.
In 25 years,
there's never been
a shooting or a murder
in this town.
No kidding?
Want a pretzel?
Where are we?
We're right in the stretch
where he's been feeding.
Can you get
The Late Show
on this thing?
No, it's a closed
circuit TV system.
I have underwater
cameras fore-and-aft.
Who pays
for all this stuff?
The government?
The Institute?
This stuff costs
a lot of money.
I paid for this
mostly myself, actually.
You're kidding.
No.
You rich?
Yeah.
How much?
Personally,
or the whole family?
Doesn't make any sense.
They pay a guy like you
to watch sharks?
Well, it doesn't
make sense for a guy
who hates the water to
live on an island either.
It's only an island
if you look at it
from the water.
That makes
a lot of sense.
What is
that thing doing?
Well, it's a fish finder.
It's probably just
a school of mackerel
or something,
all clumped together.
Wait a minute.
There's something else
out there.
What is it?
About 100 yards,
south-southwest.
That's Ben Gardner's boat.
You know him?
It's all banged up.
Sure I know him.
He's a fisherman.
What happened?
Martin, I gotta go down
and check their hull.
Wait. Why don't
we just tow it all in?
We will. I just got
to check something out.
Hit the lights for me.
Let's tow it in.
Don't worry, Martin.
Nothing's going to happen.
What am I supposed to do
while you're gone?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
Don't touch any
of the equipment.
I'll be back
in two minutes.
This is a great white,
Larry. A big one.
Any shark expert
will tell you it's
a killer, a man-eater.
The situation is
that apparently
a great white shark
has staked a claim
in the waters
off Amity Island.
He'll continue to feed here
as long as there's food
in the water.
There's no limit
to what he'll do.
We've had
three incidents.
Two people
killed within a week.
It'll happen again.
It happened before.
The Jersey beach, 1916.
Five people
were killed...
In one week.
Tell him
about the swimmers.
A shark is attracted
to the exact kind of
splashing and activity
that occurs
whenever human beings swim.
You can't avoid it.
Opening the beaches on
the Fourth of July is like
ringing the dinner bell.
Look, Mr. Vaughn
I pulled a tooth
the size of a shot glass
out of the wrecked hull
of a boat out there.
It was the tooth
of a great white.
It was Gardner's boat,
all chewed up.
I helped tow it in.
You should've seen it!
Where is that tooth?
Did you see it, Brody?
I didn't see it.
He dropped it
on the way in.
I had an accident.
And what did
you say the name
of this shark is?
It's a Carcharodon carcharias.
It's a great white.
You don't
have the tooth?
Look, we depend on
the summer people
for our very lives...
You won't have a summer
unless you deal
with this problem!
We have to close the beach
and hire someone
to kill the shark!
We have to tell
the Coast Guard.
You'll have to contact
the Shark Research Panel.
You'll have to ring
this entire harbor!
I don't think
either one of you
are familiar
with our problems!
I think that
I am familiar
with the fact
that you'll ignore
this particular problem
until it swims up and
bites you in the ass!
Wait a second!
There are two ways
to deal with this problem!
You either kill this animal
or cut off its food supply.
We have to
close the beaches.
Brody?
Sick vandalism.
That is
a deliberate mutilation
of a public service message.
I want those little
paint-happy bastards
caught
and hung up by
their Buster Browns.
That's it.
I won't waste my time
arguing with a man
who's lining up
to be a hot lunch.
I'm gonna see
you later, Brody.
Don't do this.
He's not...
What we are dealing with here
is a perfect engine,
an eating machine.
It's really
a miracle of evolution.
All this machine does
is swim and eat
and make little sharks.
And that's all.
Why don't you take
a long, close look
at this sign?
Those proportions
are correct.
You'd love to prove that,
wouldn't you?
Get your name into
the National Geographic.
Larry, if we make
an effort today,
we might be able
to save August.
August?
For Christ's sake,
tomorrow's
the Fourth of July!
We will be open
for business.
It'll be one of the best
summers we've ever had.
If you are concerned
about the beaches,
do whatever you have to,
to make them safe.
But those beaches
will be open
for this weekend.
I want to know
how many men
you're going to send.
There is no need for me
to come to Brisbane
when I have a great
white shark right here!
We need men to
patrol the swimming area.
We've got to have help.
Anybody with a gun
or a boat.
Monday!
Is Chief Federal
Officer Feldman there?
He's the little guy
with a crew cut.
Operator, isn't there
a phone on the island?
Could you connect me,
please?
Come on, get him!
Careful on the beach.
Brody to Gotcha,
do you read me?
The guys from the TV station
on the mainland are here.
All right.
I'll get to them later.
Brody to Scutbucket,
please come in.
Brody to Daisy,
do you read me?
Fascinating Rhythm,
Come in, Hooper.
What do you see?
Nothing here, Martin.
And nothing on sonar.
Amity Island has
long been known for
its clean air, clear water
and beautiful
white-sand beaches.
But in recent days
a cloud has appeared
on the horizon
of this beautiful
resort community.
A cloud in the shape
of a killer shark.
That is very shocking
in the outfield.
Two balls, one strike,
runners at first and third...
Fly ball,
deep left field.
Jerry Christian goes back,
running back near the wall
and he takes it
for the out.
Oh, hi, Larry.
Why aren't you
in the water?
I just put some
suntan lotion on,
and I'm trying
to absorb some...
Nobody's going in.
Please,
get in the water.
Mike, come here.
Listen, Mike.
Do me a favor,
will you?
You and the other guys
take the boat
and put it
in the pond instead?
The pond is
for old ladies.
I know it's for
the old ladies,
but just do it
for the old man.
Please?
All right.
Thanks.
I've got Sean.
Michael! Wait!
Michael, I don't
like you no more.
I can stand Harry,
you know...
Daisy, this is Hendricks.
Anything?
Thought I saw
a shadow. Over.
Hendricks,
this is Daisy here.
I don't see anything.
False alarm.
Must be this glare.
I'm pleased and happy
to repeat the news
that we have in fact
caught and killed
a large predator
that supposedly
injured some bathers.
As you see,
it's a beautiful day.
The beaches are open,
and people are
having a wonderful time.
"Amity," as you know,
means "friendship."
My God!
Jesus Christ!
Fin! Shark! 350!
Get in there
as fast as you can!
Red one.
Martin, get them
the hell out
of the water.
No whistles!
Everybody, please,
get out of the water.
Everybody out of the water.
Don't push!
Everybody out of
the water, please.
Come on!
I want them out
of there, guys.
Give an answer, please.
What's going on out there?
He made me do it.
He talked me into it.
Please, move back.
Give these people
some air.
Please, move back.
Martin, it's just a hoax.
There are two kids
with a cardboard fin.
Is everyone there okay?
Everyone get out of
the water all right?
Folks,
we had some practical joker
down there with a fake fin...
Shark! A shark!
It's going into the pond!
Shark in estuary!
Now what?
Michael's in the pond.
It's going in the pond!
Somebody do something!
It's in the pond!
Hurry up,
get that done.
I can't do
a damn thing.
Get that rope undone.
You gotta untangle
that up there.
I'm doing it!
Hey, fellows,
haul in your sheet.
Make it fast.
You guys okay
over there?
In the pond!
Somebody get
a gun and shoot it!
Doesn't anybody
have a gun?
Is he dead?
No, he's not.
He's in shock.
Doctor said he's okay.
Mild shock.
He can go home
in the morning.
Thank you.
How's my big kid?
I'm all right.
You going to
miss me tonight?
You can watch television.
Want me to bring
anything from home?
My cars.
What about ice cream?
Coffee.
Want to take him home?
Back to New York?
No. Home, here.
I'm sorry,
I'm truly sorry.
You got a pen, Larry?
Yeah, a pen, you know.
'Cause you're going
to do what you do best.
You're going to
sign this voucher
so I can hire a contractor.
I don't know if
I can do that without...
I'm going to hire Quint
to kill the shark.
August?
What?
What are you
talking about?
Summer's over.
You're the mayor
of Shark City.
People think you
want the beaches open.
I was acting in
the town's best interest.
You were acting in
That's why you'll
do the right thing.
That's why you're
going to sign this,
and we'll pay that guy
what he wants.
My kids were on
that beach, too.
Sign it, Larry.
$10,000.
$200 a day,
whether I catch him or not.
You've got it.
Get the Mayor off my back
so I don't have more
of this zoning crap.
You've got that.
One case
of apricot brandy,
and you buy the lunch.
Two cases.
And you get dinner
when you get back.
Champagne,
pâte de foie gras,
Iranian caviar,
and don't forget
the color TV.
Chief, you try this.
Made it myself.
Pretty good stuff.
Thanks.
Here's to swimming
with bow-legged women.
Excuse me, Chief.
Can't get a good man
these days, under 60.
All gone
at least 35 years.
Don't drink that.
Mr. Quint...
You're gonna
need an extra hand.
This is Matt Hooper.
I know him.
I've crewed
three Trans Pacs.
Transplants?
He's from
the Oceanographic Institute.
And an America's Cup trial.
Mr. Hooper,
I'm not talking
about pleasure boating
or day-sailing.
I'm talking about
working for a living.
I'm talking about sharking.
I'm not talking
about hooking some poor
dogfish or sand shark.
I'm talking about
finding a great white.
Porkers?
Talking about porkers?
Just tie me
a sheepshank.
I haven't had to
pass basic seamanship
in a long time.
You didn't say how
short you wanted it.
How's that?
Give me your hands.
Dogfish?
You got a $5,000 net
and you got $2,000
worth of fish in it.
Along comes Mr. Whitey,
and when he's finished
with that net
it looks like
a kiddies' scissors class
has cut it up
for a paper doll.
You got city hands,
Mr. Hooper.
You been
counting money
all your life.
I don't need this.
I don't need this
working-class-hero crap.
You're not going to do this
aboard the ship are you,
Mr. Quint?
Maybe I should
go alone.
It's my party.
It's my charter.
Yeah, it's your charter,
it's your party.
It's my vessel.
You're on board my vessel,
I'm mate, master, pilot
and I'm captain.
I'll take him
for ballast, Chief.
You got him.
"Straight-jet,
killing lance.
"Tail rope, eye splice, M-1,
handy billy, pliers, irons..."
Sample bottles,
dye marker, flares,
safety float
temperature gauge,
spear guns, SMG...
What are you?
Some kind of
half-assed astronaut?
Take that stuff down below
and you lash it secure,
all right?
Jesus H. Christ!
When I was a boy,
every squirt wanted
to be a harpooner
or a swordfisherman.
What have you got here?
A portable shower
or a monkey cage?
An anti-shark cage.
Anti-shark cage?
You go inside the cage?
Cage goes in the water?
You go in the water?
Shark's in the water.
Our shark.
Farewell and adieu
to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
For we've received orders
for to sail back to Boston
And so nevermore
shall we see you again
Did you take
your Dramamine?
Yes.
I put an extra
pair of glasses
in your black socks
and there's
the stuff for your nose,
the zinc oxide and
Blistex is in the kit.
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn women today,
they can't handle nothing.
Young girls just
ain't quite smart
like their
grandmothers were.
That's got to be Quint.
Colorful, isn't he?
He scares me.
Don't use
the fireplace in the den...
What am I going
to tell the kids?
Tell them
I'm going fishing.
Break it up,
will you, Chief?
Daylight's wasting!
Front, bow. Back, stern.
Better get it right,
squirt,
or I throw your ass
out the little round
window on the side!
Come on, Chief.
This isn't no
Boy Scout picnic.
See you got
your rubbers.
"Here lies
the body of Mary Lee
Died at the age of 103
"For 15 years
she kept her virginity
"Not a bad record
for this vicinity"
All right, Commissioner,
fasten your safety belt!
If you see a shark,
Hooper, swallow!
Up periscope.
Rig for depth charge.
Stand by fire drill.
Damage control report.
Nor'easter coming,
bad news for
Madison Avenue.
I'm tired of that.
How's the missus, Chief?
If they don't
like you going out,
they'll love you coming in.
Keep that chum
line going, Chief.
We got five
good miles on it.
Who's driving
this boat?
Nobody. The tide.
One time, I caught
a 16-footer off Montauk.
Had to stick
two barrels in him.
Two to wear him down
and bring him up.
Nowadays, these kids,
they take out everything.
Radar, sonar,
electric toothbrushes.
Jesus H. Christ.
Chief, best drop
another chum marker.
Damn it, Martin!
This is compressed air.
What the hell kind
of a knot was that?
You pulled
the wrong one!
You screw around
with these tanks,
and they're going
to blow up.
Yeah, that's real fine,
expensive gear
you've brought
out here, Mr. Hooper.
I don't know what
that bastard shark's
going to do with it.
Might eat it,
I suppose.
Seen one eat
a rocking chair one time.
Next time,
you just ask me which
line to pull, right?
Little brown eel
comes out of the cave
swims into the hole
comes out of the hole,
goes back into
the cave again.
It's not too good,
is it?
Nothing's easy, is it?
One more time.
Little brown eel...
I got it!
What?
Get behind me.
Hooper, reverse her!
Taking a hell
of a lot of line!
Chief, get the scoop
out of the bucket!
Wet the reel!
Hooper, reverse her!
Duck your head down.
We're swinging.
Get behind me again.
No more water.
I don't want you
to drown me.
Hooper,
you idiot, starboard!
Ain't you watching it!
Hooper, neutral.
Where'd he go now?
He ain't fooling me.
What's he yanking on now?
Go on, try it.
I don't know, Chief,
if he's very smart
or very dumb.
Jesus...
He's gone under.
He's gone under the boat.
I think he's gone
under the boat.
Yeah, it's too easy.
He is a smart, big fish.
He's gone under the boat.
Keep her steady, now.
I got something very big!
I don't think so.
Chief, put your gloves on.
You put your gloves on,
both of you!
Getting ready
to run out again.
Quint, let it go.
Maybe you're a big yahoo
in the lab,
but out here
you're just supercargo!
If you don't want
to backstroke home,
you get down here!
You don't want
to listen to me,
don't listen to me.
It's not a shark.
The wire's showing.
Unbuckle me.
Get the other side.
It's a tuna
or swordfish
wasting our time.
Take this rod.
Hooper, give the Chief
a hand, will you?
Right!
Oh, shit!
It may be a marlin
or a stingray
but it's definitely
a game fish.
Gaming fish?
Marlin, stingray bit
through this piano wire?
Don't you tell me
my business again.
You get back
on the bridge.
Quint, that doesn't
prove a damn thing.
It proves one thing,
Mr. Hooper.
You wealthy
college boys don't have
the education enough
to admit
if you're wrong.
What's the point?
Hooks and lines?
You lose one,
you rig one.
Twelve minutes,
south-southeast, now!
Full throttle!
Aye-aye, sir!
You see, what I do,
Chief, is I trick them
to the surface.
And then
I jab at them.
I'm not going
to haul them up
like a lot of catfish.
Hooper, full throttle!
I don't have to take
this abuse much longer.
Your head's bleeding.
First aid there.
Start that chum line
again, will you?
Let Hooper take a turn.
Hooper drives
the boat, Chief.
Stop playing
with yourself, Hooper.
Slow ahead,
if you please.
You heard him.
Slow ahead.
I can go slow ahead.
Come on down and
chum some of this shit.
You're going to
need a bigger boat.
Shut off that engine.
That's a 20-footer.
Twenty-five.
Three tons of him.
We're going to need
a bigger boat, right?
Gotta get to work.
How do we handle this?
Come up front, Martin.
I need you.
He's circling the boat.
This is Amity Point
Light Station to Orca.
Come in, Orca.
Orca. Come in.
I have
Mrs. Martin Brody here.
Put her on.
Come on,
Martin! Move!
I'm not
going out there!
Beyond the edge
of the barrels.
Go to the end
of the barrels,
further out.
Further out!
Why?
Go further out!
What for?
Will you go to
the end of the pulpit?
What?
Will you go to
the end of the pulpit?
I need something
in the foreground
to give it some scale!
Foreground my ass!
Your husband's okay.
He's fishing.
He just caught
some stripers.
We'll bring them for dinner.
We ain't seen anything yet.
Over. Out.
I'm not staying here!
I'm begging you!
God damn it!
Come here, darling.
Chief,
I want you up
on the bridge,
just take her forward,
steady.
I've never steered
a boat in my life.
Just watch my hand,
take her steady.
Mr. Hooper, attach
the end of this line
to the first keg.
I've got to
get a good shot at
that porker's head.
He's coming.
Hooper? Get clear
of the bow.
Hurry up, will you?
Your turn, Quint.
Hooper,
where are you?
Hurry it up now,
tie it on.
He's coming
straight for us.
Don't screw it up now.
Don't wait for me.
Come on, Hooper,
hurry it up!
Tie it on!
Now.
Kill it!
Now!
Shoot!
Time.
What were you doing?
You knew I had
to get a clean shot
right in the head.
All right, let's see
how long that barrel takes
to bring him up.
Bring another barrel!
I'm coming around again!
What do we do now?
We're quitting, right?
We got one barrel on him.
We stay out here
until we find him again.
We could radio in and
get a bigger boat...
Don't you worry
about it, Chief.
It won't be permanent.
You want to see
something permanent?
You want to feel
Just put your hand
underneath my cap.
You feel that little lump?
Knocko Nolans,
St. Patty's Day, Boston.
I got that beat.
It's a moray eel.
It bit right through
my wet suit.
Well, Hoop,
now, listen
I don't know about that,
but I entered
an arm-wrestling contest
in a bar
in San Francisco.
See this?
I can't extend that.
You know why?
'Cause in the semi-final
celebrating my
third wife's demise,
big Chinese fellow,
he pulled me right over.
Look at that.
That's a bull shark.
He scraped me when
I was taking samples.
I got something for you.
There's a thresher.
You see that?
A thresher's tail.
Thresher?
It's a shark.
You want a drink?
Drink to your leg?
I'll drink to your leg.
So we drink
to our legs.
I got
the crème de la crème.
Right here. Hold on.
Here, you see that?
You're wearing
a sweater.
Right there.
Mary Ellen Moffit.
She broke my heart.
What's that one?
What?
That one, there.
On your arm.
Oh.
A tattoo.
I got that removed.
Don't tell me.
"Mother."
What is it?
Mr. Hooper, that's
the U. S. S. Indianapolis.
You were
on the Indianapolis?
What happened?
Japanese submarine
slammed two torpedoes
into her side, Chief.
I was coming back
from the island
of Tinian to Leyte
just delivered the bomb,
the Hiroshima bomb.
1,100 men went
into the water.
Vessel went down
in 12 minutes.
Didn't see the first shark
for about half an hour.
Tiger, 13-footer.
You know how you know that
when you're in the water,
Chief?
You tell by looking
from the dorsal
to the tail.
Well, we didn't know.
Because our bomb mission
had been so secret
no distress signal
had been sent.
They didn't even list us
overdue for a week.
Very first light,
sharks come cruising
so we formed ourselves
into tight groups.
You know, kind of
like old squares
in a battle like
you see on a calendar
like the Battle
of Waterloo.
The idea was...
the shark comes
to the nearest man
and he starts pounding,
hollering and screaming.
Sometimes the shark
would go away...
but sometimes
he wouldn't go away.
Sometimes that shark,
he looks right into you,
right into your eyes.
You know, a thing
about a shark, he's got...
lifeless eyes.
Black eyes,
like a doll's eyes.
When he comes at you,
he doesn't seem to
be living
until he bites you.
Those black eyes roll
over white and then...
Then you hear
that terrible
high-pitched screaming.
The ocean turns red.
In spite of the pounding
and the hollering,
they all come in.
They rip you
to pieces.
You know,
by the end of
that first dawn...
we lost 100 men.
I don't know
how many sharks.
Maybe 1,000.
I don't know how many men,
they averaged six an hour.
On Thursday morning,
I bumped into a friend
of mine...
Herbie Robinson,
from Cleveland.
Baseball player,
bosun's mate.
I thought he was asleep.
Reached over to wake him up.
He bobbed up and down
in the water just
like a kind of top.
Upended.
He'd been bitten in half,
below the waist.
Noon the fifth day,
a Lockheed Ventura saw us.
He swung in low
and he saw us.
He was a young pilot.
Younger than Mr. Hooper.
He saw us
and he came in low,
and three hours later...
a big fat PBY comes down
and starts to pick us up.
That was the time
I was most frightened.
Waiting for my turn.
I'll never put on
a life jacket again.
So, 1,100 men went
into the water
316 men come out.
The sharks took the rest,
June 29, 1945.
Anyway,
we delivered the bomb.
What's that?
It's a whale.
Farewell and adieu
to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
Show me the way
to go home
I'm tired
and I want to go to bed
I had a little drink
about an hour ago
And it's gone right
to my head
Wherever I may roam
By land, or sea or foam
You will always hear me
singing this song
Show me the way
to go home
I'm tired
and I want to go to bed
I had a little drink
about an hour ago
And it's gone right
to my head
Wherever I may roam
On land or sea or foam
You can always
hear me singing...
Start the engines.
Fire her up!
Right in the middle!
He's busting the shaft.
Put out the fire,
will you?
Pump her out.
Done.
Everybody on deck.
He ate the light.
- Terrific.
- Excuse me.
Quint, what are you doing?
Don't waste your time.
Quint, come on.
What's wrong with this?
Hooper, take the wheel.
Brody, follow that.
Watch for him.
You okay?
Chief,
more left rudder!
Pull your left hand down.
I can't. It'll only go
about three inches.
All of our
injectors got scored
from the salt water
in the fuel.
Yeah,
the housing's bent,
you can hear it.
Try the left rudder again.
More left. Good.
Once again now.
Quint, there it is.
What do you say, Chief?
The barrel is up,
it's right in the stern.
I think he's
right under the keg.
Grab the boat hook.
Quint, if we can
get close enough...
I've got things on board
that'll kill it.
Just want to
goose him up.
Come on.
When he runs,
you drop that rope
or you'll lose your hands.
I've seen fingers
torn out at the knuckles.
Whole sea's bones,
full of them.
Give it to me a minute.
Haul in that line
or it'll foul us.
Start the engine.
Where are you going?
I'm going to
make a phone call.
Hello, mayday, Orca.
Coast Guard?
Coast Guard,
this is the Orca.
Do you read me?
Coast Guard,
this is the Orca.
Do you...
Excuse me, Chief.
That's great!
That's just great!
Now, where the hell
are we, eh?
You're certifiable,
Quint, you know that?
You're certifiable!
You're certifiable,
but I'll tell you this!
Boys,
I think he's come back
for his noon feeding.
Hook me up
another barrel.
Bring her around
after him.
Full throttle!
Get me right up
alongside of him!
I can't rev it up that high,
it's not going to take it!
Five degrees port.
All right,
hold your course.
Five degrees port now.
Hold your course.
Fast fish.
Watch my hand.
Be sure you watch
my hand! Follow me.
Lad, you watch him now!
Starboard!
Run him down, Hooper.
Hard aport.
Watch him. Starboard.
I can't believe it.
Two barrels and
he's going down again.
It's incredible.
They're up again!
Now what?
Why don't we lead
the shark into shore
instead of him
leading us out to sea?
Grab a couple of poles.
Hang on now,
we're going around.
Into starboard. Easy.
I'm going to
back her off now.
Watch those barrels, boys.
Watch them.
All right, gentlemen,
snag them.
Now then, tie them
to the stern cleats.
Brody, bring your end
around the cleat.
That's right,
it'll lock itself off.
Give him room, Brody.
Stay clear of the line!
Watch it. Stand clear.
Stand away from
those stern cleats!
Back home we got
a taxidermy man.
He's going to
have a heart attack
when he sees
what I brought him.
Throttle back.
You're losing a cleat.
My God, this one, too.
They're both going.
He's eating his way
through that line.
He's working his way
right up to us.
Quint!
Come on, Quint. Hurry!
Out of my way.
Watch it.
Untie this.
He'll pull out
the transom.
Make it fast! We got
another line in him!
I can't,
it's trying to run!
We better
get another line!
Pull,
you son of a bitch!
I hope your back breaks!
Go ahead. Pull your
bloody heart out.
Tie him off!
It's impossible!
Boys, it's too tight!
He's pulling us!
We're breaking up
over here!
We're breaking up!
Cut it!
Watch your hands!
Cut it quick.
I can't hold it!
He can't stay down
with three barrels
on him.
Not with three barrels,
he can't.
What about us?
Hooper, get the pump
out of the locker
in front of you, will you?
We're going to sink,
aren't we?
Keep an eye on the barrels.
Pump it out, Chief.
Starting to go under.
He can't with
three barrels on him.
Not with three he can't.
You ever have
one do this before?
No.
He's chasing us.
I don't believe it.
I'm going to draw him
into the shallows.
Draw him into
the shallow water.
I'm going to draw him in
and drown him.
We're heading in, Brody.
Thank Christ!
You ever had
a great white do that?
No.
How far do we
have to go?
Don't put that much
pressure on it.
God damn it.
Shut up.
Get back there.
Hold on.
Farewell and adieu
to you fair Spanish ladies
Farewell and adieu,
you ladies of Spain
For we received order
for to sail back to Boston
You idiot,
you burned out
the bearings.
All right,
stop the boat. Stop it.
What exactly can you do
with these things of yours?
I think I can pump 20 cc
of strychnine nitrate
into him.
If I can get
close enough.
Get this little needle
through his skin?
No, I can't do that.
If I can get him
close to the cage,
I can get him
in the mouth.
That shark will rip
that cage to pieces.
You got any
better suggestions?
Easy.
Up she goes.
Ease her up.
Ain't got no spit.
Try and keep him off me
until I'm lower.
Okay, I'm ready.
Bring him up, God damn it.
Bring him up now!
Pull it up. Pull it.
Pull him up.
Come on, Quint,
bring him in.
It's giving way!
Rig something!
Got it?
It's coming.
Slow it down.
Slower.
All right, come on.
Show me the tank.
Blow up!
Smile, you son of a bitch!
Quint?
No.
Can we get in
on those?
What day is this?
It's Wednesday.
It's Tuesday, I think.
I think the tide's
with us.
Keep kicking.
I used to
hate the water.
I can't imagine why.