(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION
ON POLICE RADIO)
SARAH: People once believed
that when someone dies,
a crow carries their soul
to the land of the dead.
But sometimes,
something so bad happens
that a terrible sadness
is carried with it,
and the soul can't rest.
Then, sometimes, just sometimes,
the crow can bring
that soul back
to put the wrong things right.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: Over here.
OFFICER: Hey, Sarge!
Yeah?
Shelly Webster and Eric Draven.
Wedding was tomorrow night.
Who the fuck gets married
on Halloween anyhow?
Nobody.
Sir, we got to move her.
Do it.
All right, guys, let's do it.
Devil's fucking night.
What's the count so far?
Hundred and forty-three fires.
They're slacking off
from last year.
Three hours to go. Maybe
they're just slow starters.
OFFICER:
Coming through!
(CAWING)
TORRES: You guys
just can't come in here
and take her away like this.
There are procedures
to stick by.
You guys should have
cleared this with me first.
Is this the victim?
No, it's Amelia Earhart.
We found her, Detective,
and you missed it.
I don't care what her name is.
I didn't the give
the order to move her.
Jesus, Albrecht, I can see why
they took away your gold shield.
Yeah, I wasn't a big enough
asshole. Come on, let's go.
MAN: All right,
clear out of here.
Shelly?
Stand back, kid.
Where's Eric?
Just don't worry about him.
Tell him to take care of Sarah.
Look, I will. You just
lie back. Come on, come on.
(GASPING)
Are you Sarah?
Yeah.
Yeah, look. Your sister,
she's gonna be okay.
She's not my sister.
Shelly just takes care of me.
She's my friend.
Her and Eric.
You lied to her about Eric.
Look, I had to.
And you're lying to me
about Shelly.
She's gonna die, isn't she?
Hey, uh...
Now, come on.
Come on.
It's okay.
She's gonna be fine.
SARAH:
A building gets torched.
All that is left is ashes.
I used to think that was true
about everything.
Families, friends, feelings.
But now I know that
sometimes, if love proves real,
two people who are
meant to be together,
nothing can keep them apart.
Later.
(CROW CAWING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CAWING)
What are you,
like the night watchman?
(HORN HONKS)
You know, what this place needs
is a good natural catastrophe.
Earthquake, tornado, you know?
No, no, no.
Mickey, come on, man.
You got to put the mustard
underneath first.
Maybe a flood,
like in the Bible.
Hey, hey. Hey, come on.
Let me do it.
There we go.
All right.
How about some onions?
Come on, man. Don't cheap
out on me. Lots of onions.
All right, here you go.
Hey! All right.
Now we're talkin'.
Hey. It's the Sarah monster.
How do you steer that thing
on a wet street?
Pure talent. Hi.
See, now, Sarah, she's
a genuine hot dogger.
You hungry?
You buyin'?
I'm buyin'.
No onions, though, okay?
No onions?
They make you fart big time.
(CHUCKLING)
T-BIRD: You know, Lake
Erie actually caught on fire once
from all the crap
floating around in it.
I wish I could have seen that.
(WHISTLES)
(ALL YELLING)
(CRASHING)
(BEEPING)
(CREAKING)
(WHIMPERING)
(CAWS)
(SCREAMING)
(WHOOPING)
(LAUGHING)
Fire it up! Yeah!
(ALL YELLING)
(PANTING HEAVILY)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(CAR RADIO BLARING)
Fire it up!
We busted their machines!
(CAWS)
Oh, oh, shit, guys.
T-Bird, cop car, cop car.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Bad people out
on the street tonight.
(BEEPING)
(EXPLODING)
Damn it!
WOMAN: Oh, my God!
What was that?
You wait right here.
Be careful.
Mickey, call it in for me!
(CAWS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(MEOWING)
Gabriel.
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Eric?
Department of housing!
Code violations?
Safety hazard?
Place looks fine to me.
Let's redecorate.
"Abashed, the Devil stood
"and felt how awful goodness is.
"Saw virtue in her shape,
how lovely."
It's pornography.
Virtue?
(SCREAMING)
ERIC: Shelly?
(GRUNTING)
See ya!
No, no, no.
Me first.
Eric!
(DISTORTED POLICE SIREN)
(CAWS)
Hey, that's good.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(COUGHS)
FUNBOY: See if you can top
that, man. Can you top that?
MAN: Look at that.
Look at that.
Here's to Devil's Night.
My new favorite holiday.
You need to go over there
and talk to your pals.
You sick fuck!
You're out of your
motherfucking mind, man.
FUNBOY:
Man, look at that.
Pussies drink last, man.
Fuck you, Tin Tin.
Hey...
Shit ain't even loaded, man.
This one is.
Which of you Motor City motherfuckers
wants to bet me this one isn't?
Hey, fire it up!
ALL: Fire it up!
Fire it up!
Fire it up! Fire it up!
Here's your shooters.
Put your guns away, huh, guys?
How you doing, Pussycat?
(CRYING)
Boo.
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
I love you.
Say that again.
Oh, boy.
(LAUGHS)
Restaurant.
SARAH:
Wow, you look great.
Ta-da!
Yeah!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Come here!
No, no, no!
(GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
♪ Just paint your face
the shadows smile
♪ Slipping me away from you
♪ Oh, it doesn't matter
how you hide
♪ Find you if we're wanting to
♪ So slide back down
and close your eyes
♪ S! eep a while
you must be tired
♪ But every night I burn
♪ Screaming the animal scream
♪ Every night I burn
♪ Dreaming the crow-black dream
(CROW CAWING)
♪ Dreaming
the crow-black dream ♪
TIN TIN: Couple more rings. That's 24k.
24k, huh? It's 18k.
It's crap.
It's probably fake.
Leather purse.
Leather.
Geez.
Oh, what is this, Tin Tin?
A blood stain that's on here?
I'll give you 50 bucks.
And I hate charities.
Now, you take it or leave it.
Right there for ya.
Decisions, decisions.
You cheap-ass, chrome-dome,
child-molestin'
saprophyte, motherfucker.
Close the gate when you go out!
Oh, I'll close this up
for you real good, massa.
Fuck you.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, sit on it and twirl,
you dirty scum.
Lucky I didn't stab
your fat ass.
♪ Someone take these dreams away
♪ That point me to another day
♪ A duel of personalities
♪ That stretch all true reality
♪ They keep calling me
♪ Keep on calling me
♪ They keep calling me ♪
(CAWING)
(LAUGHING)
What the fuck you all painted
up for, crackhead, huh?
Halloween ain't till manana.
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
I'll cut you!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Fuck, you murderer!
I ain't murdered nobody, man!
I don't even
fucking know you, man!
What the fuck do you want, man?
I want you to tell me a story.
A man and a woman
in a loft a year ago.
You're out of your
motherfucking mind.
Listen! I'm sure
you'll remember.
You killed them.
On Halloween.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
Halloween, yeah.
Some dude, some bitch.
Whatever, man.
Her name was Shelly.
You cut her.
You raped her.
Shelly. Yeah, yeah.
I shanked her pink ass
and she loved it!
(GRUNTS)
Murder, man? Murder?
Let me tell you about murder. It's fun.
It's easy.
You gonna learn all about it.
(LAUGHING)
I'd like you to meet
two buddies of mine.
We never miss.
Try harder.
Try again!
(SCREAMING)
Victims.
Aren't we all?
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYS)
♪ Sometimes it rains
inside my head
♪ All the words run dry
♪ Walls are breathing
hands are reaching up
Look at this mess!
What's the world coming to?
I got to go upstairs.
Report from the front.
Get out of my way, you worms!
Give me some of that,
over there!
Why don't you ladies come
by later, check me out?
Hey, guess what.
Arcade games fell down,
went boom.
Boom.
Can you imagine that?
It's tragic.
Gather your soldiers.
You're on for tomorrow night. No sweat.
Is the man in?
He's taking a meeting.
(SIGHS)
You're thinking about the past.
Dad gave me this.
Fifth birthday.
He said,
"Childhood's over the moment
you know you're gonna die."
Is she asleep?
I think we broke her.
I love her eyes.
Pretty.
♪ No, they don't have to
take you away ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CAR HONKS)
MAN: Hey, kid, get
the hell out of the road!
♪ I don't hate them
♪ But I know them
♪ I don't want them
hangin' around
♪ I won't roll my bones... ♪
(CHUCKLING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
I told you to stay out of here.
So, I guess you're
not gonna be home
till a lot later, huh, Darla?
She's busy.
Go play with your dolls
or something, okay?
I don't have any dolls.
Get some food, huh?
Somebody already bought
me dinner. The police.
(MIMICKING) "Somebody already
bought me dinner. The police."
(BOTH LAUGH)
$20, $40, $60, $80.
Who the fuck is this now?
Hey! Piss off!
We're closed!
Cerrado!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Go sleep it off
somewhere else, dusthead!
Unless you want
to get mutilated.
(MUTTERING)
Goddamn creatures of the
night, they never learn.
Hey! Hey!
(GRUNTS)
(CAWING)
(SCREAMS)
"Suddenly, I heard a tapping,
"as if someone gently rapping,
"rapping at
my chamber door."
What are you talking about?
You heard me rapping, right?
You're trespassing.
And you owe me
a fucking new door!
I'm looking for something
in an engagement ring.
Gold.
You're looking for a
coroner, shit-for-brains.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit on me!
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Shit on me.
Shit on me!
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
Mr. Gideon.
You're not paying attention.
No! My hand!
(MUFFLED CRYING)
I repeat,
a gold engagement ring, yes?
It was pawned here a year ago
by a customer of yours
named Tin Tin.
He confided in me before
he ran out of breath.
Who's this sack of shit?
That's Tin Tin, one of
T-Bird's little helpers.
I think you can rule out
accidental death.
(LAUGHS) Don't any of your street
demons have real grown-up names?
This could be a turf hit,
but it doesn't look like
your usual gang crap.
Come on, Albrecht, spare me.
You're a beat cop now,
so be a beat cop.
I'm supposed to thank
you for that, right?
Word to the wise...
Watch your fucking mouth.
What the hell do you call that?
I call it blood, Detective.
I suppose you'll
write it up as "graffiti."
You can leave
my crime scene now, okay?
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Warmer?
What are you doing?
Don't you know this game?
What game are you talking about?
Okay, the rings! I'll
tell you about the rings!
They're in that metal box!
It's under the shelf there!
Take it!
Take your fucking rings!
Choke on them,
you son of a bitch!
Look, it goes up to the attic.
Okay.
No, no.
No, no, no.
Oh, it's beautiful.
I don't believe it.
Shelly.
I love you.
(EXCLAIMS)
You have one chance to live.
Take anything you want.
Thank you.
Take anything!
Now you're gonna tell me
where to find
the rest of Tin Tin's
little party pals.
The Pit. They all hang out at The Pit.
All of T-Birds' little
potato-heads hang out there.
Funboy. He lives there
upstairs, all right?
Funboy.
Oh, baby, oh!
A whole jolly club...
Stop! Stop! Please!
...With jolly
pirate nicknames!
Stop! Please!
Jesus Christ...
Hold still!
Each one of these is a life,
a life you helped destroy.
I'm begging you, all right?
Don't kill me.
I'm not gonna kill you.
Your job will be
to tell the rest of them
that death is coming for them...
Tonight.
Tell them Eric Draven
sends his regards.
You walk out of here,
they're gonna erase
your sorry ass!
You're nothing but
street grease, you hear?
Street grease, you motherfucker!
Is that gasoline I smell?
No, man, no! No!
No!
(SCREAMING)
It's on the house, kiddo,
you know that.
One root beer.
I can't do anything.
Your mom, technically,
she's off right now.
Yeah, way off.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Police! Don't move!
I said, "Don't move!"
I thought the police
always said, "Freeze."
Well, I am the police, and
I say don't move, Snow White.
You move, you're dead.
And I say I'm dead.
And I move.
Not one more step.
I'm serious.
Then shoot, if you will,
Officer Albrecht.
What, are you, nuts?
Walking into a gun?
You high?
You don't remember me?
What are you talking about?
How about Shelly? Do you
remember Shelly Webster?
Shelly Webster's dead,
my friend.
I want you to move over
to the curb there.
Go on, real nice and
easy. Come on, move it!
Okay, we're gonna
wait here for backup.
It's getting too
freaking weird for me.
Oh, it gets better.
Do you know someone
named T-Bird?
He had a friend who shouldn't
have played with knives.
Like the coat?
You're the guy
that murdered Tin Tin.
MAN: Hey, check it out.
He was already dead.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
He died a year ago,
the moment he touched her.
They're all dead. They
just don't know it yet.
Get away from there!
MAN: Cops! Come on!
Get out of here!
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
Leave it!
Leave it! Run!
Oh, great.
Great.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Guy shows up looking like
a mime from hell,
and you lose him
right out in the open.
Well, at least he didn't do that
walking against the
wind shit I hate that.
OFFICER: Little early
for Devil's Night.
You are very restless.
Just wish I was a little
hungry again, that's all.
Be careful of what you ask for.
Yeah, I may get it.
I know.
(SIZZLING)
There are energies
aligning against you.
Seeing is believing, isn't it?
(DOOR OPENS)
Mmm, yummy.
Gideon's pawnshop just
burned down to the foundation.
Nobody cleared this
little event with me.
I didn't have nothing
to do with that.
I'm sure you must be
awful disappointed.
I got trouble. One of my
crew got himself perished.
Yeah, and who might that be?
Tin Tin.
Somebody stuck his blades in all his
major organs in alphabetical order.
Well, gentlemen, by all
means, I think we ought to have
an introspective moment of
silence for poor, old Tin Tin.
(SNORTING)
You're working for me
tomorrow night, right?
Whatever you say, I can do.
Good.
That's very reassuring.
I still ain't heard the story
on why Gideon's burned down.
Is that a natural catastrophe
or act of God or something?
Call it my need to know.
(SIGHS)
(HORN HONKS)
Hey! Let go, you creep!
Nah.
You didn't even slow down,
you dickhead!
He couldn't have stopped.
He was a buttface.
I could have made it.
What are you supposed to
be, a clown or something?
Sometimes.
It's more like surfing
than skating.
I wish the rain
would stop, just once.
It can't rain all the time.
Eric?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Don't thank me.
(CHUCKLES)
Are we fighting the good fight?
Double homicide a year ago.
No convictions.
Annie, look at that.
"We, the undersigned tenants of
1929 Caulderon Court Apartments."
What is this, a petition?
Big "kick me" sign for a very nice
girl who found herself a cause,
and the cause got her killed.
She was fighting tenant
eviction in that neighborhood?
Shelly Webster
and her nice rock-'n'- roll
boyfriend, Eric Draven.
You know, the last time you
went snooping around on a case
is when you got
put back on the beat.
Yeah, I know.
Torres keeps reminding me.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I bet he does.
You're gonna wind up
working a school crosswalk.
I'm cool.
You didn't get that file
from me, okay?
And don't tell me
you owe me one.
Ah, I owe you one!
Yeah, right.
Damn.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Tomorrow night we can get high,
and watch this whole fucking
city burn from that window.
(LAUGHS)
♪ I am the park
♪ I am glow
in the motherfucking dark
♪ I am shocked and I seethe
(CAWING)
♪ I don't want to believe
♪ No more ♪
There's a big,
fucking bird over there.
(CAWING)
It's a squab.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Come here, bird.
Hey, bird.
Bird. B-b-birdie.
Here, birdie, birdie,
birdie, birdie.
Come here, birdie, birdie,
birdie, birdie, birdie.
(LAUGHS)
Birdie?
Hey, birdie?
Here, Funboy.
What the fuck!
(STRUMMING GUITAR)
No, man!
Don't do that!
You nearly gave me
a fucking heart attack!
(LAUGHS)
Don't sweat it.
It's time for you to take
your bird and leave, freako.
Take your shot, Funboy.
You got me dead-bang.
You are seriously fucked up.
(LAUGHING)
Did you look in the mirror?
I mean, you need
professional help.
(SCREAMING)
Bingo!
He shoots, he scores!
(CAWS)
(LAUGHS) Whoo!
(LAUGHS)
Whoo-hoo!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ?
Stop me if you heard this one.
Jesus Christ walks into a hotel.
Ow!
(LAUGHS)
He hands the innkeeper
three nails and he asks...
Don't you ever fucking die?
"Can you put me up
for the night?"
(GUN FIRES)
(GROANING)
Does that hurt?
Fuck.
Does it fucking hurt?
(GROANING) Oh, God.
Look what you've done
to my sheets.
(CRYING)
I've got a gun in my pocket.
You're happy to see me,
aren't you?
Stay away from me!
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMING)
Look.
"Mother" is the name for God
on the lips and hearts
of all children.
Do you understand?
Morphine is bad for you.
Your daughter is out there on
the streets waiting for you.
If I wanted ice,
I would have asked for ice!
Now fill it up!
Fill it up yourself, macho man.
I really need this.
All right.
You burn yourself
playing with matches?
Fuck off.
You have an appointment.
Well, shit on me.
Drink up.
This is a first.
Do I bow or do I curtsy?
Get my friend here
a glass of blood.
Oh! Hey, hey, hon!
Hey, good night, Darla.
You stay put.
(GROANS)
Right there.
Get away, steamhead.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Shh.
(GROANING)
MAN: (ON RADIO)
As you can see, I'm here,
on the corner of 27th
street in Washington Place.
The site of last year's biggest
Devil's Night conflagration.
It was exactly one year ago
that the building you see
across the street from me
was totally demolished by fire.
The fire that was fought
by seven fire companies...
But lost the lives
of two fire fighters.
In fact, if it weren't for
the constant surveillance
by the local police...
Freeze!
Jesus! Don't ever
do that, man.
(EXHALES) Fuck.
Good likeness.
I saw your body, man.
You died.
You got buried.
You still have your hat on.
I got to sit down.
Shit. Holy shit.
Say...
(STAMMERING)
Are you some kind of...
Ghost?
Boo!
I don't know what I am.
I need you to tell me
what happened to us.
You took a six-storey
swan dive out of a window.
She, uh, was beaten and raped,
died at the hospital.
Hey, you asked, man.
I mean, come on, read the file.
Shelly Webster held on for
30 hours in intensive care.
Her body finally
just gave it up.
I saw it, man. I
couldn't do jack for her.
Hey.
Don't touch me!
(GROANS)
Hey.
You okay?
I saw her.
I saw her through your eyes.
You stayed with her
the whole time.
Yeah, well...
You got to understand
something, all right?
I was...
I was hoping she'd
come out of it, you know?
Give me something
I could work with.
Yeah.
Look, I...
Why didn't you
do something about it?
You think any of those
people in that building,
even the ones who
signed the petition,
would talk after
what happened to you?
I kept asking questions, and...
Finally got busted for sticking
my nose where it wasn't wanted.
This your wife?
Yeah, we, uh...
Well, not anymore.
We're getting a divorce.
It's funny.
Little things used to
mean so much to Shelly.
I used to think they
were kind of trivial.
Believe me, nothing is trivial.
You shouldn't smoke these.
They'll kill you.
You gonna vanish
into thin air again?
I thought I'd use
your front door.
Look, man, um.
I'm sorry as hell for what
happened to you and your girlfriend.
Yeah.
(DOOR CLOSES)
GIDEON: I got stabbed!
I shot the son of a bitch!
I watched the bullet hole
close by itself.
And then my business
gets blown up real good.
Other than that, my day sucked.
Yeah. I saw him, too.
He had a guitar.
He winked at me
before he jumped out a fourth-floor
window like he had wings.
He winked at you?
Musicians.
What else did you see?
So far, I haven't
heard shit about
what you're going to do
about all this crap!
I mean, what do I get?
My livelihood got flushed
away and went swirling.
You ain't lost everything.
Yeah, and maybe you're not
such a big shot, either!
Ow! Jesus!
Fair enough.
Catch.
(GASPS) Jesus!
Say hello to the last fellow
who wouldn't cooperate with me.
What, you telling me... You
tellin' me this thing is real?
All the power in the world
resides in the eyes, fella.
Sometimes, more useful than
the people who bear them.
You're directly out of
your fucking mind!
You know that!
Yeah.
Eyes see.
It's one of the most important
things I learned from my sister.
She's supposed
to be your sister?
(LAUGHING)
My father's daughter.
That's right.
What's the matter, you
don't see the resemblance?
Now, let's take it
from the top, friend.
With a lot of detail.
What do you say?
He had a bird with him.
Nearly pecked my face off.
He told me to tell T-Bird
that death was on its way,
whatever the fuck that means.
Draven. He said his
name was Eric Draven.
Want to relax that thing now?
And this bird man, he just
happened to let you live, huh?
You sure you ain't
making all of this up
just to save your own ass?
I ain't making all this up.
I ain't twisted
like you two fucks.
All right.
A boy and his bird.
Awful touching.
Yeah. (LAUGHING)
(SCOFFS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, for fuck's sake
die, will you?
Give me that thing.
(GAGGING)
Thanks.
Funboy said he
saw a black bird, too.
A big one.
Then he choked to death
on his own blood.
I'll have the janitor
come on up.
(GUITAR PLAYING)
(PURRING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAWING)
You again?
Are you lost or hungry?
Hi.
(TAPE REPEATING)
T-BIRD: I don't know how
many times I got to tell you.
We're in this together!
One part falls, it all falls!
(CAWS)
You know how long it took
us to put this together?
That piece of rat shit made Tin
Tin into a Fucking voodoo doll.
Tin Tin was a dick.
Tin Tin. Sheesh!
Fire it up! Fire it up!
Fire it up!
No Funboy?
Probably still
banging away on Darla.
(MOANING)
(WHISTLES)
Smokes and road beers.
Be quick.
I'm on it.
(CAWING)
What the fuck are you
supposed to be, man?
I'm your passenger.
Drive.
What's all this happy horseshit?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, T-Bird! T-Bird!
(HONKING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Oh, shit!
What the fuck's
the matter with you?
Stupid asshair!
You hit my car!
(GRUNTING)
What do you want, man?
Money? Drugs? I got it.
We could use you.
You did Tin Tin.
This is business, right?
Faster.
OFFICER: You got
that cream stuff?
I hate this. They can't
even call it cream legally.
What in the crap!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(YELLING)
Oh, look.
Making us popular.
When they flash us like
that, they ain't friends.
This is Vehicle 48. We got
us a big, old, red hot rod.
Turn.
You got something personal,
amigo, we can work it out.
Right? Huh?
Damn! Dead end!
(CAWING)
MAN: Look out!
Oh, my God!
Get outta the way!
Holy shit!
Goddamn foreign cars!
Shit! Shit!
Oh, I hate this.
This ain't good.
T-Bird!
I got you, man!
Shit!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
T-BIRD: Remember? Yeah, I remember
everything, but I don't know what...
What? Huh? What?
What are you talking about?
No, no, no, no, no.
You mean that place downtown?
Yeah, I remember her.
We needed to put some
fear into that little lady.
She wasn't going along with
our tenant relocation program.
And her idiot boyfriend shows up
and turns a simple
sweep-and-clear
into a total cluster fuck!
Who gives a shit?
It's ancient history!
Why? What do you want?
What is it? What?
Speak to me. Speak!
Did you send us
these complaints?
Come here!
"Abashed the Devil stood."
Does it get you sweaty?
I know you. I know you.
I knew I knew you.
But you ain't you.
You can't be you. We put
you through the window.
There ain't no coming back.
This is the really real world.
We killed you dead.
There ain't no coming back.
T-Bird.
There ain't no coming back!
(ENGINE REVVING)
"Abashed, the Devil stood
"and felt how awful goodness is.
"And felt how
awful goodness is."
T-Bird. T-Bird.
(CAWING)
TV REPORTER: This is the 7:00
am edition of Action News.
For over a decade,
the night before Halloween
has had a darker
and deadlier nickname
in the inner city,
"Devil's Night".
The name given to what has
become an annual plague of arson.
Last year, over 200 individual
blazes were reported,
and 11 people lost their lives.
Tonight will be key
of what may become the biggest
and deadliest Devil's Night ever.
The mayor has fire fighters
from all surrounding counties...
Do you like them up or
over? I can't remember.
What are you doing?
I don't even like eggs.
Wait, you loved eggs.
Yeah, when I was five.
So what do you want now?
Black coffee and cigarettes?
So what did you take to
become mother of the year?
Oh, it wasn't drugs.
Someone kind of woke me up.
Who?
Oh, it was nuts.
You're acting weird.
Did you win the lottery
or something, Darla?
Oh, forget it. I never was
too good at this mommy shit.
Over easy.
I like 'em over easy, Mom.
Hey, Albrecht.
(EXHALES)
This is the third hit
in your hood in 24 hours.
We just fished this
out of the river.
He's fused to his own car. We're
gonna have to I.D. His teeth.
His name is T-Bird.
Arson was his specialty.
Looks like he zigged
when he should have zagged.
Case closed.
Bull-fucking shit.
Come here.
You're holding out on me.
I got a goddamn vigilante killer
knocking off scumbags
left and right,
and you're covering up
for somebody.
Who's the cartoon character
in the painted face?
Hey, you're the detective.
Why don't you tell me.
Okay.
Gideon's blows all to hell
and you're having a chit chat
with some weirdo who winds up in
T-Bird's car when it zigs instead of zags.
Then you steal one of my
case files from homicide,
and you're saying this is just
a fucking automobile accident?
Come on!
Yeah.
Good speech though.
I didn't want to interrupt
you. It sounded good.
You gotta write that shit down.
All right, smart-ass.
The captain's got a little
love note waiting for you.
Welcome to the first day of
the rest of your suspension.
Suspension?
For what?
Misconduct.
Yeah, give me the lab.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PLAYING GUITAR)
SHELLY: One for sorrow, two for joy...
ERIC: Come here.
...Three for a girl,
and four for a boy.
Dancing.
Eric?
Man, Sarah, you're going crazy.
Gabriel.
(MEWS)
I thought you were dead.
You're not dead, are you?
I knew it was you.
Even with the makeup.
I remembered your song.
You said,
"Can't rain all the time."
That is from your song, right?
Come on, Eric.
I know you're here.
(CAWS)
I miss you and Shelly.
Get so lonely all by myself.
The hell with you.
I thought you cared.
Sarah, I do care.
That's him.
That's him!
But he looked different.
He was all painted up white
like some kind of dead whore.
I seen him. T - Bird, he sent
me in for some road beers, right?
Then he took him away.
But I chased him down.
And he flash fried T-Bird
to his fucking car!
Aw, T-Bird!
Here's to you, buddy.
Maybe we ought to just videotape
this. Play it back in slow motion.
Fire it up! Fire it up! Fire it up!
You see the grave?
Empty.
Fire it...
Grave?
What grave?
What about my fucking grave?
Three out of four.
He's working his way back to
this speed freak right here.
It's not fair.
It's Funboy's fault. That
boy was out of control.
T - bird, he came in, he
says, "Waste them both."
And now this ghost
gonna kill my ass next!
(GRUNTS)
This ghost gonna
kill my ass next.
This.
Hey.
It ain't no ghost.
They have all arrived.
Watch him.
We might need him.
Ghost gonna kill my...
He like his plain
or with onions?
Fine.
Don't talk to me.
When someone's dead, they
can't come back, can they?
That's what I thought.
Are you referring
to anyone in particular?
You'll just think I'm nuts.
Yeah, well, then maybe they'll
have to lock us both up.
You see him, too?
I saw somebody.
Maybe it was
your fairy godfather.
Eric didn't come back for me.
He can't be my friend
anymore because I'm alive.
You want a friend
to walk you home?
(ELECTRIC GUITAR PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: Being crucified.
(SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
Boys.
It seems our friend T-Bird
won't be joining us this evening
on account of
a slight case of death.
(MAN LAUGHS)
You wanna sit down?
(GROANING)
Well, well, well.
Devil's Night is upon us again.
I thought we'd
throw a little party,
start a bunch of fires,
make a little profit.
I like the pretty lights.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Problem is, it's all been done
before. You see what I'm saying?
That's no reason to quit.
Wrong.
Best reason to quit.
Only reason to quit.
A man has an idea.
The idea attracts others
like-minded.
The idea expands.
The idea becomes an institution.
What was the idea?
See, that's what's
been bothering me, boys.
But I'll tell ya, when I used
to think about the idea itself
it'd put a big old
smile on my face.
You see, gentlemen,
greed is for amateurs.
Disorder, chaos, anarchy.
Now, that's fun!
What about Devil's Night?
What about it?
I started the first fires
in this goddamn city.
Before I knew it, every charlatan
and shit heel was imitating me.
Do you know what they got now?
Devil's Night greeting cards.
Isn't that precious?
Yeah.
The idea has become
the institution, boys.
Time to move along.
You don't want us to do "Light
My Fire" time for the whole city?
No.
No, I want you to set
a fire so goddamn big
the gods will notice us
again. That's what I'm saying.
I want all of you boys to be able
to look me straight in the eye
one more time and say,
"Are we having fun or what?"
Hey, you! What's your name? Huh?
Skank!
You don't feel that?
I feel like a little worm
on a big fucking hook.
(ALL LAUGHING)
"I feel like a little worm
on a big fucking hook."
Well, boy, your mama
must be damn proud of you!
(CAWING)
(GASPS)
How the hell did
that thing get in here?
Gentlemen.
(SCREAMS)
SKANK: Let me go! Let me go! I gotta go!
You're him, huh?
The avenger.
The killer of killers.
Nice outfit.
I'm not sure
about the face though.
I just want him.
(WHIMPERING)
Well, you can't have him.
(MEN LAUGH)
Well,
I see you have
made your decision.
Now let's see you enforce it.
Aw, this is already boring
the shit out of me. Kill him!
Ooh! That had to hurt.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Well, that's that.
That guy was crazy.
He's gone.
(GUN FIRING)
Get him!
Right here! Here, help me!
He's gonna kill me!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Jesus Christ!
Hey!
You're all going to die.
(SCREAMING)
(MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
Guess it's not a good day
to be a bad guy, huh, Skank?
I'm not Skank.
There's Skank right there.
Skank's dead.
That's right.
No!
(CRASHING)
What the crap!
Don't move!
Hold it!
That's all she wrote!
Move and we shoot!
OFFICER: (ON BULLHORN) You are surrounded
by police units. Do not attempt to escape.
Stop running immediately.
Holy shit!
Stop immediately, lie down,
spread your arms and legs.
Come on! Move it!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
My advice.
Next time duck.
So many cops, you'd think they
were giving away doughnuts.
Shit!
Oh.
I knew you were gonna do that.
TOP DOLLAR:
Look at that out there.
The whole city ought
to be in flames by now.
Sky ought to be red.
So that, I take it, is the
late, great Eric Draven.
He has power, but it is
power you can take from him.
I like him already.
The crow is his link between
the land of the living
and the realm of the dead.
So, kill the crow
and destroy the man.
Hmm.
I'm coming home, Shelly.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES)
(ALL LAUGHING)
You're gonna say I
shouldn't be in the cemetery
in the middle
of the night, right?
Safest place in the world to be.
It's 'cause everybody's dead.
I knew you'd come here.
It's really late, Sarah.
You didn't say good-bye.
You're just gonna have
to forgive me for that.
And you're never coming back.
I gave this to Shelly once.
I think she'd like
you to have it.
This way you'll
always remember her.
I'll never take it off.
I better go sneak
back in the house.
Bye.
(WIND HOWLING)
Shh! Shh!
Shh. Take it easy,
sweetheart.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
What is that? Some sort of
souvenir there from your pal?
I'll just keep it for good
luck. What do you say, hmm?
Her eyes are so innocent.
SARAH: Eric!
Eric, help! Eric!
(CAWING)
Quick impression for ya.
Caw! Caw! Bang!
Fuck, I'm dead!
Give me the girl and I'll
let you walk out of here.
Well, well.
Why don't you just give me a
minute to think about that, huh?
Nah. Fuck it.
(GROANS)
Aw, fuck.
Well, well, well.
It does seem to me that our
little life has undergone
a rather significant change
in the past few minutes now.
Wouldn't you agree?
Well, for a ghost,
you bleed just fine.
(CAWING)
It's still alive.
Well, then kill it!
Bye-bye, birdie.
Ah, shit.
Well, just came by
to pay my respects
and here you are
getting all shot up again.
They've taken Sarah.
How many?
Two more.
I can handle it.
Don't worry.
I'm not worried.
Look, here's the plan.
You stay in front,
and when they run out
of ammo, I'll arrest 'em.
That sounds like a great plan.
There's just one problem.
Oh, shit. You're bleeding
all over the place.
I thought, you know,
you were invincible.
I was.
I'm not anymore.
(SIGHS)
Well, I guess you really
will need my help, won't you?
Come on.
(GROANS)
You take that.
You were supposed
to stay behind me.
I think I messed up.
This is all the power
you ever had.
Now it is mine.
Pity there's not more time
for us.
(SCREAMING)
(BELL TOLLING)
SARAH: Help, Eric!
I'm scared!
Let me go!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Let her go!
You can have me.
I won't fight you.
All right.
(SCREAMS)
No!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
SARAH: Eric!
(LAUGHING)
Sarah?
Look out!
(CAWING)
Eric!
You know, my daddy used to say
"Every man's got a devil
"and you can't rest
till you find him."
What happened back there with
you and your girlfriend...
I cleared that building.
Hell, nothing in this town
happens without my say-so.
So I'm sorry if I spoiled
your wedding plans, friend.
But if it's
any consolation to you,
you have put a smile on my face.
You got a lot of spirit, son.
I am going to miss you.
I have something to give you.
I don't want it anymore.
Thirty hours of pain!
All at once!
(GROANING)
All for you.
(CAWS)
(GRUNTING)
Yeah.
Go help him.
Are you alive?
God, I need a cigarette.
Everybody else dead?
You helped me.
What you kept in here saved me.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
I've been meaning
to come to church anyway.
Oh, yuck.
I'm quitting as of now, if I live.
(POLICE SIREN
WAILING IN THE DISTANCE)
Stay with him until help comes.
He'll be okay, right?
Eric?
(SCOFFS)
He does that a lot.
Shelly.
At least it
stopped raining, huh?
It can't rain all the time.
TORRES:
No, I don't believe it.
This nightmare
your fault, Albrecht?
Look, you go on home.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Want to tell me what's going on?
Your vigilante's up on the roof.
You missed it.
Get him outta here!
(CHUCKLING)
(CAWS)
Thanks.
SARAH: If the people we
love are stolen from us,
the way to have them live on
is to never stop loving them.
Buildings burn, people die,
but real love is forever.
♪ We walk the narrow path
♪ Beneath the smoking skies
♪ Sometimes barely
tell the difference
♪ Between darkness and light
♪ Do we have faith
♪ In what we believe
♪ The truest test
♪ Is when we cannot
♪ When we cannot see
♪ I hear pounding feet
♪ In the streets below
♪ And the women crying
♪ And the children know
♪ That there's something wrong
♪ It's hard to believe
that love will prevail
♪ Oh, it won't rain all the time
♪ The sky won't fall forever
♪ And though
the night seems long
♪ Your tears won't fall
♪ Forever
♪ Oh
♪ When I'm lonely
♪ I lie awake at night
♪ And I wish you were here
♪ I miss you
♪ Can you tell me
♪ Is there something more
to believe in
♪ Or is this all there is
♪ And the pounding feet
♪ In the streets below
♪ And a window breaks
♪ And a woman falls
♪ And there's something wrong
♪ It's hard to believe
that love will prevail
♪ It won't rain all the time
♪ The sky won't fall forever
♪ And though
the night seems long
♪ Your tears won't fall
♪ Forever
♪ Last night I had a dream
♪ You came into my room
♪ You took me into your arms
♪ Whispering and kissing me
♪ And telling me
to still believe
♪ Within the emptiness of
the burning cities
♪ Against which we set
our darkest of selves
♪ Until I felt safe and warm
♪ I fell asleep in your arms
♪ And when I awoke I cried again
♪ For you were gone
♪ Can you hear me?
♪ It won't rain all the time
♪ The sky won't fall forever
♪ And though
the night seems long
♪ Your tears won't fall forever
♪ It won't rain all the time
♪ The sky won't fall forever
♪ And though
the night seems long
♪ Your tears won't fall
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Drivin' faster in my car
♪ Falling farther
from just what we are
♪ Smoke a cigarette
and lie some more
♪ These conversations kill
♪ Falling faster in my car
♪ Time to take her home
♪ Her dizzy head is
conscience laden
♪ Time to take a ride
♪ It leaves today
no conversation
♪ Time to take her home
♪ Her dizzy head is
conscience laden
♪ Time to wait too long
♪ To wait too long
to wait too long ♪