No!
Oh!
When someone
you love dies...
...you will know emptiness.
You will know what it is
to be completely
and utterly alone.
You will never forget...
...and you will never...
ever forgive.
-Zadie?
-Shelly.
Did you see what I sent you?
No. What is it?
I showed the video to someone.
I think they found out.
What the fuck is going on?
Check your texts.
Hey, Shelly.
Oh, stop!
What the fuck?
What did you do to her?
Where did you get this?
Dom shot it.
Look, we can get him with this.
He's not invincible, Shelly.
Yes, he is.
I'm getting my shit
and getting the fuck out.
Come with me.
You and Dom.
The three of us.
Why the fuck did you do this?
It's not safe
for us here anymore.
Stay there.
I'm coming to you.
I think
they've got someone on me.
If they're following me,
they're following you.
Hello, Zadie.
Zadie?
Hey, Shelly.
Oh, stop!
There were
other options, Zadie.
I wish you'd talked to me first.
Hi, you've reached Dom.
Leave a message.
Dom, it's me.
Zadie's lost her fucking mind.
She just sent me
some video that you shot.
Meet me at Zadie's.
I'm gonna check on her.
Whoa, whoa.
What're you doing, huh?
- Yeah, we have a 10-50,
female in her 20s.
Bringing her in.
- Say something.
- Wake up, Eric.
Are you gonna
stand up for yourself?
Look at me.
What're you gonna do about it?
You're fucking old enough
to look after yourself.
Daddy's gonna come back.
- We're here.
- Say something.
-Hello. Are you there?
-Say something!
-Nothin'? You got nothin'?
-Where's your mom right now?
Say something, son!
-Wake the fuck up.
-Say something, man!
Say fucking something!
I know
this is hard, Eric.
But these exercises
are meant to get you past
the destructive behaviors
that brought you here.
Burying it... using drugs...
That's the easy way out.
It's what allows you
to hide that pain away.
You, uh, going to join us?
You know, Hemingway wrote,
"The world breaks everyone,
"and afterwards,
"many are strong
at the broken places.
"But those
that will not break...
"it kills."
...group therapy after that.
No phones.
No talking after dark.
No fraternizing with the men.
Mr. Roeg.
Here's the young protege
from Vienna
I was telling Marion about.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Mr. Roeg.
Please.
Sit.
Now, you know
I was born in Vienna,
a cradle of immortal music.
I've lived long enough to see
some of the greats play.
They tell me that
you're quite dynamic yourself.
-May I borrow you?
-Yes.
Um...
I look forward
to hearing you play.
What is it?
We found her.
It's all right, Zadie.
It's all right.
What's done is done.
We're looking for your friends.
Have you seen Shelly?
No.
You're a good person, Zadie.
You wouldn't tell me
if you knew.
Would you?
I've killed hundreds
of innocents like you
in the centuries
that I've been here.
It never gets any easier.
I wish
the murderers and rapists,
and scum of the earth would do,
but...
they go to hell already,
you see.
Whereas people like you,
those are the souls
that he wants.
That's the... the deal I made.
You go to hell
so I don't have to.
Please...
Please let me go.
You can go.
What the fuck is going on here?
Get your shit together!
You know why we still out here?
It's because of your bullshit!
Huh?
Hi.
They don't like you in here,
do they?
No, not really.
They have a thing about
men and women
not sitting together.
I know.
They told me.
I like your tattoo.
Thanks.
"Laugh now. Cry later."
It's kind of how things
have been playing out for me.
Well, for me,
it's more like "cry now,
"cry later."
Wanna hear a joke?
Uh, I don't know. Is it funny?
Not really.
Great. Go for it.
What kind of tea
is hard to drink?
I don't know.
Reali-ty.
Yeah. Wow. Well, that's...
That's something.
I'll keep working on it.
Hey, time
for your group session.
Here he comes,
like fucking clockwork.
What's your name?
I'm Eric.
Shelly.
I'll see you around, Shelly.
If you were
forced to be silent,
step into the circle.
If you were made
to feel that anything wrong
is your fault,
step into the circle.
If you were abandoned,
neglected, manipulated
by those who were
meant to protect you,
step into the circle.
If you are ready to look forward
to the good things
that life will bring you,
step into the circle.
We're pleased you found her.
We're so fond of you
and your daughter.
You all right?
Oh, hey. Yeah.
Fuck, they really
trashed the place, huh?
Um... Yeah.
Is this me?
All right.
These songs or poems?
I wouldn't call them either.
It's just shit that I write.
You write beautifully.
Some of this would be great
set to music.
Do you play music?
Used to.
Well, maybe we could, um...
I don't know, maybe, um...
Maybe we could
play together sometime.
Maybe.
See how we get along.
What are you doing in here?
I don't know.
I guess everything
just finally caught up with me.
Patient 005, Shelly,
please be advised
you have a visitor.
No one knows I'm here.
Hey. I'll go have a look, okay?
I mean, it just looks
like fucking lawyers to me.
Come on, take a look.
What the fuck?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
-Who are they?
-They can't find me here.
If they find me here,
I'm fucked.
Her room is right this way.
-I've got to get out of here.
-Yeah, yeah.
-They can't find me here.
-Um...
-Fuck!
-Come with me.
Could you give me a location
update on Patient 005?
Okay, here it is. You see
those windows up there?
-Yeah.
-They'll take you out
to the yard.
-Okay.
-Wait, wait, wait.
You gotta get the tag off.
Can you pick up their signal?
They're in the laundry room.
What're you doing?
Fuck this place.
I'm rehabilitated.
Think we fucking did it.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, slow, slow down.
Stop.
Who were those people?
A former life.
Right.
Got one of those.
I bet you do.
Jesus, this is crazy.
It's my friend's place.
He lives in Antigua.
Lets me crash here sometimes.
So, um...
What now?
You know,
you don't have to stay.
Maybe it's safer if you don't.
I want to stay.
Okay. Well, then,
we'll hide out here for a while.
And then what?
We'll hide somewhere else.
Just figure it out.
Good plan.
It is a good plan.
You stink, dude.
I'm sorry.
Do you mind if I use the shower?
Not yet.
Pretty good.
What's the first thing
you liked about me
when you saw me?
What's, um...
There's like an aura about you.
It feels powerful.
What's the first thing
you liked about me?
I thought that you were
quite brilliantly broken.
You are.
What's the, um...
What's the worst thing
you've ever done?
I once escaped rehab with
a complete fucking degenerate.
Probably the best thing
I've ever done.
Mm.
Wait, I just
remembered something.
You have a secret stash here?
All right.
Hello.
Aha.
-Those are the ones?
-Mm-hmm.
Lamb of God.
Stop looking at me
or I'll poke your eye out.
-Poke out my eye?
-Mm-hmm. You don't need that.
You've got me now.
How many people have you loved?
Like seriously, seriously loved?
Mm.
Me neither.
Promise me something.
What?
If I'm ever hard to love,
try to love me harder.
Marion.
You have a problem.
Call for you, Mr. Roeg.
Yes?
They found Zadie's body.
And here I thought
there was nothing left to find.
It's a setback, but we're close
on one of the others.
If this video gets out,
you know what they'll do to me.
I find this tiresome, Marion.
This running around.
I can feel you sweating
through the phone.
This ends here.
You're infatuated.
You're obsessed, bro.
- Hi.
What are you reading?
Rimbaud.
Shall I read you some?
-Yeah.
Hell yeah!
I don't want it to end.
Doesn't have to.
We could be living like this
all the fucking time.
Why'd you stop?
That was beautiful.
Mm...
Why don't you play?
No.
No. We both know
you're better at this than me.
No. No, no, no.
Please, please.
Yes. Go on.
I can't do this right now.
Okay.
You all right? What's going on?
Could we just go out for a bit?
I haven't played piano
for a while.
I loved playing.
It was my whole life.
But my mom took it
and twisted it all,
pushed me
into performing at places
I was too young to be at.
Didn't want to play
for any of them.
I saw things.
I shouldn't have seen any of it.
I hurt people.
And I just...
I know.
It's okay.
It's not okay.
What did you do?
I can't tell you.
If you knew, you'd leave me.
And if you left me, I'd die.
If I left you,
I'd already be dead.
I just want to start over.
Well, why don't we?
Where would we go?
Fuckin' anywhere.
Anywhere is better
than this fucking place.
Anywhere?
Anywhere.
So you're saying
if I jumped,
you'd jump with me.
Of course I would.
Do you think angsty teens
would build
little shrines for us?
Yeah. They'd be lining up
to leave cigarettes and whiskey.
No.
No?
Lilies.
A sea of white lilies.
All right. Lilies, it is.
I told you, bro.
I fucking love this guy!
I'm gonna go
and get some water.
I can get it for you.
No, no. You stay there.
Sure.
Can I get
some water, please?
Shelly! Shelly!
-Dom... What the fuck?
-Just listen to me.
Just listen to me. Just listen.
Zadie's dead.
They're gonna
come for us, Shelly.
You need to leave town now.
What do you mean?
Shelly, you gotta
listen to me. It's true.
No, no, no.
I'm not leaving without Eric.
No.
Shelly, just listen to me.
Are you hearing what I'm saying?
Zadie's fucking dead!
-Come on, we've gotta leave.
-What's going on?
-We've gotta leave, Eric.
-Who the fuck was that?
I'll tell you
everything.
Let's just get back
to your place.
Shelly?
Shelly!
Get off her! Get off her!
No, don't do this.
No, please don't do this.
Get off of her!
Please don't do this.
What the fuck!
Shelly?
Hey.
Hey!
Hey?
Where am I?
What is this place?
You'd think they'd come up
with something better,
wouldn't you?
But you know,
they don't expect us to linger.
How long we stay here
is entirely up to you.
...we stay
here is entirely up to you.
What the fuck
is happening to me?
People once believed
when someone dies,
a crow carries their soul
to the land of the dead.
But sometimes,
something so bad happens
that a terrible sadness
is carried with it...
and the soul cannot rest.
What are you talking about?
The crow will guide you
to put the wrong things right.
What do you mean?
Oh, fuck this. This isn't real.
You stay the fuck away from me.
There's nothing there but here.
This is all
just a fucking nightmare.
This is just
a fucking nightmare.
Then go wake up.
The sadness is killing...
Shelly?
My turn.
Come on, Shelly.
You don't respect my art.
I'm here.
What am I looking for exactly?
- Her cell phone.
- All right.
We looked,
but we were interrupted.
- What's on it?
- You don't need to know.
Just find it.
All right. All right.
You can come out, boy.
Who are you?
I'm a cop.
Here.
Come on.
- Okay.
- It's okay.
-Drop that. Drop that.
-Yeah.
Listen, I think I'm going crazy.
I don't know what's real
or not anymore.
I just think
something really bad
has happened with my girlfriend.
Fuck.
What the fuck?
Oh, fuck.
Oh, no.
Ah, what the fuck!
What the fuck!
The crow will guide you
to put the wrong things right.
...wrong things right.
The crow will guide you
to put the wrong things right.
People once believed...
People once believed
when someone dies,
a crow carries their soul
to the land of the dead.
But sometimes,
something so bad happens
that a terrible sadness
is carried with it.
And the soul cannot rest.
...will guide you.
Shelly?
Shelly, baby.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's okay.
It's okay. Don't...
Look, come down from there.
It's okay. No, no, no, no, no!
No!
She's dead, isn't she?
We're both dead.
I'm afraid so.
What are you?
Some kind of angel?
Do I look like an angel?
I don't understand.
Why am I here and she isn't?
You're not gonna
like the answer.
Just tell me.
She's on her way down.
To a place far worse than this.
You said I could make
the wrong things right.
What does that mean?
The one who killed you
is not supposed to be
in your world.
They made a deal with the devil
to gain eternal life
by sending the innocent to hell.
That's not balance.
Kill them.
Kill them all.
And you get your lives back.
You're saying
I can get her back?
Yeah.
Kill the ones who killed you,
and you will get her back.
When I was up there,
I got shot.
And it taught you something,
didn't it?
What I, um... I can heal?
I can't die?
Your body? No.
Feel pain? Yes.
If your love remains pure,
you cannot die.
How am I supposed to trust you?
Do you have another choice?
Are you ready?
Holy shit.
Eric, what the fuck?
Where have you been?
Everyone thought you was dead.
Everyone was right.
Very funny. Just come inside.
I need your help, man.
What do you need?
I need a gun.
A gun.
Eric, what...
What are you gonna do with a...
You know what, it's not my...
You're going to need these.
I'm a friend of your daughter's.
We need to talk.
Who was after her?
Why did you
come for her that day?
I saw you there
with the people who killed her.
What are you talking about?
It was an overdose.
How would you know?
Because I was there.
You don't understand
who you're dealing with.
I loved her.
I need to know
who these people are
because I'm going to kill them.
Every single one of them.
And I'm gonna bring her back.
She's not coming back.
My baby's gone.
She's gone.
And she's not coming back.
Please leave me.
Just stop.
She's gone.
I fucking killed you.
Yeah. You did.
Don't move.
Turn it off.
I want names
of all the people
that you work for.
Don't!
Fuck!
Get down!
Drive!
Get in the back!
Hello, Sophia.
I'm sorry it's been so long.
Truly.
My condolences.
Shelly was such a special girl.
I heard you had a visitor.
What did he want?
He wants to kill you.
Oh. Anger.
First impulse.
It's not anger.
What is it, then?
Love.
Loved her so much.
He told me he was going
to bring her back.
What was that?
He thinks if he kills you,
he'll be able to bring
her back from the dead.
Oh, Shelly.
So many times you needed me,
and I was never there.
Stop it.
She's gone.
You traded her
for a better life.
That took a lot of courage.
What you gave me was not a gift,
it was a curse.
I would rather have died.
Well, then you should
go and be with her.
No!
-Marion.
-Yes?
He has been sent back.
The power to escape death
exists within him.
Bring him to me.
Fuck.
I'm just... Don't hurt me, man.
-Please.
-Why the fuck not?
-I didn't do anything, man.
-I saw you.
-What?
-In the club.
You brought them to us.
No, no. I was just
trying to get her out.
I was just trying
to help her get away, man.
Get away from what?
Get away from what? Huh?
That woman who was after her,
who is she?
Who, Marion?
No. No. She's just part of it.
She just works for him.
Who are you talking about? Who?
His name is Vincent Roeg, man.
He used to have us
over to party.
I thought it was just
an easy place to score.
That shit got so dark.
He made it so dark.
He's got this voice, man.
Voice.
He... burrows inside you.
Finds the darkest parts
of your soul
and gives them a voice.
And it just gets
louder and louder
until you do something evil.
I still hear it.
I never would have
made that fucking video
if I'd known
what would have happened, man.
What video?
Where is it?
Shelly had it on her phone.
Said she had it hidden.
She didn't want
anyone to see it.
I tried to warn her,
but she wouldn't leave
without you.
I knew Shelly a long time.
When I saw the way
she looked at you,
something was different.
I tried to do
something right, man.
I just fucked it up.
I'm sorry.
They won't be far behind me.
You do what we couldn't do.
Get the fuck out.
Thanks, man.
How many people
have you loved?
Like seriously,
seriously loved?
Oh, stop!
I will come back.
What the fuck!
What did you do to her?
Oh, my God,
there's blood everywhere.
What the fuck, Shelly? Help me!
She's dying.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh...
I found
what they killed her for.
Shelly, she did something
really bad.
And now I can't get it
out of my head.
I don't think I can do this.
I don't think
I can do this, man.
Eric, you just need
to sit down, bro.
-Fuck.
-Eric, sit down, please.
Please. Eric, come on.
Come on. Just sit down.
What's going on?
Holy shit.
Why didn't she just
fucking tell me?
She should have
just fucking told me.
Okay, but, if she did tell you,
could you still love her?
Eric?
What the fuck?
You need to come with us.
Fuck.
What the fuck have you done?
Why am I back here?
You couldn't see it through.
Hey. Why...
Why did I stop healing?
I said your love
needed to remain pure.
The enemy of love is not hate.
It's doubt.
I never doubted her.
Didn't you?
You had a chance
and you wasted it.
You were given
the power of a god.
In the end, you were just a boy.
At least your soul can move on.
Her soul is gone forever
into the darkness.
For you, eternity is easy.
You just have to breathe.
And let her go.
I can't.
I'm sorry.
Mine for hers.
My soul for hers.
Her soul is damned.
The place she's going,
you can't imagine it.
It's not about me.
Even if you save her,
you will never
be with her again.
I know.
Now let me do this.
It's not up to me.
There is no going back
from this.
With this black blood,
you will move between worlds,
just like them.
Go put the wrong things right.
Hold this.
Hmm.
Marion.
Vincent.
Is it true?
I'm afraid so.
He was killed.
Are you sure?
I'm sorry.
Damn.
Please can we ask you
to make your way
to your seats. Thank you.
Stefan?
Front entrance secure.
Hey!
We have a situation.
He's here.
He's killing all of our people.
I'm so grateful to you, Marion.
For what? Wh...
For getting us this far.
That's all you're going to say?
We're on this ride
together, Marion.
You just happen
to be in the front.
Where is he?
He's not in here.
He's...
His country estate.
Hillhurst Manor.
You fucking killed us.
For what?
Was it worth it?
It starts off so small.
It's all kept from you.
You know what's being done,
but you're not part of it.
And then, just like that,
you are.
You're swallowed up.
And the only direction
you can go is down.
You have the same look as him.
What look is that?
The look of someone who hates
everything inside of him.
He just hides it
better than you.
Lilies.
A sea of white lilies.
Face me.
Who are you?
Just an old man...
but I'm real.
See?
I'm flesh and blood.
Not like you.
I heard you think
you can bring her back.
You can't.
Where she is,
you don't come back from that.
That video, did you see it?
I know, I'm sorry.
She's not what
you thought she was.
No, it wasn't her.
It was you.
You corrupt people.
You can't corrupt
what's not already there.
A pearl. It's a seed.
Hmm.
Look at yourself.
Look at what you've become.
Those eyes.
That face.
Why would she want
to be with you?
You have no love left.
Only hate.
You fool.
You don't feel anything.
Do you?
You don't feel any of it.
I feel it all.
Say something!
-Wake the fuck up.
-Say something, man!
You have no love left.
Only hate.
She's not what
you thought she was.
When I'm hard to love,
love me harder.
Love me harder.
How many people have you loved?
Like seriously,
seriously loved?
Don't leave me.
I don't want it to end.
What is this place?
This is the place
where it all ends.
Where you pay
for what you did to her...
to all of them.
Are you scared?
You should be.
Oh, you stupid boy.
Is this what you want?
You think she's worth it?
All this?
Eternal hell?
For what?
For some fucking whore?
You have no idea
what hell awaits you.
Yeah, I do.
Eric.
I had this terrible dream.
I was falling.
I thought I'd lost you.
It's okay, baby.
It's over.
It's all over.
You get to go back.
Eric...
what have you done?
I can't come with you.
What?
This was the only way.
No.
I'm going with you.
This isn't the way
it was supposed to end.
I would do it again.
All of it.
Every moment.
I love you.
Forever.
Do you hear me?
Yes.
It's okay.
He fought hard for you.
Our love
will live on
in everything she does.
Someday, I know...
our souls
will find each other again.
Till then,
I will have just the memory.
That perfect sensation
of loving her.
And that's enough.
Almost enough.