No, it's too risky.
I'm through doing that shit,
You always say that: `'I'm through,
never again, too dangerous,.,"
- I'm always right too.
- But you forget about it in a day,
- The days of me remembering have
just begun, - You sound Iike.,,
- I sound like a sensible man. - No,
you sound like a duck. Quack, quack!
You`II never have to hear it again,
because l`ll never `'quack'` again!
- After tonight? - Correct,
l`ll have all tonight to "quack`'!
- Can I get anyone more coffee?
- Yes.
- Thank you,
- You're welcome.
The way it is now l`m taking
the same risk as robbing a bank.
I'm talking more of a risk, federal
banks aren't supposed to stop you.
They're insured. What do they care?
You don't even need a gun there,
This one bloke walks into the bank
with a portable phone,..
,.he gives the phone to the teller,
the bloke on the other end says,..
.,"Give this guy all your money
or we'Il kill his girl,", - Well?
It worked. The guy walked in with
a fucking phone, not a pistol!
- He cleaned the place out and they
didn`t do anything, - And the girl?
There probably never was a girl.
They robbed a bank with a telephone,
- You want to rob a bank? - It would
be easier than whatwe've been doing.
- No more liquor stores?
- No!
There are too many foreigners now:
Vietnameses, Koreans,.,
If you say to empty the register,
they don't know what you're saying!
- These fuckers will make us kill
them. - I don`t want to. - Me either,
But we`II be in a situation
where it's either us or them,
It's them or these fucking Jews who
have owned the store 15 generations.
You've got Grandpa lrving sitting
behind the counter with a Magnum!
Walk into one of those places with
a phone and see how far you get!
- Do you want a day job?
- Not in this Iife. - What then?
"Garçon'`, coffee!
This place,
"Garçon'` means `'boy".
This place?
A coffee shop?
What's wrong with that?
Nobody ever robs restaurants,
Why not?
Bars, Iiquor stores, gas stations,
you get your head blown off.,,
,.sticking up one of them!
Restaurants, on the other hand,
you catch with their pants down,
They're not expecting to get robbed,
at least not as expecting,
- There's Iess of a hero factor here.
- They`re insured, just Iike banks,
The manager just wants to get you out
the door before you plug the diners,
The waitresses will never take
a bullet to save the register,
Some busboy getting paid
$ 1,50 an hour,.,
,.doesn't give a fuck
if you're stealing from the owner!
The customers don`t know
what`s going on,
One minute they're eating, then
there's a gun stuck in their face,
- Remember the last Iiquor store?
The customers came in. - Yes.
- You took their wallets,
that was a good idea. - Thank you.
We made more money from the wallets
than we did from the register.
- Lots of people come to restaurants,
- Lots of wallets! - Pretty smart.
Pretty smart!
- l`m ready, Let's do it right now,
right here. - All right.
Same as Iast time, you're crowd
control, I handle employees,
- I Iove you, pumpkin,
- I Iove you, honey bunny.
- Keep cool, this is a robbery!
- If any of you pricks move.,,
..I`ll execute every
motherfucking Iast one ofyou!
- Tell me again about the hash bar.
- What do you want to know?
- Is hash Iegal now? - Yes, but you
can't smoke a joint in a restaurant,
- You can smoke home or in designated
places, - A hash bar, - Yeah,
It's Iegal to buy it,
it's Iegal to own it.,.
,.and if you're the proprietor of
a hash bar, it's Iegal to sell it.
It's illegal to carry it,
but that doesn't matter.,.
,.because if you get stopped by a cop
in Amsterdam, they can`t search you.
- That's a right the cops don't have.
- Man, I'm fucking going!
You'd dig it the most. You know what
the funniest thing about Europe is?
- What?
- It's the little differences.
- They've got the same shitwe have,
but it's a Iittle different. - How?
You can walk into a movie theater
in Amsterdam and buy a beer.
I don`t mean a paper cup,
I mean a glass of beer,
In Paris you can buy a beer
in McDonald's,
- You know whatthey call a '`Quarter
Pounder with Cheese" in Paris? - No.
- They've got the metric system, they
don't know what a pound is, - So?
- They call it "Royal with Cheese",
- Royal with Cheese!
- What do they call a "Big Mac'`?
- "Le Big Mac'`.
Le Big Mac!
What do they call a "Whopper"?
I don't know,
I didn't go to Burger King.
- In Holland they put mayonnaise
on French fries, - Yuck!
I saw them do it, man! Theyfucking
drown them in that shit!
We should have shotguns
for this kind of deal,
- How many up there?
- Three or four,
- Counting our guy?
- l`m not sure.
- That means there could be
up to five guys. - It's possible,
We should have shotguns.
- What`s her name? - Mia,
- How did Marsellus and her meet?
I don't know,
however people meet people,
- She used to be an actress.
- Did she do anything I've seen?
- She starred in a pilot,
- What's a pilot?
- You know the shows on TV?
- I don't watch TV.
- But you're aware of the television,
that they show shows on it. - Yeah!
The way they pick TV shows is they
make one show that's called a pilot.
They show it to people who pick shows
and decide if they want to make more,
Some get chosen and become television
programs and others become nothing.
She starred in one
that became nothing,
Do you remember Antwan Rockamora?
Half black and half Samoan.
- They called him "Tony Rocky
Horror", - The fat one.
I wouldn't say fat, He's got a weight
problem, poor nigger, he`s Samoan,
- I think I know him.
- Marsellus fucked him up good.
The word is that it was on the count
of Marsellus Wallace`s wife,
- What'd he do, fuck her?
- No, nothing that bad.
- Well, what then?
- He gave her a foot massage.
- A foot massage? That's it?
- Yeah,
- Then what'd Marsellus do?
- He sent a couple cats to his place,
They threw his ass over the balcony,
the nigger fell four stories.
He had a Iittle garden at the bottom
enclosed in glass Iike a greenhouse.
The nigger fell through it and then
he developed a speech impediment,
What a damn shame!
- If you play with matches,
you get burned. - What do you mean?
You don't give Marsellus
Wallace's wife a foot massage,
- Didn't he overreact? - Antwan
probably didn't expect that reaction,
- But he had to expect some reaction.
- It was only a foot massage,
It's laying your hands in a familiar
way on Marsellus` new wife.
It's not as bad as eating her pussy
out, but it`s the same ball park,
Eating the bitch out and giving her
a foot massage isn't the same thing.
- But it's the same ball park,
- It ain`t no fucking ball park!
Touching his wife's feet and sticking
his tongue in the holiest of holes,..
..ain't the same fucking ball park,
it ain't even the same sport!
- Foot massages don't mean shit.
- Have you ever done a foot massage?
I`m the foot fucking master!
- Have you done it a lot? - l`ve
got my technique down, no tickling,
Would you give a guy a foot massage?
Fuck you!
- Do you give them a Iot?
- Fuck you!
- I'm tired, I could use a foot
massage myself! - Back off.
I`m getting a little pissed here!
- This is the door.
- Here it is.
-What time have you got?
- 7:22 a,m,
It ain`t quite time yet,
let's hang back.
It's not right for Marsellus
to throw Antwan into a glass house..,
,,fucking up the way
the nigger talks,
If the motherfucker did that to me,
I'd kill him.
I ain't saying it's right,
but a foot massage means something,
I've given a million foot massages
and they all meant something.
We act like they don't, but they do,
That's what's so cool about them.
You don't talk about it,
but you know and she knows.
Fucking Marsellus knew it
and Antwan should have known better.
That's his wife, no man has
a sense of humor about this shit,
- You know what I'm saying?
- It`s an interesting point.
Come on, Iet's get into character.
- What's her name? - Mia, Why are
you so interested in his wife?
He's going to Florida and he asked me
to take care of her while he`s gone.
- Take care of her? - No, just take
her out, make sure she's not Ionely.
- You're going to take Mia Wallace
out on a date? - It is not a date.
It's like if you were going to take
your buddy's wife to a movie,
It`s just good company, that's all,
It's not a date,
Hey, kids. How are you boys doing?
Hey, keep chilling.
We`re associates of your business
partner Marsellus Wallace,
You do remember your business
partner, don't you?
Now, let me take a wild guess here.
- You're Brett, right? -Yeah,
- I thought so,
You remember your business partner
Marsellus Wallace, don't you?
- Yes, I remember.
- Good,
Looks Iike me and Vincent caught you
at breakfast. What are you having?
- Hamburgers. - The cornerstone
of any nutritious breakfast!
- What kind of hamburgers?
- Cheeseburgers,
- No, where did you get them, Wendys,
McDonald's? - Big Kahuna Burger.
Oh, that`s the Hawaiian
burger joint!
I ain't never had one myself,
how are they?
- They're good,
- Do you mind if I try one of yours?
- This is yours, right?
- Yeah,
This is a tasty burger,
Vincent!
- Have you ever had
a Big Kahuna Burger? - No.
- Want a bite? They`re real tasty,
- I ain't hungry. - Give them a try.
I can't get them because
my girlfriend is a vegetarian,
That makes me a vegetarian too, but
I do Iove the taste of a good burger.
Do you know what they call a Quarter
Pounder with cheese in France?
- No, - Tell him, Vincent,
- Royal with Cheese.
Do you know why they call it that?
- Because of the metric system,
- Our Brett has a big brain!
You're a smart motherfucker!
Right, the metric system.
- What's in this?
- Sprite. - Good.
- Can I have some of your beverage
to wash this down? - Go right ahead.
That hit the spot!
Do you know whywe're here? Tell
my friend where you hid the shit,
- It`s over there. - I don't remember
asking you a Goddamn thing!
- You were saying?
- It's in the cupboard,
No, the one byyour knees,
Are we happy, Vincent?
- Are we happy?
-Yeah, we're happy.
I'm sorry, I didn't get your name.
Yours is Vincent, right?
But I never gotyours,
- It's Pip and your ass ain't talking
your way out of this shit! - No.
I just want you to know.,.
We`re really sorrythat things got
so fucked up with us and Mr. Wallace,
We got into this thing
with the best intentions.
I'm sorry, did I break your
concentration? I didn't mean to,
Continue, you were saying something
about best intentions,
What's the matter?
Oh, you were finished!
Well, allow me to retort,
- What does Marsellus Wallace
Iook like? - What?
- What country're you from? - What?
- Do they speak English in "What`'?
- What?
- Do you speak English? - Yes.
- Then you know what I'm saying!
- Yes. - Describe Marsellus Wallace.
- What?
- Say "what" one more time!
I dare you, say '`what"
one more Goddamn time!
- He's black,
- Go on! - He's bald,
- Does he look Iike a bitch?
- What?
- No!
- Then why are you trying to fuck him
Iike a bitch? - I didn't! - Yes!
- You tried to fuck him!
- No!
Marsellus Wallace don't like to be
fucked by nobody except Mrs. Wallace.
- Do you read the Bible, Brett?
- Yes.
I've got this passage memorized,
it fits the occasion,
Ezekiel: 25-17.
"The path of the righteous man,,."
",.is beset on all sides by
the inequities of the selfish.,.'`
`'..and the tyranny of evil men."
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity and good will.,,"
'`.,shepherds the weak
through the Valley of Darkness,`'
'`For he is truly his brother`s keeper
and the finder of Iost children."
"l will strike down upon thee
with great vengeance,.."
".,and furious anger
those who attempt to destroy.,."
'`.,my brothers,`'
"And you will know my name
is the Lord.,,'`
'`..when I lay my vengeance
upon thee!"
When all this shit
is over and done,.,
,.I think you're going to find
yourself one smiling motherfucker.
The thing is that right now
you've got ability,
But, painful as it may be,
ability doesn`t last,
Your days are just about over.
That's a hard
motherfucking fact of life,
But it's a fact your ass is going
to have to get realistic about.
This business is filled to the brim
with unrealistic motherfuckers,.,
,.motherfuckers who thought their ass
would age like wine,
If you mean itturns to vinegar,
it does,
If you mean it gets better with age,
it doesn`t,
Besides, how many fights do you think
you've got in you anyway?
Two?
There are no fights for old boxers.
You came close,
but you never made it.
If you were going to make it,
you would've made it before now.
Are you my man?
It certainly appears so,
The night of the fight,
you may feel a slight sting,
That's pride fucking with you.
Fuck pride!
Pride only hurts,
it never helps.
Fight through that shit!
Because a year from now, when you're
kicking it in the Caribbean,,.
.,you'Il say to yourself:
"Marsellus Wallace was right".
I`ve got no problem with that,
Mr. Wallace,
In the fifth, your ass goes down.
Say it,
In the fifth, my ass goes down.
Oh, Vincent Vega,
our man in Amsterdam,..
..and Jules Winnfield, our man in
Englewood. Get your asses down here,
- What's up with those clothes?
- You don't want to know.
- Where's the big man? - He's over
there taking care of some business.
Hang back for a second. When you see
the white boy Ieave, go on over.
- How have you been? - Pretty good,
How about yourself? - All right.
I hear you`re taking
Mia out tomorrow.
At Marsellus' request.
- Have you met Mia?
- Not yet,
- What's so fucking funny?
- Nothing. - I've got to pee,
I`m not a fucking idiot.
She's the big man's wife. I'Il sit
across from her, chew my food..,
,.and Iaugh at her jokes! - My name
is Paul, this is between you all!
Then what did you fucking ask me
about itfor?
- A pack of '`Red Apples`'.
- Filters? - No.
-What are you Iooking at, friend?
- You ain't my friend, palooka,
- What was that? - You heard me
just fine, punchy!
Vincent Vega is in the house?
My man!
Here's your pack of Red Apples,
$ 1,40,
And some matches.
It's as if it turns every part
of your body into the tip of a penis.
- Wow! - I'Il lend it to you,
it's a great book on piercing.
Do they use a gun to pierce your
nipples like they do your ears?
That gun goes against
the entire idea behind piercing.
All my piercing, 18 places on my
body, have been done with a needle.
Five in each ear,
one through my Ieft nipple.,,
,.two in my right nostril,
one in my left eyebrow.,.
.,one in my belly, one in my Iip,
one in my clit.
- And I wear a stud in my tongue,
- Excuse me, I'm just curious.
- Why would you wear a stud
in your tongue? - It's a sex thing.
- It helps fellatio,
- Vincenzo.
Step in my office,
Let's go, This is `'Panda'`
from Mexico, very good stuff,
That's "Bava`'.
Different, but equally good,
That is "Choco`'
from the mountains of Germany.
The first two are 300 a gram,
Those are friendly prices.
But this one is a Iittle
more expensive. This is 500 a gram,
When you shoot it, you will know
where that extra money went,
There's nothing wrong with these,
This is real good shit,
- But this one is a fucking madman!
- I just got back from Amsterdam.
Am I a nigger? Are we in Englewood?
No, you're in my home,
White people who know the difference
between good and bad shit come here.
My shit can challenge
that Amsterdam shit..,
,,any old day of the week.
- That's a bold statement.
This ain`t Amsterdam,
this is a sellers` market.
Coke is fucking dead,
- Heroine is coming back
in a big fucking way. - All right.
Give me three grams of the madman.
If it's as good as you say,
I'll come back and buy another 1000,
I just hope that I still
have some left for you.
I'm giving you some out of my private
stash to show you how nice I am.
- I'm out of balloons, is a baggy
all right? - Yes, - AIl right,
- Honey, will you get me some baggies
and twisties from the kitchen? - OK,
Trudi ain`t got a boyfriend.
Want to hang out and get high?
Is Trudi the one
with all the shit in her face?
No, that's Jody, my wife.
- l`m sorry, man.
- That's all right.
- No, I can't. I've got to be
some place, - AII right,
Thank you!
- Have you still got your Malibu?
- You know what some fucker did?
-What? - He fucking keyed it,
- That's fucked up!
I had it in storage for three years.
I had it out for five days and
some piece of shit fucked with it,
They should be killed, No trial,
no jury, straight to execution.
I'd have given anything
to catch that asshole doing it.
- It would've been worth him doing it
so I could've caught him. - Fucker!
Only a chicken-shit
fucks with a man's automobile.
- You don't do it,
- It's against the rules.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Do you mind if I shoot up here?
- My house is your house,
- Thanks a lot.
"Hi, Vincent, l`m getting dressed,
The door is opened,`'
"Come inside and make yourself
a drink. Mia.'`
Hello?
Vincent.
- Vincent, I'm on the intercom.
- Where is the intercom?
It's on the wall,
by the two African fellows,
To your right.
Warm!
Warmer!
- Disco.
- Hello.
- Push the button
if you want to talk. - Hello.
Make yourself a drink,
I'll be down in two shakes,
The bar is by the fireplace.
Okay.
Let's go.
What the fuck is this place?
This is "Jackrabbit SIim's",
An "EIvis man" should Iove it,
- Mia, let's go get a steak.
- You can get a steak here,
Don't be a,.,
After you, kitty cat,
Good evening, how can I help you?
- There's a reservation
under Wallace, - Wallace?
- We reserved a car,
- Oh, a car!
Seat them over there in the Chrysler,
Hello,
Let`s hear it for Ricky Nelson!
Fantastic job, thank you very much.
Vincent!
Ricky will be back
in the second half of our show,
We hope you enjoy your meal
here at Jackrabbit SIim's,
Call for Philip Morris!
- What do you think? - It's Iike
a wax museum with a pulse!
Hi, I'm Buddy. What can I get you?
Steak, steak?
Yes, `'Douglas Sirk Steak",
- I'Il have that. - Burned to a crisp
or bloody as hell?
BIoody as hell, l`ll also have
a "Vanilla Coke".
What about you, Peggy Sue?
I'II have
the `'Durward Kirby Burger",
Bloody,
- And a 5 dollar shake, - Which one?
- A '`Martin and Lewis",
- Did you just order
a 5 dollar shake? - Yes.
- A shake is milk and ice cream?
- The Iast I heard,
- That's 5 dollars? You don't put
bourbon in it or nothing? - No,
- Just checking. - I'Il be right back
with your drinks.
Could you roll me
one of those, cowboy?
- You can have this one, cowgirl!
- Thanks,
Think nothing of it,
Marsellus said you
just got back from Amsterdam.
- I sure did. - How long were you
there? - Just over three years.
- I go there once a year to chill out
for a month. - I didn`t know that.
Why would you?
- I heard you did a pilot.
- That was my 15 minutes,
- What was it? - It was a show about
a team of female secret agents.
- It was called "Fox Force Five".
- What?
"Fox Force Five". `'Fox" as in
we're a bunch of foxy chicks.
'`Force'` as in we're forced
to be reckoned with,
'`Five" as in there were five of us,
The blonde was the leader,
The Japanese was a kung fu master.
The black girl
was a demolition expert.
The French fox's specialty was sex,
- What was your specialty?
- Knives.
My character grew up
raised by circus performers,
She was the deadliest woman
in the world with a knife.
She knew a zillion jokes,
her grandfather taught her,
If we would have gotten picked up,..
.,in every show
I would have told another joke,
- Do you know a lot of jokes?
- I only got the chance to say one.
- We only did one show.
- Tell me,
- It`s corny.
- Don't be that way, tell me.
No, you wouldn't Iike it.
I'd be embarrassed,
You've already told
50 million people.
- I promise I won't laugh,
- That's what I'm afraid of,
- That's notwhat I meant. - I'm not
telling you, we built it up too much,
What a gyp!
"Martin and Lewis".
'`Vanilla Coke",
- Yummy.
- Can I have a sip?
Be my guest.
- I have to taste a 5 dollar shake!
- Use my straw, I don't have cooties,
- Maybe I do.
- I can handle cooties, - AII right,
- This is a fucking good milkshake.
- I told you,
I don't know if it`s worth 5 dollars,
but it's good.
- Don'tyou hate that?
- Hate what?
Uncomfortable silences,
Why do we feel it's necessary to yack
about bullshit to be comfortable?
- I don't know, it's a good question.
-You know you`ve found someone,..
,.special when you can shut the fuck
up and comfortably share silence!
I don't think we're quite there yet,
we just met each other,
I'Il tell you what.
I'll go powder my nose and you sit
here and think of something to say,
I'Il do that!
Okay.
I said, Goddamn!
Goddamn!
- I love finding my food waiting.
- We're lucky we got anything at all.
I don't think Buddy Holly
is much of a waiter,
We should have sat
in Marilyn Monroe's section,
- Which one? There are two, - No,
there are not. That's Marilyn Monroe,
That's Mamie Van Doren,
- I don't see Jayne Mansfield, she
must be off, - Smart. - At times!
- Did you think of something to say?
- Actually, I did.
However.,,
- You seem Iike a nice person and
I don't want to offend you, - Ohh!
This doesn't sound like the usual
boring getting to know you chitchat.
- It sounds Iike you actually
have something to say, - I do.
But you have to promise
notto get offended,
No, I can`t promise something like
that, I don`t know what you'Il ask,.,
,.and my natural response could be
to get offended, then through,,.
,.no fault of my own, I would have
broken the promise. - Forget it!
That's impossible,
this is far too intriguing,
- Is that so? - It's more exciting
that you don't have permission.
All right.
Here it goes.
What did you think about
what happened to Antwan?
- Who's Antwan?
- Tony Rocky Horror,
- He fell out of a window,
- That is one way to say it!
Another way to say it
would be that he was thrown out.
Another way would be is that
he was thrown out by Marsellus,..
,,or that he was thrown out
of a window because of you,
- Is that a fact?
- No, it's just what I heard.
- Who told you? - They.
- They talk a Iot, don't they?
They certainly do!
- Don't be shy, what else
did they say? - l`m not shy.
- Did it involve the "F'` word?
- No,
- They said that Antwan had given you
a foot massage. - And?
And nothing, that's it.
You heard Marsellus threw Tony Rocky
Horror out of a window.,.
,,for giving me a foot massage?
-Yes, - And you believe that?
- It sounded reasonable. - Marsellus
throwing Tony out of a window..,
.,for massaging my feet
seemed reasonable?
No, but it could've happened,
Marsellus is very protective of you.
A protective husband is one thing,
a husband almost killing a man,..
,.for touching his wife's feet
is something else. - Did it happen?
The onlything Antwan ever touched
of mine was my hand at my wedding.
- Really? - The only ones who know
why Marsellus threw Tony..,
..out the window are Marsellus and
Tony, You men are worse than women!
Now the moment
you've all been waiting for.,.
..the world famous,
Jackrabbit Slim's twist contest.
One lucky couple will win this trophy
that Marilyn is holding.
Who will be our first contestants?
Right here.
- I want to dance,
- No, no, no!
Marsellus, my husband, your boss,..
.,told you to take me out
and do whatever I wanted.
- I want to dance, I want to win,
I want that trophy. - All right.
- So dance good.
- AIl right,
Let's hear it for our contestants,
Let`s meet our first contestants.
Young lady, what is your name?
Mrs. Mia Wallace,
- How about your fellow?
- Vincent Vega,
Let's see what you can do,
Take it away!
Is that what you call
"uncomfortable silence"?
I don`t know what you call that,
- Drinks, music!
- I'm going to take a piss.
That's a Iittle more information
than I needed, but go right ahead.
One drink and that's it,
Don't be rude, drink your drink!
But do it quickly,
Say "good night`' and go home.
This is a moral test to see whether
or not you can maintain loyalty.
Because being loyal
is very important,
You're going to go out there
and say.,.
.,`'Good night,
I've had a very Iovely evening",
You'Il walk out, get in the car,
go home, jerk off and that's all!
Mia, l`ve got to go, All right?
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Oh, Jesus! Fuck me!
Come on, girl!
We're getting out of here.
Don't die, Mia! I'm such a fucker,
Answer!
- `'PIease, hurry up!"
- "Yes.'`
'`Hold hands, you lovebirds."
Lance, answer!
"Now what do you say?"
"l give up, I'Il marry you."
Lance, the Goddamn phone is ringing!
I can hear it.
- I thought you told those assholes
never to call here this late! - Yes.
And that is exactly what l`m going
to tell this asshole now!
- Hello? - Lance, it`s Vincent.
I'm in big trouble, I'm coming over.
Hold your horses, man!
What's the problem?
- I've gotthis chick, she's ODing.
- Don`t bring her here.
- Do not be bringing some fucked up
chick to my house! - No choice.
- She's ODing?
- She's dying on me!
- Then take her to a hospital
and call a lawyer. - Negative!
This is not my problem. You fucked
her up, you fucking deal with this,
Are you talking on a cellular phone?
I don't know you, don't come here,
Prank caller, prank caller!
What the hell was that?
Have you Iost your mind? You were
talking about drugs on the phone.,.
,,and now you drive into
myfucking house! - Grab her feet.
- Don't bring this bitch in my house,
- She's Marsellus Wallace's wife,
Do you know who Wallace is? If she
croaks, l`m a fucking grease spot.
I'll tell him that you did not help,
that you let her die on your lawn,
Now come on! Help me, Pick her up,
Shit!
Lance!
It's 1 :30 in the morning,
what the fuck is going on out here?
- Who's she? - Go get the thing
with the adrenaline shot,
- What's wrong with her? - She's
ODing. - Get her out of here!
- Get the fucking shot!
- Fuck you!
- What a bitch! - Keep talking
to her, I'll go get my medical book.
- What for? - I've never had
to give an adrenaline shot.
- I don`t "trip`' with a bunch of
bubble-gummers, - Get the shot, - OK,
- l`m not stopping you, - Stop
talking to me! - Get the shot!
- Hurry up, Lance!
- I'm Iooking as fast as I can,
- What's he Iooking for?
- Some book.
- What are you looking for?
- A little black medical book,
- What? - It`s like a text book
they give to nurses,
- I never saw no medical book.
- Trust me, I have one.
- If it's so important, keep it
with the shot. - Stop bothering me!
- You'll never find anything
in this mess. - Shut up!
- I've been telling you to clean this
room for months! - Lance, come on!
- Get out of my way!
- Pig!
- Give her the shot. - AIl right.
While I do this, find her heart.
- Does it have to be exact? - Of
course, it`s a shot for her heart,
- Where the fuck is her heart?
Here? - That's it,
AII right, What I need is a big
magic marker, You got it?
- What?
- A magic marker, a felt pen!
- A fucking black magic marker!
Come on, man, - Fuck!
Okay, I think it's ready,
- All right. - Hurry up,
- Here, I'll tell you what to do.
- No, you`re going to give her
the shot. - I ain't giving itto her.
- I've never done this before,
- Me either,
You brought her here
and you're giving her the shot.
- Give her the shot,
- Here, - Give me that!
- Tell me whatto do, -You're giving
her an injection of adrenaline,,.
.,in her heart, You have to pierce
through here with a stabbing motion.
- I've got to stab her three times?
- No, just once,
You have to get through her bone and
to her heart, then press the plunger,
- Then what happens?
- I'm curious about that myself.
- Am I going to kill her? - No,
she's supposed to come out of it.
- AIl right, count to three.
- One.
Two,
Three!
If you're all right, say something,
Something!
That was fucking "tripy"!
Oh man!
Mia.
What..,
What's your thought
on how to handle this?
What's yours?
I`m of the opinion that Marsellus
doesn't need to know about this,
If Marsellus knew about this,
I'd be in as much trouble as you.
I doubt that!
I can keep a secret if you can.
Shake on it!
Mum's the word?
Cool!
If you'II excuse me, l`m going home
to have a heart attack!
Vincent.
- Do you want to hear
my `'Fox Force Five" joke? - Sure,
But I think I'm still
too petrified to laugh,
You won't laugh because it's not
funny, But I'll tell you if you want,
I can't wait!
Papa Tomato, Mamma Tomato and Baby
Tomato are walking down the street.
Baby Tomato starts Iagging behind
and Papa Tomato gets really angry,
He goes back, squishes him
and says: `'Ketchup!'`
Ketchup!
See you around.
"That funny silly dog thinks
totem pole is alive."
"He's an arctic tender foot."
`'That totem pole
has been here forever."
Butch.
- Stop watching TV for a second.
- Yeah?
You've got a social visitor,
Remember when I told you that
your daddy died in a POW camp?
This is Captain Koons,
he was in the POW camp with daddy,
Hello, little man.
I heard a bunch about you,
I was a good friend of your dad`s.
We were in that Hanoi pit of hell
together for over five years.
Hopefully you`II never have
to experience this yourself,
When two men are in a situation,.,
,.Iike me and your dad were
for as Iong as we were,.,
..you take on certain
responsibilities of the other.
If it had been me
who had not made it.,.
.,Major Coolidge would be talking
right now to my son Jim.
But the way it turned out,
l`m talking to you, Butch.
I've got something for you,
This watch was first purchased
by your great-grandfather.,.
.,during the First World War,,.
,.in a Iittle general store
in Knoxville, Tennessee.
It was made by the first company
ever to make wrist watches.
It was bought
by Private Eryne Coolidge..,
,.on the day he set sail for Paris.
Your great-grandfather wore this
watch every day he was in the war,
Then he went home
to your great-grandmother.,,
,.and put the watch
in an old coffee can,,.
..where it stayed until
your granddad, Dane Coolidge.,,
,,was called upon by his country
to go overseas and fight,
This time it was called World War Il.
Your great-grandfather gave this
watch to your granddad for good Iuck,
Unfortunately Dane was a marine.
He was killed with all the other
marines at the battle of Wake lsland.
Your granddad was facing death,
he knew it.
None of those boys had any illusions
about Ieaving that island alive.
Three days before the Japanese
took the island..,
,.he asked a gunner on an Airforce
transporter named Winocki.,.
.,a man he'd never met before,
to deliver to his infant son,,.
.,who he`d never seen in the flesh,
his gold watch.
Three days Iateryour granddad
was dead, but Winocki kept his word.
After the war was over, he went
to see your grandmother delivering.,.
,.to your infant father,
his dad's gold watch, this watch,
This watch was on your daddy's wrist
when he was shot down over Hanoi,
He was captured
and put in a prison camp,
If the gooks ever saw the watch,
it would be confiscated,..
..taken away, The way your dad saw
it, this watch was your birth right.
He`d be damned if he'd let anyone
put their greasy yellow hands on it.
So he hid it in the one place he knew
he could hide something, in his ass.
Five Iong years he wore
this watch up his ass,
Then he died of dysentery,
he gave me the watch.
I hid this uncomfortable hunk
of metal up my ass for two years.
Then after seven years
I was sent home to my family,
Now,.,
,.Iittle man,
I give the watch to you,
It`s time, Butch.
Wearing blue trousers, weighing
210 pounds, FIoyd Ray Wilson,
- Wilson is dead, - Dan, that was the
most brutal fight we've ever seen.
Coolidge ran straight out. Do you
think he knew Wilson was dead?
Yes, I could see the frenzy in
his eyes, he knew what he was doing,
- Any man would've run straight out.
-Will this tragedy effect boxing?
Atragedy Iike this can`t help
but shake the world of boxing,
It's of paramount importance, during
the sad weeks ahead, that the WBA.,,
- Marsellus,
- I swear, it's not my fault!
- How are you doing? - Great,
I neverthanked you for dinner,
- What have you got? - He booked,
His trainer doesn`t know nothing.
- I think he's as surprised as we
are. - We want to know, not think.
Take him to the kennel, sick the dogs
on him. We'll find out what he knows.
- What about the search for Butch?
- I'Il scour the earth for him!
If he goes to Indochina, I want our
man in his rice ready to shoot him!
I will take care of it.
Mister.
- Mister,
- What?
You were in that fight on the radio.
- Are you the fighter? - Whatever
gave you that idea? - No, come on!
You're him, I know you're him!
- Tell me you're him.
- Yes, I'm him.
You killed the other boxing man.
- He's dead?
- The radio said he was dead,
I'm sorry about that, FIoyd.
- What it is like? - What is
what like? - Killing a man.
Beating another man to death
with your bare hands!
- Are you a weirdo? - No, it is
a subject I have much interest in.
You are the first person I have ever
met who has killed somebody.
What does it feel like
to kill a man?
Give me one of your cigarettes
and I'Il tell you all about it,
So, "Esmarelda",,.
.,`'Villa Lobos",
- Is that Mexican? - The name
is Spanish, but I'm Colombian,
- That`s some name, honey!
- Thank you,
- What is your name?
- Butch,
Butch!
- What does it mean? - You're in
America, our names don't mean shit!
So, Esmarelda,
what is it you want to know?
- I want to know what itfeels Iike
to kill a man. - I couldn't tell you.
I didn't know he was dead
until you told me he was dead.
Now that I know, you want to know
how I feel about it?
I don't feel
the least bit bad about it,
As soon as the word got out about the
fix, the odds went through the roof,
I know, unbelievable,
Fuck him! If he was a better boxer,
he'd still be alive.
Who gives a fuck! It's over now.
Enough about the poor Mr. FIoyd,
Iet's talk about the rich Mr, Butch!
How many bookers did you Iay it on?
All eight?
How Iong to collect? So you`II have
it all by tomorrow night,
I understand, a few stragglers aside.
Scotty, that is great news,
Me and Fabienne are going to leave
in the morning.
It'Il take us a couple days
to get down to Knoxville, Okay.
You're Goddamn right!
AII right, Scotty, The next time
I see you will be in Tennessee.
$ 45,60,
Now.
Here's a little something
forthe effort,
-What do you say if someone asks who
your fare was tonight? - The truth.
Three well-dressed,
slightly toasted Mexicans,
- Bon soir, Esmarelda.
- Buenas noches, Butch.
- Keep the Iight off,
- Is that better? - Yes.
- Hard day at the office?
- Pretty hard, I got in a fight!
Poor baby!
Can we make spoons?
I was thinking about taking a shower,
I'm stinking like a dog,
- I Iike the wayyou stink,
- Let me take this jacket off.
I was Iooking at myself in
the mirror, I wish I had a pot.
- You Iooked in the mirror and you
wished you had some pot? - A pot,
A potbelly, potbellies are sexy.
Well, you should be happy,
because you have one.
Shut up, fatso!
I don't have a pot.
I have a bit of a tummy, Iike Madonna
when she did `'Lucky Star",
- Is there a big difference between
a potbelly and a tummy? - It's huge,
- Would you Iike it
if I had a potbelly? - No.
Potbellies make a man look Iike
an oaf or Iike a gorilla.
But on a woman a potbelly is sexy.
The rest of you is normal, your face,
your Iegs, your hips, your ass,..
,.butwith a big
perfectly round potbelly.
If I had one I'd wear a T-shirt two
sizes too small to accentuate it,
- Men find that attractive? - l
don't give a damn what they think!
What we find pleasing to the eyes
and to the touch is seldom the same,
- If you had a potbelly, I'd punch
you in it, -You'd punch it? - Yes.
I`d smother you, I'd drop it on your
face until you couldn`t breathe!
- You`d do that?
- Yes.
- Did you get everything? - Yes.
- Good job, sugarpop.
- Did everything go as planned?
- You didn't listen to the,., Ouch!
- You didn't Iisten to the radio?
- I never Iisten to your fights,
- Were you the winner?
- I won all right.
- Are you still retiring?
- I sure am.
- So it all worked out in the finish.
- We're not at the finish yet, baby,
We're in a lot of danger, aren't we?
If they find us,
they'll kill us, won't they?
But they won't find us, will they?
Do you still want me to go with you?
I don`t want to be a burden, it`s.,.
Say it,
Fabienne, I want you to be with me,
- Forever?
- Forever and ever,
- Do you Iove me?
- Very much.
- Butch.,,
- Yes?
Will you give me oral pleasure?
Will you kiss it?
You first.
- Okay,
Butch, my Iove, the adventure begins.
- I think I cracked a rib.
- Giving me oral pleasure?
- No, retard, in the fight.
- Don`t call me "retard".
- My name is Fabienne!
- Stop it,
- Shut up, I hate that
Mongoloid voice, - Okay, sorry.
I take it back.
Will you hand me a dry towel,
my beautiful tulip?
I like being called a tulip, "Tulip"
is much better than '`Mongoloid".
I called you "retard",
not "Mongoloid" and I took it back.
- Butch,
- Yes, Iemon pie!
- Where are we going to go? - I'm
not sure yet, wherever you want,
I'm going to get
a lot of money from this,
But we can't live like hogs
in the fat house forever.
I was thinking that we could go
some place in the South Pacific.
The money we'Il have is going
to carry us a long way down there,
- We could live in Bora Bora.
- You bet.
If you don`t dig it after a while,
we can go to Tahiti or Mexico,
- I do not speak Spanish,
- Mexican is easy,
- '`Donde està Ia zapateria?'`
- What does that mean?
- "Where is the shoe store?"
- "Donde està..,`' - Spit,
- '`Donde està Ia zapateria?'`
- Excellent pronunciation!
You'Il be my little
mamasita in no time!
"Qué hora es?`'
- "Qué hora es?'`
- It`s time for bed!
Sweet dreams, jelly bean.
Butch.
Never mind.
You startled me.
Did you have a bad dream?
- What is this? - A motorcycle
movie, I don't know the name,
- Are you watching it?
- In a way!
It's a little early in the morning
for explosions!
- What was it about? - You're
the one who was watching it!
- Silly, what was your dream about?
- I don`t know, I don't remember,
- I never remember my dreams, - Look
at the grumpy man in the morning!
- Get up and we`II have breakfast,
- One more kiss.
- Satisfied?
- Yes.
Get up, lazybones!
- What time is it?
- AImost 9.
- What time does our train arrive?
- At 11:00,
- You know what l`m having
for breakfast? - What?
A big plate of blueberry pancakes
with maple syrup,.,
,.eggs over easy and five sausages,
- Anything to drink with that?
- That looks nice!
To drink a tall glass of orange juice
and a black cup of coffee,
After that l'II have a slice of pie.
- Pie for breakfast? - Anytime
of day is a good time for pie,
BIueberry pie and on top
a thin slice of cheese,
Where`s my watch?
- It's there,
- No, it's not.
- Have you Iooked? - Yes! What
the fuck do you think I'm doing?
- Are you sure you got it?
- Yes, bedside table drawer.
- And the Iittle kangaroo?
- Yes.
Well, it's not here now!
- It should be, - Yes, but it's not!
Where the fuck is it?
Fabienne, that was
my father's fucking watch,
Do you know what he had to go through
to get me that watch? A Iot!
You could have set
all this other shit on fire.
But I specifically reminded you
not to forget the watch!
- Did you get it?
- I believe so.
What the fuck does that mean?
You either did or you didn't!
Then I did.
- Are you sure?
- No,
Fuck! Fuck! Motherfucker!
Do you know how fucking stupid
you fucking are?
It's not your fault,
If you Ieft it at the apartment.,,
If you left it at the apartment,
it's not your fault,
I had you bring a bunch of stuff.
I reminded you about it,..
.,but I didn't illustrate
how personal the watch was to me.
If all I gave a fuck about
was the watch, I should've told you,
You're not a mind reader, are you?
- I'm sorry, - Don't be, I just
can`t have breakfast with you.
Why is that?
I've got to go back to my apartment
and get my watch.
-Won`t the gangsters be looking
for you there? - I'Il find out,
If they are and I don't think
I can handle it, I'Il split,
I saw your watch,
I thought I brought it.
Here`s some money,
have a nice breakfast,
I'Il be back before you can say
"blueberry pie'`.
BIueberry pie!
Maybe not that fast.
But pretty fast, okay?
- Bye.
Of all the fucking things,
she forgets my father`s watch!
I specifically reminded her:
"Bedside table, on the kangaroo`'!
`'Don`t forget my father's watch.'`
Looking good, Butch!
That's how you're going to beat them.
They keep underestimating you.
You motherfucker!
- Do you think he's dead?
- He's dead.
I`ll be glad to go to court,
that drunk hityou and then that car.
- Who?
- Him.
I'Il be damned!
- Can I help you with something?
- Shut the fuck up!
Hey, wait a minute!
What the fuck are you up to?
Come here, motherfucker!
Do you feel that sting?
That`s pride fucking with you!
You've got to fight
through that shit!
- You'd better kill me,
- Yeah, somebody's gonna get killed,
- Hold it rightthere!
- This ain't none of your business!
- I'm making it my business, Toss
the weapon, - You don't understand.
Toss the weapon!
Take your foot off the nigger
and put your hand behind your head.
- Approach the counter.
- This scum is trying to kill me!
Shut up, keep coming. Come on!
Zed, it's Maynard. The spider
just caught a couple flies!
Nobody kills anybody in my place
of business except me or Zed.
That's Zed.
- You said you'd wait for me,
- I did,
- How come they're all beat up?
- They did that to each other,
They came in fighting.
This one here
was going to shoot that one,
You were gonna shoot him, boy?
Is Grace all right out front?
- Yeah, Today's not Tuesday,
- No, it's Thursday,
She ought to be fine.
Bring out the gimp,
I think the gimp is sleeping,
I guess you'Il have to go
wake him up, won't you?
Get up.
Get down.
Which one of them
do you want to do first?
I ain't so sure yet,
Eeny, meany, miny, mo,
Catch a nigger by the toe,
If he hollers, let go!
Eeny, meany, miny, mo!
My mother said pick a perfect one.,,
,.and you are.,.
,.it!
I guess that means you, big boy!
- Do you wantto do it in here?
- No, in Russell's old room,
That sounds good to me,
Keep an eye on this one,
You want that gun, Don't you, Zed?
Huh?
Go ahead and pick it up,
Go ahead, pick it up.
Come on, Zed!
I wantyou to pick it up,
Step aside, Butch,
You okay?
No, man,
I'm pretty fucking far from okay.
What now?
What now,,.
I'Il tell you: I'm going to call a
couple hard, pipe-hitting niggers.,.
.,to go to work on the homes here.,.
..with a pair of pliers
and a blowtorch.
You hear me talking,
hillbilly boy?
I ain`t through with you,
I'm gonna get medieval on your ass!
I meant,
what now between me and you?
Oh, thatwhat now!
I'Il tell you what's now
between me and you,
There is no me and you,
Not no more.
So, are we cool?
Yeah, we're cool.
Two things.
Don't tell nobody about this,
This shit is between me, you.,.
,.and mister, soon to be Iiving the
rest of his Iife in agonizing pain,.,
,.rapist!
It ain`t nobody else's business,
Two: you Ieave town tonight,
right now,.,
.,and when you're gone,
you stay gone or you'Il be gone!
You lost all your LA privileges,
Deal?
Deal.
Get your ass out of here,
Oh, shit!
Fabienne!
Fabienne, get your shit.
We've got to go right now.
- And our bags? - Fuck the bags!
Let's split or we'll miss the train,
- Come on, I'Il be downstairs.
- Is everything well? - Come on!
Are we in danger?
Come on, honey!
- Where did you get this motorcycle?
- It`s a "chopper", Let's go.
- What happened to my Honda?
- l`m sorry, I had to crash it.
Come on now, please!
- Are you hurt? - I might've broken
my nose, no biggie, Hop on,
Baby, we`ve got to hit
the fucking road. Get on!
I'm sorry, come here,
- l`m sorry, - You were gone so long,
I started to think dreadful thoughts,
- I'm sorry. How was your breakfast?
- It was good,
- Did you get the pancakes? - They
didn't have any, I got buttermilk,
- Are you okay? - This has been
the single weirdest day in my Iife.
I`ll tell you all about it.
Get on, we've got to go.
- Whose motorcycle is this?
- It's a chopper.
- Whose chopper is this? - Zed`s.
- Who's Zed? - Zed's dead,
- Brett, you tried to fuck him!
- No!
Marsellus Wallace don't like to be
fucked by nobody except Mrs. Wallace.
- God, I don`t want to die! - Do you
read the Bible, Brett? - Yes.
There`s this passage I memorized,
it fits the occasion,
Ezekiel: 25-17.
"The path of the righteous man,,."
",.is beset on all sides
by the inequities of the selfish.,."
`'..and the tyranny of evil men."
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity and good will.,,"
'`.,shepherds the weak
through the Valley of Darkness,`'
'`For he is truly his brother`s keeper
and the finder of Iost children."
"l will strike down upon thee
with great vengeance,.."
".,and furious anger
those who attempt to destroy.,."
'`.,my brothers,`'
"And you will know
my name is the Lord,.,"
'`..when I lay my vengeance
upon thee!"
I'm fucked!
- I'm fucked! I'm fucked!
- Is he a friend of yours?
- Goddamn!
- Vincent, Marvin,
- Tell him to shut up.
- l`m fucked! - Marvin!
Knock it off.
Die, you motherfuckers!
Why the fuck didn't you tell us
somebody was in the bathroom?
Did you forget somebody was in there
with a "hand cannon"?
Did you see the size of that gun?
It was bigger than him.
- We should be dead.
- We were Iucky.
No, that wasn't luck,
- Yeah, maybe.
- This was divine intervention.
Do you know what
`'divine intervention" is?
It means that God came down from
heaven and stopped the bullets?
Exactly, Vincent. God stopped
these motherfucking bullets!
- It's time for us to Ieave,
- Don't blow this shit off!
- What happened here was a miracle!
- This shit happens!
- This shit doesn't just happen, - Do
you want to continue in the car.,.
..or in a jailhouse with the cops?
- We should be dead!
What happened here was a miracle
and I want you to acknowledge it!
All right, it was a miracle.
Can we go now?
Let's go, nigger, come on!
Once I saw a show with this cop on
who was talking about a gunfight,.,
,.he had in the hallwaywith
this guy. He unloaded on this guy,
Nothing happened, he didn't hit
nothing, It was just him and the guy,
You know, it's freaky,
but it happens,
Go ahead and play blind man ifyou
want, but my eyes are wide open.
- What's that mean? - That`s it
for me, consider me retired.
- Jesus Christ.,.
- Don't blaspheme!
- Are you freaking out? - Today I'm
telling Marsellus that I'm through.
- Tell him why too,
- I will.
- I bet he'Il laugh his ass off.
- I don't give a damn if he does!
- Marvin, what do you make of this?
- I don't even have an opinion.
Do you think that God came down
and stopped the bullets?
- What the fuck happened?
Oh, shit! - Ah, man!
- I shot Marvin in the face, -Why'd
you do that? - It was an accident.
- I've never seen this kind of shit!
-You probably went over a bump,
- I didn't hit no bump! - I didn't
mean to shoot him, the gun went off,
-We're in a city in broad daylight,
- I can't believe it. - Believe it!
- We've got to getthis car off the
road. - Take it to a friendly place,
- Marsellus ain`t got no friends
in the Valley. - This ain't my town!
- Shit! - What are you doing? - I'm
calling my partner in Toluca Lake.
It's over the hill, If Jimmie ain't
home, I don't know what we'Il do.
I ain`t got no other partners in
this area. Jimmie! Hi, it's Jules.
Me and my homeboy are in deep shit,
We need your garage for a few hours.
We have to be delicate with Jimmie.
One remark and he`ll kick us out,
- If he does, what do we do? - We
ain`t going until we make some calls,
- I don'ttell a friend what's what.
- Tell him notto be abusive!
- He freaked out when he saw Marvin,
- Put yourself in his position.
He just woke up,
he wasn't expecting this shit.
- He`s doing us a favor. - If I have
to take shit, he can stick his favor.
- What are you doing? - I'm drying
my hands. - You have to wash them.
- I did. - I saw you get them wet.
- This shit is hard to get off!
I used the same soap you did, but the
towel didn`t look Iike a maxi-pad!
What if he sees this? Shit Iike this
will bring the situation to a head!
I ain'tthreatening you,
you know I respect you,..
.,but don't put me in this position,
AIl right? - AIl right, fine.
Ask me nice Iike that, no problem.
Just go handle your friend.
Damn! This is serious gourmet shit!
We would've been satisfied
with some Taster's Choice.
- What flavor is this?
- Knock it off, Jules!
- What? - I don`t need you
to tell me how good my coffee is.
I buy it, I know it's good. I buy the
expensive stuff, I want to taste it.
But this coffee ain't on my mind now,
it's the dead nigger in my garage,
- Jimmie, don't worry about it.
- Is there a sign outside my house.,.
..that says `'dead nigger storage'`?
- Jimmie, you know,,.
Is there a sign that says
"dead nigger storage`'?
- No,
- Right, because there ain't one.
- Storing dead niggers ain't
my business! - We're not going to..,
If Bonnie comes home and finds a dead
body here, I'm going to get divorced,
No trial separation, no, I'm going
to get divorced and I don't want to!
I want to help you,
but I don'twant to Iose my wife.
- Jimmie, she ain`t going to Ieave
you, - Don't Jimmie me, Jules!
Nothing you can say will make me
forget that I Iove my wife.
She comes home from work
in about an hour and a half.
She worked the graveyard shift
at the hospital.
If you've got to make some phone
calls, do it. Then get out.,.
.,before she gets here.
- We don't want to fuck your shit up,
- l'II just call my people for help,
- You'Il fuck my shit up big time.,.
..if Bonnie comes home.
Just go make your calls.
Say she comes home.
What do you think she'll do?
Don't tell me she'II freak,
That ain't no kind of answer,
How much? A Iot or a Iittle?
You've got to appreciate what
an explosive element Bonnie is.
If she comes home and finds a bunch
of gangsters doing gangster shit..,
,,there ain't no telling
what she'Il do,
I grasp that,
I'm contemplating the "ifs".
I don't want to hear no "ifs'`. I want
to hear: '`You ain't got no problem."
"I'm on the motherfucker, Go chill
them out and wait for the cavalry."
You ain't got no problem.
I'm on the motherfucker,
Go chill them out
and wait forthe Wolf,
- You're sending the Wolf? - Do you
feel better? - Yes, head negro!
That's all you had to say.
Is she the hysterical type?
When is she due?
Give me the names again.
Jules.
Vincent.
Jimmie, Bonnie.
I`ll be there in ten.
- You're Jimmie, This is your house?
- Yes, - I'm Wolf, I solve problems.
- Good. We've got one, - So I heard.
May I come in? - PIease do,
You must be Jules and you`re Vincent,
Let's get down to business,
- If I was informed correctly,
the clock is ticking. - 100%,
Your wife comes home at 9:30 a,m.
- If she comes home and finds us
here, she won't appreciate it, - No,
That gives us 40 minutes,
Do what I say when I say to do it,
There's a corpse in a car minus
a head in a garage, Take me to it.
Jimmie, I smelled some coffee
back there. Will you make me a cup?
Sure,
- How do you take it?
- Lots of cream, Iots of sugar.
How's the car? Does it stall, smoke,
make noise, is there gas, anything?
- The car is cool, - Positive?
I don't want to get on the road,..
,.and find out that the brake Iights
don`t work. - It's tip-top. - Good.
Let's go back to the kitchen.
- Here, Mr. Wolf,
- Thank you, Jimmie,
You two take the body
and stick it in the trunk.
This is a domesticated house. This
makes me think you've got cleaners,
- Yes, under the sink. - You two
have to clean the inside of the car.
I'm talking fast.
Go into the back seat and scoop up
all the pieces of brain and skull.
Wipe down the upholstery,
but don't overdo it,
What you need to take care of
are the really messy parts,
The pools of blood that have
collected, soak them up.
Jimmie, I need blankets,
quilts, bedspreads,
The thicker and darker, the better,
No whites,
We're going to Iine the front
and back seats and the floorboards.
If a cop stops us and sticks
his snout in the car, it won'twork,
But at a glance the car will appear
to be normal, Boys, get to work!
- A "please'` would be nice,
- Come again?
- I'm not here to say "please`'.
I'm here to tell you what to do.
If self-preservation is an instinct
you possess, do it quick.
I`m here to help, If my help's not
appreciated, Iots of Iuck, gentlemen.
Your help is definitely appreciated.
I don't mean disrespect. I just don't
Iike people barking orders at me,
Time is a factor.
I think fast and I talk fast.
I need you to act fast
if you want to get out of this,
Pretty-please,
clean the fucking car!
Don't look at me Iike that.
I can feel your look,
It's a 1974 Chevy,
Green.
Nothing, except the mess inside.
About twenty minutes.
Nobody who will be missed.
You`re a good man, Joe. Thanks,
- How are we coming?
- Good. I`ve got it all here,
-You've got to understand,.,
- Call me Winston.
You've got to understand something,
This is our best Iinen here,
It was a wedding present from
my Uncle Conrad and Aunt Jinny.
- They're not with us anymore and..,
- Let me ask you a question.
- If you don't mind,
- No!
- Were your Uncle Conrad
and Aunt Jinny millionaires? - No.
Well, your Uncle Marsellus is,
I`m positive that if Uncle Conrad
and Aunt Jinny were here,.,
.,they would furnish you
with a whole bedroom set,
Your Uncle Marsellus
is more than happy to do this.
I like oak myself.
That's what I have in my bedroom,
How about you, Jimmie?
Are you an oak man?
Oak is nice.
I'Il never forgive your ass for this.
This is fucked up repugnant shit!
Haven't you heard of the philosophy
that once a man admits he's wrong,.,
,,he is forgiven for all wrong
doings. - Get out of my face!
I have to pick up pieces of skull
because ofyour dumb ass!
I've got a threshold
for the abuse that I will take!
Right now l`m a race car in the red
and it's dangerous to be in the red!
- I could blow.
- Really? - Yeah!
Well I'm a mushroom cloud laying
motherfucker, motherfucker!
Every time myfingers touch brain,
I'm "The Guns of the Navarone"!
What the fuck am I doing?
You should be on brain detail!
I'm washing the windows!
Fine job, gentlemen.
We'Il make it out ofthis yet.
I can't believe
this is the same car!
Let`s not start
sucking each other's dicks yet,
Phase one is complete. Let's move on
to phase two, clean you two!
- Strip! - All the way?
- To your bare ass!
Quickly, gentlemen. We`ve got 15
minutes before Jimmie's wife comes.
- This morning air is chilly.
- Is this absolutely necessary?
You know what you look like? Two
guys who just blew off a man's head,
Stripping off
those bloody rags is necessary.
- Toss them in the garbage bag!
- Don't Ieave this shit out front!
Don't worry, we're taking it with us.
Jim, the soap!
I'm sure you've been to the county
jail, Here it comes!
- It's fucking cold!
- Better you than me, gentlemen.
- Don't be afraid of the soap,
- Getthem up there a Iittle.
- Vincent's hair,
- Goddamn it.
Towels!
They're dry,
toss them their clothes!
Perfect!
We couldn't have planned this better,
You guys Iook Iike.,,
What do they Iook like, Jimmie?
Dorks!
They look Iike a couple of dorks!
- They're your clothes! - Come on
or we'Il laugh ourway into prison,
We're going to a place called
'`Monster Joe's Truck and Tow",
Monster Joe and his daughter
were sympathetic to our dilemma.
The place is North Hollywood.
We`ll be going up Hollywood Way,
I'Il drive the tainted car.
Jules, you'll ride with me.
Vincent, you'II follow in my car,
If we come across any kind of Iaw,
nobody does a fucking thing.,.
,,till I do something,
What did I say? - Don't do shit.
- Unless what? - Unless you do it
first, - Spoken Iike a true prodigy.
Can you keep your spurs
from jingling and jangling?
I don't know why the gun went off.
I'm cool.
I drive fast, So, keep up,
If you wreck my car, Monster Joe
will dispose of two bodies!
Get out of my way, Rex!
- We cool?
- Like it never happened!
This is Raquel,
- Some day all this will be hers!
- What`s with the outfits?
Are you guys
going to a volleyball game?
I`m going to breakfast. I`ll drop
you off. Where do you live?
- Redondo. - Englewood,
- Shh! In your future I see..,
..a cab ride!
Move out of the sticks, fellows!
- Say good night, Raquel.
- "Good night, Raquel"!
- See you guys around!
Stay out of trouble. - Mr. Wolf,
- It was a pleasure watching
you work. - Thank you very much,
Call me Winston,
You see that, young Iady?
- Respect for one's elder shows
character, - I have character!
You are a character
doesn't mean that you have character,
- Want to share a cab? - Do you feel
Iike having breakfast with me?
Cool,
I thought he'd be European,
- He's about as European
as English Bob, - I know that now,
-Was he cool or what? - Thank you,
- Totally cool, in control!
He didn't even get pissed
when you were fucking with him,
- Want some bacon?
- I don't eat pork.
- Are you Jewish? - No.
I just don't dig swine, - Why not?
- Pigs are filthy animals,
- But bacon tastes good.
A sewer rat may taste Iike
pumpkin pie, but I'd never know,.,
.,because I wouldn`t eat it!
Pigs sleep and root in shit,
- I don't eat animals that don`t
disregard their feces, - And dogs?
- I don't eat dog either, - Do you
consider a dog a filthy animal?
I wouldn't call it filthy,
but they're definitely dirty.
But a dog's got personality.
If a pig had a better personality,
he'd cease to be a filthy animal,
He'd have to be one charming
motherfucking pig!
Ten times more charming
than the one on Green Acres.
Good, you're starting to Iighten up!
You were so serious!
- I was thinking, - About what?
- The miracle we witnessed,
I witnessed a freak occurrence,
What is a miracle?
- An act of God!
- What`s an act of God?
When God makes
the impossible possible.
But this morning doesn't qualify,
You're judging this the wrong way.
It could be that God
stopped the bullets,.,
,.or changed Coke to Pepsi.
You don't judge this shit
based on merit.
It's insignificant if what
we experienced was a miracle,
I felt the touch of God!
God got involved.
- But why? - I don't know why,
but I can`t go back to sleep.
Are you serious? You're really
thinking about quitting?
The life? Most definitely!
Fuck! What are you going to do?
That's what I've been contemplating,
I`m going to deliver
this case to Marsellus,
- Then I'm going to walk the earth.
- What do you mean?
Like Cane in '`Kung Fu",
Meet people, get in adventures.
- How Iong do you intend to do this?
- Till God puts me where he wants me,
- What if he don't do that?
- Then l`II walk forever,
- You've decided to be a bum.
- I'll just be Jules,
No, you'Il be a bum Iike all those
pieces of shit who beg for change.,.
.,sleep in garbage bins
and eat what I throw away,
Without a job or a residence.,,
.,you'Il be a fucking bum!
This is where you and I differ.
Garçon! Coffee!
What happened this morning
is peculiar.
But water into wine,.,
- All shapes and sizes.
- Don`t talk to me that way.
If my answers frighten you,
cease asking scary questions!
I'm going to take a shit.
Did you make this decision
when you were eating that muffin?
Yeah, I was eating my muffin
and drinking my coffee.,.
.,when I had what alcoholics refer to
as '`a moment of clarity`'.
Fuck! To be continued.
- I Iove you.
- Keep cool, this is a robbery!
- If any of you pricks move.,,
.,I'Il execute every one
of you motherfuckers!
You got that?
Keep quiet over there. Get down!
You, take your dames over
to that booth on the count of ten!
- Come out of the kitchen!
- Three, four, five, six,.,
What the fuck are you doing?
Throw those bags,
Wake up!
Move!
Get on the fucking floor!
- Grandpa, get down!
- I'm the manager here,
- There`s no problem.
- Are you going to give me problems?
- We've got a hero here.
- Just execute him!
I am not a hero.
I'm just a coffee shop manager,
- The restaurant is ours!
- Just take whatever you want.
Talk to the customers,
tell them to be fucking cool.
- Everything will be over,
You understand? - Yes.
Listen everybody!
Be calm.
Cooperate and this
will all be over in a minute,
Get the fuck down!
I'm going to come around
and collect yourwallets,
Don`t talk, justthrow them
in the bag. Are we clear?
Wallets out.
Fuck this, In the bag.
Put it in the fucking bag!
What are you waiting for?
In the bag,
Tips, in the bag.
Is that a cellular phone?
- Yes.
- In the fucking bag.
That's it. Now get on the floor.
In the bag,
- What's in the case?
- My boss' dirty Iaundry.
- You have to do it? That`s a shit
job. - I was thinking the same thing.
- Open it.
- I can`t do that.
- I didn't hear you,
- Yes, you did.
- What's going on?
- We've got a vigilante in our midst.
- Shoot him in the face! - I've
already had a gun pointed at me,
Take yourfucking hand off that case,
Stop causing problems,
you'll get us all killed,
Shutthe fuck up, fat man!
Be cool, honey bunny, No problem,
l`ve got it under control.
Now I'm gonna count to three.
If you don't open that case,
I'm gonna unload in your face.
Are we clear?
One.,.
,.two.,.
.,three,
- Okay, you win. It's yours,
Open it,
What is it?
- Is that what I think it is?
- Yes.
- It`s beautiful.
- What is it?
You let him go!
- Tell her to be cool!
- I'll kill you! - Say be cool!
- Tell that bitch to be cool!
- Let him go, I'll kill you!
- Tell that bitch to chill!
- Be cool! - Chill that bitch out!
- Tell her it's going to be
all right. - It`s gonna be all right,
- Tell her to chill. - Chill out.
- Tell me her name, - Jolanda,
- Jolanda, we're not going to do
anything stupid. - Don't hurt him.
Nobody is going to hurt anybody.
We`re all going to be Iike Fonzie,
- Jolanda, what's Fonzie Iike?
- He's cool.
Correct! And that's what
we're gonna be, We're gonna be cool.
Now I'm gonna count to three.
When I count three,
I wantyou to let go of your gun.,.
.,put your palms flat on the table
and sit your ass down,
When you do it, do it cool,
Are you ready?
One, two.,.
.,three,
- Now you let him go!
- I thought you were gonna be cool,
When you yell at me,
it makes me nervous.
When I get nervous, I get scared
and somebody could get shot.
If you hurt him, you die.
Well, that seems to be the situation.
But I don't want that,
and you don't want that,.,
,,and Ringo doesn`t want that,
So, Iet's see what we can do.
Now, here's the situation.
Normally your asses would be dead
as fucking fried chicken.
But I'm in a transitional period
and I want to help you,
But I can't give you this case
because it don't belong to me.
Besides, l`ve been through
too much shit over this case,..
..to hand it over to your dumb ass,
Vincent!
Be cool, Jolanda, it`s cool,
We're still just talking!
Come on, Point the gun at me.
Point the gun at me! There you go,
Vincent, just hang back.
Don't do a Goddamn thing.
Tell her it's still cool.
- It`s still cool, honey bunny. - How
are we doing? - I've got to pee.
- I want to go home.
- I'm proud of you.
And Ringo's proud of you,
Tell her you're proud of her.
- I'm proud of you.
- I Iove you.
- I Iove you too,
- Now, go in that bag,.,
,,and find my wallet,
- Which one is it? - The one
that says "bad motherfucker",
That's it.
Open it up, take outthe money,
Count it.
How much is there?
- About 1,500 dollars,
- Take it, It's yours,
With the rest of those wallets and
the register this is a good score,
If you give him 1,500 dollars,
I'Il shoot him.
No! Jolanda, he ain't gonna do
a thing. Shutthe fuck up, Vincent!
- Shut up!
- Jolanda, stay with me.
I ain't giving it to him, Vincent.
I`m buying something.
- Want to know what I'm buying,
Ringo? - What? - Your life.
I'm giving it to you so I don't have
to kill you, Do you read the Bible?
- No,
- There's this passage I memorized.
Ezekiel: 25-17.
"The path of the righteous man
is beset by the inequities.,,`'
`',.of the selfish
and the tyranny of evil men."
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity shepherds the weak,.."
`',.through the Valley of Darkness."
'`For he is truly his brother`s keeper
and the finder of Iost children."
"l will strike down
with great vengeance,.."
'`..those who attempt
to destroy my brothers."
"You will know I am the Lord,.,"
",.when I Iay my vengeance upon you,`'
I`ve been saying that shit for years.
If you heard it, that meant your ass,
I never gave much thought
to what it meant,
I thought it was some shit to say
before I popped a cap in a guy's ass,
But this morning I thought twice,
Maybe it means that you`re the evil
man and I'm the righteous man,
This gun is the shepherd protecting
my ass in the valley of darkness.
Or it could mean that you're the
righteous man and I'm the shepherd,
It's the world
that's evil and selfish,
I'd like that,
but that shit ain't the truth.
The truth is that you're the weak,.,
.,and I am the tyranny of evil men,
But I'm trying, Ringo. I'm trying
real hard to be the shepherd,
Go.
- I think we should be Ieaving now.
- That`s probably a good idea,