Forget it. It's too risky.
I'm through doing that shit.
You always say that.
The same thing every time.
"I'm through, never
again, too dangerous."
I know that's what I always say.
I'm always right too.
You forget about it in a day or two.
The days of me forgetting are over.
The days of me
remembering have just begun.
You know, when you go on
like this, what you sound like?
I sound like a sensible fuckin' man.
You sound like a duck.
Quack, quack, quack. Take heart, 'cause
you're never gonna have to hear it again.
Since I'm never gonna do it again,
you're never gonna have to hear me quack.
After tonight? Correct.
I got all tonight to quack.
Can I get anyone more coffee? Oh, yes!
Thank you. You're welcome.
I mean, the way it is now,
you're takin' the same risk
as when you rob a bank.
Takin' more of a risk. Banks are easier.
Federal banks ain't supposed to
stop you in any way during a robbery.
They're insured.
Why should they give a fuck?
I don't even need a
gun in a federal bank.
Heard about this one bloke, he
walks into a bank with a portable phone.
He gives the phone to a teller.
The bloke on the other end says,
"We got this guy's little girl.
If you don't
give him all your money,
we're gonna kill her."
Did it work?
Fuckin' right it worked.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Knucklehead walks into
a bank with a telephone,
not a pistol, not a
shotgun, a fuckin' phone.
Cleans the place out. They don't lift a
fuckin' finger.
Did they hurt the little girl?
There probably never was a little girl.
The point of the
story isn't a little girl.
The point of the story is they
robbed a bank with a telephone.
-You want to rob banks?
-I'm not saying I wanna rob banks.
I'm illustrating if we did, it'd be
easier than what we've been doing.
No more liquor stores?
What've we been talkin' about?
Yeah, no more liquor stores.
Besides, it ain't the
giggle it used to be.
There's too many
foreigners own liquor stores.
Vietnamese, Koreans, don't
even speak fuckin' English.
You tell 'em empty out the register,
they don't know what you're talkin' about.
They make it too personal.
We keep on, one of
these gook fuckers gonna
make us kill him.
I'm not gonna kill anybody.
I don't want to either.
But they'll probably
put us in a situation
where it's us or them.
And if it's not the gooks,
it's these old fuckin' Jews who've owned
the store for 15 fucking generations.
You got Grandpa Irving sitting behind the
counter with a fucking
Magnum in his hand.
Try walkin' into one of those
places with nothing but a phone.
See how far that gets you. Forget it.
We're out of it.
Well, what then, day jobs?
Not in this life. What then?
Garçon, coffee!
This place.
"Garçon" means boy.
This place? A coffee shop?
What's wrong with that?
Nobody ever robs restaurants. Why not?
Bars, liquor stores,
gas stations; you get your head
blown off stickin' up one of them.
Restaurants, on the other hand,
you catch with their pants down.
They're not expectin' to get robbed.
Not as expectin' anyway.
I bet you could cut down on the
hero factor in a place like this. Correct.
Same as banks, these places are insured.
Manager. He don't give a fuck.
They're just trying to get you out
before you start pluggin' the diners.
Waitresses. Fuckin' forget it. No way
they're takin' a bullet for the register.
Busboys.
Some wetback gettin' paid $1.50 an hour…
Really give a fuck you're
stealin' from the owner?
Customers sittin' there with food in their
mouths, they don't know what's goin' on.
One minute, they're
havin' a Denver omelet, the
next, someone is
stickin' a gun in their face.
See, I got the idea the last liquor
store we stuck up, remember?
-All the customers kept comin' in.
-Yeah.
You got the idea of takin' their wallets.
Now, that was a good idea.
Thank you.
Made more from the wallets
than we did from the register.
Yes, we did.
A lot of people come to restaurants.
-A lot of wallets.
-Pretty smart, huh?
Pretty smart.
I'm ready. Let's do it.
Right now, right here.
Come on. All right.
Same as last time, remember?
You're crowd control.
I'll handle the employees.
I love you, pumpkin.
I love you, honey bunny.
Everybody be cool! This is a robbery!
Any of you fucking pricks move,
and I'll execute every
motherfuckin' last one of you.
["MISIRLOU"]
[RADIO DIAL TUNING]
["JUNGLE BOOGIE"]
♪ Jungle boogie
get down with the boogie ♪
♪ Jungle boogie, get it on ♪
♪ Jungle boogie
get down with the boogie ♪
♪ Jungle boogie, get it on ♪
♪ Jungle boogie, get up with the boogie ♪
♪ Jungle boogie
get up with the get down ♪
♪ Jungle boogie, get down and boogie ♪
♪ Jungle boogie, shake it around ♪
Okay, so tell me again about the hash
bars. Okay, what you want to know?
Hash is legal there, right?
Yeah, it's legal, but it ain't 100% legal.
You just can't walk into a restaurant,
roll a joint and start puffin' away.
I mean, they want you to smoke in
your home or certain designated places.
Those are hash bars? Yeah.
It breaks down like this.
It's legal to buy it.
It's legal to own it.
And if you're the proprietor of
a hash bar, it's legal to sell it.
It's illegal to carry it, but-but that
doesn't matter, 'cause get a load of this.
If you get stopped by a cop in Amsterdam,
it's illegal for them to search you.
I mean, that's a right the cops in
Amsterdam don't have. Oh, man! I'm goin'.
That's all there is to it.
I'm fuckin' goin'.
I know, baby. You'd dig it the most.
But you know what the funniest
thing about Europe is? What?
It's the little differences.
I mean, they got
the same shit over
there that they got here,
but it's just there,
it's a little different.
Example.
You can walk into a movie theater
in Amsterdam and buy a beer.
And I don't mean just like no paper cup.
I'm talkin' about a glass of beer.
And in Paris, you can buy a beer in
McDonald's. You know what they call…
A Quarter Pounder with Cheese in Paris?
They don't call it a Quarter
Pounder with Cheese?
They got the metric system. They wouldn't
know what the fuck a quarter-pounder is.
-What do they call it?
-They call it a Royale with Cheese.
Royale with Cheese. That's right.
What do they call a Big Mac?
Big Mac's a Big Mac,
but they call it Le Big Mac.
[IMITATING FRENCH ACCENT] Le Big Mac.
[LAUGHS]
What do they call a Whopper? I don't know.
I didn't go into Burger King.
You know what they put on french
fries in Holland instead of ketchup? What?
Mayonnaise. [CHUCKLES] Goddamn!
I seen 'em do it, man.
They fuckin' drown 'em in that shit. Yuck.
We should have shotguns
for this kind of deal.
How many up there? Three or four.
That's countin' our guy? Not sure.
So that means that it could be up
to five guys up there? It's possible.
We should have fuckin' shotguns.
What's her name? Mia.
Mia. How did Marsellus and her meet?
I don't know.
However people meet people.
She used to be a actress.
Oh, really?
She do anything I'd have seen?
I think her biggest deal was she
starred in a pilot. Pilot? What's a pilot?
Well, you know the shows on TV?
I don't watch TV.
Yeah, but you are aware that
there is an invention called television,
and on this invention they
show shows, right? Yeah.
The way they pick TV shows is they
make one show. That show's called a pilot.
Then they show that one show
to the people who pick shows…
And on the strength of that one show,
they decide if they wanna make more shows.
Some get chosen and become television
programs. Some don't, become nothin'.
She starred in one of the
ones that became nothing.
You remember Antwan Rockamora?
Half-black, half-Samoan.
Used to call him "Tony Rocky Horror."
Yeah, maybe. Fat, right? I wouldn't
go so far as to call the brother fat.
He got a weight problem. I mean,
what's a nigga gonna do? He's Samoan.
I think I know who you mean. What
about him? Marsellus fucked him up good.
Word 'round the campfire is it was
on account of Marsellus Wallace's wife.
[ELEVATOR BELL RINGS]
So what he'd do? Fuck her?
No, no, no, no, no. Nothin' that bad.
Well, then what then?
He gave her a foot massage.
A foot massage?
That's it? Mm-hmm.
Then what'd Marsellus do?
Sent a couple cats over to his place.
They took him out on his patio.
Threw his ass over the balcony.
Nigga fell four stories.
He had a little garden down at the bottom
enclosed in glass, like a greenhouse.
Nigga fell through that.
Since then, he kind of
developed a speech impediment.
That's a damn shame. Hmm.
But still, you play with matches,
you get burned. What do you mean?
You don't be givin' Marsellus
Wallace's new bride a foot massage.
You don't think he overreacted?
Antwan didn't expect
Marsellus to react the
way he did, but he
had to expect a reaction.
It was a foot massage. A foot massage is
nothin'. I give my mother a foot massage.
It's laying your hands in a familiar
way on Marsellus's new wife.
I mean, is it as bad as eatin' her pussy
out?
No, but it's the same fuckin' ballpark.
Whoa, stop right there.
Eatin' the bitch out…
And givin' the bitch a foot massage
ain't even the same fucking thing.
It's not. It's the same ballpark.
Ain't no fuckin' ballpark neither.
Now, look, maybe your method
of massage differs from mine.
But touchin' his wife's feet and sticking
your tongue in the holiest of holies…
Ain't the same fuckin'
ballpark; it ain't the
same league; it ain't
the same fuckin' sport.
Foot massages don't mean shit!
Have you ever given a foot massage?
[SCOFFS] Don't be tellin'
me about foot massages.
I'm the foot fuckin' master.
You given a lot of them?
Shit, yeah! Got my technique down and
everything.
I don't be ticklin' or nothin'.
Would you give a guy a foot massage?
Fuck you. [CHUCKLES]
You give 'em a lot? Fuck you.
You know, I'm kind of tired. I could
use a foot massage. Yo, yo, yo, man.
You best back off.
I'm gettin' a little pissed here.
This is the door. Yeah, it is.
What time you got?
7:22 in the a.m.
No, it ain't quite time yet.
Come on. Let's hang back.
Now, look, just 'cause I wouldn't give no
man a foot massage don't make it right…
For Marsellus to throw Antwan off a
building into a glass motherfuckin' house,
fuckin' up the way the
nigga talks; that shit ain't right.
Motherfucker do that
shit to me, he better
paralyze my ass, 'cause
I kill the motherfucker.
I ain't sayin' it's right,
but you sayin' a foot
massage don't mean nothin'.
I'm sayin' it does.
Now, look, I've given
a million ladies a million
foot massages, and
they all meant somethin'.
We act like they don't, but they do.
That's what's so fuckin' cool about them.
There's a sensuous thing goin' on…
Where you don't talk about it,
but you know it and she knows it.
Fuckin' Marsellus knew it. And Antwan
should've fuckin' better known better.
That's his fuckin' wife, man.
This ain't a
man with a sense of
humor about this shit.
You know what I'm sayin'?
It's an interestin' point.
Come on. Let's get into character.
What's her name again? Mia.
Mia.
Why you so interested in big man's wife?
He's goin' out of town, Florida.
And he asked
me if I'd take care of
her while he's gone.
Take care of her?
No, man. Just take her out.
Show her a good time.
Make sure she don't get lonely.
You're gonna be takin'
Mia Wallace out on a date?
It is not a date.
It's just like if you were gonna take
your buddy's wife to a movie or somethin'.
It's just good company, that's all.
[SIGHS]
It's not a date.
It's definitely not a date. [SIGHS]
Hey, kids. How you boys doin'?
Hey, keep chillin'.
You know who we are?
We're associates of your
business partner, Marsellus Wallace.
You do remember your
business partner, don't you?
Now, let me take a wild guess here.
-You're Brett, right?
-Yeah.
I thought so. You remember your
business partner Marsellus Wallace,
don't ya, Brett? Yeah, I remember.
Good. Looks like me and Vincent
caught you boys at breakfast.
Sorry about that. Whatcha havin'?
Hamburgers.
Hamburgers! The cornerstone
of any nutritious breakfast.
What kind of hamburgers?
Uh, ch... cheeseburgers. No, no, no.
Where'd you get 'em?
McDonald's, Wendy's, Jack in the Box?
Where? Uh, Big Kahuna Burger.
Big Kahuna Burger!
That's that Hawaiian burger joint.
I hear they got some tasty burgers. I
ain't never had one myself. How are they?
They're… They're good.
You mind if I try one of yours?
This is yours here, right? Yeah.
Mmmm.
This is a tasty burger! Vincent!
You ever had a Big Kahuna burger?
Want a bite? They're real tasty.
I ain't hungry. Well, if you like
burgers, give 'em a try sometime.
Me, I can't usually get 'em
'cause my girlfriend's a vegetarian,
which pretty much makes me a vegetarian.
But I do love the taste of a good burger.
Mmmm.
You know what they call a Quarter
Pounder with Cheese in France?
No. Tell 'em, Vincent.
A Royale with Cheese.
You know why they call it that?
Uh, because of the metric system?
Check out the big brain on Brett!
You're a smart motherfucker.
That's right. The metric system.
What's in this? Sprite.
Sprite. Good.
You mind if I have some of your
tasty beverage to wash this down with?
Go right ahead.
[SLURPING, SIGHS]
That hit the spot.
You. Flock of Seagulls.
You know why we're here?
Why don't you tell my man Vince here
where you got the shit hid at. It's over…
I don't remember askin'
you a goddamned thing!
You were sayin'?
It's in the cupboard.
N-No, the one by your kn... knees.
[PANS RATTLING]
[RATTLING CONTINUES]
HIT MAN: We happy?
Vincent?
-We happy?
-Yeah, we happy.
[SIGHS]
BRETT: Look, I'm sorry, uh, I…
I didn't get your name.
I got yours. Vincent. Right?
B-But I never got yours.
My name's Pitt, and your ass ain't talkin'
your way outta this shit. No, no, no.
I just want you to know how…
I just want you to know how sorry
we are th... that things got so fucked up…
With us and Mr. Wallace.
W-We got into this thing with
the best intentions. Really. I never…
Oh, I'm sorry, did I
break your concentration?
[GASPING] I didn't mean to do that.
Please.
Continue. You were saying
something about "best intentions."
What's the matter? Oh, you were finished!
Oh, well, allow me to retort.
What does Marsellus Wallace look like?
What?
What country you from? What?
"What" ain't no country I ever heard of.
They speak English in What? W-What?
English, Motherfucker!
Do you speak it? Yes!
Then you know what I'm sayin'! Yes.
Describe what Marsellus
Wallace looks like!
What? I… Say "what" again!
Say "what" again! I dare ya!
I double dare you, motherfucker!
Say "what" one more goddamn time!
H-H-He's black.
-Go on!
-He's bald!
-Does he look like a bitch?
-What?
-[GUNSHOT]
-[SCREAMING]
Does he look… like a bitch?
No! Then why you tryin' to
fuck him like a bitch, Brett?
I didn't. Yes, you did.
Yes, you did, Brett!
-You tried to fuck him.
-[GASPING] No, no.
But Marsellus Wallace don't like to be
fucked by anybody except Mrs. Wallace.
You read the Bible, Brett? Yes!
Well, there's this passage I got
memorized. Sort of fits this occasion.
Ezekiel 25:17.
"The path of the righteous man…
"Is beset on all sides by
the inequities of the selfish…"
"And the tyranny of evil men."
"Blessed is he who, in the
name of charity and goodwill,"
"shepherds the weak
through the valley of darkness,"
"for he is truly his brother's keeper…"
"And the finder of lost children."
"And I will strike down upon
thee with great vengeance…"
"And furious anger…"
"Those who attempt to poison
and destroy my brothers!"
"And you will know my name is the Lord…"
When I lay my vengeance upon thee!"
[SCREAMS]
["LET'S STAY TOGETHER"]
MAN: I think you gonna find…
When all this shit is over and done…
I think you're gonna find
yourself one smilin' motherfucker.
The thing is, Butch,
right now… you got ability.
But painful as it may be,
ability… don't last.
And your days are just about over.
Now, that's a hard
motherfuckin' fact of life.
But that's a fact of life your ass is
gonna have to get realistic about.
You see, this business is filled to
the brim with unrealistic motherfuckers.
Motherfuckers who thought
their ass would age like wine.
If you mean it turns to vinegar… it does.
If you mean it gets better with age…
it don't.
Besides, Butch,
how many fights you think
you got in you anyway?
Hmm?
Two?
Boxers don't have an old-timers' day.
You came close, but you never made it.
And if you were gonna make it,
you would have made it before now.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
You my nigga?
Certainly appears so.
[CHUCKLES]
The night of the fight,
you may feel a slight sting.
That's pride fuckin' with you.
Fuck pride!
Pride only hurts.
It never helps.
You fight through that shit.
'Cause a year from now, when
you kickin' it in the Caribbean,
you gonna say to yourself,
"Marsellus Wallace was right."
[CHUCKLES]
I got no problem with that, Mr. Wallace.
In the fifth, your ass goes down.
Say it.
In the fifth, my ass goes down.
Yo, Vincent Vega. Our man in Amsterdam.
Jules Winfield, our man in Inglewood.
Get your asses on in here.
Goddamn, nigga, what's up with them
clothes? You don't even want to know.
Where's the big man?
The big man's right over there
takin' care of some business.
Why don't you hang back a second or two.
You see the white boy
leave, just go on over.
VINCENT: How ya been?
I been doin' pretty good.
How 'bout yourself? All right.
So I hear you're takin' Mia out tomorrow.
At Marsellus's request.
Have you met Mia? Not yet.
[CHUCKLES] What's so fuckin' funny?
Not a goddamn thing. I got to piss.
Look, I'm not a fuckin' idiot, all right?
It's the big man's wife.
I'm gonna sit across from her,
chew my food with my mouth closed,
laugh at her fuckin'
jokes, and that's it.
Hey, my name's Paul,
and this shit's between y'all.
Then what'd you fuckin'
ask me about it for?
[WHISPERS] Asshole.
Gimme a pack of Red Apples. Filters?
No.
You lookin' at somethin, ' friend?
You ain't my friend, palooka.
What was that?
I think you heard me just fine, punchy.
Vincent Vega's in the house?
My nigga, get your ass over here.
What's up? Man, I'm really sorry.
You shouldn't worry about it.
Pack of Red Apples. $1.40.
And some matches.
Thanks.
WOMAN: It's as if it turns every
part of your body into the tip of a penis.
Whoa.
I'll lend it to you.
It's a great book on piercing.
That gun to pierce your ears, they don't
use that to pierce your nipples, do they?
Forget that gun. That guns goes
against the entire idea behind piercing.
All my piercing, 18 places on my body,
every one of 'em done with a needle.
Five in each ear, one through
the nipple of my left breast,
two in my right nostril,
one in my left eyebrow,
one in my belly, one
in my lip, one in my clit,
-and I wear a stud in my tongue.
-VINCENT: Excuse me.
I was just curious,
but, um…
why would you wear a stud in your tongue?
Sex thing. Helps fellatio.
Vincenzo. Step in my office.
This is Panda from Mexico.
Very good stuff.
Now, that's Bava.
Different, but equally good.
And that is Choco from the
Harz Mountains of Germany.
Now, the first two are the same.
300 a gram. Those are friend prices.
But this one is a little more expensive.
This is 500 a gram.
But, when you shoot it, you will
know where that extra money went.
There's nothing wrong with these two.
This is real, real, real good shit.
But this one is a fuckin' madman.
Remember, I just got back from Amsterdam.
Am I a nigger? Are we in Inglewood? No.
You're in my home.
Now, white people who know the difference…
Between good shit and bad shit,
this is the house they come to.
Now, my shit, I'll take the Pepsi
Challenge with that Amsterdam shit…
Any old day of the fuckin' week.
That's a bold statement.
This ain't Amsterdam, Vince.
This is a seller's market.
Coke is fuckin' dead as… dead.
Heroin, it's comin'
back in a big fuckin' way.
All right.
Gimme three grams of madman. Okay.
Now, if it's as good as you say it is,
I'll come back and buy another thousand.
I just hope that I still
have some left for ya,
but I'm givin' you some
out of my own private stash.
That is what a nice guy I am.
I'm outta balloons.
Is a baggie all right? Yeah, that's cool.
All right. I'll just get one for ya.
Honey, will you get me some baggies
and, uh, twistix from the kitchen?
WOMAN: Okay.
Hey, uh, what do you think about Trudi?
She ain't got a boyfriend.
You wanna hang out and get high?
Which one's Trudi?
The one with all the shit in her face?
No, that's Jody.
That's my wife.
[CHUCKLES] I'm sorry, man. Thank you.
No, I can't. I gotta be someplace.
All right, no problemo.
-I'll take a rain check.
-[KNOCKING]
Oh. Thank you, Jody.
Still got your Malibu?
Oh, man, you know what
some fucker did the other day?
What? Fuckin' keyed it.
Oh, man, that's fucked up.
Tell me about it.
I had it in storage for three years.
It was out five days, and some
dickless piece of shit fucked with it.
They should be fuckin' killed, man.
No trial, no jury, straight to execution.
I wish I could've caught him doin' it.
I'd
have given anything
to catch that asshole.
It'd been worth him doin' it just so I
could've caught him. What a fucker!
What's more chicken-shit than
fuckin' with a man's automobile?
Don't fuck with another man's vehicle.
You don't do it.
It's just against the rules. Thank you.
Mind if I shoot up here?
Hey, mi casa es su casa.
Muchas gracias.
["BULLWINKLE PART II"]
[CAR DOOR CLOSING]
MIA'S VOICE: Hi, Vincent.
I'm getting dressed The door's open.
Come inside and make yourself a drink.
Mia.
["SON OF A PREACHER MAN"]
Hello?
♪ Billy Raye was a preacher's son ♪
♪ And when his daddy
would visit he'd come along ♪
Vincent.
[OVER INTERCOM] Vincent.
I'm on the intercom.
Where is… Where is the intercom?
It's on the wall by the
two African fellows.
To your right.
Warm.
Warmer Disco.
Hello?
Push the button if you want to talk.
Go make yourself a drink, and I'll
be down in two shakes of a lamb's tail.
The bar's by the fireplace.
Okay.
♪ When he started sweet talkin' to me ♪
♪ He come and tell me
everything is all right ♪
♪ He'd kiss me and tell
me everything is all right ♪
♪ Can I get away again tonight ♪
♪ The only one who could ever reach me ♪
♪ Was the son of a preacher man ♪
♪ The only boy who could ever teach me ♪
♪ Was the son of a
preacher man Yes, he was ♪
♪ He was ♪
♪ Lord he knows he was yes, he was ♪
♪ How well I remember ♪
♪ The look that was in his eyes ♪
♪ Stealing kisses from me on the sly ♪
♪ Taking time to make time ♪
♪ Telling me that he's all mine ♪
-♪ Learning from each other's knowin' ♪
-[SNIFFING]
♪ Looking to see how much we've grown ♪
♪ And the only one who
could ever reach me ♪
♪ Was the son of a preacher man ♪
♪ The only boy who could ever teach me ♪
♪ Was the son of a
preacher man, yes, he was ♪
♪ Was, was, he was ♪
-♪ Oh, yes, he was ♪
-[MUSIC STOPS]
Let's go.
What the fuck is this place?
This is Jackrabbit Slim's.
An Elvis man should love it. [SIGHS]
Come on, Mia. Let's go get a steak.
You can get a steak here, Daddy-O.
Don't be a… Oh, after you, kitty-cat.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Now, how may I help you?
There's a reservation under Wallace.
Wallace?
-["WAITIN' IN SCHOOL"]
-We reserved a car.
Oh, a car. Why don't you seat
'em over there in the Chrysler.
♪ School gal, baby
gonna tell you some news ♪
♪ Sure do look good in
them baby-doll shoes ♪
♪ It's one, two, buckle the shoes
three, four, get out on the floor ♪
♪ Five, six, come get your kicks down
at the corner of Lincoln and 46th, yeah ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ I've been waitin' in
school all day long ♪
♪ Waiting on the bell to
ring so I can go home ♪
♪ Throw my books on the
table, pick up the telephone ♪
-♪ Come on, baby ♪
-MAN: Coffee, please? Decaf.
MARILYN: Just a minute.
♪ Heading down to the
drugstore to get a soda pop ♪
♪ Throw a nickel in the
jukebox then we start to rock ♪
♪ School gal baby gonna
tell you some news ♪
♪ You sure do look good
in them baby-doll shoes ♪
♪ Well, it's one, two buckle the shoes ♪
♪ Three, four get out on the floor ♪
♪ Five, six, come get your kicks
down at the corner of Lincoln and 46th ♪
[CHATTERING]
♪ Gonna rock all night
just wait and see ♪
MAN: Ricky, Ricky, Ricky!
ED SULLIVAN IMPERSONATOR:
Let's hear it for Ricky Nelson!
Fantastic job, Rick. Thank you very much.
Vincent!
SULLIVAN: Just to let you all know, Ricky
will be back in the
second half of our show,
so we hope you enjoy your
meals here at Jackrabbit Slim's.
Thank you.
Call for…
Phil-lip Mor-ris. What do you think?
I think it's like a wax
museum with a pulse.
Hi, I'm Buddy. What can I get you?
["LONESOME TOWN"]
Let's see, steak, steak, steak. Oh,
yeah, I'll have the Douglas Sirk steak.
I'll have that.
How do you want that cooked?
Burned to a crisp or bloody as hell?
Bloody as hell, and…
Oh, yeah, look at this… vanilla coke.
What about you, Peggy Sue?
I'll have the…
Durward Kirby burger, bloody.
And… a five-dollar shake.
How do you want that shake,
Martin and Lewis, or Amos 'n Andy?
-Martin and Lewis.
-Did you just order a five-dollar shake?
Mm-hmm.
That's a shake?
That's milk and ice cream?
Last I heard. That's five dollars?
You don't put bourbon in it or nothin'?
-No.
-Just checking.
I'll be right back with your drinks.
[ON JUKEBOX] ♪ To lonesome town ♪
♪ To cry my troubles away ♪
Could you, um…
roll me one of those, cowboy?
You can have this one, cowgirl.
-Thanks.
-[IGNITES LIGHTER]
♪ The streets are filled with regret ♪
Think nothin' of it.
♪ Lay me down in lonesome town ♪
-♪ I can learn to forget ♪
-So…
Marsellus said you just
got back from Amsterdam.
Sure did. How long were you there?
[INHALES] Just over three years.
I go there about once a
year to chill out for a month.
No kiddin'? I didn't know that.
Why would you?
["ACE OF SPADES"]
I heard you did a pilot.
-That was my 15 minutes.
-What was it?
It was a show about a team of female
secret agents called Fox Force Five.
-What?
-Fox Force Five.
Fox, as in were a bunch of foxy chicks.
Force, as in we're a
force to be reckoned with.
And five, as in there's
one-two-three-four-five of us.
There was a blond one, Sommerset O'Neal.
She was the leader.
The Japanese fox was a kung fu master.
The black girl was a demolition expert.
French Fox's specialty was sex.
-What was your specialty?
-Knives.
The character I played, Raven McCoy,
her background was she grew
up raised by circus performers.
According to the show, she was the
deadliest woman in the world with a knife.
And she knew a zillion old jokes.
Her grandfather, an old
vaudevillian, taught her.
And if we would have got picked up,
they would've worked in a gimmick…
Where every show I
would've told another joke.
You know any of them old jokes?
Well, I only got the chance to say
one 'cause we only did one show.
-Tell me.
-It's corny.
Don't be that way. Tell me.
No, you wouldn't like it, and I'd
be embarrassed. You'd be embarr…
You told 50 million people,
and you can't tell me?
I promise I won't laugh.
That's what I'm afraid of, Vince.
That's not what I meant. You know it.
Now I'm definitely not gonna tell
you 'cause it's been built up too much.
What a gyp. [SIGHS]
Martin and Lewis.
Vanilla coke.
Mmm. Yummy.
You think I could have a sip of that?
Be my guest.
I gotta know what a
five-dollar shake tastes like.
You can use my straw.
I don't have cooties.
Yeah, but maybe I do.
Cooties I can handle.
All right.
Goddamn, that's a pretty
fuckin' good milk shake!
Told ya.
I don't know if it was worth five
dollars, but it's pretty fuckin' good.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
-Don't you hate that?
-Hate what?
Uncomfortable silences.
Why do we feel it's necessary to yak
about bullshit in order to be comfortable?
I don't know. That's a good question.
That's when you know you
found somebody really special.
When you can just shut the fuck up for
a minute and comfortably share silence.
Well, I don't think
we're quite there yet,
but don't feel bad.
We just met each other.
I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna go to the
bathroom and powder my nose.
You sit here…
and think of something to say.
I'll do that.
Okay.
[WOLF WHISTLE]
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
[SNIFFING]
I said goddamn!
Goddamn! Goddamn.
WOMAN: I need some hair spray.
["SINCE I FIRST MET YOU"]
Mmmm.
Don't you just love it
when you come back from
the bathroom to find
your food waiting for you?
We're lucky we got anything at all.
I don't think Buddy
Holly's much of a waiter.
Maybe we should've sat
in Marilyn Monroe's section.
Which one? There's two Monroes.
No, there's not.
That is Marilyn Monroe.
That is Mamie Van Doren.
I don't see Jayne Mansfield,
so she must have the night off.
-Pretty smart.
-Yeah. I got my moments.
-So did you think of somethin' to say?
-Actually, I did.
However…
You seem like a really
nice person, and I…
I don't want to offend you. Oooh.
This doesn't sound
like the usual, mindless,
boring, gettin'-to-know-you chitchat.
This sounds like you
actually have somethin' to say.
Well, well, I do. I do.
[INHALES] But you have to
promise not to be offended. No, no.
You can't promise somethin' like that.
I have no idea what you're gonna ask me.
You can ask me what
you're gonna ask me, and
my natural response
could be to get offended.
Then through no fault of my own,
I would have broken my promise.
Let's just forget it.
That's an impossibility.
Trying to forget anything as intriguing
as this would be an exercise in futility.
Is that a fact? And besides,
isn't it more, uh, exciting when you don't
have permission? All right, all right.
Well, here goes.
What did you think about
what happened to Antwan?
-Who's Antwan?
-Tony Rocky Horror. You know him.
-He fell out of a window.
-Hmm. Hmm.
Well, that is one way to say it.
Another way
to say it would be
that he was thrown out.
Another way would be he
was thrown out by Marsellus.
Yet, even another way
is to say he was thrown
out of a window by
Marsellus because of you.
Is that a fact? No.
No, it's not a fact. It's just what
I heard. That's just what I heard.
Who told you? They.
"They" talk a lot, don't they?
[CHUCKLES]
They certainly do. They certainly do.
Don't be shy, Vincent.
What else did "they" say?
I'm… I'm not shy.
-Um…
-Did it involve the "F" word?
No, no, no, no, no. They just said that
Antwan had given you a foot massage.
-And?
-And… And nothin'.
That's it.
You heard Marsellus…
Threw Tony Rocky
Horror out of a fourth-story
window for giving me a foot massage?
Mm-hmm. And you believe that?
[CHUCKLES] Well, at the time I
was told it sounded reasonable.
Marsellus throwing Tony
out of a fourth-story window…
For massaging my feet seemed reasonable?
No, it seemed excessive, but
that doesn't mean it didn't happen.
I understand that Marsellus
is very protective of you.
A husband being protective
of his wife is one thing.
A husband almost killing another man for
touching his wife's
feet is something else.
But did it happen?
Only thing Antwan ever touched of mine was
my hand when he shook it… at my wedding.
Really?
Truth is, nobody knows why
Marsellus threw Tony out that window…
Except Marsellus and Tony.
When you little scamps get together,
you're worse than a sewing circle.
Ladies and gentlemen. Now the
moment you've all been waiting for.
The world-famous
Jackrabbit Slim's twist contest.
[APPLAUSE]
Now, this is where one lucky couple…
Will win this handsome trophy
that Marilyn here is holding.
Now, who will be our first contestants?
-Right here!
-MAN: All right!
-I wanna dance.
-No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no. I do believe
Marsellus, my husband, your boss,
told you to take me out
and do whatever I wanted.
Now I wanna dance; I
wanna win; I want that trophy.
-So dance good.
-All right. You asked for it.
Let's hear it for our first contestants.
Now let's meet our first contestants here
this evening.
Young lady, what is your name?
Mrs. Mia Wallace.
And how 'bout your fella here?
Vincent Vega.
All right, let's see what you can do.
Take it away!
-WOMAN: Go for it.
-MAN: Come on!
["YOU NEVER CAN TELL"]
♪ It was a teenage wedding and
the old folks wished them well ♪
♪ You could see that Pierre
did truly love the mademoiselle ♪
♪ And now the young monsieur and
madame have rung the chapel bell ♪
♪ "C'est la vie" say the old folks, it
goes to show you never can tell ♪
♪ They furnished of fan apartment
with a two-room Roebucks sale ♪
♪ The 'coolerador was crammed
with TV dinners and ginger ale ♪
♪ But when Pierre found work the
little money comin' worked out well ♪
♪ "C'est la vie" say the old folks, it
goes to show you never can tell ♪
♪ They had a hi-fi phono
and boy did they let it blast ♪
♪ Seven hundred little records
all rock, rhythm and jazz ♪
♪ But when the sun went down
the rapid tempo of the music fell ♪
♪ "C'est la vie" say the old folks, it
goes to show you never can tell ♪
♪ They had a teenage wedding
and the old folks wished them well ♪
♪ You could see that Pierre did
truly love the mademoiselle ♪
[SIGHS]
[ALARM FAINTLY BEEPING]
[BEEPING STOPS]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Is that what you call an
uncomfortable silence?
I don't know what you call that.
[CHUCKLES] Drinks! Music!
I'm gonna take a piss.
That's a little bit more information
than I needed, Vince, but go right ahead.
♪ Girl ♪
♪ Bomp, bomp, bom ♪
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
♪ I love you so much
Can't count all the ways ♪
♪ I'd die for you, girl
and all they can say is ♪
[SINGING WITH TAPE]
♪ He's not your kind ♪
♪ You never get tired of putting me down
and I never know when I come around ♪
♪ What I'm gonna find ♪
♪ Don't let them make up your mind ♪
♪ Don't you know, girl ♪
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
One drink, and that's it.
Don't be rude.
Drink your drink, but do it quickly.
Say good night… and go home.
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
♪ Soon ♪
♪ You'll need a man ♪
♪ I've been misunderstood
for all of my life ♪
♪ But what they're sayin',
girl it cuts like a knife ♪
♪ The boy's no good ♪
♪ Well, I've finally have
found what I been lookin' for ♪
♪ But if they get a chance they'll
end it for sure, sure they would ♪
♪ Baby, I've done all I could ♪
[SIGHS] You see, this
is a moral test of oneself.
Whether or not you can maintain loyalty.
Because… being loyal is very important.
♪ You never get tired of putting me down
and I never know when I come around ♪
♪ What I'm gonna find ♪
♪ Don't let them make up your mind ♪
♪ Don't you know, girl ♪
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
♪ Please ♪
♪ Come take my hand ♪
♪ Girl ♪
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
♪ Please ♪
♪ Come take my hand ♪
-Hello.
-♪ Girl ♪
So, you're gonna go out there
and you're gonna say, "Good night.
I've had a very lovely evening."
Walk out the door, get in the car, go
home,
jerk off and that's all you gonna do.
♪ Now it's up to you, girl ♪
♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
-♪ Please ♪
-[SNIFFING]
♪ Come take my hand ♪
-♪ Girl ♪
-[MOANS]
-♪ You'll be a woman soon ♪
-[BREATHING HEAVILY]
♪ Soon ♪
♪ You'll need a man ♪
[BATHROOM DOOR OPENS]
All right, Mia.
So listen, I gotta go, all right?
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ.
You fu… Oh, Jesus Christ!
Oh, fuck me. Fuck me!
Oh… Come on, girl. We're gettin'
outta here. We gotta walk now.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Don't fuckin' die on me, Mia!
Fuck!
[DIALING]
Answer.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
MAN [ON TV]: Have you got the ring?
Why certainly. Join
hands, you two lovebirds.
-[RINGING CONTINUES]
-WOMAN: Please! Please!
Yes, yes. Hold hands, you lovebirds.
-[RINGING CONTINUES]
-[PEOPLE ON TELEVISION YELLING, SHOUTING]
[RINGING]
Fuck you, Lance! Answer!
-[RINGING CONTINUES]
-[YELLING, SHOUTING CONTINUE]
WOMAN: Now what do you say?
MAN: I give up! I'll marry you!
-[RINGING CONTINUES]
-JODY: Lance! The goddamn phone's ringing!
I can hear it.
JODY: I thought you told those fuckin'
assholes never to call here this late!
Yeah, I told them.
And that is exactly what I'm going
to tell this fucking asshole right now.
WOMAN [ON TV]: Don't you dare strike me!
Hello.
Lance! Vincent.
I'm in big fuckin' trouble, man.
I'm coming to your house.
W-Whoa. Whoa. Hold your horses, man.
W-What's the problem?
I got this chick, she's
fuckin' ODin' on me!
Well, don't bring her here!
I'm not even joking with you! Do not be
bringing some fucked-up
pooh-bah to my house!
-No choice.
-Wh… She's ODin'?
-She's fuckin' dyin' on me, man!
-MAN [ON TV]: Just dandy
Okay, then you bite the fuckin' bullet,
take her to a hospital and call a lawyer.
-Negative!
-This is not my fuckin' problem, man!
You fucked her up,
you fuckin' deal with this!
Uh, are you talkin' to
me on a cellular phone?
I don't know you. Who is this?
Don't come here!
I'm hanging up the phone!
Prank caller! Prank caller!
[TIRES SCREECHING, ENGINE RACING]
-[LOUD CRASH]
-JODY: What the hell was that?
Have you lost your fucking mind?
You were talking about drug shit
on a cellular phone! Lance, help me.
You crashed your car into my
fucking house! Grab her feet.
Are you deaf? You are not bringing
this fucked-up bitch into my house!
This "fucked-up bitch" is
Marsellus Wallace's wife.
Do you know who Marsellus Wallace is?
Yeah.
If she croaks on me, I
am a fucking grease spot!
I will be forced to tell him that you did
not help and let her die on your lawn.
Now, come on, help me, help me.
Pick her up.
Shit. [GRUNTS]
Lance!
Shit.
It's 1:30 in the goddamn morning.
What the fuck's going on out here?
Who's she?
Go to the fridge and get the
thing with the adrenaline shot.
What's wrong with her? She's ODing!
-Get her outta here!
-[TOGETHER] Get the shot!
Fuck you! Fuck you too!
What a fuckin' bitch.
Just keep talking to her, all right?
She's gettin' the shot. I'm going to
go get my little black medical book.
What the fuck you
need a medical book for?
I've never had to give
an adrenaline shot before!
I don't go joy-poppin'
with bubble-gummers!
My friends can handle their highs!
Get the shot! I am, if you'll let me!
I ain't stopping you!
Stop talking to me. Start talking to her!
Get the shot! All right!
VINCENT: Hurry up. We're losing her!
I'm looking as fast as I can!
JODY: What's he looking for?
-VINCENT: I don't know. Some book.
-JODY: What are you looking for?
A little black medical book.
What are you looking for?
My little black medical book!
It's like a textbook they give to nurses.
I never saw no medical book.
Trust me. I have one.
If it's so important, why don't you
keep it with the shot? I don't know!
Stop bothering me! While you're looking,
that girl's gonna die on our carpet.
You're never gonna
find anything in this mess!
I'm gonna fucking kill you if you
don't shut up! Lance, get in here!
Right? Pig. Get the fuck outta my way.
Quit fuckin' around and give her the shot.
While I'm doing this,
you take off her shirt
and find her heart.
Does it gotta be exact?
We're giving her a shot in
the heart, so it's gotta be exact.
I don't know exactly where her heart is.
I think it's right here.
That's it. All right, what I
need is a big, fat magic marker.
You got it? What?
A magic marker. A felt pen!
A fuckin' black magic marker! Christ.
Come on, man. Hurry up! Fuck!
Okay, okay. Okay. I think it's ready.
-Hurry up, man.
-I'll tell you what to do.
You're gonna give her the shot.
No, you're gonna give her the shot.
I ain't giving her the shot. I never done
this before. I never done this either!
I ain't starting now! You brought
her here. You give her the shot.
The day I bring an ODing bitch to
your house, then I give her the shot.
Give it to me. Give me that.
All right, tell me what to do.
Okay, you're giving her an injection
of adrenaline straight to her heart.
But she's got a breastplate…
you gotta pierce through that.
[THUMPING]
You gotta bring the needle
down in a stabbing motion.
I gotta… I gotta stab her three times?
No, just stab her once!
But it's gotta be hard enough to get
through her breastplate into her heart.
Once you do that, you
p-press down on the p-plunger.
Okay. Then what happens?
Kinda curious about that myself.
This ain't no fuckin' joke!
Am I gonna kill her?
She's supposed to come out of it like
that. It's… All right, count to three.
All right. Ready? One.
[VINCENT PANTING]
Two.
Three!
-[LOUD THUMP]
-[GASPS, SCREAMS]
[GASPING CONTINUES]
[COUGHS, GASPS]
If you're all right, then say something.
Something.
[CHUCKLES] That was fuckin' trippy.
[CHUCKLES]
Ohh. Oh, man.
[CAR PULLS UP]
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
-[ENGINE STOPS]
-[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
Mia. Mia.
What's…
What's your thoughts on… on…
On how to handle this?
What's yours?
Well, I'm of the opinion that if
Marsellus lived his whole life,
he doesn't need to know
nothing about this incident.
If Marsellus knew about this incident,
I'd be in as much trouble as you.
I seriously doubt that.
I can keep a secret if you can.
Shake on it?
Mum's the word?
Cool.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm going
to go home and have a heart attack.
Vincent.
Do you wanna hear my Fox Force Five joke?
Sure.
Except I think I'm still a
little too petrified to laugh.
No, you won't laugh
'cause it's not funny.
But if you still wanna
hear it, I'll tell it.
I can't wait. Okay.
Three tomatoes are
walkin' down the street.
Papa Tomato, Mama Tomato and Baby Tomato.
Baby Tomato starts lagging behind,
and Papa Tomato gets really angry.
Goes back and squishes him and says,
"Ketchup."
[WEAK CHUCKLE]
Ketchup.
See you around.
[DOG BARKING]
Oh, that paddlefoot. He funny silly dog.
He think totem pole alive!
[GIGGLING] He Arctic tenderfoot!
[LAUGHING] That totem
pole been here forever!
-WOMAN: Butch?
-[PADDLEFOOT BARKING]
MAN ON [TV]: One
more thing, and we'll start for…
-Butch, stop watching TV for a second.
-Yeah?
-You've got a special visitor.
-[ON TV] Stand up. Stand up.
Now, do you remember when I told
you your daddy died in a POW camp?
Well, this here is Captain Koons.
He was in the POW camp with Daddy.
Hello, little man.
Boy, I sure heard a bunch about you.
See, I was a good friend of your dad's.
We were in that Hanoi
pit of hell together…
Over five years.
Hopefully…
You'll never have to
experience this yourself,
but when two men are in a
situation like me and your dad were…
For as long as we were,
you take on certain
responsibilities of the other.
If it'd been me who'd…
Not made it,
Major Coolidge'd be talking
right now to my son Jim.
But the way it turned
out, I'm talking to you.
Butch…
I got something for ya.
This watch I got here…
Was first purchased by your
great-grandfather during
the First World War.
It was bought in a little general
store in Knoxville, Tennessee.
Made by the first company
to ever make wristwatches.
Up till then, people just
carried pocket watches.
It was bought by Private
Doughboy Erine Coolidge…
On the day he set sail for Paris.
This was your
great-grandfather's war watch,
and he wore it every day
he was in that war, and…
When he'd done his duty, he went
home to your great-grandmother,
took the watch off, put it in an old
coffee can, and in that can it stayed…
Until your grandad, Dane Coolidge,
was called upon by his country…
To go overseas and fight
the Germans once again.
This time they called it World War II.
Your great-grandfather gave this
watch to your grandad for good luck.
Unfortunately, Dane's luck
wasn't as good as his old man's.
Dane was a Marine, and he was killed,
along with all the other Marines
at the battle of Wake Island.
Your grandad was facing death.
He knew it.
None of those boys had any illusions
about ever leaving that island alive,
so three days before the
Japanese took the island,
your grandad asked a gunner on an
Air Force transport, name of Winocki…
A man he'd never met before in his life…
To deliver to his infant son,
who he'd never seen in
the flesh, his gold watch.
Three days later, your grandad
was dead, but Winocki kept his word.
After the war was over, he
paid a visit to your grandmother,
delivering to your infant
father his dad's gold watch.
This watch.
This watch was on your daddy's wrist
when he was shot down over Hanoi.
He was captured, put in a
Vietnamese prison camp.
He knew if the gooks ever saw the watch,
it'd be confiscated, taken away.
The way your dad looked at it,
this watch was your birthright.
He'd be damned if any
slope's gonna put their
greasy, yellow hands
on his boy's birthright,
so he hid it in one place he knew
he could hide something… his ass.
Five long years he wore
this watch up his ass.
Then he died of dysentery…
He give me the watch.
I hid this uncomfortable hunk
of metal up my ass two years.
Then…
After seven years, I was
sent home to my family and…
Now…
little man, I give the watch to you.
-[BELL RINGS]
-[GASPS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[GRUNTING]
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
It's time, Butch.
[EXHALING]
RING ANNOUNCER: In
the lightweight division,
in the right corner
wearing the blue trunks,
[GRUNTS]
Weighing 210 pounds, Floyd Ray Wilson!
-[CROWD CHEERING, YELLING]
-[BELL RINGS]
ANNOUNCER: It's official It's official
Wilson is dead!
ANNOUNCER 2: Well, Dan,
that had to be the bloodiest…
Hands down, the most brutal
fight this city's ever seen.
Coolidge was out of
there faster than I've
ever seen a victorious
boxer leave the ring.
Do you think he knew Wilson was dead?
My guess would be yes.
I could see the frenzy
in his eyes give way
to the realization of what he was doing.
I think any man would've left the ring
that fast. Do you feel this tragedy...
Is gonna affect the world of boxing?
A tragedy like this can't help but shake
the world of boxing
to its very foundations.
It's of paramount
importance, during the sad
weeks ahead, the eyes of the WB.A.
remain…
[CROWD CHEERING, YELLING CONTINUES]
-[ENGINE STARTS]
-[TIRES SCREECHING]
[HORN HONKING]
MAN: Man, you know I didn't…
Marsellus. No, it wasn't. I didn't do it.
I didn't do it.
How you doing? Great.
I never thanked you for dinner.
What you got? He booked.
His trainer? Says he don't know nothin'.
I believe him.
I think Butch surprised his ass same
as us. No, we don't wanna "think."
We wanna know. Take him to
the kennel, sic the dogs on his ass.
We'll find out for goddamn sure
what he knows and what he don't.
Butch's search… how do you want it done?
I'm prepared to scour the
earth for that motherfucker.
If Butch goes to Indochina, I want
a nigga hiding in a bowl of rice…
Ready to pop a cap in his ass.
I will take care of it.
Mister.
Hey, mister. What?
You were in that fight,
the fight on the radio.
You're the fighter?
Whatever gave you that idea?
No, come on.
You're him.
I know you're him.
Tell me you're him.
I'm him.
You killed the other boxing man.
He's dead?
The radio said he was dead.
Sorry about that, Floyd.
What does it feel like?
What does what feel like?
Killing a man.
Beating another man to
death with your bare hands.
What are you, a weirdo?
No.
It is a subject I have much interest in.
You are the first person I have
ever met who has killed somebody.
So?
What does it feel like to kill a man?
[SNIFFS]
I'll tell you what.
Give me one of them cigarettes you got
up there and I'll tell you all about it.
So, Esmarelda…
Villa Lobos… is that Mexican?
The name is Spanish, but I am Colombian.
-That's some handle you got there, honey.
-Thank you.
And what is your name?
Butch.
What does it mean?
I'm an American, honey.
Our names don't mean shit.
So, moving right along, Esmarelda,
what is it you want to know?
I want to know what it feels
like to kill a man. I couldn't tell ya.
I didn't know he was dead
till you told me he was dead.
Now that I know he's dead, you
wanna know how I feel about it?
I don't feel the least bit bad about it.
What the fuck'd I tell ya? Huh?
As soon as the word got out the fix was
in, man, the odds went through the roof.
I know. I know. Unbelievable.
Hey, fuck him, Scotty. If he was
a better boxer, he'd still be alive.
If he never laced up his gloves,
which he never shoulda done in the
first fuckin' place, he'd still be alive.
[HAWKS, SPITS]
Yeah, well, who gives a fuck?
It's over now.
Yeah, well, enough about
the poor, unfortunate Mr. Floyd.
Let's talk about the rich
and prosperous Mr. Butch.
How many bookies
did you lay it around on?
All eight? How long to collect?
So you'll have it all by tomorrow night?
No, I understand.
A few stragglers aside.
Oh, fuck, Scotty, that is good news.
That is great news, man.
Yeah. Mm-hmm. No, me and
Fabienne are gonna leave in the morning.
It'll probably take us a couple
days to get down to Knoxville.
Okay, my brother.
[LAUGHING] You're right.
You're goddamn right.
All right, Scotty, next time I see
you, it'll be on Tennessee time.
Cool, brother.
$45.60.
And, uh,
here's a little something for the effort.
Now…
If anybody asks you who your fare
was tonight, what are you gonna say?
The truth.
Three well-dressed,
slightly toasted Mexicans.
Bonsoir, Esmarelda Villa Lobos.
Buenas noches, Butch.
Whew.
Keep the light off.
Is that better, sugar pop? Oui
-[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
-[DOG BARKING]
Hard day at the office?
Pretty hard.
Got in a fight.
Poor baby.
Can you make spoons?
You know what?
I was thinkin' about takin' a shower.
I'm stinkin' like a dog over here.
I like the way you stink.
Let me take this jacket off.
I was looking at myself in the mirror.
Uh-huh.
I wish I had a pot.
You were looking at yourself in the
mirror and you wish you had some pot?
A pot. [GIGGLES] A pot belly.
Pot bellies are sexy.
Well, you should be happy… [GRUNTS]
'Cause you have one.
Shut up, fatso. I don't have a pot.
I have a bit of a tummy, like
Madonna when she did "Lucky Star."
It's not the same thing.
I didn't know there was such a difference
between a pot belly and a tummy.
The difference is huge.
[KISSING] Would you
like it if I had a pot belly?
No.
Pot bellies make a man look
either oafish or like a gorilla.
But on a woman a pot belly's very sexy.
The rest of you is normal… normal face,
normal legs, normal hips, normal ass…
But with a big,
perfectly round pot belly.
If I had one, I'd wear a
T-shirt two sizes too small…
To accentuate it.
You think men would find that attractive?
I don't give a damn
what men find attractive.
It's unfortunate what we find pleasing
to the touch and pleasing to the eye…
Is seldom the same.
[SIGHS]
If you had a pot belly,
I would punch you in it.
You'd punch me in the belly?
Right in the belly.
Ohh! I'd smother you!
I'd drop it right on your face till
you couldn't breathe! [LAUGHING]
You'd do that? Yeah.
Promise? Yeah.
[MOANING SOFTLY]
Mmm. Mmm.
[MOANING, LAUGHING]
Oh. [INHALING]
[GRUNTING]
Did you get everything?
Yes, I did. Good job, sugar pop.
Did everything go as planned?
You didn't listen to the… Ow! [GIGGLES]
You didn't listen to the radio?
I never listen to your fights.
Were you the winner?
I won, all right.
Are you still retiring? Sure am.
So it all worked out in the finish.
We're not at the finish yet, baby.
[MOANING]
We're in a lot of danger, aren't we?
If they find us, they'll
kill us, won't they?
But they won't find us, will they?
Do you still want me to go with you?
I don't want to be a burden or a nuisance.
It's…
[MOANS]
Say it.
[MOANS] Fabienne,
I want you to be with me.
Forever? Forever and ever.
Do you love me?
Very, very much.
[MOANING]
Butch. Yes?
Will you give me oral pleasure?
Will you kiss it?
But you first.
Okay. Okay.
[MOANS]
Butch.
Mon amour L'aventure commence.
[MOANING CONTINUES]
-[SHOWER WATER RUNNING]
-[BUTCH GRUNTING]
BUTCH: I think I cracked a rib.
Giving me oral pleasure?
No, retard, from the fight.
-Don't call me "retard."
-[SLURRING] My name is Fabby.
My name is Fabienne! Stop it.
Stop it! My name is Fabi…
Shut up, fuckhead!
I hate that mongoloid voice.
Okay, okay. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
-[WATER STOPS]
-BUTCH: I take it back.
Will you hand me a dry
towel, Miss Beautiful Tulip?
Oh, I like that.
I like being called a tulip. [COUGHS]
"Tulip" is much better than "mongoloid."
I didn't call you a mongoloid.
I called you a retard.
And I took it back.
[GRUNTS] Butch?
Yes, lemon pie?
Where are we going to go?
Well, I'm not sure yet.
Wherever you want.
We're gonna get a lot of money from this,
but it ain't gonna be the kind of money…
That we can live like hogs
in the fathouse forever.
I was thinking maybe we could go
down someplace in the South Pacific.
Kind of money we're gonna have's
gonna carry us a long way down there.
If we wanted, we could live in Bora Bora?
You betcha.
And if after a while you didn't dig
that, we could go someplace else.
Maybe Tahiti, Mexico.
But I do not speak Spanish.
Well, you do not speak Bora-Boran either.
Besides, Mexican's easy.
¿Donde esta el zapatería?
What does that mean?
Where is the shoe store?
¿Donde esta… Spit, please.
[SPITS]
¿Donde esta el zapatería?
Excellent pronunciation.
Mmm. [GIGGLES]
You'll be my little mamacita in no time.
-[YAWNING] ¿Que hora es?
-¿Que hora es?
-What time is it?
Time for bed.
Sweet dreams, jellybean.
[SPITS]
Butch?
Never mind.
[BRUSHING]
[MOTORBIKE ENGINES
RACING, EXPLOSIONS ON TV]
Aah! [PANTING]
Merde! You startled me.
Did you have a bad dream?
-[YAWNS]
-[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES, EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE]
[PANTING CONTINUES]
-What is this you're watching?
-A motorcycle movie.
I'm not sure the name.
-Are you watching it?
-In a way.
It's a little early in the
morning for explosions and war.
What was it about?
How should I know?
You were the one watching it.
-No, imbecile, what was your dream about?
-I don't know.
I don't remember.
It's really rare that I
remember my dreams.
Well, let's look at the
grumpy man in the morning.
[BOTH MOANING]
FABIENNE: Why don't you get
up and we'll get some breakfast.
One more kiss and I'll get up.
[MOANS]
-Satisfied?
-[EXHALING] Yep.
[GRUNTS] Get up, lazy bones! Ohh!
Ohh. God. [GIGGLES]
What time is it?
Almost 9:00 in the morning.
What time does our train arrive? 11:00.
You know what I'm gonna have
for breakfast? What, lemon pie?
I'm gonna order a big
plate of blueberry pancakes…
With maple syrup,
eggs over easy and five sausages.
Anything to drink with that?
Wow, that looks nice. [GIGGLES]
To drink… a tall glass of orange juice…
And a black cup of coffee.
After that, I'm going to have a
slice of pie. Pie for breakfast?
[LAUGHING] Any time of
the day is a good time for pie.
Blueberry pie to go with the pancakes.
And on top, a thin
slice of melted cheese.
Where's my watch?
It's there.
No, it's not. Have you looked?
Yes, I've fuckin' looked.
What the fuck do you think I'm doin'?
You sure you got it?
Yes. Bedside table drawer.
-On the little kangaroo?
-Yes, it was on the little kangaroo.
Yeah, well, it's not here now.
-[RUMMAGING]
-Well, it should be.
Yes, it most definitely should be, but
it's not here now!
So where the fuck is it?
Fabienne, where's my
father's fucking watch?
Do you have any idea what he had
to go through to get me that watch?
I don't have time to go into
it, but he went through a lot.
All this other shit you could've set
on fire, but I specifically reminded you…
Not to forget the fucking watch!
Now think.
Did you get it? I believe so.
"You believe so"? What the fuck does that
mean? You either did or didn't get it.
Then I did.
Are you sure?
No.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Motherfucker! Motherfuckin'
-[SCREAMING]
-[CRASH]
Do you know how fucking
stupid you fucking are?
No! [GRUNTS]
It's not your fault.
You left it at the apartment.
If you left it at the
apartment, it's not your fault.
I had you bring a bunch of stuff.
[EXHALING]
I reminded you about it,
but I didn't illustrate how
personal the watch was to me.
If all I gave a fuck about was
the watch, I shoulda told you that.
You're not a mind reader.
Are you?
[SNIFFLING]
I… I'm sorry.
Don't be. Just means I
can't have breakfast with you.
Why does it mean that?
Because I gotta go back to
my apartment and get my watch.
Won't the gangsters
be looking for you there?
Well, that's what I'm gonna find out.
If they are, and I don't
think I can handle it,
then I'll split.
I saw your watch.
I thought I brought it. I'm so sorry.
Here's some money.
Go out and get those pancakes.
Have a nice breakfast.
I'll take your Honda. I'll be back
before you can say "blueberry pie."
Blueberry pie.
Maybe not that fast.
But pretty fast. Okay? Okay.
Bye. Bye.
Shit! Of all the fuckin'
things she could fuckin' forget,
she forgets my father's watch!
I specifically reminded her…
Bedside table, on the kangaroo.
I said the words: "Don't
forget my father's watch."
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE STOPS]
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Visit the
Jackrabbit Slim's nearest you…
[CAR HORN PLAYING "LA CUCARACHA"]
RADIO ANNOUNCER: ¡El burro!
[ICE CREAM TRUCK BELLS]
[CHILDREN PLAYING, CRYING]
[WOMAN, CHILDREN TALKING]
-[GIRL TALKING]
-[DOG BARKING]
[WOMAN CONTINUES TALKING]
Lookin' good, Butch.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[CRASH, GLASS SHATTERING]
[SMOKE ALARM BEEPING]
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
[BEEPING CONTINUES, FAINT]
[BABY TALKING]
-[ENGINE STARTS]
-[RADIO PLAYING "FLOWERS ON THE WALL"]
♪ If I were walkin' in your shoes ♪
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
♪ Countin' flowers on the wall
That don't bother me at all ♪
♪ Playin' solitaire till
dawn with a deck of 51 ♪
That's how you're gonna beat 'em, Butch.
♪ Smokin' cigarettes and
watchin' Captain Kangaroo ♪
They keep underestimatin' ya.
♪ Now don't tell me ♪
[SINGING ALONG]
♪ Countin' flowers on the wall ♪
♪ That don't bother me at all ♪
♪ Playin' solitaire till
dawn with a deck of 51 ♪
♪ Smokin' cigarettes and
watchin' Captain Kangaroo ♪
♪ Now don't tell me ♪
♪ I've nothin' to do ♪
♪ It's good to see you I must go ♪
♪ I know I look a fright ♪
♪ Anyway my eyes ♪
Motherfucker.
-♪ Are not accustomed… ♪
-Uhh!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
WOMAN: Do you think he's dead? He's dead.
Oh, my God. He's dead.
If you need someone
to go to court, I'll be
glad to help.
That guy was a drunken maniac.
He hit you, then he
crashed into that car.
Who? Him.
I'll be damned.
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING, PANTING]
-[GUNSHOT]
-Ohh!
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
-[SCREAMS] I'm shot!
-[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[GRUNTING, GROANING]
-[GRUNTS]
-[GUNSHOT]
-MAN: Sally! Sally!
-[GRUNTING CONTINUES]
[PANTING]
-[GUNSHOT]
-Aaah!
[WHISTLING ON RADIO]
MARSELLUS [MUFFLED]: Motherfucker!
-[DOOR BELLS JINGLING]
-[PANTING]
Can I help you with somethin'?
Shut the fuck up.
Now you just wait a goddamn minute, now!
What the fuck you up to?
-Come here, motherfucker!
-[BOTH GRUNTING, GROANING]
MARSELLUS [GROANING]: You
feel that sting, huh, big boy?
That's pride fuckin' with you, see?
You gotta fight through that shit!
[GRUNTING] Huh?
-You'd better kill me…
-Yeah, somebody's gonna get killed.
Somebody's gonna get their
motherfuckin' head blown to
-[SHOTGUN COCKS]
-Hold it right there, goddamn it.
This ain't none of your business, mister.
I'm makin' it my business.
-Toss the weapon.
-You don't understand, man.
Toss the weapon.
[PANTING]
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: ♪ It's time ♪
-♪ To find love ♪
-Take your foot off the nigger.
-[MUSIC CONTINUES]
-Put your hand behind your head,
approach the counter right now.
-This motherfucker's trying to…
-[GROANS]
kill me. Shut up.
Keep comin'. Come on.
♪ If love ♪
♪ Is shelter ♪
[ROTARY DIALING]
[WHISTLING ON RADIO]
Zed. Maynard.
Yeah, the spider just
caught a couple flies.
♪ Whoa, my angel ♪
[RECEIVER HANGS UP]
♪ Down to you ♪
[BOTH GRUNTING, GROANING]
[COUGHING]
[GAGGING]
Nobody kills anybody
in my place of business…
-Except me or Zed.
-[DOORBELL CHIMES]
That's Zed.
[DOOR BELLS JINGLING]
ZED: I thought you
said you waited for me.
MAYNARD: I did.
[FOOTSTEPS DESCENDING STAIRS]
ZED: Then how come they're all beat up?
They did that to each other, man.
They came in fightin'.
Now, this 'un right here,
he was gonna shoot that one.
Is that right?
You gonna shoot him, boy?
Huh?
Hey, is Grace all right out front?
Yeah. It ain't Tuesday, is it?
No, it's Thursday.
She oughta be fine. Mmm.
[SIGHS] Well, bring out the gimp.
I think the gimp's sleepin'.
Then I guess you'll just have to
go wake him up now, won't you?
Get up.
Get down.
[TAPPING FINGERS]
Which one of 'em you wanna do first?
-[TAPPING FINGERS]
-ZED: I ain't for sure yet.
[WHISPERING] Eenie-meenie-minie-mo,
catch a nigger… by his toe.
If he hollers, let him go.
Eenie-meenie-minie-mo.
My mother said… pick the perfect one,
and… you… are…
It.
-ZED: Guess that means you, big boy.
-[MUFFLED] Fuck you!
-[MUFFLED MUMBLING]
-Shh.
You wanna do it in here?
No, let's take him back
to Russell's old room.
Sounds good to me.
[MUFFLED YELLING]
[GRUNTING]
You keep an eye on this 'un. [SNIFFS]
["COMANCHE" BY THE REVELS ON RADIO]
[ZED, MAYNARD TALKING, YELLING]
-[GRUNTING]
-[TALKING, YELLING CONTINUE]
[LOUD, RHYTHMIC GRUNTING]
-[GIGGLING]
-[GRUNTING CONTINUES] Yeah!
[GRUNTING, STRAINING]
ZED [SHOUTING]: Now! Go!
Come on, motherfucker!
-Now, motherfucker! Aaah! [GRUNTING]
-[GIGGLING CONTINUES]
-[SLAPPING]
-ZED [SHOUTING]: Come on! Yeah!
-[MUSIC CONTINUES]
-[MUFFLED YELLING]
-[GRUNTING CONTINUES]
-ZED: Yeah!
[SLAPPING, GRUNTING CONTINUE]
Ohh! Yeah!
-[CONTINUES, FAINT]
-ZED [FAINT]: Yeah! Yeah!
Yeee! Yeeee-hah!
[YELLING CONTINUES]
[DOOR BELLS JINGLING]
[LOUD GRUNT, YELLING]
[GRUNTING, YELLING CONTINUE]
ZED: Yeah!
[YELLING CONTINUES]
[LOUD, RHYTHMIC GRUNTING CONTINUES]
Come on! Get down there!
Aaah! Do it! Yeah!
[MUSIC CONTINUES, LOUDER]
ZED [SHOUTING]: Yeah! Yeah!
[YELLING CONTINUES]
[MARSELLUS SCREAMING, MUFFLED]
-MAYNARD: Shut the fuck up!
-[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
MAYNARD: Fuck him!
ZED: Come on!
-[MARSELLUS GROANING, MUFFLED]
-Fuck him. Yeah.
[CONTINUES YELLING, STOPS]
[SCREAMS]
[GROANING]
-[YELLS]
-[MUSIC FINISHES]
[GROANS]
-[GROANS]
-[THUD]
You want that gun, don't ya, Zed?
Huh?
Go ahead and pick it up.
Go ahead, pick it up.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Come on… Thatta boy!
I want you to pick it up, Zed.
[SHOTGUN COCKING]
-[BREATHING SLOWLY]
-Step aside, Butch.
[ZED WHEEZING]
Fuck! [GROANING]
-You okay?
-[GROANING CONTINUES]
No, man.
I'm pretty fuckin' far from okay.
[ZED SCREAMS]
[LOUD, HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM]
-[GROANING CONTINUES]
-What now?
"What now"?
-Let me tell you what now.
-[GROANING, COUGHING]
I'm gonna call a couple of
hard, pipe-hittin' niggers…
To go to work on the homes here…
With a pair of pliers and a blowtorch.
You hear me talkin', hillbilly boy?
I ain't through with you by a damn sight!
I'm gonna get medieval on your ass.
I meant what now between me and you.
Oh, that "what now."
-I tell you what now between me and you.
-[WHEEZING]
There is no me and you.
Not no more.
[GROANING, COUGHING]
So, are we cool?
Yeah, we cool.
-[LOUD GROAN]
-Two things:
Don't tell nobody about this.
This shit is between me, you…
And Mr. "Soon-to-be-livin'
the-rest-of-his-short-ass-
life-in-agonizing-pain"…
Rapist here.
It ain't nobody else's business.
Two… You leave town tonight. Right now.
And when you gone, you stay gone,
-or you be gone.
-[LOUD GROAN, COUGHING]
You lost all your LA privileges. Deal?
Deal.
Get your ass outta here.
[ZED WHEEZING]
[GROANING]
[GROANING CONTINUES]
Oh, shit.
[DOOR BELLS JINGLING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE STOPS]
Fabienne! [GROANS]
Fabienne! [GROANING CONTINUES]
Fabienne! Come on, baby.
Come on. Get your shit.
We gotta go right now. I was so worried.
What about our bags? Fuck the bags; if we
don't split right now,
we'll miss the train.
I'll be downstairs. Is everything well?
Just come on! No talking now!
Are we in danger?
[GROANING CONTINUES]
Come on, honey!
Where did you get this motorcycle?
It's not a motorcycle, baby.
It's a chopper. Let's go.
What happened to my Honda?
I'm sorry, baby, I had to crash that
Honda. Will you come on now, please?
Come on, let's go, let's go, let's go.
You're hurt? No, no, I might've
broken my nose. It's no biggie.
Come on. Hop on. Baby, please, we…
Honey, we gotta hit the fuckin' road!
Get on!
Oh, baby, I'm sorry.
Come here, come here.
[WEEPING QUIETLY]
I'm sorry. Mmm.
I'm so sorry. You were gone so long,
I started to think dreadful thoughts.
I didn't mean to worry you.
Everything's fine.
How was your breakfast? It was good.
Did you get the blueberry pancakes?
They didn't have blueberry; I had to
get buttermilk. Are you sure you're okay?
Since I left you, this has
been, without a doubt,
the single weirdest fuckin' day
of my life… I'll tell you all about it.
Gotta go. Come on.
Butch, whose motorcycle is this?
It's a chopper, baby.
Whose chopper is this?
Zed's. Who's Zed?
Zed's dead, baby. Zed's dead.
[ENGINE STARTS]
JULES: Yes, you did, Brett!
You tried to fuck him, and Marsellus
Wallace don't liked to be fucked…
By anybody except Mrs. Wallace. [PANTING]
Oh, God, please, I don't wanna die.
You read the Bible, Brett?
[WHIMPERING]
Yes! Well, there's this
passage I got memorized.
Sorta fits the occasion.
Ezekiel 25:17.
"The path of the righteous
man is beset on all sides…
"By the inequities of the selfish…"
-"And the tyranny of evil men."
-[WHIMPERING CONTINUES]
"Blessed is he who, in the
name of charity and good will,"
"shepherds the weak
through the valley of darkness,"
"for he is truly his brother's keeper…"
"And the finder of lost children."
"And I will strike down upon
thee with great vengeance…"
"And furious anger…"
"Those who attempt to poison
and destroy my brothers."
"And you will know my name is the Lord…"
When I lay my vengeance upon thee."
-[GROANS LOUDLY]
-[GUNSHOTS]
[SCREAMS]
I'm fucked. Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
VINCENT: Is he a friend of yours?
Oh, goddamn. Goddamn.
JULES: Hmm? Oh.
Vincent, Marvin. Marvin, Vincent.
Better tell him to shut up. He's
gettin' on my nerves. Fuck. [MUTTERING]
Marvin. Marvin!
I'd knock that shit off if I was you.
-[DOOR SLAMS]
-Die, you motherfuckers! Die!
[HAMMER CLICKING]
Why the fuck didn't you tell us
somebody was in the bathroom?
Slip your mind?
Did you forget that someone was in there…
With a goddamn hand cannon?
You see the size of that gun he
fired at us? It was bigger than him.
We should be fuckin' dead, man.
I know. We was lucky.
No, no, no, no. That shit wasn't luck.
-Yeah, maybe.
-This was divine intervention.
You know what divine intervention is?
I think so.
That means that God came down
from heaven and stopped the bullets.
That's right.
That's exactly what it means.
God came down from heaven and
stopped these motherfuckin' bullets.
I think it's time for us to leave, Jules.
Don't do that.
Don't fuckin' blow this shit off!
What just happened
here was a fuckin' miracle!
Chill. This shit happens.
Wrong! Wrong.
This shit doesn't "just happen."
Do you want to continue this
theological discussion in a car…
Or in a jailhouse with the cops?
We should be fuckin' dead, my friend!
What happened here was a miracle,
and I want you to fucking acknowledge it!
All right, it was a miracle.
Can we go now?
Let's go, nigga! Come on! Shit.
VINCENT: You ever seen that show Cops?
I was watching it one time
and there was this cop on,
and he was talkin' about this gunfight he
had in the hallway with this guy, right?
He just unloaded on this guy and
nothin' happened. He didn't hit nothin'.
Okay? It was just him and this guy.
I mean, you know, it's-it's
freaky, but it happens.
You wanna play blind
man, go walk with the
shepherd, but me, my
eyes are wide fuckin' open.
-What the fuck does that mean?
-It means that's it for me.
From here on in, you can
consider my ass retired.
Jesus Christ. Goddamn it.
Don't blaspheme.
I said, don't do that!
Hey, why are you
fuckin' freakin' out on us?
Look, I'm tellin' Marsellus today…
I'm through.
Why don't you tell him
at the same time why?
Don't worry, I will.
And I bet you $10,000
he laughs his ass off.
I don't give a damn if he does.
[SIGHS] Marvin, what
do you make of all this?
Man, I don't even have an opinion.
You gotta have an opinion. You think
God came down from heaven and stopped
-[GUNSHOT]
-What the fuck's happenin'?
Aw, shit, man! Aw, man!
Oh, man, I shot Marvin in the face.
Why the fuck'd you do that?
I didn't mean it. It was an accident.
Man, I seen some crazy-ass shit
in my time, but this… Chill out, man!
It was an accident.
We probably went over a bump or somethin'.
The car ain't hit no motherfuckin' bump.
I didn't mean to shoot the son of a bitch.
The gun went off.
Look at this fuckin' mess! We're on
a city street in broad daylight here!
I don't believe it!
Well, believe it now, motherfucker!
We gotta get this car off the road. Cops
notice shit like a car drenched in blood.
Just take it to a friendly place,
that's all! This is the Valley, Vincent.
Marsellus ain't got no
friendly places in the Valley.
Well, Jules, this ain't my
fuckin' town, man! Shit!
What you doing?
I'm calling my partner in Toluca Lake.
Where's Toluca Lake?
Over the hill here, by Burbank Studios.
If Jimmie's ass ain't home, I don't
know what the fuck we gonna do,
'cause I ain't got no
other partners in 818.
Jimmie, how you doin', man?
It's Jules. Just listen up, man.
Me and my homeboy are in a car,
and we gotta get it off the road, pronto.
I need to use your
garage for a couple hours.
We gotta be real fuckin'
delicate with this Jimmie situation.
He's one remark away from
kickin' our asses out the door.
If he does, what do we do? We
ain't leavin' till we make a couple calls,
but I don't want it to reach that pitch…
Jimmie's a friend.
You don't come into your friend's
house and start tellin' him what's what.
Just tell him not to be abusive.
He kinda freaked out back
there when he saw Marvin.
Put yourself in his position…
It's 8:00 in the morning, he just woke up.
He wasn't expectin' this shit.
We gotta remember here
who's doin' who a favor.
If that favor means I gotta take shit, he
can stick that favor straight up his ass.
Fuck, nigga, what the fuck'd you just do
to his towel, man? I was dryin' my hands!
You're supposed to wash 'em first!
You watched me wash 'em.
I watched you get 'em wet. I was
washin' 'em. This shit's hard to get off.
Maybe if he'd had Lava I
coulda done a better job.
I used the same fuckin' soap you did,
and when I finished, the towel
didn't look like no goddamn maxi-pad!
What if he was to come in
here and see his towel like this?
It's shit like this that's gonna
bring this situation to a head, man!
Look, I ain't threatenin'
you or nothin', all right?
You know I respect you and all. But just
don't put me in this position, all right?
All right. Fine. Fine.
Ask me nice like that, no problem.
Just go handle your friend.
Go ahead. I don't care.
Mmm! Goddamn, Jimmie!
This some serious gourmet shit.
Me and Vincent would've been satisfied…
With some freeze-dried Taster's Choice.
Right? [CHUCKLES]
And he springs this
serious gourmet shit on us.
-What flavor is this?
-Knock it off, Julie.
What?
I don't need you to tell me
how fuckin' good my coffee is.
I'm the one who buys it.
I know how good it is.
When Bonnie goes shopping, she buys shit.
I buy the gourmet expensive stuff
'cause when I drink it, I wanna taste it.
But you know what's on my mind right now?
It ain't the coffee in my kitchen.
It's the dead nigger in my garage.
Jimmie, don't even worry…
-Don't tell me about anything.
I wanna ask you a question.
When you came pulling in here,
did you notice the sign on the front of
my house that said, "Dead nigger storage"?
You know I ain't seen no…
Did you notice the sign
on the front of my house…
That said, "Dead nigger storage"?
No. I didn't.
You know why you didn't see that sign?
[SIGHS] Why?
'Cause it ain't there,
'cause storing dead
niggers ain't my fuckin'
business, that's why!
-We're not gonna store the motherfucker…
-Don't you fuckin' realize…
That if Bonnie comes
home and finds a dead
body in her house,
I'm gonna get divorced?
No marriage counselor. No trial
separation.
I'm gonna get fuckin' divorced.
Okay?
And I don't wanna get fuckin' divorced!
Man, you know, fuck, I wanna help you,
but I don't wanna lose my wife doin' it.
Jimmie, Jimmie, she
ain't gonna leave you.
Don't fuckin' "Jimmie" me, Jules!
Okay? Don't fuckin' "Jimmie" me.
There's nothin' you're
gonna say that's gonna
make me forget I love my wife. Is there?
Now, look, you know, she comes home
from work in about an hour and a half.
The graveyard shift at the hospital.
You gotta make some phone calls?
You gotta call some people?
Well, then, do it, and then get the fuck
out of my house before she gets here.
That's Kool & the Gang.
We don't wanna fuck your shit up.
All I wanna do is call my
people and get 'em to bring us in.
You're fucking my shit up right now!
You're gonna fuck my shit up
big time if Bonnie comes home.
Do me that favor, all right? The phone is
in my bedroom. I suggest you get going.
Well, say she comes home.
What do you think she'll do?
Oh, no fuckin' shit she'll freak.
That ain't no kinda answer.
I mean, you know, I don't.
How much? A lot or a little?
You got to appreciate
what an explosive element…
This Bonnie situation is.
She comes home from a hard day's work,
finds a bunch of gangsters in her kitchen…
Doing a bunch of gangster shit,
there ain't no tellin'
what she's liable to do.
[ALL GASPING]
Yeah, I grasp that, Jules.
All I'm doing is contemplating the ifs.
I don't wanna hear
about no motherfuckin' ifs!
All I want to hear from
your ass is, "You ain't
got no problem, Jules,
I'm on the motherfucker.
Chill them niggas out and wait for the
cavalry, which should be coming directly."
You ain't got no problem, Jules.
I'm on the motherfucker.
Chill them niggas out and wait for
the Wolf, who should be coming directly.
You sendin' the Wolf?
Oh, you feel better, motherfucker?
Shit, yeah, negro!
That's all you had to say!
-[PIANO PLAYING]
-MAN: She the hysterical type?
-When is she due?
-[PARTYGOERS CHATTERING]
Mm-hmm.
Give me the principals' names again.
MAN: Place your bets.
Jules. Mm-hmm. Cards, please.
Vincent.
Jimmie.
Bonnie. Mm-hmm.
It's 30 minutes away.
I'll be there in ten.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
You're…Jimmie, right? This is your house?
It sure is. I'm Winston Wolf.
I solve problems.
Good. We got one.
So I heard. May I come in?
Uh, yeah. Please do.
You must be Jules.
Which would make you… Vincent.
Let's get down to brass tacks, gentlemen.
If I was informed correctly, the
clock is ticking. Is that right, Jimmie?
Uh, one hundred percent.
Your wife Bonnie comes home at
9:30 in the a.m., correct? Uh-huh.
I was led to believe if
she comes home and
finds us here, she
wouldn't appreciate it much.
She wouldn't at that. That gives us
40 minutes to get the fuck outta Dodge,
which, if you do what I say,
when I say it, should be plenty.
Now, you got a corpse in a car,
minus a head, in a garage. Take me to it.
[SIGHS]
Jimmie. Uh-huh.
Do me a favor, will ya?
Thought I smelled some coffee back there.
Would you make me a cup? Uh, yeah, sure.
Oh, uh, um, how do you take it?
Lotsa cream, lotsa sugar.
About the car, is there anything
I need to know? Does it stall?
Does it smoke? Does it make
a lot of noise? Is there gas in it?
Aside from how it looks, the car's cool.
Positive?
Don't get me on the road and I
find out the brake lights don't work.
As far as I know, the
motherfucker's tip-top. Good enough.
Let's go back to the kitchen.
[EXHALES]
Here you go, Mr. Wolf. Thank you, Jimmie.
Mmm.
Okay, first thing. You two.
Take the body, stick it in the trunk.
This looks to be a pretty
domesticated house.
That would lead me to believe you got
cleansers and shit. Yeah. Under the sink.
Good. What I need you two fellas to
do is take those cleaning products…
And clean the inside of the car…
I'm talkin' fast, fast, fast.
Go in the back seat, scoop up all
those little pieces of brain and skull.
Get it out of there.
Wipe down the upholstery.
It don't need to be spick-and-span.
You don't need to eat off it.
Just give it a good once-over.
What you need
to take care of are
the really messy parts.
The pools of blood that have
collected, you gotta soak that shit up.
We need to raid your linen closet.
I need blankets, I need
comforters, quilts, bedspreads.
The thicker the better, the darker
the better. No whites. Can't use 'em.
We'll need to camouflage the front
seat and back seat and floorboards…
With quilts and blankets,
so if a cop starts stickin' his big snout
in the car, the subterfuge won't last,
but at a glance the car
will appear to be normal.
Jimmie, lead the way. Boys, get to work.
"Please" would be nice.
-Come again?
-I said, a "please" would be nice.
Get it straight, buster. I'm not here to
say please.
I'm here to tell you what to do.
And if self-preservation
is an instinct you possess,
you'd better fuckin'
do it and do it quick.
I'm here to help. If my help's not
appreciated, lotsa luck, gentlemen.
No, Mr. Wolf, it ain't like that;
your help is definitely appreciated.
Mr. Wolf, listen. I don't mean
disrespect, okay? I respect you.
I just don't like people
barkin' orders at me.
If I'm curt with you, it's
because time is a factor.
I think fast, I talk fast, and I need you
guys to act fast if you
wanna get out of this.
So pretty please, with sugar
on top, clean the fuckin' car.
Don't be lookin' at me like that,
all right? I can feel your look.
It's a 1974 Chevy Nova.
[SIPPING]
Green.
Nothin' except for the mess inside.
Mmm, about 20 minutes.
Nobody who'll be missed.
You're a good man, Joe. Thanks a bunch.
How we comin', Jimmie? Pretty good.
I got it all here, but, uh, [SIGHS]
Mr. Wolf, you gotta understand something.
Winston, Jimmie, Winston.
Okay. You gotta understand
something, uh, Winston.
Uh… Uh, no, thank you.
Uh, this is our best linen here,
and it's, uh… it was a wedding present…
From my uncle Conrad and my aunt Ginny.
They're not with us anymore.
I wanna help… Let me ask you a question.
If you don't mind.
No, no, please. Go ahead.
Your uncle Conrad and Aunt
Ginny, were they millionaires?
No.
Well, your uncle Marsellus is.
And I'm positive that if
Uncle Conrad and Aunt…
Ginny. Ginny were here,
they would furnish you
with a whole bedroom set,
which your uncle Marsellus
is more than happy to do.
I like oak myself.
That's what I have in my bedroom.
How about you, Jimmie?
You an oak man?
Oak's nice.
Oh, man, I will never
forgive your ass for this shit.
This is some fucked-up, repugnant shit.
Jules, did you ever hear the philosophy
that once a man admits that he is wrong,
that he is immediately
forgiven for all wrongdoings?
Get the fuck out my face with that shit!
The motherfucker
that said that shit never
had to pick up
itty-bitty pieces of skull…
On account of your dumb ass. I got a
threshold, Jules, for
the abuse that I will take.
Right now, I'm a fuckin' race
car, and you got me in the red.
I'm just sayin' it's fuckin' dangerous
to have a race car in the fuckin' red.
That's all. I could blow.
Oh, you ready to blow? Yeah.
Well, I'm a mushroom-cloud-layin'
motherfucker, motherfucker.
Every time my fingers
touch brain, I'm Superfly TNT.
I'm the Guns of the Navarone.
In fact, what the fuck
am I doin' in the back?
You're the motherfucker should be
on brain detail! We're fuckin' switchin'!
I'm washin' windows, you're
pickin' up this nigga's skull!
Fine job, gentlemen.
You may get out of this yet.
I can't believe this is the same car.
Well, let's not start suckin'
each other's dicks quite yet.
Phase one is complete… clean the car…
which moves us right along to phase two:
clean you two.
Strip.
-All the way?
-WOLF: To your bare ass.
Quickly, gentlemen.
We got about 15 minutes…
Before Jimmie's better half
comes pulling into the driveway.
Goddamn, this morning
air is some chilly shit.
Are you sure this is
absolutely necessary?
-You know what you two look like?
-VINCENT: What?
Like a couple of guys who
just blew off somebody's head.
Strippin' off those bloody
rags is absolutely necessary.
Toss 'em in Jimmie's garbage bag.
Don't do nothin'
stupid, like leavin' this
shit out front for the
garbageman to pick up.
Don't worry, we're taking it with us.
Jim, the soap.
-Vincent.
-WOLF: Okay, gentlemen.
You both been to county before, I'm sure.
Here it comes.
Goddamn! The water's fuckin' cold!
Yo! Yo! Yo!
Better you than me, gentlemen.
[CHUCKLING]
Don't be afraid of the soap.
Spread it around.
[YELLING CONTINUES]
Get 'em there a little bit.
Vincent's hair.
Hey, get out of my hair!
-Come on, do it, goddamn it! Do it!
-Uh, um…
Towel.
WOLF: You're dry enough.
Toss 'em their clothes.
WOLF [LAUGHING]: Perfect.
Perfect.
We couldn't have planned this better.
You guys look like…
What do they look like, Jimmie?
Dorks. They look like a couple of dorks.
[LAUGHING]
-[BOTH LAUGHING]
-Ha-ha-ha.
They're your clothes, motherfucker.
Come on, gentlemen.
We're laughing our way right into prison.
Don't make me beg.
Okay, gentlemen, let's get
our rules of the road straight.
We're going to a place called
Monster Joe's Truck and Tow.
Monster Joe and his daughter
Raquel are sympathetic to our dilemma.
The place is North Hollywood,
so a few twists and turns aside,
we'll be goin' up Hollywood Way.
Now, I'll drive the tainted car.
Jules, you ride with me.
Vincent, you follow in my Acura.
Now, if we come across
the path of any John Q. Laws,
nobody does a fuckin' thing
till I do something. Right.
What did I say? Don't do shit unless.
Unless what? Unless you do it first.
Spoken like a true prodigy.
How about you, Lash LaRue? Can you keep
your spurs from jingling and jangling?
The gun went off. I don't know why.
I'm cool, I promise you.
Fair enough. Now, I drive
real fuckin' fast, so keep up.
If I get my car back any
different than I gave it,
Monster Joe's gonna be
disposing of two bodies.
-[METAL DOOR SLAMMING]
-[ENGINE IDLING]
Outta my way, Rex.
-We cool?
-Like it never happened.
-VINCENT: All right.
-Boys, this is Raquel.
Someday all this will be hers.
Hi. So, what's with the outfits?
You guys going to a
volleyball game or something?
[WOLF LAUGHS]
I'm takin' milady out to breakfast.
Maybe I could drop you two off.
Where do you live?
Redondo. Inglewood.
It's… It's your future. I…
I see a… a cab ride.
Move outta the sticks, fellas.
Say good night, Raquel.
Good night, Raquel.
I'll see you guys around.
Stay outta trouble, you crazy kids.
Mr. Wolf, I just wanna tell you it
was a real pleasure watching you work.
Yeah, really.
And thank you very much, Mr. Wolf.
Call me Winston.
-You see that, young lady? Respect.
-[ALARM DEACTIVATES]
Respect for one's elders shows character.
I have character.
Because you are a character doesn't
mean that you have character. [CHUCKLES]
-[TIRES SCREECHING]
-Wanna share a cab?
I'd go for some breakfast. Feel like
-havin' breakfast with me?
-[PHONE DIALING]
Cool.
I don't know why, I just thought
he'd be European or something.
Yeah, he's about as European as
fuckin' English Bob. I know that now.
But was he cool or what? Thank you.
Totally fuckin' cool, in control.
Didn't even really get pissed when
you were fuckin' with him; I was amazed.
[CHUCKLES] Want some bacon?
No, man, I don't eat pork.
Are you Jewish? I ain't Jewish; I
just don't dig on swine, that's all.
Why not? Pigs are filthy animals.
I don't eat filthy animals.
Yeah, but bacon tastes good.
Pork chops taste good.
Sewer rat may taste like
pumpkin pie, but I'd never know…
'Cause I wouldn't eat
the filthy motherfuckers.
Pigs sleep and root in shit.
That's a filthy animal.
I ain't eatin' nothin' ain't got sense
enough to disregard its own feces.
How about a dog? Dog eats its own feces.
I don't eat dog either.
Yeah, but do you consider
a dog to be a filthy animal?
I wouldn't go so far
as to call a dog filthy,
but they're definitely dirty.
But a dog's got personality. Personality
goes a long way.
Ah, so, by that rationale,
if a pig had a better personality,
he would cease to be a filthy animal.
Is that true? We'd have to be talkin'
about one charming motherfuckin' pig.
I mean, he'd have to be ten times more
charming than that Arnold on Green Acres.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Oh, man, that's good.
That's good, man.
You're startin' to lighten up.
You've been sittin'
there, all serious and shit.
I just been sittin' here, thinkin'.
About what?
-About the miracle we witnessed.
-Miracle you witnessed.
-I witnessed a freak occurrence.
-What is a miracle, Vincent?
Act of God. And what's an act of God?
When, um, God makes
the impossible possible.
But this morning…
I don't think qualifies. Hey, Vincent.
See, that shit don't matter.
You're judging this shit the wrong way.
It could be God stopped the bullets,
changed Coke to Pepsi, found my car keys.
You don't judge shit
like this based on merit.
Now, whether or not what we experienced…
Was an According-to-Hoyle
miracle is insignificant.
But what is significant
is, I felt the touch of God.
God got involved.
But why?
Well, that's what's fuckin'
with me: I don't know why.
-But I can't go back to sleep.
-You're serious.
You're really thinkin' about quittin'.
For life? Most definitely. Yeah.
Fuck. What you gonna do then?
Well, that's what I been
sitting here contemplating.
First I'm gonna deliver
this case to Marsellus.
Then, basically, I'm
just gonna walk the earth.
-What you mean, "Walk the earth"?
-Like Caine in Kung Fu.
Walk from place to place,
meet people, get in adventures.
And how long do you
intend to walk the earth?
Till God puts me where he wants me to be.
What if he don't do that?
If it takes forever,
then I'll walk forever.
So you decided to be a bum.
I'll just be Jules, Vincent.
No more, no less.
No, Jules, you decided to be a bum,
just like all those pieces of shit
out there who beg for change,
who sleep in garbage
bins, eat what I throw away.
They got a name for that, Jules…
It's called a bum.
And without a job, a residence or legal
tender, that's what you're gonna be, man.
You're gonna be a fuckin' bum.
Look, my friend, this is
just where you and I differ.
Garçon! Coffee!
Jules, look, what happened this
morning, man, I agree it was peculiar.
-But water into wine, I…
-All shapes and sizes, Vincent.
-Don't fuckin' talk to me that way, man.
-If my answers frighten you,
then you should cease
asking scary questions.
I'm gonna take a shit.
Let me ask you something.
When did you make this decision, when
you were sittin' there eatin' that muffin?
Yeah. I was sittin' here eatin'
my muffin, drinkin' my coffee,
replayin' the incident in my head,
when I had what alcoholics
refer to as a moment of clarity.
Fuck. To be continued.
I love you, pumpkin.
I love you, honey bunny.
-Everybody be cool! This is a robbery!
-[CUSTOMERS MURMURING]
Any one of you fucking
pricks move and I'll
execute every one of you motherfuckers!
You got that? You just be quiet
over there! Waitresses on the floor!
Get on the fuckin'… get the fuck down!
You're in a blind spot. Take your dames
over to that booth, on the count often!
-Mexicans, out of the fucking kitchen!
-1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8…
What the fuck are you doing,
you fucking yuppie? Get down!
-Get down!
-Throw those bags!
-Fucking move! Move!
-[RANCHERO MUSIC]
-[COOKS SPEAKING SPANISH]
-Move! Get the fuck…
Get down on the fucking floor!
Grandpa! Down!
I'm the manager here, and there's
no problem. No problem at all.
You gonna give me a problem?
No, sir, I'm not.
Thought you said you were
gonna give me a fucking problem!
-I think we got a hero here, honey bunny.
-Well, just execute him!
[PANTING] I am not a hero.
I'm just a coffee shop manager.
Get the fuck down!
The restaurant's ours!
Just take whatever you want. [PANTING]
You talk to the customers. Yeah.
You tell them to be fucking
cool and everything will be over.
You understand me? Yes!
Listen, everybody. Be calm, cooperate,
and this'll all be over in a minute!
Get the fuck down! Well done.
[COUNTRY/WESTERN MUZAK]
All right, now, people, gonna
come around and collect your wallets!
You don't fucking talk, you just
throw 'em in the bag! Are we clear?
I said, are we fucking clear?
Good! Now, wallets out!
PUMPKIN: That's it.
Get the fuck down. In the bag.
In the fucking bag!
CUSTOMER: I don't
have nothin' on me, man.
In the bag.
What am I waiting for?
In the fucking bag.
Laura. Laura. Tips. In the bag.
Is that a cellular phone? Yeah.
In the fucking bag.
Tidy up, tidy up, that's it.
Now get the fuck down on the floor.
In the bag. In the bag.
In the bag.
-What's in the case?
-My boss' dirty laundry.
Your boss makes you do his laundry?
When he wants it clean.
-Sounds like a shit job.
-Funny, I was thinkin' the same thing.
-Open it.
-'Fraid I can't do that.
-I didn't hear you.
-Yes, you did.
What's going on?
Looks like we got a
vigilante in our midst.
Shoot him in the face!
I hate to shatter
your ego, but this ain't
the first time I've had
a gun pointed at me.
If you don't take your hand
off that case, it'll be your last.
Stop causing problems!
You'll get us all killed! Give 'em
what you got and get 'em outta here!
Shut the fuck up, fat man!
This ain't none of your goddamn business!
Be cool, honey bunny, be cool.
No problem. I got it under control.
Now, I'm gonna count to three.
If you don't open that case, I'm
gonna unload in your fucking face.
We clear?
One.
Two.
-Three.
-Okay, Ringo.
You win.
It's yours.
-Open it.
-[LATCHES SPRINGING]
HONEY BUNNY: Hey, what is it?
What is it?
Is that what I think it is?
Mm-hmm.
It's beautiful.
[GIGGLING] Goddamn it, what is it?
You let him go! You let him go!
-Let go of him, or I'm gonna kill you!
-Tell that bitch to be cool.
Say, "Bitch, be cool!"
Say, "Bitch, be cool!" Be cool! Be cool!
-Tell that bitch to chill!
-You're gonna die so fuckin' bad!
Chill that fuckin' bitch out!
Chill out, honey bunny!
-Let go of him!
-Chill out, honey bunny!
Now, promise her it's gonna be all right!
I promise!
Tell her to chill!
Chill out, honey bunny!
Now tell me her name. Yolanda.
All right, now, Yolanda, we're not
gonna do anything stupid, are we?
-Don't you hurt him!
-Nobody's gonna hurt anybody!
We're all gonna be like three little
Fonzies here. And what's Fonzie like?
Come on, Yolanda!
What's Fonzie like? He's cool.
What? Cool.
Correctamundo.
And that's what we're gonna be.
We're gonna be cool.
Now, Ringo, I'm gonna count to three.
And when I count three,
I want you to let go of your gun,
put your palms flat on the
table and sit your ass down.
And when you do it, you do it cool.
You ready?
One, two, three.
[PANTING] Okay, now you let him go!
Yolanda!
I thought you were gonna be cool. Now,
when you yell at me, it makes me nervous.
When I get nervous, I get scared.
When motherfuckers get scared, that's
when motherfuckers accidentally get shot.
Just know, you hurt him, you die.
Well, that seems to be the situation.
But I don't want that.
And you don't want that.
And Ringo here
definitely doesn't want that.
So let's see what we can do.
Now… here's the situation.
Normally both your asses would
be dead as fuckin' fried chicken,
but you happened to pull this
shit while I'm in a transitional period,
and I don't wanna kill
you; I wanna help you.
But I can't give you this case,
'cause it don't belong to me.
Besides, I been through too much
shit over this case this morning…
To just hand it over to your dumb ass.
-Vincent!
-[YELLS]
Be cool! Yolanda, it's cool, baby.
Get back!
It's cool! We still just talkin'.
Come on. Point the gun at me.
Point the gun at me.
[YOLANDA WHIMPERING]
There you go.
Now, Vincent, you just hang back…
And don't do a goddamn thing.
Tell her it's still cool.
It's still cool, honey bunny.
How we doin', baby?
I… I gotta go pee.
I wanna go home.
Hang in there, baby. I'm proud of you.
And Ringo's proud of you.
It's almost over.
Tell her you're proud of her.
-I'm proud of you, honey bunny.
-I love you.
I love you too, honey bunny. Now,
I want you to go in that
bag and find my wallet.
Which one is it?
It's the one that says "bad motherfucker."
That's it. That's my bad motherfucker.
Open it up. Take out the money.
JULES: Count it.
How much is there?
About 1,500 dollars.
Okay, put it in your pocket. It's yours.
Now, with the rest of those
wallets and the register,
that makes this a pretty
successful little score, huh?
Jules, you give that fuckin' nimrod 1,500
dollars, and I'll shoot
him on general principle.
No, Yolanda! Yolanda! He ain't gonna
do a goddamn, motherfuckin' thing!
Vince, shut the fuck up!
Shut up! Come on, Yolanda.
Stay with me, baby.
Now, I ain't givin' it to him, Vincent.
I'm buyin' something for my money.
Wanna know what I'm buyin', Ringo? What?
Your life. I'm givin' you that money
so I don't have to kill your ass.
You read the Bible, Ringo?
Not regularly, no.
Well, there's this
passage I got memorized.
Ezekiel 25:17.
"The path of the righteous
man is beset on all sides…
"By the inequities of the selfish…"
"And the tyranny of evil men."
"Blessed is he who, in the
name of charity and good will,"
"shepherds the weak
through the valley of darkness,"
"for he is truly his brother's
keeper and the finder of lost children."
"And I will strike down upon thee with
great vengeance and furious anger…"
"Those who attempt to poison
and destroy my brothers."
"And you will know I am the Lord…"
When I lay my vengeance upon you."
I been sayin' that shit for years,
and if you heard it, that meant your ass.
I never gave much
thought to what it meant.
I just thought it was some coldblooded
shit to say to a motherfucker…
Before I popped a cap in his ass.
But I saw some shit this
morning made me think twice.
See, now I'm thinkin' maybe it means…
You're the evil man, and
I'm the righteous man,
and Mr. 9-millimeter
here, he's the shepherd…
Protecting my righteous
ass in the Valley of Darkness.
Or it could mean…
You're the righteous
man, and I'm the shepherd,
and it's the world
that's evil and selfish.
Yeah, I'd like that.
But that shit ain't the truth.
The truth is,
you're the weak…
And I'm the tyranny of evil men.
But I'm tryin', Ringo.
I'm tryin' real hard…
To be the shepherd.
Go.
I think we should be leaving now.
-["SURF RIDER"]
-Yeah, that's probably a good idea.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]