People once believed
that when someone dies,
a crow carries their soul
to the land of the dead.
But sometimes, something so bad happens
that a terrible sadness is
carried with it, and the soul can't rest.
Then, sometimes, just sometimes,
the crow can bring that soul back
to put the wrong things right.
I got one here.
Over here.
Hey, Sarge.
Yeah?
Shelly Webster and Eric Draven.
Wedding was tomorrow night.
Who the fuck gets married
on Halloween anyhow?
Nobody.
-Sir, we gotta move her.
-Do it.
All right, guys. Let's do it.
Devil's fucking Night.
What's the count so far?
143 fires.
They're slacking off from last year.
Three hours to go.
Maybe they're just slow starters.
Coming through.
Yeah, I realize that,
but you can't come in here
and take her away like this.
There are procedures to stick by.
You guys should have cleared this
with me first.
Is this the victim?
No, it's Amelia Earhart.
We found her, Detective,
and you missed it.
I don't care what her name is.
I didn't give the order to move her.
Jesus, Albrecht. I can see why
they took away your gold shield.
Yeah, I wasn't a big enough asshole.
Come on. Let's go.
All right. Clear out of here.
-Shelly?
-Stand back, kid.
-Where's Eric?
-Just don't worry about him.
Tell him to take care of Sarah.
Look, I will. You just lie back.
Come on. Come on.
-Are you Sarah?
-Yeah.
Yeah, look. Your sister,
she's gonna be okay.
She's not my sister.
Shelly just takes care of me.
She's my friend.
Her and Eric.
You lied to her about Eric.
Look, I had to.
And you're lying to me about Shelly.
She's gonna die, isn't she?
Hey.
Now, come on. Come on. It's--
I promise. It's okay.
She's gonna be fine.
A building gets torched.
All that is left is ashes.
I used to think
that was true about everything.
Families, friends, feelings.
But now I know that sometimes,
if love proves real,
two people who are meant to be together--
nothing can keep them apart.
Later.
What are you, like the night watchman?
You know, what this place needs
is a good, natural catastrophe.
Earthquake, tornado-- you know?
No, no. Mickey, come on, man.
You got to put
the mustard underneath first.
Maybe a flood like in the Bible.
Hey, come on. Let me do it.
There we go. All right.
How about some onions?
Come on. Come on, man.
Don't cheap out on me. Lots of onions.
All right. Here you go.
All right.
Now we're talking.
Hey, it's a Sarah monster.
How do you steer that thing
on a wet street?
Pure talent. Hi.
See, now, Sarah,
she's a genuine hotdogger. You hungry?
-You buying?
-I'm buying.
-No onions though, okay?
-No onions?
They make you fart big-time.
You know,
Lake Erie actually caught on fire once
from all the crap floating around in it.
I wish I could have seen that.
-Fire it up!
-Yeah! Yeah!
All right. We busted that machine.
Boom!
Oh, shit, guys. T-Bird. Cop car. Cop car.
Bad people out on the street tonight.
-Damn it.
-Oh, my God!
What was that?
-You wait right here.
-Be careful.
Mickey, call it in for me.
Gabriel.
Eric?
Department of Housing.
Code violations? Safety hazards?
Place looks fine to me.
Let's redecorate.
"Abashed the Devil stood
and felt how awful goodness is."
Saw virtue in her shape, how lovely--"
It's pornography.
Virtue?
Shelly?
-No! Eric!
-See ya!
No, no, no, no. Me first.
Please.
-Shelly.
-Eric.
-Hey, that's good.
-That's good.
See if you can top that, man.
Can you top that?
Look at that. Look at that.
Here's to Devil's Night,
my new favorite holiday.
To Devil's Night.
Baby, you need to go over there
and talk to your pals.
You sick fuck.
Are you out of
your motherfucking mind, man?
And look at that!
Pussies drink last, man.
Fuck you, Tin Tin.
Hey.
That shit ain't even loaded, man.
This one is.
Which of you Motor City motherfuckers
wants to bet me this one isn't?
Hey!
-Fire it up!
Fire it up!
Here's your shooters.
-Put your guns away, guys.
-How you doing?
Pussycat.
Boo.
- I love you.
-Say that again.
I love you.
Oh, boy.
Restaurant.
Wow, you look great.
Yeah.
-Come here.
-No! No! No!
Couple more rings. That's 24K.
24K, huh? It's 18K.
It's crap. It's probably fake.
Leather purse. Leather.
Geez.
What is this, Tin Tin?
A bloodstain that's on here?
I'll give you 50 bucks.
And I hate charities.
Now, you can take it or leave it.
Right there for you.
Decisions, decisions. Yes, right.
Cheap-ass, chrome-dome,
child-molesting, saprophyte motherfucker.
Close the gate when you go out!
I close this up for you real good, massa.
Fuck you.
Yeah, sit on it and twirl, you dirty scum.
You're lucky I didn't stab your fat ass.
What the fuck you all painted up for,
crackhead. Huh?
Halloween ain't till manana.
Come on.
Fuck! You murderer!
I didn't murder nobody, man.
I don't even fucking know you, man.
-What the fuck you want, man?
-I want you to tell me a story.
A man and a woman in a loft a year ago.
-You're out of your motherfucking mind--
-Listen!
I'm sure you'll remember.
You killed them on Halloween.
Yeah, yeah. Right. Halloween, yeah.
Some dude, some bitch-- Whatever, man.
Her name was Shelly.
You cut her. You raped her.
Shelly, yeah. Yeah.
I shanked her pink ass, and she loved it!
Murder, man.
Murder? Let me tell you about murder.
It's fun.
It's easy.
You gonna learn all about it.
I'd like you to meet two buddies of mine.
We never miss.
Try harder. Try again.
Victims.
Aren't we all?
Sometimes it rains inside my head
All the words run dry
Walls are breathing, hands are reaching up
Look at this mess.
What's the world coming to?
Yeah, it's a mess.
To touch my thigh
No, they don't have to take you away
I got to go upstairs.
Report from the front.
No, they don't have to take you away
Get out of my way, you worms!
Give me some of that over there.
Why don't you ladies come by later?
Check me out.
Hey, guess what?
-Arcade Games fell down, went boom.
-Boom.
Can you imagine that? It's tragic.
Gather your soldiers.
You're on for tomorrow night. No sweat.
-Is the man in?
-He's taking a meeting.
You're thinking about the past.
Dad gave me this.
Fifth birthday.
He said, "Childhood's over
the moment you know you're gonna die."
Is she asleep?
I think we broke her.
I love her eyes.
Pretty.
No, they don't have to take you away
Hey, kid, get the hell out of the road!
I told you to stay out of here.
So I guess you're not gonna be home
till a lot later, huh, Darla?
She's busy.
Go play with your dolls
or something, okay?
I don't have any dolls.
Get some food.
Somebody already bought me dinner.
The police.
"Somebody already bought me dinner.
The police."
Who the fuck is this now?
Hey! Piss off! We're closed!
Cerrado!
Go sleep it off somewhere else, dust head,
unless you want to get mutilated.
I'm gonna blow this guy's dick off.
Goddamn creatures of the night.
They never learn.
Hey! Hey!
"Suddenly I heard a tapping,
as if someone gently rapping--
rapping at my chamber door."
What the fuck are you talking about?
You heard me rapping, right?
You're trespassing,
and you owe me a fucking new door!
I'm looking for something
in an engagement ring.
-Yeah?
-Gold.
You're looking for a coroner,
shit-for-brains.
Oh, shit.
Shit on me!
Shit on me. Shit on me!
Mr. Gideon, you're not paying attention.
No! My hand!
I repeat: A gold engagement ring, yes?
It was pawned here a year ago
by a customer of yours named Tin Tin.
He confided in me
before he ran out of breath.
So who's this sack of shit?
That's Tin Tin,
one of T-Bird's little helpers.
I think you can rule out accidental death.
Don't any of your street demons
have real grown-up names?
This could be a turf hit,
but it doesn't look like
your usual gang crap.
Come on, Albrecht. Spare me.
You're a beat cop now, so be a beat cop.
I'm supposed to thank you for that, right?
Word to the wise:
Watch your fucking mouth.
What the hell do you call that?
I call it blood, Detective.
I suppose you'll write it up as graffiti.
You can leave my crime scene now, okay?
-Warmer?
-What are you doing?
-Don't you know this game?
-What game are you talking about?
All right, the rings!
I'll tell you about the rings!
They're in that metal box.
It's under the shelf there.
Take them. Take the fucking rings!
You can chew them, and you can choke
on them, you son of a bitch!
-Look, it goes up to the attic.
-Okay.
No, no, no.
No, no.
It's beautiful. I don't believe it.
Shelly.
I love you.
-You have one chance to live.
-Look, man, take anything you want.
-Thank you.
-Take anything!
Now you're gonna tell me where to find
the rest of Tin Tin's little party pals.
The Pit. They all hang out at The Pit.
All of T-Bird's little potato heads
hang out there.
Funboy, he lives there--
upstairs, all right?
Funboy.
Oh, baby.
A whole jolly club...
-Stop! Jesus, stop.
-...with jolly pirate nicknames.
-Jesus Christ in a taxicab!
-Hold still!
Each one of these is a life.
A life you helped destroy.
I'm begging you, all right. Don't kill me.
I'm not gonna kill you.
Your job will be to tell the rest of them
that death is coming for them.
Tonight.
Tell them Eric Draven sends his regards.
You walk out of here,
they're gonna erase your sorry ass.
You're nothing but street grease,
you hear?
Street grease, you motherfucker!
Is that gasoline I smell?
No, man.
No! No! No!
No!
On the house, kiddo. You know that.
Root beer.
I can't do anything.
Your mom, technically,
she's off right now.
Yeah, way off.
Police! Don't move. I said don't move.
I thought the police
always said, "freeze."
Well, I am the police,
and I say don't move, Snow White.
You move, you're dead.
And I say I'm dead and I move.
Not one more step. I'm serious.
Then shoot, if you will, Officer Albrecht.
What are you, nuts? Walking into a gun?
You high?
You don't remember me?
What are you talking about?
How about Shelly?
Do you remember Shelly Webster?
Shelly Webster's dead, my friend.
I want you to move over to the curb there.
Come on, real nice and easy.
Come on. Move it!
We're gonna wait here for backup.
It's getting too frigging weird for me.
It gets better.
Do you know someone named T-Bird?
He had a friend
who shouldn't have played with knives.
Like the coat?
You're the guy that murdered Tin Tin.
Check it out.
He was already dead.
He died a year ago,
the moment he touched her.
They're all dead.
They just don't know it yet.
Get away from there!
-Cops!
-Come on. Get out of here!
Leave it. Leave it. Run!
Oh, great.
Great.
Guy shows up
looking like a mime from hell,
and you lose him right out in the open.
Well,
at least he didn't do
that walking-against-the-wind shit.
I hate that.
Little early for Devil's Night.
What the hell is going on here?
You are very restless.
I just wish I was a little hungry again,
that's all.
-Be careful what you ask for.
-Yeah, you may get it. I know.
There are energies aligning against you.
Seeing is believing, isn't it?
Yummy.
Gideon's pawnshop just burned down
to the foundation.
Nobody cleared this little event with me.
I didn't have nothing to do with that.
I'm sure you must be awful disappointed.
I got trouble.
One of my crew got himself perished.
-Yeah? And who might that be?
-Tin Tin.
Somebody stuck his blades
in all his major organs
in alphabetical order.
Well, gentlemen, by all means,
I think we ought to have an introspective
moment of silence for poor old Tin Tin.
You're working for me
tomorrow night, right?
-Whatever you say, I can do.
-Good. That's very reassuring.
I still ain't heard the story
on why Gideon's burned down.
Is that a natural catastrophe
or act of God or something?
Call it my need to know.
Let me go, you creep!
Yeah.
You didn't slow down, dickhead!
He couldn't have stopped.
He was a butt face. I could have made it.
What are you supposed to be,
a clown or something?
Sometimes.
It's more like surfing than skating.
I wish the rain would stop, just once.
It can't rain all the time.
Eric?
Don't thank me.
Are we fighting the good fight?
Double homicide a year ago.
No convictions.
Annie, look at that.
"We, the undersigned tenants
of 1929 Caulderon Court apartments--"
What is this, a petition?
A big kick-me sign for a very nice girl
who found herself a cause,
and a cause that got her killed.
She was fighting tenant eviction
in that neighborhood?
Shelly Webster and her
nice rock-and-roll boyfriend Eric Draven.
You know, the last time
you went snooping around on a case
is when you got put back on the beat.
-Yeah, I know. Torres keeps reminding me.
-I bet he does.
You're gonna wind up
working a school crosswalk.
-I'm cool.
-You didn't get that file from me, okay?
And don't tell me you owe me one.
-I owe you one.
-Yeah, right.
Damn.
Tomorrow night, we can-- we can get high
and watch this whole fucking city burn
from that window.
There's a big fucking bird over there.
It's a squab.
Come here, bird.
Hey, bird. Hey, bird.
Bird. Birdie.
Here, birdie, birdie, birdie.
Come here, birdie, birdie, birdie.
Birdie? Hey, birdie?
Here, Funboy.
What the fuck?
No, man! Don't do that!
You nearly gave me a fucking heart attack!
Don't sweat it.
It's time for you to take your bird
and leave, freako.
Take your shot, Funboy.
You got me dead bang.
You are seriously fucked-up.
Did you look in the mirror?
I mean, you need professional help.
Bingo!
He shoots! He scores!
-Jesus Christ.
Stop me if you heard this one.
Jesus Christ walks into a hotel.
He hands the innkeeper three nails
and he asks...
Don't you ever fucking die?
"Can you put me up for the night?"
-Does that hurt?
-Fuck.
Yes, it fucking hurt.
Oh, God.
Look what you've done to my sheets.
I've got a gun in my pocket.
You're happy to see me, aren't you?
Stay away! Stay away from me!
No!
Look.
"Mother is the name for God
on the lips and hearts of all children.”
Do you understand?
Morphine is bad for you.
Your daughter is out there on the streets
waiting for you.
If I wanted ice,
I would have asked for ice!
Now fill it up!
Fill it up yourself, macho man.
I really need this.
All right.
You burn yourself playing with matches?
-Fuck off.
-You have an appointment.
-Well, shit on me.
-Drink up.
This is a first. Do I bow or do I curtsy?
Now, get my friend here a glass of blood.
Hey. Hey, hon.
Hey, good night, Darla.
You stay put. Right there.
Get away, steam head.
As you can see, I'm here on the corner
of 27th street and East Washington Place,
the site of last year's biggest
Devil's Night conflagration.
It was exactly one year ago
that the building you see
across the street from me
was totally demolished by fire--
A fire that was fought
by seven fire companies.
We lost the lives of two firefighters.
In fact, if it weren't for
the constant surveillance
by the local police precinct...
Freeze!
Jesus. Don't ever do that, man.
Fuck.
Good likeness.
I saw your body, man.
You died. You got buried.
You still have your hat on.
I gotta sit down.
Shit.
Holy shit.
Say...
are you some kind of ghost?
Boo!
I don't know what I am.
I need you to tell me what happened to us.
You took a six-story swan dive
out of a window.
She was beaten and raped.
Died at the hospital.
Hey, you asked, man.
I mean, come on. Read the file.
Shelly Webster held on for 30 hours
in intensive care,
and her body finally just gave it up.
I saw it, man. I couldn't do jack for her.
-Hey.
-Don't touch me!
Hey.
-You okay?
-I saw her.
I saw her through your eyes.
You stayed with her the whole time.
Yeah, well, you got to understand
something, all right?
I was-- I was hoping
she'd come out of it, you know.
Give me something I could work with.
Yeah.
Look, I--
Why didn't you do something about it?
You think any of those people
in that building,
even the ones who signed the petition,
would talk after what happened to you?
I kept asking questions
and finally got busted for
sticking my nose where it wasn't wanted.
This your wife?
Yeah, we-- Well, not anymore.
We're getting a divorce.
It's funny.
Little things used to mean
so much to Shelly.
I used to think they were kind of trivial.
Believe me. Nothing is trivial.
You shouldn't smoke these.
They'll kill you.
Are you gonna vanish into thin air again?
I thought I'd use your front door.
Look, man,
I'm sorry as hell for what happened
to you and your girlfriend.
Yeah.
I got stabbed. I shot the son of a bitch.
I watched the bullet hole close by itself.
And then I heard that my business
gets blown up real good.
-Other than that, my day sucked.
-Yeah.
I saw him too. He had a guitar.
He winked at me before he jumped out
a fourth-floor window like he had wings.
He winked at you?
Musicians.
What else did you see?
So far I haven't heard shit about what
you're going to do about all this crap.
I mean, what do I get?
My livelihood--
it got flushed away and went swirling.
You ain't lost everything.
Yeah, and maybe
you're not such a big shot either!
Jesus!
Fair enough.
Catch.
Jesus.
Say hello to the last fella
who wouldn't cooperate with me.
What, are you telling me
this thing is real?
All the power in the world
resides in the eyes, fella.
Sometimes they're more useful
than the people who bear them.
You know, you're directly
out of your fucking mind! You know that?
Yeah.
Eyes see.
It's one of the most important things
I learned from my sister.
Sister? She's supposed to be your sister?
My father's daughter. That's right.
What's the matter?
You don't see the resemblance?
Now, let's take it from the top, friend.
In a lot of detail.
What do you say?
He had a bird with him.
Nearly pecked my face off.
He told me to tell T-Bird
that death was on its way.
Whatever the fuck that means. And--
Draven. He said his name was Eric Draven.
Want to relax that thing now?
And this bird man--
He just happened to let you live, huh?
You sure you ain't making all of this up
just to save your own ass?
I ain't making all this up.
I ain't twisted like you two fucks.
All right.
A boy and his bird.
Awful touching.
Yeah.
For fuck's sake, die, will you?
Give me that thing.
Thanks.
Funboy said he saw a black bird too.
A big one.
Then he choked to death on his own blood.
I'll have the janitor come on up.
You again.
Are you lost or hungry?
Hi.
I don't know how many times
I gotta tell you. We're in this together.
If we ain't, and one part falls,
it all falls.
You know how long it took us
to put this together.
Yeah, a long time.
That piece of rat shit made Tin Tin
into a fucking voodoo doll!
Tin Tin was a dick.
Tin Tin...
-Fire it up!
Fire it up!
No Funboy.
Probably still banging away on Darla.
Smokes and road beers. Be quick.
I'm on it.
What the fuck are you supposed to be, man?
I'm your passenger.
Drive.
What's all this happy horseshit?
Hey, T-Bird! T-Bird!
-Oh, shit!
-What the fuck's the matter with you?
Stupid ass hair! You hit my car!
What do you want, man?
Money? Drugs? I got it.
We could use you. You did Tin Tin.
That's business, right?
Faster.
You got that cream stuff?
I hate this.
You can't even call it cream legally.
What in the crap?
Look. You're making us popular.
When they flash us like that,
they ain't friends.
This is vehicle 48.
We got us a big, old, red hot rod.
T-Bird?
If you got something personal, amigo,
we can work it out, right?
Damn! Dead end!
Look out!
Get out of the way!
Holy shit! Goddamn foreign cars!
Shit!
I hate this. This ain't good.
T-Bird! I got you, man. I'm coming.
Shit!
Oh, man!
Help me--
Remember? Yeah, I remember everything.
But I don't know--
What? What?
What? What are you talking about?
No, no, no, no.
You mean that place downtown?
Yeah, I remember her.
We needed to put some fear
into that little lady.
She wasn't going along with
our tenant relocation program.
And her idiot boyfriend shows up
and turns a simple sweep-and-clear
into a total clusterfuck!
Who gives a shit? It's ancient history.
Why? What do you want?
What is it? What? Speak to me. Speak!
Did you send us these complaints?
Come here. "Abashed the Devil stood--"
Does it get you sweaty?
I know you.
I know you. I knew I knew you.
I knew I knew you.
But you ain't you.
You can't be you.
We put you through the window.
There ain't no coming back.
This is the really real world.
We killed you dead.
There ain't no coming back.
T-Bird--
There ain't no coming back!
"Abashed the Devil stood
and felt how awful goodness is."
"And felt how awful goodness is."
T-Bird.
This is the 7:00 a.m. edition
of Action News.
For over a decade,
the night before Halloween
has had a darker and deadlier nickname
in the inner city, "Devil's Night--"
The name given to what has become
an annual plague of arson.
Last year, 200 individual blazes
were reported,
and 11 people lost their lives.
Tonight, on the eve
of what may become the biggest
and deadliest Devil's Night ever,
the mayor has firefighters
from all surrounding counties...
Do you like them up or over?
I can't remember.
What are you doing?
I don't even like eggs.
Wait. You loved eggs.
Yeah, when I was five.
So what do you want now?
Black coffee and cigarettes?
So what did you take
to become mother of the year?
It wasn't drugs.
Someone kind of woke me up.
Who?
It was nuts.
You're acting weird.
Did you win the lottery
or something, Darla?
Forget it.
I never was too good at this mommy shit.
Over easy.
I like them over easy, Mom.
Hey, Albrecht.
This is the third hit
in your hood in 24 hours.
We just fished this out of the river.
He's fused to his own car.
We're gonna have to ID his teeth.
His name is T-Bird.
Arson was his specialty.
Looks like he zigged
when he should have zagged.
-Case closed.
-Bull-fucking-shit.
Come here.
You're holding out on me.
I got a goddamn vigilante Killer
knocking off scumbags left and right,
and you're covering up for somebody.
Who's the cartoon character
in the painted face?
Hey, you're the detective.
Why don't you tell me?
Okay. Gideon's blows all to hell, and
you're having a chitchat with some weirdo
who winds up in T-Bird's car
when it zigs instead of zags.
Then you steal one of my case files
from homicide,
and you're saying this is just
a fucking automobile accident?
-Come on!
-Yeah. Good speech though.
I didn't want to interrupt you.
It sounded good.
You gotta write that shit down.
All right, smart-ass.
The captain's got
a little love note waiting for you.
Welcome to the first day
of the rest of your suspension.
Suspension?
-For what?
-Misconduct.
Yeah, give me the lab.
One for sorrow, two for joy.
-Come here.
-Three for a girl and four for a boy.
Dancing--
Eric?
Man, Sarah, you're going crazy.
Gabriel.
I thought you were dead.
You're not dead, are you?
I knew it was you.
Even with the makeup.
I remembered your song.
You said, "Can't rain all the time."
That is from your song, right?
Come on, Eric. I know you're here.
I miss you. And Shelly.
I get so lonely all by myself.
To hell with you. I thought you cared.
Sarah, I do care.
That's him. That's him.
But he looked different.
He was all painted up white
like some kind of dead whore.
I seen him. T-Bird sent me in
for some road beers, right?
Then he took him away.
But I chased him down.
And he flash fried T-Bird
to his fucking car!
T-Bird! Here's to you, buddy.
Maybe we ought to just videotape this,
play it back in slow motion.
Fire it up! Fire it up!
-You see the grave?
-Fire it up!
-Empty.
-Fire it--
Grave? What grave?
What about my fucking grave?
Three out of the four.
He's working his way
back to this speed freak right here.
It's not fair. It's Funboy's fault.
That boy was out of control.
T-Bird, he came in.
He says, "Waste them both."
And now this ghost gonna kill my ass next!
This ghost gonna kill my ass next.
-This ghost gonna kill--
Hey.
It ain't no ghost.
They have all arrived.
Watch him.
We might need him.
Ghost gonna kill my...
He like his plain or with onions?
Fine. Don't talk to me.
When someone's dead,
they can't come back, can they?
That's what I thought.
Are you referring to anyone in particular?
You'll just think I'm nuts.
Yeah, well, then maybe
they'll have to lock us both up.
You see him too?
I saw somebody.
Maybe it was your fairy godfather.
Eric didn't come back for me.
He can't be my friend anymore
because I'm alive.
You want a friend to walk you home?
You things, things, things of the flesh
Do it slow
Down avenues, cut me
Lust my eyes
Licking lips, encouraging Mr. Careworn
To gaze upon a screen
Bask on after the flesh
Boys.
It seems our friend T-Bird
won't be joining us this evening
on account of a slight case of death.
You wanna sit down?
Well, well, well.
Devil's Night is upon us again.
I thought we'd throw a little party,
start a bunch of fires,
make a little profit.
I like the pretty lights.
Problem is, it's all been done before.
You see what I'm saying?
That's no reason to quit.
Wrong. Best reason to quit.
Only reason to quit.
A man has an idea.
The idea attracts others, like-minded.
The idea expands.
The idea becomes an institution.
What was the idea?
See, that's what's
been bothering me, boys.
And I'll tell you. When I used to think
about the idea itself,
it put a big old smile on my face.
You see, gentlemen,
greed is for amateurs.
Disorder, chaos, anarchy--
Now, that's fun!
-What about Devil's Night?
-What about it?
I started the first fires
in this goddamn city.
Before I knew it, every charlatan
and shit heel was imitating me.
Do you know what they got now?
Devil's Night greeting cards.
Isn't that precious?
Yeah.
The idea has become the institution, boys.
Time to move along.
You don't want us to do
light-my-fire time for the whole city?
No.
No, I want you to set a fire
so goddamn big
the gods will notice us again.
-That's what I'm saying.
-Right.
I want all of you boys to be able to
look me straight in the eye one more time
and say, "Are we having fun or what?"
Hey, you! What's your name?
Skank! You don't feel that?
I feel like a little worm
on a big fucking hook.
"I feel like a little worm
on a big fucking hook."
Well, boy, your mama must be
damn proud of you!
How the hell did that thing get in here?
Gentlemen.
Let me go. Let me go. I gotta go.
Well, you're him, huh? The avenger.
The killer of killers.
Nice outfit.
I'm not sure about the face though.
I just want him.
Well, you can't have him.
Well...
I see you have made your decision.
Now let's see you enforce it.
This is already boring the shit out of me.
Kill him!
-All right.
-Go!
That had to hurt.
Well, that's that.
That guy was crazy.
He's gone.
Get him!
Here. Help me.
He's coming to try to kill me.
Jesus Christ!
Hey!
You're all going to die here.
Get the fuck out of here!
Guess it's not a good day
to be a bad guy, huh, Skank?
I'm not Skank. There's Skank right there.
Skank's dead.
That's right.
No!
What in the crap?
-Don't move!
-Hold it!
That's all she wrote. Move and we shoot.
You are surrounded by police units.
Do not attempt to escape.
Stop running immediately.
Holy shit!
...and spread your arms and legs...
Repeat. Stop immediately.
Lie down and spread your arms and legs...
Come on! Move it!
My advice: Next time, duck.
So many cops, you'd think
they were giving away doughnuts.
Shit!
I knew you were gonna do that.
Look at that out there.
The whole city ought to be
in flames by now.
The sky ought to be red.
So that, I take it,
is the late, great Eric Draven.
He has power,
but it is power you can take from him.
I like him already.
The crow is his link
between the land of the living
and the realm of the dead.
So, kill the crow and destroy the man.
I'm coming home, Shelly.
You're gonna say
I shouldn't be in the cemetery
in the middle of the night, right?
Safest place in the world to be.
It's 'cause everybody's dead.
I knew you'd come here.
It's really late, Sarah.
You didn't say goodbye.
You're just gonna have to
forgive me for that.
And you're never coming back.
I gave this to Shelly once.
I think she'd like you to have it.
This way, you'll always remember her.
I'll never take it off.
I better go sneak back in the house.
Bye.
Take it easy, sweetheart.
Come on. Come on.
What is that? Some sort of souvenir there
from your pal, huh?
I'll just keep it for good luck.
What do you say?
Her eyes are so innocent.
Eric!
Eric, help! Eric!
Quick impression for you.
Caw! Caw! Bang! Fuck, I'm dead!
Give me the girl
and I'll let you walk out of here.
Well, well.
Why don't you just give me a minute
to think about that, huh?
Nah. Fuck it.
Oh, fuck.
Well, well, well.
It does seem to me that our little life
has undergone a rather significant change
in the past few minutes now.
Wouldn't you agree?
Well, for a ghost, you bleed just fine.
-It's still alive.
-Well, then Kill it!
Bye-bye, birdie.
Oh, shit.
Well, I just came by to pay my respects
and here you are
getting all shot up again.
-They've taken Sarah.
-How many?
Two more.
I can handle it. Don't worry.
I'm not worried.
Look, here's the plan.
You stay in front, and when
they run out of ammo, I'll arrest them.
That sounds like a great plan.
There's just one problem.
Oh, shit.
You're bleeding all over the place.
I thought, you know, you were invincible.
I was. I'm not anymore.
Well, I guess you really will
need my help, won't you?
Come on.
You take that.
You were supposed to stay behind me.
I think I messed up.
This is all the power you ever had.
Now it is mine.
Pity there's not more time
for us.
Help, Eric! I'm scared!
Let me go!
Let her go!
You can have me. I won't fight you.
All right.
No!
Eric!
Sarah?
Look out!
Eric!
You know, my daddy used to say,
"Every man's got a devil,
and you can't rest till you find him."
What happened back there
with you and your girlfriend,
I cleared that building.
Hell, nothing in this town happens
without my say-so.
So I'm sorry if I spoiled
your wedding plans there, friend.
But if it's any consolation to you,
you have put a smile on my face.
You got a lot of spirit, son.
I am going to miss you.
I have something to give you.
I don't want it anymore.
Thirty hours of pain.
All at once!
All for you.
Yeah.
Go help him.
Are you alive?
God, I need a cigarette.
Everybody else dead?
You helped me.
What you kept in here saved me.
-Thanks.
-Don't mention it.
I've been meaning
to come to church anyway.
Oh, yuck.
I'm quitting as of now. If I live.
Stay with him until help comes.
He'll be okay, right?
Eric?
He does that a lot.
Shelly.
All right.
I saw the ambulance.
-Night turn ugly?
-Multiple homicides.
At least it stopped raining, huh?
It can't rain all the time.
No, I don't believe it.
This nightmare your fault, Albrecht?
Look, you go on home.
-I'm okay.
-Okay.
-Want to tell me what's going on?
-Your vigilante's up on the roof.
You missed it.
Get him out of here.
Thanks.
If the people we love are stolen from us,
the way to have them live on
is to never stop loving them.
Buildings burn, people die,
but real love is forever.