Simon Magus was a
magician and a sorcerer in...
- Hmm...
- In Sumeria.
And what happened to
Simon Magus, Bartolo?
Jesus' disciples performed miracles.
When Simon Magus saw the miracles
he offered Peter gold for God's powers.
And how did Peter respond?
John Rossi?
Stand up.
Answer my question, John Rossi.
That's not my name.
You and all the other bastards
lucky enough to be here,
children of sin, spawn of the
damned, are all named for saints!
Saints who were disciplined.
Saints who were chaste.
You were named for John Baptist Rossi,
a Capuchin priest who gave
away all his possessions.
A man who had nothing, like you.
Now what is your
name, you ungrateful cur?
Your name, boy!
Have you lost your
tongue? What is your name?
All the girls will remain
locked in their dormitory
and no food will be served to any boy
until you acknowledge
your namesake before God.
Food, food, food!
Wow.
They should name you
Simon Magus, the magician.
No. Simon Templar.
Agnes!
- What are you doing?
- Agnes!
When they catch you, they'll cane you.
It won't happen, because
we're leaving tonight,
this hardy brotherhood, on a crusade.
That's why I risked everything,
Agnes, my love, to bid you farewell.
I can't leave you behind
without a kiss, can I?
Hey, watch this.
We've lost some girls!
The girls are missing!
There are girls missing!
Come on, boys, hurry up.
Hurry up! Come on, hurry!
Wait, John Rossi, my kiss.
There he is! Get him!
October 3rd, entering
foyer of Tretiak Industries.
Heavy security in the
elevators. Guards in uniform.
Elevator to vault on 26th floor
requires separate pass key.
Maybe use stairs. No traffic there.
October 4th. Personal tidbits.
Tretiak's former partner
died suddenly in 1995.
It left Tretiak the sole
owner of gas and oil empire.
Tretiak's first son killed
in car crash five years ago.
Who are you?
Vehicle was driven by
younger son, Ilya, now 27.
Wife now lives in Geneva following
an assassination attempt in 1996.
- I'm Ivan Ivanovich.
- No other children.
October 5th. Ilya spent most of today
in Cafe Eldorado with Bandido buddies.
Gangster rap coffee
flirting with teenage girls.
Small firearms in coats,
machine pistols in cars.
...compulsory military service.
Family company employs
all four as fix-it guys...
There were three great
empires that dominated the world,
both culturally and militarily:
Rome, Constantinople and Russia.
All three have fallen.
Only one can be restored.
And only one man can restore it:
Ivan Petrovich Tretiak!
Friends. Countrymen. Russians!
You people here in this room...
are the cream of Russia.
And the whole nation
is listening with us.
But why do you all listen to me rave?
Set aside my oil company,
forget about my best-selling book,
And all I am is a lunatic
haunted by the fantasy
of an empire that reclaims her
former might, her former size.
All I am is a poet
spinning rhymes of Russia
not cut off at the knees,
but armed to the teeth!
Not ridiculed, but revered!
No, more than revered. Feared!
But who am I to dazzle you
with this dream? All I've done...
How does it look for the leader's son
to walk out when the leader speaks?
You'd prefer the leader's son to
piss his pants on live TV, hmm?
And still the people freeze to death!
I love this country.
I don't speak Russian.
In that case, stand up, put
your hands behind your head
and turn around slowly.
Wrong place for a condom. Take it off.
Listen, if I give this to you,
you're gonna give it to your daddy.
And what's he gonna give you?
Not even a Christmas bonus.
The guy I'm stealing this for
will give me a million dollars.
If we partner, we'll split 50-50,
that's half a million in hard currency.
Think of the drugs you
could buy with that much cake.
You'll be discoing for a
decade in Moscow, mate.
I don't need your small
change. That's your first problem.
Here is your second.
Microchip, please.
- Freeze!
- Sorry. Guns make me nervous.
Suck me sideways.
My eyes!
Give it up!
You've got no place to go!
A goddamn button!
Back of the building! Come on!
- Where's the body?
- No body. Just some guy in rags.
As the bitter chill of winter
descends on Moscow,
Russians are warming
to the angry rhetoric
of former communist boss Ivan Tretiak.
Now, a billionaire oil magnate
and leader of his own political party,
Tretiak predicted that the
civil unrest engulfing Russia
will only worsen unless reformist
President Karpov can overcome
the heating oil shortage that has
already killed scores of Russians.
In his speech today, Tretiak called
on elements of the Russian army
who are opposed to the elected
government, to seize control
and end the heating oil crisis...
What beautiful work.
...angry siege at the American embassy.
Fired by Tretiak's attacks on U.
S. Foreign policy, the protesters...
Huh. Cloisonné. It is old.
Yes. It belonged to my grandmother.
Please.
Tonight I feel like the
oldest person on this plane.
My husband, he's sending me to England
to live until things change.
You are married not even a year
and already this
bastard has a girlfriend!
I'm sorry, it's not my business.
How come you know so much about me?
It is a gift.
I am Martin de Porres.
I'm from Spain, but I'm
named for a Peruvian saint
who could cure the sick or the
injured by the laying of hands.
He's the same build as the
description the Russians gave us,
but he doesn't sound like an Aussie.
He could be faking it.
X-rays are clear, he hasn't
swallowed the microchip. Anything?
You English with your fish and
chips. On the plane I have chicken.
Van Gogh theft, Netherlands,
last year. Same eyes.
Different chin.
Halcyon Hotel, sir.
Stand up! What is your name?
Answer the question!
What is your name... Name... Name...
Hey, Lou. The microchip arrived.
I put the dough in your Swiss account.
Sorry I didn't get back to
you about the diamonds.
But Moscow's like Dodge City now.
All them greedy commies
have turned into capitalists.
It's disgusting. It's made them sloppy.
One or two more easy score, I
top 50 mill, I'm out of the game.
- Yeah, I heard that before.
- Not from me.
I don't know nothing. If you
don't believe me, try and find me.
- Fuck you, Lou!
- Cheers.
I can't seem to break 50.
"One million U.S.
dollars, non-refundable..."
"Reserves you a quiet table at
a romantic little spot in Berlin"
"called Templehof, which
has a cozy transit lounge."
"To get inside, you walk
through the metal detectors,"
"and I walk through the metal detectors."
"And since you know I'm not
armed and I know you're not armed,"
"we can both fall in love
and nobody gets hurt."
- I can't see him.
- Then look for him.
You have a long, beautiful cane.
Along with your beautiful eyes.
That photograph doesn't do you justice.
- Who are you?
- My name is Bruno Hautenfaust.
I was named for a saint
who was a very wealthy man.
Had the wine, the women, the
songs, and then, inexplicably,
took a vow of poverty and became a hermit
went off to live in
the forest, in the nude.
Please leave.
I represent the professional you hired.
I'm his business
manager. I speak for him.
We don't deal with underlings.
Come on, Father, let's go.
Wait, sit down. Listen and learn.
Ah, youth.
Who runs this thief? CIA? MI-6? Libya?
He's not a race car, nobody runs
him. He's an independent contractor.
Good. Then no one
will mind if I kill him.
Oh, yes, I can have a man
killed and stroll away like that.
Even with metal detectors.
Even in this transit lounge.
It's so early. You guys want to
get some coffee or something?
Sure.
Be quiet.
What is it you request of my employer?
- Do you know what cold fusion is?
- Of course.
It's the theory of nuclear
fusion at room temperature.
- Free energy forever.
- Yes.
As far as science goes, it
ranks just above astrology.
Those who claim to have achieved it,
have never been able to duplicate it.
Until now.
There is an electrochemist
working at Oxford.
We believe that this good lady
made a breakthrough in cold fusion.
Your employer will
obtain the formula for me.
He's very busy. And you're very boring.
Your offer must inspire him.
This woman has repeatedly avoided
my agents' attempts to find the formula.
She's cagey, difficult.
Maybe your agents are stupid.
I think this inspiration would
cost you three million dollars.
- Ridiculous.
- Why?
You'll have the world market in energy.
Cost you a nickel for every million
you make. His deposit should go...
Hey, it is not for me.
It is for Mother Russia.
But you want Mother
Russia too, Mr. Tretiak.
Three million on deposit in a
bank account in Zurich. Agreed?
Yes.
And, uh, how long to get
your employer's agreement?
I'll ask.
Your offer has inspired her. I'll do it.
Bank account number in Zurich.
- Bye, sonny.
- Bye-bye.
I really love this guy.
- Too bad we have to kill him.
- Yeah, too bad.
When the electro-chemists Hans
and Fleischman announced in 1989
that they had discovered cold fusion,
a revolutionary process
of generating energy,
They were at first acclaimed as geniuses,
and then condemned as charlatans.
The protocols of cold fusion...
What are those? Drugs?
Can I have one? My head is
pounding. She's boring the life out of me.
- They're for my heart.
- Oh.
You have very pretty eyes. Pretty lady.
- Who are you?
- Me?
I'm here to do an interview
with that Dr. Russell.
I'm gonna expose her as a fraud.
You don't put any stock in this
cold fusion mumbo-jumbo, do you?
- Actually, I do.
- Really?
Dr. Emma Russell!
Oops.
Well, I didn't prepare
any formal remarks.
Um, I'm more interested
in what questions you
all have about cold fusion.
So I thought we would start
with those. Any questions?
- Please?
- Yeah, I have, Dr. Russell.
Can you explain the actual process
of fusion? You know, the theory?
Yes. There it is.
This is the apparatus.
And very simply, when
positively charged deuterons
are attracted to the palladium cathode,
they cram together.
There are millions and millions
of them getting closer and closer,
and then they fuse. And they
create energy in the form of helium.
But I read that the experiment
couldn't be replicated. So...
- How do we know it works?
- Well, we don't.
Not yet.
But if you remember, Einstein, he
knew the theory of relativity to be true
long before he could
prove it. He felt the truth.
And some of us feel the
same way about cold fusion.
Because it's there, it's in nature,
the raw, natural power
just waiting to be harnessed.
And when we ignite that cold fusion fire,
I mean, just imagine...
There's more energy in
one cubic mile of sea water
than in all the known
oil reserves on Earth.
You could drive your car 55 million
miles on a gallon of heavy water.
It would be the end of pollution.
Warmth for the whole world.
So why don't I, uh, demonstrate for you
why other people in the past
have been so unsuccessful?
They use very complex...
November 17th, 11.30 a.m.
Entering flat of Dr. Emma
Russell, High Street, Oxford.
No alarms on outer doors. Strange.
No messages.
Shelley monument.
Entering bathroom.
Books.
More books.
Walls covered with reminder notes.
Poetry.
Aw...
Dad.
"Stop and talk to Shelley every day.
How can I love a man named Percy?"
"Isn't there someone in the world
who can consume me like that?"
"Magic. Romantic."
No recent applications.
Cold fusion notes.
"Although I pass the
Shelley monument every day,"
"its sadness strikes me every time."
"For some reason, I feel a very
personal loss when I look at it."
"So much pain and so much passion."
"To give light to them
that sit in darkness,"
"and in the shadow of death."
"Luke 1, Verse 79."
Tretiak's wrong, she's not cagey.
She's not difficult,
she's just eccentric.
She's innocent.
Maybe it's in her head.
She needs a poet.
An artist.
Someone who understands truth.
She needs Thomas Moore.
Do you like it?
- What?
- The sculpture. Do you like it?
Oh...
Yes.
What do you love about it?
The way it... glows.
And how the light holds him in silence,
taking care of him.
Yeah, that's what I like about it.
- Are you an artist?
- No.
Just a traveler searching for purity.
- What do you search for?
- Energy.
Yes.
Have you ever been on a long journey?
No, not really.
Perhaps I'll take you
to my home in Africa.
You should experience the
energy of where all life began.
Sorry, I'm not very good with people.
Me neither.
"I see my angel for the first time."
"Know my purpose, feel my birth."
"Hear, at first faintly,
then distinctly,"
"The sweet strains of our union,"
"Our love heats up the cold universe"
"And gives my tired, desperate heart..."
...are eternally healed.
- Do you like it?
- Who did you write it for?
You.
You're following me or it's destiny.
- Either way, it's weird.
- Very weird.
Destiny, then.
This must look strange.
It's, uh, something that I'm working on.
A formula for creating energy.
That you carry around in your underwear?
Yeah. I do.
How did you do that?
Magic.
Give it back.
- It looks like Sanskrit.
- Give it back.
I'm sorry. I just wanted
to watch you put it away.
- What else do you keep in there?
- Nothing.
That's not true.
Can I get you anything else?
Drink your wine.
Uh, Latour '57.
The Latour, sir, is 400 pounds a bottle.
Then we'll have two bottles.
There, you count it.
All these little tubes and microbes.
- And molecules.
- Those too.
- Can I tell you something?
- What? You must. Everything.
- It's a secret.
- What?
I'm done.
My energy research, I'm finished.
I still have some sequencing to work out
to make sure that
it's safe, but I did it.
It's been you against
the whole world, hasn't it?
How have you done it
and stayed so positive?
The gift of faith.
To see...
Well, to believe in
something that's all around us
but hidden from our sight.
It's a beautiful thought.
I can't believe I'm telling you all this.
I don't even know your name.
My name is...
I don't want to tell you my
name. No, I don't want to do that.
I don't want to do that.
What difference does it make?
- What's your name?
- Emma.
Emma. Now I know everything about you.
You're a genius.
You have a weak heart.
You have beautiful dreams.
Great courage.
Unafraid in this world.
You get that from your father.
You can't cook to save your life.
And you love fish.
I do love fish.
That's weird.
- I want to try that.
- No.
- Yes.
- I don't want you to. Drink your wine.
Yes, I do. What's your name?
My name is Thomas Moore.
I was named after a saint...
who died for his faith.
Okay.
Your work...
is very dangerous and alive.
And I love your poems. They move me.
But that's not who you really are.
You're running away from
your past and your pain
and yet you keep it so close to you.
You don't have to be
afraid of who you are...
because you're beautiful.
What are you doing?
Oh, my God, you're... You're
bleeding! Wha... What happened?
I don't know, I was
weeping and I slipped.
I was thinking of you, I don't know...
Well, I live right down the
street, I could clean you up.
Why do you cover your
mouth when you laugh?
- I don't know.
- Wait.
I'm glad that it stopped
bleeding. You don't need stitches.
We have to disinfect it, though.
You really are an angel.
You are.
This is gonna hurt.
Ahhh!
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry. Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry, I was just joking.
- I... I should go.
- No.
Yes, you... I...
- Take off your pants.
- Pardon?
I mean, your sweater.
There's blood on it. I'll wash it.
You're very domestic.
There's blood on your blouse as well.
I'll wash it.
Do you have any wine?
I'm so overwhelmed
that you even noticed me.
How could I not?
You make me feel so good.
I wish...
I wish you could understand.
I want you to know who I am.
Oh...
Oh, my heart.
Don't disappear, I'll be right back.
Ugh, you can't do this. She's so great.
I can't believe this is happening.
Hi.
"To Spider. Must fly. Have better offer."
Greedy Westerner. Wants more money.
Who cares? Can't spend
hard currency in hell.
Send this message: "Fly. Don't buzz off."
"I'll double your fee."
"Or send my own boys to
take care of the woman."
Are you okay?
It's... I just want to lie here.
Can we just be like this tonight?
Is that what you want?
It's so magic.
It just feels so perfect.
It's 7:00 a.m. and here
are the news headlines...
Thomas?
- Lev Naumovitch! It's here.
- It's revolutionary, sir.
She's boldly cast aside
a slew of stale ideas.
But I think the formula is
incomplete. It will take months...
But that won't do.
Now that the people
are beginning to freeze,
Tretiak must swoop in from the
wings with a miracle to save them.
How high do you want it?
To the top.
- Good morning, Yuri.
- Good morning.
Perhaps I can confirm the
validity of this formula more quickly
if I dispense with
certain protocols. But...
How long, Dr. Botvin, since you
received your last salary check
from Moscow University?
Ukrainian Independence Day.
Last August.
Ivan, he's online.
Do it.
"To Spider. You've got the recipe..."
- "Where's my dough?"
- "To Human Fly.
"Recipe incomplete. The cake won't rise."
"Hence, no dough."
"I'm not the baker."
"Don't make me the butcher."
I like this guy.
"No play, no pay."
"I'm certain you kept the cookbook."
Holland Park.
I'll check that for you. Yes, that
seems to be fine. One moment.
He's keeping me online.
You wait here.
You! Beside the car!
Now turn around! Step
away from the vehicle!
He's armed!
Come on, drive!
Go the other way! Go! Go! Go!
What about him?
What about this one?
Yeah, that...
You see, we believe
they're all the same villain.
Oh, my God.
- They're all him?
- We believe so.
He eluded a hit squad this
morning in Holland Park.
Then he fled the UK out of Heathrow.
We've got a handful of
false identities used on
visas, passports, leases...
Nicholas Owen. Louis Guanella.
Peter Damian.
Charles Borromeo.
Of course.
Thomas Moore. All the
names of Catholic saints.
Can you access Heathrow's passenger
lists for the last, uh, eight hours?
- I think it might be possible.
- Good.
Yes!
Oh!
See, my friends, you
back the biggest rat.
Out! Out! Freeloaders, out!
I want to drink alone. Close the curtain!
- What?
Don't look down.
- Do you know who I am?
- No.
I'm the thief you tried to cheat.
And this is your accountant.
Talk to him.
The phone goes the other way, you moron.
Hello? Tretiak speaking.
That money to Zurich, send it now.
I said now.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Do you know what the
hardest part about being you is?
Pretending to be so bad in bed.
You son of a bitch!
There is an impostor
in there! Get him out!
Hey, hey. Hey.
Take your hands off me, you idiots!
Are you crazy? It's me!
Go! Go! Get him! Go!
Ilya, get the bastard!
Fifty million. I'm out.
Mr. Ferrer, checking out.
I'll have one too.
- Emma.
- Hi.
I am... I'm overwhelmed.
- You found me.
- It wasn't very hard.
Two men with saints' names
flew into Moscow yesterday.
Isadore Bakanja is a short, bald African.
Whereas Vincent Ferrer...
Named after a saint who
betrayed his best friend.
How could you do it?
Emma, I, I had to.
- I'm a thief.
- I want my cards back.
You flew all this way
because you want your cards?
- Yes, I did.
- No. It's because you're in love.
- I rest my case.
- Who are you?
No one has a clue, least of all me.
And why would you
steal cold fusion? It's free.
Why would you do that?
- Eight million reasons.
- Oh, eight million? Wow, is that all?
I would have given them
to you if you'd only asked.
You've got to get away from me.
I'm not going anywhere until
you tell me why you lied to me.
- You lied to me.
- I lied to you?
You almost got me killed. The
guy I stole it for says it doesn't work.
- Well, screw him!
- I don't think you'd enjoy that.
Yeah, you're right,
I don't think I would.
Emma, you don't know
what you're dealing with here.
- They took my pills.
- No, I palmed them from your purse.
I need one or two, I need...
I have a bad heart and...
- I know.
- It's starting to pound.
It's okay, I've got your pills.
I've got two in my hand.
- I'm gonna pass out.
- Sit down on the floor.
Just get down on the floor. That's right.
That's right, eat two out
of my hand. That's right.
Okay?
While you're down there...
Get the pocketknife out of my boot.
This formula makes certain assumptions
which contradict all we know
about cold fusion cathodes.
Testing at any level becomes
futile without any further information.
Mr. Tretiak.
Don't despair, Dr. Botvin. Help is here.
The two came very quietly.
And they left even more quietly.
Close the city. Kill him.
And bring her alive.
Why? Why are they after me?
Tretiak, the guy I worked for,
owns this city. Cops and all.
We have to convince him there's
nothing more he wants from you.
What do you want from me?
- Everything's on those cards?
- Yes.
- So the formula works?
- Kiss me again.
- No.
- Make up your mind.
I... I have to figure out the
order before the formula works.
- I'm not gonna give it to him.
- Tretiak will find you.
- No.
- He found me, and that's very hard.
- I found you.
- Yes, you did.
What do you need?
I need some time, and I need...
I need a place to work.
- Where's everyone going?
- To their country relatives.
To cut firewood. There's
no heat in this city.
How long will it take
you to finish the formula?
I don't know.
- Uh, two hours maybe. I don't know.
- It should be enough time...
to get our passports together
and for us to get married.
- We're getting married?
- Yes.
I want you to be Mrs. Martin de Porres.
- You're not Martin.
- No.
Who are you?
I don't have a name.
Sad.
- Will you have one when we get home?
- I don't have a home.
When we get back, you do
the science, I'll do the math.
We'll market your formula around
the world, we'll make a fortune.
And then... we'll see.
Okay?
Emma!
No trouble, okay?
If you want to live, never leave my side.
I've got you.
Come on.
Here we go.
Now we've got to get you warm.
Come on, almost there.
Come on, come on.
You'll wait till Christ comes to Moscow.
Elevator was made of mahogany.
Tenants used it for firewood.
We need your help. He
fell in the river. He's freezing.
- We're just people who...
- You're not people.
- You're Americans.
- Yes.
But we ran into trouble with your Mafia.
She disapproves of what I
do, but eats the bread it buys.
No heat for sale, but these
clothes will make you warm.
I said "Mashenka, go back to
bed." She's always puttering around.
It's here. Built to escape...
the Secret Police. In you go.
You've got hypothermia.
We've have to get
these wet clothes off...
and keep you warm.
They must be in one of these buildings.
Check every apartment.
How are you doing? Talk to me.
Snug as a bug in a rug.
We're gonna have to do this
before your body temperature falls
below 95 degrees.
Two kids talking about foreigners.
Listen to me, tenants!
Show me where the Americans
are. You'll be paid in American dollars.
Five hundred bucks reward.
Have you seen by chance two Americans?
Just one American and
one polar bear. Do I get 250?
We'll check upstairs.
What's your name?
Who are you really?
- Simon.
- Simon?
- So you were named for a saint.
- No, Simon the magician.
I did tricks. Tricks for Agnes.
That's how I got things.
Priests took everything.
Took Agnes. Dog's too big... Teeth...
She fell. I escaped.
I always escape.
I don't believe in magic anymore.
I do.
I've never felt like this before.
How?
I'm freezing.
These are here! These Americans are here!
These are here!
We've got to get out of here.
Are you okay? They're coming.
The Americans are here!
Hurry, put this on.
Here they are!
Upstairs!
Maybe we can jump.
Let's jump.
Run!
We need her alive, idiot!
The embassy's east of here.
You're late. Where have you been?
I've been waiting two hours.
I've got some beautiful paintings
for you to buy. In here, come on.
Don't fret, it's just my curator, Toli.
I'm Alexa Frankievitch.
But being you're Americans,
you can call me Frankie.
- Okay, I've got money. We want...
- I know.
The icon of the Virgin of the Don.
- Are those maps of the tunnels?
- Yes.
We're not here to buy art. Take
us to the American embassy.
Right. I need 10,000 dollars up front.
No.
Okay, 7,000, and not a penny less.
Shh!
- Police?
- No. Tretiak's goons.
- Wait!
- Sasha, go east, to the embassy.
- Are we lost?
- What's wrong?
You're in Russia.
Everything's complicated.
- But you know the way?
- Like the face of a...
Bulgari chronograph.
Mmm...
I remember. This way.
At last, water main. They shut
it down each afternoon in winter.
What time do they turn it back on?
You have five minutes.
- Plus or minus.
- Plus or minus?
It means several
minutes earlier or later.
Don't worry. Third opening
is under your embassy.
Quick, someone's coming.
Come on, come on.
Here's the second one. Embassy's next.
- About two more minutes.
- Yeah, unless it's minus.
Damn! It's sealed.
- We'll have to go back.
- Come on.
Hurry!
Up you go!
The embassy's only about
a hundred yards away.
There's a car right above us.
Watch your head.
I'll create a diversion. Should take
you ten seconds to run to the gates.
They'll open them when
they see you coming.
- Okay, I can do that.
- You can do it.
Wait. When am I gonna see you?
I'll find you. You found me.
Yeah, I did.
I'm an American! Open
the gate! Open the gate.
Back off from the gate! Back off!
I said back off!
Stand back from the gate.
She out-ran you? How humiliating.
One shot left.
Can't come all the way to Russia
and not play Russian roulette.
Before you shoot me, don't you want
to know where all the money's hidden?
- Whose money?
- Tretiak's, yours.
He treats you like dirt.
You could have it all.
- What are you saying?
- Your father's stashed billions.
And I know where it's
hidden. Let's make a deal.
Where are all those hidden billions?
I know.
But I don't think I'm gonna tell you.
You're worse than all the others.
However, the burns will heal.
Maybe a little chance of scarring.
But I'd say he's a very lucky boy.
Lucky? Look at me, I'm a damn devil.
I have run every test on
this cold fusion formula,
and must conclude that it is not
merely incomplete, but impossible.
You may as well try to create
perpetual motion, Mr. Tretiak.
I invest millions,
and you can't make it work!
What are you doing with my money?
Do you think it comes so easy? No!
Sir, I have been working for
nearly two weeks without sleep.
At first blush, the theorem appears
quite impressive. Convincing.
It does?
Yes, it does.
Good man. We can use
it to destroy our enemies.
Only Dr. Russell can spoil my plan.
If she gets back to London
and speaks to the press.
From here to the airport are three
army checkpoints, all loyal to us.
Make sure they all get the message.
She doesn't leave Moscow alive.
Mr. President, as former Vice
Minister of Energy and Power,
I hear all manner of schemes
that provide cheaper energy.
And as our countrymen freeze to death,
I've become aware of a
marvelous new technology,
about which I'm hopelessly out of
my league from a scientific viewpoint.
That's why I brought our
eminent physicist here,
Dr. Lev Botvin from the
University of Moscow.
Before we are dazzled by the good
news, let's dispense with the bad.
What is the price of this marvel?
The cost of research and
development are there,
which is all you are asked to defray.
Ten billion in hard currency?
I can't even pay my teachers,
my miners, my doctors.
Where are you heading?
I thought we'd drink
some vodka to get warmer.
Like the miracle of socialism,
our miracle of cold fusion failed.
But no matter. We have sold
cold fusion to President Karpov.
We will use the scandal
of his failure to destroy him.
The army must be mobilized
by midnight tomorrow.
You're in a hurry, Ivan
Petrovich. That's one day.
Not now, old witch, we're working.
Yes, think of it.
In one day you can be proud
again to be a Russian general.
With a big nuclear missile
where your prick used to be.
You have to fill out a form
before we put you on a flight.
Medical problems, that sort of thing.
- Oh, I have a heart condition.
- Do you need any medication?
Well, I haven't needed
a pill. That's strange.
Get a form from down the
corridor. I'll be back in ten.
- I'll be by your side to the airport.
- Thank you.
...where overnight a mob attacked
several companies with ties to America.
Apparently, four U. S. citizens
were badly injured in the attack.
I'm told that American citizens are
asked to report to the U. S. embassy
for immediate evacuation...
Excuse me, lady, you look lost.
No, I'm, uh... I'm fine.
May I help you? Allow me to introduce
myself. My name is August Christopher,
I was named after Saint Augustin,
who coined my favorite phrase:
"Give me chastity and
constancy, but do not give it yet."
Simon, I'm on... I'm on
the next flight out of here.
Are you coming with me?
No. But they are.
I need you to develop
a sudden fear of flying.
Find a quiet room, finish the
formula and fax it back to me.
My number's on the back.
I don't understand. Why
are you keeping my cards?
We've got to do a deal with the
Russians or you'll never be safe.
Be good at school.
Wait!
- Don't you trust me, darling?
- Trust who?
- That hurts, Emma.
- I'm serious.
- What's your name?
- My name is August Christopher.
Of course I trust you,
August Christopher.
I mean, Vincent Ferrer.
I mean, Martin de Porres.
Thomas Moore.
After all, you are my personal saint.
You have to be very good and
usually very dead to become a saint.
And more importantly, you
have to work three miracles.
Now get to work. Who's that man?
You're leaving on the
transport at 9 o'clock, ma'am?
Probably your last chance
out of here. Hurry, it's leaving.
The troops will depose the President
and install Ivan Tretiak
as leader of Russia.
Moscow must be ringed
with tanks by early evening.
Don't worry, the people will follow
me. They'll be crying for revolution.
Still no one's guessed
the simple truth of
where the heating oil went.
Who would believe the sea of oil...
...was hidden under this very building?
Yuri, I understand your Natalia is...
Francis, you devil.
I heard you came down
here and you didn't call me.
Give me a ring, Charles...
Lou, I've heard on the grapevine
that you're brokering a
revolutionary new energy source.
If it's as good as it's cracked up to be,
I have friends who can
double your best offer.
On deposit, in Zurich, within one
hour of delivery and confirmation.
I'll be waiting.
The work could be here. This
machine could work, couldn't it?
Who are you?
- A friend of Dr. Russell's.
- Dr. Russell...
What's this equation?
It's so simple, it's...
- The key to Dr. Russell's formula.
- Yes.
The alarm! You had better go.
I need a miracle. You've got 12 hours.
- But Mr. Tretiak's rally is tonight.
- Can you make it work? Make it work.
- What is wrong here?
- It's the alarm.
Uh...
I tripped.
You are Nikolai Petrovich.
You are Nikolai Protrovich... Petrovich.
Tunnel built by KGB.
Leads to machine room in Kremlin.
Great. Do you happen to know
where the President's quarters are?
President Karpov is... there.
But there are many guards.
- So I suggest...
- An alternate route?
Money. Now.
Oh, ye of little faith.
Russia stands tonight on the
brink of a second revolution
as the number of deaths
from freezing mounts,
hundreds of thousands of
protestors have taken to the streets.
Even as Russian President Karpov
is promising a mysterious solution
to the crippling heating oil shortage,
troops opposed to the elected
government led by General Leo Sklarov,
have begun to ring
the Russian capital city.
- Tretiak! Tretiak!
- Angry, frightened citizens
are gathering outside
the Kremlin in Red Square.
But they're not braving the cold
for yet another a political rally.
They've been drawn here
by the promise of a revelation,
whatever that may be,
in what's become a
life and death struggle
for the future of democracy in Russia.
Mr. President, I'm your friend.
What do you want?
I want to help you to destroy Tretiak.
I need you to listen for 30 seconds.
I'm all right! Stay outside.
Please, continue.
Tonight you're going to stand trial
on Red Square before the world.
Whatever Tretiak accuses
you of, I need you to admit to it.
- Agree with this criminal?
- If you want to destroy Tretiak, yes.
Gruschev, take Mr. Karpov downstairs.
The wife stays here.
Hands off! What you are doing is illegal.
- The people won't stand for it!
- They are too cold to stop it.
Who are you?
Tretiak! Tretiak! Tretiak! Tretiak!
Friends! Countrymen! Russians!
You heard about this
morning's sensational event.
Shocking documents were recovered
from the president's secret files,
locked within his private safe.
The documents, which will
be published in today's papers,
prove that the traitor
Karpov was about to steal
over 40 trillion of our
precious Russian rubles
in a reckless scheme to save his hide!
To add insult, millions
of dollars were to be paid
to this international criminal!
And for what was your president
hoping to bankrupt our national treasury?
What you see is the fairy
tale called cold fusion.
You pass electric
current into the machine,
and there is supposed
to be a chemical reaction!
Watch! It can't even
light up a tiny light-bulb!
Do you dare deny this, Mr. Karpov?
Absolutely not. I proudly admit it!
But enough puny failure!
Failure is in the past!
Begging is behind us!
The balance of power is about to shift!
Miracle one.
Karpov! Karpov! Karpov!
- Ilya! Ilya!
- Go! Go, go, go!
I order all troops loyal to Mother Russia
to seize the criminal Tretiak!
A thousand apologies, Mr. President.
There was a miscommunication
somewhere in the chain of command.
Miracle two.
The billionaire industrialist
and his son Ilya were
taken to Lubyanka prison
where they await trial along with
fellow conspirator General Sklarov.
Moscow woke today to the
forgotten sensation of warmth,
as millions of gallons of heating oil
flowed from a storage depot discovered
beneath Tretiak's riverside mansion.
He made no threat to contact you?
He never had the chance.
- You'll tell us if he does?
- Oh, yes.
Which he may well do.
He's a proper rogue, you see.
He charms women, this so-called saint.
It seems it's his
stock-in-trade. No offense.
I am offended. All I got from this
saint was near-death experiences.
Count yourself lucky.
I have an important
conference to prepare for.
We understand. You have a life.
- We appreciate you taking the time.
- Ah, no problem.
She's in love with him.
I wanted to call and tell you everything.
- It just hasn't been safe.
- I couldn't stop thinking about you.
So, have you, uh, been busy?
Yeah, I've been working real hard.
Thank God I have my cards back.
You don't believe in that cold
fusion mumbo-jumbo, do you?
You're a very pretty lady.
Oh, my God! That was you?
That's who I thought
Dr. Russell would like.
I thought you were an old biddy,
not a gorgeous soon-to-be trillionaire.
You know you're gonna be
the richest woman in the world?
- I am?
- Why do you think I'm hanging around?
- Emma?
- Yeah?
My life is very strange.
I just...
I don't do anything
normal. I... I can't...
I know.
I know you.
I know your life.
- What do you want?
- I want you.
- For how long?
- It doesn't matter.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
Simon...
I love you, Simon.
Miracle three.
Dear Simon, the pin is something
I've kept for years, God knows why.
A graduation gift from Catholic school.
But don't worry, you
don't have to wear it.
I just wanted you to
have something I loved.
Simon, a sainthood
requires three miracles,
then I'd say, you've made it, my love.
And so I hope you'll understand.
Last night, it became clear to
me what I have to do this morning.
You see, I'm going to give
cold fusion to the world.
It's the only way, if
we're ever together again,
that I'll know it's for you
and you'll know it's for me.
If cold fusion is free, then you
and I, Simon, will be free too.
Listen. If you think giving away
everything in front of the world,
preventing us from making a
fortune, will accomplish anything,
you're absolutely right.
Simon, what are you doing here?
- There are police everywhere.
- I wouldn't miss it for the world.
- You wore the pin.
- Of course.
You'd better go.
How am I gonna find you?
I'll find you. You found me.
Although our next speaker
requires no introduction
after last week's Moscow fireworks,
uh, please let me
welcome Dr. E.J. Russell...
Excuse me, is this seat taken?
No.
Dr. Russell.
You don't believe in this cold
fusion mumbo-jumbo, do you?
No.
Well, we all know that cold fusion
has had, uh, a difficult childhood.
Those of us in the field are
orphans, bastards at best.
But difficult childhoods, I believe,
make the most interesting adults.
I know that most of you thought...
I'm her biggest fan. I think she's a fox.
Some may feel that its practical
application is still speculative.
But I want to share with you how
that dream is slowly becoming reality.
Oh, look at the time. Got to go.
With your help, we can all
work towards making the...
dream of cold fusion finally come true.
Got you, you slippery son of a...
What's going on here?
Damn!
Donations totaling three billion
dollars were made today to
the Red Cross, The Salvation Army,
and the United Nations' Children's Fund.
The funds were wired from the account
of jailed Russian tycoon Ivan Tretiak.
In other philanthropic news, a
non-profit research foundation
has been established to
develop cold fusion technology,
funded with an anonymous donation
and to be headed by Russian
physicist, Dr. Lev Botvin.
The E.J. Russell Foundation...