CONLI: Welcome to
our audio commentary
on our film Treasure Planet.
My name's Roy Conti.
I'm the producer of the film.
And I'm Ron Clements.
I'm the co-director and co-writer
of the film.
And this is John Musker,
the other co-director/co-writer.
Hi. I'm Glen Keane.
I'm a supervising animator at Disney,
and my job on this film was to design
and animate the character John Silver.
Hi. I'm John Ripa, and I was
supervising animator on Jim Hawkins.
Hi. I'm Ian Gooding. I'm the associate
art director on Treasure Planet,
and hopefully I can give you
some insight into how color is done
on a Disney animated feature
during the course of this commentary.
MUSKER: The entire prologue here,
we actually changed around
during the course of production,
in that it used to take place...
The story used to be told first-person.
Jim was the adult narrator of this story,
and he sort of pulled us into it,
but we discovered through the course
of some previews and whatnot
that it was playing kind of dark,
and we didn't have Jim
as a character involved in it,
so fairly late into production,
we reworked this opening
such that we see young Jim as a child.
We don't hear Jim
as an adult narrator anymore,
we hear Tony Jay who is...
Those of you voice recognition experts
from the FBI know
he was the voice of Frollo
in Hunchback,
in which Roy worked closely with Tony
and knew him from theatrical days
as I understand it.
CLEMENTS: Great voice.
MUSKER: Exactly.
CLEMENTS: Now we see young Jim,
little five-year-old Jim Hawkins.
Voices of Laurie Metcalf
and Austin Majors,
who is the little kid on NYPD Blue,
he plays Dennis Franz's son.
CONLI: You should talk
about the recording.
MUSKER: Yes, he was recording
in the same room
that we're in right now, actually,
and he was funny 'cause we had
Glen Keane in here working with him
'cause Glen really works well
with children
and was gonna animate some of this,
and we wanted to get him involved
in the recording,
and so Austin was all over the place,
so they had to put tape on the floor,
"Austin, stay by the tape,"
and it was an interesting
recording session.
KEANE: This was fun for me
because after doing Long John Silver
for the whole film,
to get a chance to do something cute,
it wasn't supposed to
look mean and ugly.
It was a nice change.
RIPA: Yeah, well,
we certainly appreciated
and needed your help at the time.
MUSKER: Jim's mother, Sarah,
it was an interesting
acting challenge for us
because we wanted to find someone
whose voice was old enough
that you bought as his mother,
and yet young enough
because she had Jim at an early age.
And Laurie Metcalf was special to us in
that she could play the maternal thing,
but she could get this sort of weariness
of being the single mother
who really had to make ends meet
on her own,
and yet a kind of vulnerability
underneath the kind of toughness
that she had to acquire to be
her own woman.
Sarah's clean-up,
that is the refined drawings done
over the rough animator's drawings
was done by Vera Pacheco,
a wonderful draftsperson
and the woman who, in fact,
supervised all of the clean-up
animation on the entire movie.
And Vera did a wonderful job
of really giving us
such a rich-looking, well-drawn film.
It had to be crafted particularly well.
It's being blown up
to large format systems,
and every little nuance
shows up on those big screens,
and we've been delighted to see
how solid the drawing is,
and our hats are off to Vera
for the great job she did on this movie.
CONLI: This was actually...
As we said we changed the story.
John had this idea of doing this
whole thing with the storybook,
making this pop-up book,
which wasn't part of the original thing,
and then we take this into
the transition to Jim Hawkins.
He's now 15-years-old.
We added that title
just in case you didn't know
that it was several years later.
RIPA: This section was a lot of fun.
Jin Kim, who was one
of the animators on the character,
did such an outstanding job.
These scenes were very difficult.
They dealt
with a three-dimensional board,
which, a lot of times,
he had to indicate beforehand,
3-D moving backgrounds.
He just really took to it
and did such a fun job.
The sequence, overall,
was just a lot of fun to design
and come up with movements
and poses, it really uses a lot of things.
It kind of went X Game crazy, I guess,
where there's sky surfing,
there's windsurfing, there's
skateboarding, snowboarding, surfing.
It kind of incorporates
a little bit of everything.
Also, Anthony Wong, Mike Cedeno,
John Pomeroy
did these few scenes here.
Um, Danny Galieote,
some of the other animators
that worked on the character
and just did a nice job,
everybody matching each other,
and clean-up did a nice job
because everybody does draw
a little bit different.
No matter what you do, everybody
has their set way of drawing.
And did a nice job pulling the character
into a consistent range.
GOODING: Establishing shot of the
Benbow Inn, painted by Carl Jones.
Really interesting 70/30 rule
that we had,
which was 70% 18th century mostly,
and 30% science fiction,
so we have half-timbered houses
with all sorts of techie stuff on them.
CONLI: And here we introduce
Doctor Doppler, David Hyde Pierce.
This part was written
with David Hyde Pierce in mind.
MUSKER: ironically, then we tested
a bunch of other actors
before coming back
to David Hyde Pierce.
Why we did that, I don't know exactly.
CONLI: Because it's your prerogative.
MUSKER: I know.
CONLI: Well, we wanted to make sure,
but he was definitely right for the part.
Although, we struggled a little bit
trying to get the right feeling,
and this bit here with the little girl,
this was added, actually,
fairly late in the game.
We felt we needed
a better introduction to Doppler.
(SCREAMS)
MUSKER: Yeah, we had a meeting
with some other writers
and story people to kick around
ideas for punching up his introduction.
Baird and Gerson,
if I've got their names straight,
they did some writing in this area,
some of which is here.
And David certainly was
a great improv guy,
so some of his funniest dialogue
throughout the film,
and even in this section,
were things that he winged in,
and he was just great,
great to work with, funny.
Ooh... Wrong turn.
-Okay. Thanks for the lift, guys.
-Not so fast.
RIPA: Joey Gordon-Levitt did the voice
of Jim, and that was just really a treat.
He did such a good job.
One of the things, as supervising
animator that you get to do,
which is really cool, is you get to go
to the recording sessions,
and watching Joey record the lines
was really inspiring.
He has a good, strong range,
and I always felt like
he put a lot of emotion into it.
There were some scenes that he did
that were so explosive,
and you're just chomping at the bit.
You really can't wait to get to them.
And another thing that he did
that I really was inspired by
was you felt he believed
in the character,
and he had a certain take
on the character,
and if lines came up that he wasn't
comfortable or sure about,
where it didn't feel like the character,
he'd try and improve them,
and come up with lines
that he could believe
were coming from this character.
And that's kind of what we do as a
supervisor when we approach a scene,
is to try and find something
that's true to the character,
and something that you believe in
and feels right.
And to watch him doing
the same things at the voice level,
really helped to set up and inspire me
and our team, I think,
for the scenes that we
were going to do.
Jim?
Jim, look at me.
CONLI: We added this bit
with Jim helping clear the tables
just to make him
a little more sympathetic.
MUSKER: Yeah, this was John Ripa's
idea to make Jim a little more active.
He's actually helping his mother out
in the end, here,
rather than just standing there
kind of moping.
We wanted to make him more active
to build a little sympathy for him.
In the earlier versions of the story,
he used to just sort of walk out
in the middle of their conversation.
She'd turn around and he was gone.
That seemed maybe a little too rude,
so we reworked it where he stayed
there in the scene.
CONLI: Lot of discussion about this
and the off-screen conversation
and what Sarah would say.
MUSKER: I thought it was more
emotional to have Jim be listening,
and hear himself discussed.
It just seemed like that if you're a kid
and you're hearing your parents
talk about you or adults talk about you,
they're not aware of it,
and you're overhearing this,
and they can speak frankly
about what they feel about you,
but you're on...
We sort of see his face
as he's hearing this,
we just thought this was a way
of getting inside his head
and feeling a little more
sympathy for him.
This dialogue used to be played
in a scene where he wasn't there,
and we just felt it was good
to play the dialogue off his face.
CONLI: There was also a question,
like the father thing,
this was the first real reference
to the father and that he's not there.
It was a big question about how much
to say at this point,
how much to reveal, and how much
to reveal in the course of the story
because Jim's loss of his father
is a big part of his problem,
but we didn't want to say it all too early.
MUSKER: We've got
Billy Bones' entrance here,
who is voiced by Patrick McGoohan,
who those of you fellow boomers know
from The Prisoner
and Secret Agent Man.
Braveheart, more recently.
And The Scarecrow of Romney Marsh.
So, it was a big geek fest for all of us
baby boomers
to be recording Patrick McGoohan,
who came in and was actually having
a very bad cold, was very phlegmy
and coughy, and it worked well
with things like this,
with his coughs of...
CONLI: He loved doing that coughing.
MUSKER: Yeah, 50 different coughs.
CONLI: I think he did... We could have
10 minutes of that cough.
KEANE: Nancy Beiman, who did
this Billy Bones character,
she researches everything.
This character was truly a believable,
organic character.
She developed his whole planet
where he had come from.
He's kind of from a turtle planet.
The way the neck comes out,
she had worked on all the anatomy.
Everything that she put into him,
there's nothing by chance on this guy.
And she's a pretty good example
of all the animators,
how everybody takes these characters
so seriously. These are real to them.
And there he'll be, just the way he was.
A smiling, happy little boy,
holding a new pet
and begging me to let him keep it.
CONLI: We used to have a line here
when Doppler opened the door
where he said,
"In the dream, is the pet dead?"
Which was John's line,
but as it played,
it almost seemed like the audience was
ahead of it, and we didn't need the line.
MUSKER: And this is funny
'cause some people thought
when Billy said, "My chest!"
Like you got shot in the chest,
and if you look at the chest,
that spelling almost spells "Ron"
backwards and upside-down.
CONLI: Not deliberately,
it just sort of came out that way.
MUSKER: I think there will be
several lawsuits involving that
by the time you hear this commentary.
CONLI: By Ron?
MUSKER: Yeah. By someone.
I don't know.
CONLI: This was where we had our
first Star Trek joke in the movie.
There used to be Doppler examine
Bones and then he said the line,
"He's dead, Jim."
And it was a funny line
and some people really liked it,
but it felt like it wasn't right
for what was going on there,
the emotion was too serious,
so we took the line out.
MUSKER: These holo-blinds here
that sort of work like venetian blinds,
but they show off a different scene.
Tina Price,
our assistant artistic coordinator,
was involved in developing this idea,
as was Ian Gooding and Andy Gaskill,
and Dave Tidgwell on effects,
and it really was a fun visual way
to mask the bleak planet outside.
And I'll tell you, at one point
we had more different scenes
that they went through, I think,
where again, in the interest of time,
we don't have as many,
but we just liked the idea
that it was sort of
an analogous thing to a phenomenon
people know,
venetian blinds
with sort of a sci-fi twist to it.
CONLI: I like to call them
Venutian blinds.
MUSKER: Venutian blinds, right.
CLEMENTS: We also used to have
a scene, a kind of dramatic scene
where the window
was blown to pieces,
shattered by the pirates
as they're bursting in the Benbow.
We took that out for various reasons,
but you will notice
that the window is there in the one
Doppler shot, and now it's shattered,
but we never actually
saw it shatter on screen.
CONLI: He's been bellyaching
about this for three months now.
CLEMENTS: I always liked that shot.
I always liked that shot.
MUSKER: Doppler's observatory.
A lot of the interior is based
on drawings that Michael Spooner did,
and they were really just trying to
set up this sort of eccentric bachelor,
but it had to serve different masters
in that we wanted Doppler
to be wealthy enough that he could
finance the expedition,
so we wanted a certain opulence
and scale to the place,
but also this sort of eccentricity and
this sort of scientific overlay to it all,
and we went through
a number of stages,
and yet we didn't want it to seem...
Some of the earlier drawings were
too cartoony, and we wanted it to fit
the rest of the style of the film
and not make it stand out.
So that was a bit of a struggle
for us to come up with something
that served all those ends, and
ultimately, I think it accomplished that
but it took a while to get there.
This is sort of a tour de force
of the effects animation
Dave Tidgwell
and his team supervised.
And Bill Konersman,
one of the effects guys,
worked on this for quite a while,
and just tried...
It was a fun sequence,
although it was one of those things,
in storyboards and in the script,
you're like,
"You have to take our word for it,"
"it's gonna look really cool
when it's done."
And people sometimes didn't realize that,
but it turned out really well, I think.
GOODING: Now, one of the interesting
things in the movie, color-wise,
is that we don't
use the color green a lot
because it associates
only with Treasure Planet,
so whenever you see green,
it represents good and moral,
and comfortable and, obviously,
exotic because Jim's home world
doesn't have any green,
so when you see the map,
it's all green
associating with Treasure Planet.
This is the answer
to all our problems.
MUSKER: There was a whole issue
of the flicker in the room,
we wanted this to feel
like it was a fire-lit room,
but the first pass on this,
it was so violent,
it seemed like the room was in flames,
and we had to go back several times
like, "Too much. ""Not enough."
And Tom Baker
and his scene planning crew
had to really back up
and go through this.
CLEMENTS: People take things like the
flicker for granted, but it was not easy.
It had to be redone several times
for continuity.
MUSKER: We did have to rewrite
this scene sometimes, too,
because we... There was a question,
"Why does Sarah let him go
on this big expedition?"
And we were rewriting
a number of times.
CONLI: This particular joke...
"Go, Delbert! Go, Delbert!"
(CONLI STAMMERS)
Early on, we had this.
This was an ad-lib by David, right?
And it made the film, got great laughs,
but it really was split
in terms of "love it, " and "hate it."
A lot of the staff didn't like it,
and said that it was
-too contemporary.
-MUSKER: Right, and so we wrote
ten different alternates
which we had David record,
and we tried out at various screenings,
and nothing ever got as big a laugh
as David's ad-lib, even though it was
anachronistic. So we said,
-"We got to go back to that."
-CONLI: Went with the original.
MUSKER: We went with the funniest
one, David's spontaneous ad-lib.
CONLI: I was one of the people who
thought that it was a little intrusive,
-but I've grown to love it.
-CLEMENTS: Go with the audience.
-It's so great.
-CONLI: Go with the audience.
CLEMENTS: Great animation.
Sergio Pablos, who did Doppler,
some great subtle animation.
MUSKER: Yes.
All of the other animators
I think were in awe of Sergio.
He's a brilliant draftsman, animator,
and impeccable in his timing,
his overlap, his technical skills
as well as his acting skills,
and people would just
study his scenes.
He was tough on his crew,
people working with him
had a high standard to live up to,
but it was always a thrill for us
to see his scenes
'cause they just were dazzling in their
technical mastery and acting chops.
CONLI: Here comes
the momma kahuna of all.
CLEMENTS: One of the
biggest shots in the movie.
CONLI: CGI shots.
CLEMENTS: Probably took,
how long to do this shot? Two years?
CONLI: Yeah, two years easy.
CLEMENTS: More than several days,
I think, yeah.
MUSKER: Peter Clarke really did
some great visual development on this,
one of our designers.
GOODING: Amazing model
built by Thomas Debitus.
Incredibly fun concept, I thought.
This was one of the earliest concepts
that the directors came up with,
and I just think it's a really fun,
magical storybook conceit
that the moon is really just a crescent,
and one of the things that really
attracted me to the movie, initially.
KEANE: Rick Maki
is a character designer
who worked on this movie
almost as long as we did.
Rick did, literally,
thousands of drawings.
He did aliens
of every possible persuasion.
And this spaceport sequence
was sort of a tour de force
where we tried to dig out as many
of these great Rick Maki concoctions.
Some have got tentacles, some fly,
some walk, whatever,
but Rick,
just a brilliantly inventive mind.
Familiarity breeds,
well, contempt, but in our case...
Look, let's just find the ship. Okay?
MUSKER: This is our special
Hitchcockian cameo.
That skinny, frail robot up there
is me, John.
CLEMENTS: And the little, hairy,
red-haired guy is me, Ron.
It started with Aladdin accidentally.
We did a little cameo in Aladdin,
and then we did one in Hercules,
so we felt
-we had to do one in this, too.
-MUSKER: We did the dialogue
here, as well, as we did in those.
-"Second berth on your right."
-"You can't miss it."
MUSKER: Boy. Is that acting?
-Don't answer that question.
-CLEMENTS: Okay.
MUSKER: So, this is our ship,
the Legacy,
that went through many name changes
on the course of arriving
where it was here.
CLEMENTS: I think we had a contest
at some point to name the ship.
Originally, we toyed with the idea
of using the Hispaniola,
which is the name
of the ship in the book.
MUSKER: I wanted to use that name.
CLEMENTS: John wanted to do that.
I didn't want to use that.
MUSKER: I wanted to.
CLEMENTS: Finally, we ended up
with Legacy, which I think
it was Glen Gagnon who came
up with the Legacy.
MUSKER: That was his legacy.
CLEMENTS: Exactly.
And we should talk a little bit
about Mr. Snuff,
the voice of that and the animation
is done by Adam Dykstra.
One of the rare cases
where an animator actually
animates the character
and supplied the voice.
How he did it, we're not quite sure.
I think that he used this stuff called Gak
but he was always by himself
in the recording session,
so we don't know for sure.
MUSKER: Captain Amelia,
voiced by Emma Thompson.
Emma was great to work with,
and animated by Ken Duncan,
one of the best draftsmen at the studio.
We recorded all of her, I guess,
in London,
and she really came into the sessions,
having looked at the lines,
and with ideas for rewrites,
and it was always fun working with her,
because we sat down
and actually hashed out the lines.
CLEMENTS: She's a great writer
as well as an actress.
CONLI: Literally, we would sit down
each sequence at a time, go through it,
-and then go into the recording booth.
-MUSKER: Right.
CONLI: Always beplussed us.
MUSKER: Right. She came up
with a particular word or something
that would just make it
very British, very precise,
and very much in character for her.
Captain Amelia, the captain of the ship,
is based on Captain Smollett
from Robert Louis Stevenson's novel.
Of course, in the novel, he's a man,
as, I think, just about all ship captains
were in that era.
Ted and Terry,
Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio,
when they did their treatment
based on Ron's original treatment,
thought the captain could be a woman,
sort of a woman alien,
and I think they described her as a
bird-like alien in their original treatment
but we liked the idea
of a female captain.
It just gave a whole twist to the story,
and we then wrote the part
with Emma Thompson in mind,
never knowing whether or not
she would do it,
but her kind of wittiness,
and take-chargeness,
and authoritativeness
and intelligence, we thought would be
great coupled with this sort of...
And there's an element of Emma Peel
in there, slightly...
CLEMENTS: I remember in the
first draft of the script,
we described Amelia as a combination
between Emma Peel
and Mary Poppins.
And there's still a little of that,
I think, that comes through.
GOODING: This set
is Amelia's state room.
We tried to come up
with a very soft lighting situation,
so that the characters
would not require tones.
Tones are the shadows
on the actual characters
that render them more dimensional,
and they take a lot of time,
and since this movie had a lot
of very cool effects sequences,
we didn't want to tie up the effects
people with doing too many tones,
so we tried to come up
with lighting situations
that would be better without the tones,
rather than having a movie
that just looked cheap.
Um...
We have a nice sort of
photographic light effect
happening here on the characters,
which we called "overspill,"
which happens when you
take a picture into a light source.
The edges of the characters
and backgrounds
get chewed away a bit
by the light behind them,
which is that sort of nice haze you see
working around the edges.
Mr. Arrow, please escort
these two neophytes
down to the galley straightaway.
Young Hawkins will be working
for our cook, Mr. Silver.
What? The cook?
CLEMENTS: So this sequence,
which is actually
the introduction of John Silver,
was actually one of the first scenes
animated in the movie,
one of the first to come out of story,
Barry Johnson did the storyboards
on this sequence,
and so a lot of this is some
of the first animation that was done.
This is like the first scene
that was animated on Silver
'cause Glen Keane, who did Silver,
kind of went in order,
and I think that was the second scene
that was animated.
KEANE: Silver is a
very unique character
in that he's the first time
we've animated
a character that's traditional
hand drawn and computer generated
in the same character.
And we really wondered,
"ls the audience going to believe this
character is real?"
"Is it going to look like he's got
metal pieces stuck onto him,"
"and they don't belong, they're not part
of his being? Are they going to buy it?"
And I was very happy to find that
the biggest challenges with Silver
were not the technical,
sticking a CG part onto him,
but as it should be,
it was the acting, the performance.
How do you make him real?
Right from the start, I knew that I could
do the hand-drawn part,
but I wasn't going to step into territory
that I wasn't comfortable with,
and Eric Daniels, who I had worked
closely with on Tarzan,
and he created the deep canvas look
with the jungle being able
to move in dimension.
And I just felt like
this guy is an inventor,
and we need somebody
doing the mechanical arm
who's not just a technician
and an animator, but an inventor.
CONLI: Probably good to note right
now the performance by Brian Murray,
which is just phenomenal.
It's probably one of the best voice
performances we've had at Disney.
(LAUGHING)
KEANE: Brian's voice, it comes from
somewhere way down inside of him,
and he can go from very light
and jovial, feels very sincere,
and just as easily switch
into a dark, ominous side
that you find just as believable,
which had to work for Silver,
that you had to genuinely believe that
this was a man who was torn
between the greed and lust
for this treasure
and a genuine compassion that he's
beginning to feel for Jim Hawkins.
CLEMENTS: Mike Show
did the animation on Morph,
and he studied lava lamps.
MUSKER: It was the cross between
a puppy dog and a lava lamp.
Mike didn't have a puppy dog,
but he actually has a little, at the time,
a little son, maybe a year old,
so he tried to get
some of his son's expressions in this.
CONLI: It's like a puppy dog.
CLEMENTS: Yeah, it is.
And Dane Davis, our sound designer,
who's a great sound designer,
he actually provided
the voice for Morph.
MUSKER: We're about to move
into this area now
where we tried to feature what's called
the virtual set,
where we built this whole
galley in the computer
and then rendered it and painted it
with deep canvas techniques,
such that we could move the camera
around and in it,
and this was sort of a unique use
because it wasn't
a bravura action scene,
it was more of a personality scene,
and we were trying to build tension
by the way the camera moves
in the scene.
CLEMENTS: There it starts to move,
and that is a three-dimensional set
painted to look
like a painted background.
Who be a humble cyborg
to argue with a captain?
KEANE: This moment,
I thought was, for me,
one of the most enjoyable acting
moments I've ever had
working at Disney,
working with you on this one.
RIPA: Yeah, this whole sequence
is interesting, but this scene actually...
Normally, the process is
you work on your characters yourself
in your room
at a separate time, usually,
and for that scene,
Glen and I actually worked
on the scene at the same time
at the same desk.
He would go up and do a drawing,
and he'd step back and we'd act it out,
and then I'd step up
and I'd do a drawing.
KEANE: Fortunately, John draws
at his desk standing up.
Everybody else sits in a chair,
but John stands up,
so we can actually do this
tag-team animating pretty easily.
RIPA: Yeah, it was pretty cool,
and this was some of the first
stuff that we did on the character,
and it's so huge
in terms of their relationship,
and the play back and forth.
Just the contact between them
and the interaction,
and keeping it going from this point
'cause it seemed like such a nice setup
between them
that trying to keep that in mind
whenever they're on screen and how
they relate and really working together
closely and knowing each other's
characters, I think, really helped.
We're all clear, Captain!
CLEMENTS: Early on, I think we've
always considered that these ships,
we would be using solar power a lot.
The technology of this universe
relies a lot on solar power
and artificial gravity.
Those are two of their big things.
MUSKER: Well, we always said
we wanted this to feel almost like
if they had discovered solar power
like in the 17th century
on a major scale
and really developed it,
this was where
they would have gotten then.
I think Andy Gaskill did some
of the early drawings on this
where he did these sort of hexagonal
patterns in the sails
which we really liked
in terms of just feeling like there was
this sort of fiber filament that
was a conduit in these things.
GOODING: We did a lot of research
on the color of ships,
how they were painted
back in the 18th century,
and settled, eventually,
on a white hull for the ship
because, several reasons,
it shows up very nicely
against the dark-colored backgrounds,
and also it picks up color.
White is a very good reflector
of what's happening around it,
so when it's in a colorful Etherium
that actually reflects onto the hull,
and it's really attractive.
MUSKER: This shot of the ship
with the manta birds swooping by
was based on a painting
that Ian Gooding did of the ship,
and these birds going by,
and it was just a majestic image.
CONLI: it was one of the
really early paintings,
and it really set a tone
for the whole movie.
MUSKER: it was sort of an icon,
and it was just
based on a visual development thing,
and we said, "We've got to get that
image into the movie."
So we really tried to duplicate
the feeling of that,
and I'm really happy
with the way it turned out.
The manta birds,
animated by Mark Austin.
CLEMENTS: I think there is one frame
that pretty much
matches the painting very closely.
MUSKER: It was really
Ian Gooding's vision of that image
that we really tried to duplicate on film.
CLEMENTS:
Deep canvas space whales.
These are the first characters that
Disney has ever done in deep canvas.
CONLI: Except for the manta birds,
but you don't notice them as much.
These take full advantage of that,
so they're painted like backgrounds
but animated as computer animation.
MUSKER: This scene was
a little bit of a struggle
because Doppler
was gonna be kind of slimed
by these whales and we discussed
what was the funny color
of this sort of slime
and went through various ones
and we wound up with...
This was our funny color.
KEANE: These scenes,
Marc Smith animated, who just became
my right hand man
on animating Long John Silver.
He has a natural appeal.
Appeal is something that I used to hear
all the time
from Frank Thomas, Ollie Johnson,
Eric Larson,
the old guys who did
Pinocchio, Snow White.
They were always talking about
appeal and sincerity.
And the word "appeal"
I haven't heard as much lately,
and looking at Marc's work,
it reminded me
of how important that is.
It's a natural thing.
You're born with this ability to just draw
and all the parts are in the right place,
and you are attracted to that character.
CONLI: It's interesting to note that
in the development process,
both in terms of characters
and backgrounds,
that we have about 15,000 pieces
of artwork that were developed
during the period
before we got into production.
So there's a lot of artwork
that gets generated
just in terms of spawning ideas
and massive amounts of character stuff
and background stuff.
MUSKER: A lot of this
cast of characters,
we really wanted to get
a range of shapes and sizes
in this supporting cast
of pirates and species.
And Peter De Sève was
fairly instrumental in doing that,
the character designer who did these
really fun designs,
little tentacled people
and huge hulking people
and the spidery guy and all that.
He kicked off a lot of that stuff,
and much of what he did,
Andy adapted and we adapted
and the animators jumped off from.
CLEMENTS: And Mr. Scroop here,
voiced my Michael Wincott,
who has a terrific voice.
Actually, originally, we had
a different voice for Scroop,
a different actor who was doing more
of a raspy, insectoid kind of voice,
and it didn't quite work, I think.
It didn't quite feel right
and so we went with Michael Wincott
and we're not doing anything
to his voice. It's a great voice.
And another one of
the character designers
was Eric Pigors who did
a lot of these characters.
His style was a little bit reminiscent
of Big Daddy Roth.
People from the '60s
may remember that.
And he's particularly represented with
the one alien with the one eye
that sticks out.
MUSKER: That was Eric's design
and we called him Pigors
in honor of Eric himself.
CLEMENTS: And we should
mention Mr. Arrow.
We haven't talked about Mr. Arrow,
voiced by Roscoe Lee Browne
who did a great, great job,
and T. Dan Hofstedt did the animation.
MUSKER: Right.
Yeah, we really liked, sort of,
the reserve that he animated with
and gave him that kind of solidity
and stolidity
and really made him...
CONLI: T. Dan's a real genius
at understatement.
MUSKER: Yeah. Yeah, he did
the emperor in Mulan
and found a lot to work with
a little on that as well.
Hey, I was doing it until that bug thing...
Belay that!
CLEMENTS: You mentioned Jim's
eye mask, which you just sort of notice.
I mean, he's had this little shadow
around his eyes
throughout the movie.
It's kind of a trademark,
along with his jacket that
makes him feel kind of internalized
and gives that dark,
brooding sort of edge,
presumably, the eye mask
actually becomes a thematic element
in the movie.
This section actually
started out much longer,
had a lot more exposition in it.
Then it got taken out.
We cut it out of the movie
completely at one point
to sort of keep
more mystery about Silver.
And then we ended up putting it
back in, in a much shortened version.
MUSKER: Also our movies are always
running... They have too much story
or they run too long,
and we wind up having to look for cuts,
and it's always difficult for us
to figure out
what we can cut,
what exposition can you cut
and still make the audience
understand the story.
CLEMENTS: We cut a lot
of exposition from this.
Here he used to talk about Billy Bones,
he talked about
why they needed the Captain
-to run the ship.
-CONLI: You really spelled it out.
CLEMENTS: And now it's pretty much
down to bare basics.
(LAUGHING)
This little bit with Morph here where
he turns into a little version of Scroop
was added just as a gag
and it just seemed a way of kind of
de-demonizing Scroop
to sort of make fun of
the boogeyman a little bit here.
So we added this and Mike Show
animated a very funny...
With his little Nijinsky move there.
CONLI: You can see Jim's
eye mask pretty clearly there.
Dark brooding eye mask.
And Silver's striped pants turned into
a little bit of a nightmare, too,
because they were
very difficult to draw.
MUSKER: So the clean-up people,
"Vera Pacheco,
was pleading with us, "Please don't,
"let's not do the striped pants
through the whole movie."
So we found a convenient spot
for him to go into a changing room,
and during the latter half of the movie,
he has remarkably unstriped pants,
which I don't think anyone ever notices.
But he has more than one
pair of pants, right?
CONLI: Sure.
Your father not the teachin' sort?
No.
CLEMENTS: Once again, there was
some rewriting on this scene,
just the question of how much to reveal
about Jim's father and what happened,
and how much to leave
for the song to reveal.
It's still leading into this father-son
arc, this surrogate father-surrogate son,
which is kind of what we're building
toward with Jim and Silver.
The captain has put you in my charge,
like it or not.
MUSKER: The montage
that we're entering into
was in the film for a long time,
but originally it had
a different temp song behind it.
It had a U2 song behind it,
and it featured other sort of visuals,
and we went through a lot on that.
Ultimately, Glen Keane
went and re-boarded it
and really changed it around
into what you see now.
And really changed it around
We delved more into Jim's back-story.
CLEMENTS: And even before he
re-boarded it, I think it was Glen's idea
to actually put the song
Iris by the Goo Goo Dolls
in as a temp track instead of
the U2 song, which we did.
CONLI: Glen really brought
Johnny Rzeznik to our attention.
MUSKER: Yeah, Johnny Rzeznik
who's the lead singer
of the Goo Goo Dolls
and kind of its central core member,
came in, we met with him.
We discovered that he actually
had a lot in common with Jim,
just in terms of his background,
growing up in Buffalo,
and his relationship with his father,
and just a guarded and troubled youth
who sort of came out of it
on the other side.
CLEMENTS: With a mentor's help.
I mean, a lot of parallels.
MUSKER: Right.
And so he performed the song
that he wrote here for us in a room
before he had lyrics,
so he would just lean over Roy, and,
"Hey," you know, just sort of...
(MUMBLING)
CLEMENTS: He did this sort of
Bob Dylan thing.
MUSKER: A little Bob Dylan-y,
and Angela Lepito
was filming the whole thing.
You can talk to her
about the tape, yeah.
CONLI: The whole idea here
of the flashbacks
was actually Glen Keane's idea.
That wasn't part of the original story.
This was originally just sort of
a Disney mentoring sequence,
but Glen had the idea of,
"Let's take this into Jim's past"
"and kind of show
what really happened."
CONLI: I think it's a testament to Glen
because here's the guy
who's the lead animator for Silver,
and then he's able to kind of
get into Jim's mind as well.
MUSKER: Well, the core
of this whole movie
is Jim and Silver, their relationship,
and I think Glen and John were both
intimately involved in developing that.
KEANE: I remember,
I had to storyboard this
and it just wasn't working,
but I felt in my gut
that we had to do these flashbacks.
So I left the studio
and went up to Lake Arrowhead,
about two hours from here,
and just sat up there and thought,
"Okay, if I was just going to do this
just the way Rzeznik wrote it,"
"this is what it would be."
But I wasn't sure if this
was gonna work,
so I called my wife
and I started to describe this,
and there was this silence
on the phone.
I said, "What, you don't like it?"
She said, "No, I'm crying."
"Well, then I'm gonna do it.
That's how it has to be."
CLEMENTS: I think it's interesting,
Johnny is just amazing
in terms of being able to interpret
the dramatic structure of a film
into the music.
I mean, he really gets the concept
of what the story is about
and he's able to kind of
transfer that pretty easily into...
And his lyrics are very strong, I think,
and really express a lot
of the underlying things
that we wanted to get through
in the character of Jim.
MUSKER: We're about to get into
this whole sequence where they...
After Jim sees his father
leaving for the last time,
now Silver invites him on board,
where he's going to
show him the ropes of driving,
and then Jim takes over.
And I think it was Glen's idea
to really work in
something with a comet
or something that just had
a spectacular visual to it.
So that became the basis for this
last little movement within the song
where Jim really takes Silver
kind of on this joy ride
and shows him that
he really knows what he's doing.
CLEMENTS: Sky continuity
was a nightmare.
MUSKER: Maybe we should also
talk about the size of stars, too.
CLEMENTS: Stars and sky.
We've said many times on this,
"if we ever do another movie again,
we don't want to have any sky,"
"or any clouds, or any stars."
It's just too complicated.
And there again,
people take it for granted,
like, if they look the same in every shot,
and they're moving
at the same speed in every shot...
And it doesn't always happen,
because somehow continuity
is very, very difficult to keep going.
And this movie, I think, is probably
one of the most complicated
in terms of continuity
and trying to match from shot to shot.
In terms of continuity
And we had to redo a lot of these skies.
CONLI: Well, basically, you're
just sticklers on continuity. (LAUGHS)
MUSKER: No one will ever notice.
GOODING: Now, this scene
ends up having
a very Brandywine School
of illustration look to it
because of the pool of light that we use
to stage the two characters in.
It's a very nice balance
of warm and cool here.
It sort of spotlights the two characters
and focuses your attention
on them nicely.
CONLI: Well, this is, I think,
some of the best acting
-in the film.
-MUSKER: Yeah.
Rick Hoppe did a number
of these scenes
of Silver and Jim at the beginning
and then Dean Wellins
did the latter half.
And really just some great
acting moments, I think, from Dean.
This was a subtlety in thought process.
Yeah, Dean Wellins was an animator
who worked at Warner Brothers,
and was a schoolmate of
John Ripa's and Sergio Pablo's,
and this is the first Disney film
he's worked on,
and he just was an outstanding talent.
CONLI: The whole Silver team
and the Jim unit was just amazing.
CLEMENTS: That scene of Jim
was just beautifully acted.
And this scene of Silver, I think,
is one of the best scenes in the movie
in terms of how well the acting...
MUSKER: Yeah. It's amazing.
KEANE: And something that we tried
on this picture
was to have a crew, a shared crew,
between John and I
where some of the animators
would do both characters,
just so that they would understand
the relationship that much better.
RIPA: And that, hopefully, yeah,
that that would make
the relationship on screen
come across better.
CONLI: The storm sequence
is a real showcase
for our head of layout, Rasoul Azadani,
and head of effects, Dave Tidgwell.
It was great, in terms of doing
an action-adventure movie,
I think it was exciting for Rasoul
to work with virtual sets.
This is the first movie
where we were really able
to move the camera
through environments.
And Rasoul is sort of the equivalent
of a live-action cinematographer,
so it was really a freeing thing for him
to be able to move the camera
wherever we wanted it,
and I think we really take advantage
of it in some of these shots.
And certainly this is
a big, big effects movie,
probably one of the biggest
that Disney's ever done.
And Dave and his staff really
responded to that challenge,
and did just sort of magnificent work.
I think we were really blown away
by the work of the effects department
on this film.
CLEMENTS: A lot of the reason
for the Etherium
and being able to breathe
in outer space
is so you could do something
like this on an open-deck ship
and it just made it
a lot more fun and visceral
than if they were in
some kind of a spaceship.
CLEMENTS: What would a space
sea adventure be without a storm?
MUSKER: Yeah.
Peter De Mund did
some of the effects here
with the explosions and all the smoke
trailing off this giant meteor.
I guess the idea for this,
Francis Glebas...
CLEMENTS: Francis Glebas came up
with the giant star shard
that reverses direction
and kind of breaks the sequence
into part one and part two.
Part one being the star shards,
part two being the black hole.
CONLI: This sequence really was
a tent pole for us.
We were able to get this
into production really early
because we knew
we wanted this storm.
MUSKER: Yeah, it was one of
the first sequences begun,
although it took a long time
because it had all these special effects.
CLEMENTS: Very.
And it's an effects tour de force
with a combination of
2-D effects and 3-D effects.
No, Captain. They're not erratic at all.
CLEMENTS: Those screens are cool.
MUSKER: Yeah.
...followed by the biggest
magilla of them all!
MUSKER: We were told
by Nancy Beiman
that we misused
the word "magilla" here,
but we took our lives
in our hands and said,
"Nancy, we're keeping 'magilla."
And she moved to
Savannah, Georgia after.
Aye, Captain. You heard her, men.
Unfurl those sails.
CONLI: Nice little piece of acting
for Arrow back there.
MUSKER: Yeah.
Birdbrain Mary, the little bird on legs,
that was John Mahoney's, I think,
character design.
One of our designers.
CLEMENTS: Although
not originally a female,
I think Ellen Woodbury, the animator...
MUSKER: She saw
something female there.
CLEMENTS: ...wanted to have
one female pirate.
And we agreed it would be nice
to at least have one female pirate.
MUSKER: To have the allure
of that woman there, yes.
CLEMENTS: Some people find her
attractive, which is really scary.
MUSKER: Ron, you do.
CLEMENTS: That's pretty scary.
(SCREAMING)
Now we've started to kill off
some of the more complicated
characters in the movie.
Arrow was very difficult to draw
and clean up.
MUSKER: Yeah, there are some
pirates that die during this movie,
and they die in order of
how complicated they are, I think.
The hardest ones to draw
went first,
so once the characters actually
realized they were hard to draw,
they started trying to erase
their own lines, but it didn't...
Captain, the last wave!
Here it comes!
Hold on to your lifelines, gents!
It's gonna be a bumpy ride!
MUSKER: As the ship descends down
into the black hole,
this scene actually was quicker
at one time,
and Michael Kelly felt strongly
we needed a beat
that really said,
"They're gone. This is over."
And so he expanded that time,
and I think that really to its benefit,
that you really have this moment
of suspension
where you're not sure
what's going to happen.
And he really let that hang there
and play out.
So all this movement de-crescendoed
down into this rest,
and then suddenly exploded out
and made the next part more powerful.
And I think Michael really sort of
went to the wall on that,
retiming that and really trying
to give that its maximum impact.
CLEMENTS: And Michael's
a brilliant editor,
and I think did a great job on this film.
And I think did a great job on this film.
And the most easy-going guy
you could possibly work with.
I mean, just unflappable, really.
MUSKER: It's that lighthearted
Irish thing.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Well, I have a lot of help
to offer anatomically...
Amanamonically... Astronomically.
CLEMENTS: That's a great line,
a very funny line,
written by Rob Edwards,
who joined us fairly early
in the writing process on this film.
He's actually one of the writers
from the sitcom Fresh Prince of Bel-Air.
And he worked on this movie with us,
writing the script for quite a bit of time,
and did a great job
and was a really big help
in the writing of the movie.
MUSKER: We had to cheat, sort of,
that Arrow's hat hung around
even though he went away
so we'd have a little prop
for them to react to here.
CONLI: Nice editing
by Michael Kelly with the...
MUSKER: Yeah, Michael Kelly devised
some of this, the pacing of this,
and the round robin of looks
that come up in terms of Jim's guilt.
Michael really had a fine eye for just
the pace and the length of these shots,
and who you go to when.
Right, coming up,
he cooked this relationship up here.
CLEMENTS: And Emma did a great job
on this little...
Eulogy for Mr. Arrow.
A fine spacer,
finer than most of us
could ever hope to be.
CLEMENTS: It used to be
a little longer,
and we actually followed her
all the way back into her...
MUSKER: Yeah, there was a scene
where she went into her quarters
and was sort of leaning against
the wall like she was overcome.
CLEMENTS: There was a bit
with Doppler offering to help
and she just can't talk to him,
and goes and closes the door.
It was very emotional, but it seemed
like it took away from Jim's emotion.
MUSKER: Ian Gooding design
of that big nebula.
CLEMENTS: This is a very key
sequence of the movie,
story-boarded by Ken Harsha
who did a beautiful job
on the storyboards of this.
And the animation by
Glen Keane and John Ripa
pretty much reflects a lot
of what was in those boards.
MUSKER: Yeah, it's almost
shot for shot.
Why, half the crew would be
spinning in that black abyss...
Look, don't you get it? I screwed up!
CLEMENTS: This was
a pivotal sequence,
I think, that we always
pictured this moment
as the bonding moment
between the two,
and that from this point in the movie,
actually that Silver and Jim
have become father and son.
At least, surrogate father and son.
And that that will remain.
That sort of can't be taken away.
So, this is the moment
where that happens
and that's going to play off a lot
in terms of what happens later.
James Hawkins.
You got the makings of greatness in ya.
KEANE: if there was ever
a sequence that I would love to go
and keep trying to make it reach
its potential, it's this sequence.
Because it's so deep,
and the emotions that I felt with this
were so much tied into my own history
and what happened to me as a...
When I was 18 years old
and my football coach comforted me
in the parking lot one night
after a football game
where I had completely lost
the starting position,
and I felt unjustly treated.
And he came out, and put his hand
on my shoulder and said,
"Glen, you're gonna do great things,"
"I'm gonna be there
when you're making that touchdown."
And, I mean, he had tears in his eyes,
and I had tears in my eyes.
And looked a lot like Long John Silver.
It was one of those soul inspirations
for me in this character.
And when you're drawing on
an emotion like that, that's so real,
you're setting yourself up for a fall.
You're never going to be able
to capture how you felt.
I think we both probably animated
every scene in this
at least two or three times.
Next thing ya know,
they'll be saying I've gone soft.
CLEMENTS: The softer side of Silver.
It was tricky, Silver was a very complex
character to deal with
'cause he's part bad guy,
part good guy,
and we were always walking
that tightrope as far as...
MUSKER: Yeah. If he was too nice,
that hurt the story.
If he was too dark,
that seemed to hurt the story.
We really struggled to find
a balance between the two.
This is a very complicated shot,
although it doesn't look like it.
It's a 3-D set combined with
some 2-D elements.
CLEMENTS: This is a lot of
Adam animation, right?
MUSKER: Yeah,
Adam Dykstra doing stuff.
And Dean Wellins did Jim here,
did some really fine attitudes.
CLEMENTS: Some of the first
animation that Dean did on the movie.
MUSKER: And Mike Show did Morph
through all this.
Mike Show and Jay Jackson
did all of Morph pretty much,
I guess there's a scene here
that other people did,
but Mike really did most of him,
which was great.
Joey Gordon-Levitt
who did a great job on Jim's voice,
he had to say,
"You little squidge," here,
and somehow he didn't like
the word "squidge"
and we had to talk him into it,
but Joey...
He loosened up in the course
of the acting process.
In the initial going,
he was kind of reserved.
"What is this all about? I've never acted
without other actors. "And all this.
But he eventually came
to embrace this,
and just did a wonderful job,
and did improv stuff as well.
CLEMENTS: With Joey,
it was very much like Jim,
that he started out very cautious
and reserved, and then he sort of
opened up more and more
in the course of, like,
several years of recording.
-These things take so long to do.
-MUSKER: Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
GOODING: Now here we see
the 3-D virtual set
re-lit with a completely different look.
With a sort of nice green light.
Now, everything has turned green
at this point,
so you know you're approaching
Treasure Planet.
CLEMENTS: This whole scene is one
of the tent-pole scenes
from the novel Treasure Island.
Of course, we haven't mentioned
Robert Louis Stevenson too much,
but he was the whole reason
for this going.
And there's the famous
apple barrel scene in there
where Jim Hawkins learns the truth
about Long John Silver,
and this is sort of our homage to that.
And we just felt it was important for Jim
to realize how he's been betrayed,
and we wanted to hang on
to that scene,
so this is sort of our adaptation
of Stevenson's scene.
CONLI: I mean, with the adaptation,
we were fairly faithful
to several tent poles in the book,
to kind of maintain that through-line.
CLEMENTS: And you
children at home,
we'd recommend
turning off the tape now
and going and reading the book
because it is actually a great book,
and well-worth reading,
and holds up to this day.
CONLI: It's worth noting
that the three of us
read the book when we were kids
and we fell in love with it,
and that's why the film is what it is.
GOODING: Towards the end
of this sequence,
you'll see that
everything's transitioning
towards a more golden-orange light.
Another difficult sequence to do,
as transitions always are.
Because we have our mutiny
coming up,
and that, we had originally keyed
the mutiny with orange light,
so we needed to somehow
transition to that,
so you see it gradually happening.
And it helps to highlight the characters
getting more and more angry, also.
MUSKER: We're coming up on
the reveal of Treasure Planet,
which, again, was one of those
slight nightmare shots,
but David Krentz did some drawings.
David Krentz was in layout, and
did these beautiful charcoal drawings
that showed how the planet
might be displayed.
And then Uma Thumrugoti,
that was one of the more difficult
names to pronounce on the movie,
really worked for months in terms of
just getting all that cloud animation
and the reel of the planet
working just right.
CLEMENTS: Originally,
we had Silver set down
his spyglass in the earlier sequence,
but the way it was staged,
there really wasn't any way to show it.
But, of course, the bigger question is
why does Silver
need a spyglass anyway
since he's got this cyborg eye?
MUSKER: We did record this scene
with Joey Gordon-Levitt
and Brian Murray
in the same room at the same time,
which we also did
in that earlier sequence.
CLEMENTS: A lot of the stuff we did
with the two of them together...
MUSKER: I think Joey felt strongly
he could play off another actor better,
and felt less like he was in a void.
And he was right, it really
brought a lot to the scenes
to have them both in the same room
and playing off each other.
CLEMENTS: And they bonded.
You had the sort of older actor
and the younger actor,
and they became good friends.
MUSKER: This scene through
Silver's eye we had to retake
because the first version of this,
it was all green and obscure.
You couldn't tell what was going on.
And we had to sort of rework it.
Dave Tidgwell sort of reworked it
to make it clear.
Now we're getting into
pirates as pirates here,
so we really wanted our homage to...
You know, classic things.
So pirates start swinging into camera
and storming down,
and we have a shot coming up of Silver
with the Jolly Roger
rising up behind him.
Very iconic images
we were going for here.
Brandishing the weapons,
I mean, all these...
Racing around the deck.
CLEMENTS: You might notice here
that Mr. Hands is also
very difficult to draw.
MUSKER: Here's one of the icons.
That pirate flag was designed
by Andy Gaskill, our art director.
By Andy Gaskill, our art director.
I'll see they all hang.
Doctor, familiar with these?
Oh, I've seen... Well, I've read...
Uh, no. No. No, I'm not.
MUSKER: The shot of Morph looking
at his reflection, I think,
was based on a Roy Disney comment,
where he needed to,
or wanted to get that set up
more clearly, why Morph was...
That it was a playful thing
and not a malicious thing.
CLEMENTS: Yeah, the idea of Morph
is that he is just
all feelings and emotions
and no intellect, and really has no idea
of anything that's going on.
Stop them!
RIPA: These are our big
submarine-type shots
where the camera is running through
and the characters are running through
these tight cornerways
and things like that.
Shawn Keller had handled Jim
and most of those running ones,
did a nice job matching
the atmosphere and everything.
(GRUNTS)
MUSKER: This is an example
of interactive lighting,
where there's a light source outside
that changes the lighting of the set.
CLEMENTS: I think Emma
really enjoyed the fact
that she could play action-adventure.
She's never really done
an action-adventure movie before,
and she was actually pregnant through
most of the Amelia recording.
CONLI: She was very happy
she didn't have to get buff.
CLEMENTS: So, we lost several
complicated characters there
that were very difficult to draw.
CONLI: So it's a lesson to you, kids,
don't ever be a complicated character.
MUSKER: You notice Silver's eye
changing color
through these sequences.
He sort of had a mood eye.
When he was in his normal mode,
and kind of full of blarney, it's yellow.
But as he gets angrier, or more
incensed or whatever, it gets redder.
So you'll see through
some of this section, it's a red eye,
and as he softens,
it goes back into the yellow mode.
KEANE: The recording session
between Brian Murray and Joey here
was just the greatest.
RIPA: Yeah, we could have stretched
this area out for about 10 minutes.
They did so much fun stuff
KEANE: You really felt
like there was this
competition between the two of them,
and actually, in the recording session,
when they were talking,
you felt like they genuinely
wanted to win...
RIPA: Yeah.
KEANE: ...between each other.
I felt like this was an animator's film
in that even though there's all kinds
of amazing effects and everything,
it's still character-centered.
That it gives you time to really explore
the expressions,
the attitudes of the characters.
It's only going to work if the audience
really believes and likes
your main character,
and relationships are growing,
and causing the audience
to want to see
what's going to happen
between Doppler and Amelia,
and Silver and Jim.
RIPA: Where it's all gonna go.
KEANE: Yeah.
MUSKER: These trees are 2-D
for the most part.
They're hand-drawn, but a million
levels of them so they get dimensional.
Except that was 3-D right there.
So we keep bouncing back and forth
between 2-D and 3-D.
And this shot was all 2-D.
It was a challenge because 3-D
is more expensive, takes longer to do,
and we really had to pick our spots
for our 3-D shots.
(GRUNTS)
Ow!
Oh, my goodness.
That was more fun than
I ever want to have again.
(CHUCKLES)
CLEMENTS: The basic idea
of the planet was, as we will learn later,
that the planet is really
a machine that is covered
-with a bunch of, like, moldy stuff.
-MUSKER: Fungi.
CLEMENTS: Kind of the stuff that
would grow in your refrigerator
if you left stuff in your refrigerator
over a million years.
And I actually think
there was research done
in terms of various bacteria.
MUSKER: When I went to CalArts,
it was our refrigerator that was like that.
Or was it the bathroom?
No, it was the refrigerator.
CLEMENTS: So,
there were subliminal things
that kind of may hint
that this is not a normal planet.
Although, until we see the structure,
I think we wanted people to sort of
take it more as just a planet.
MUSKER: But our layout department,
Rasoul and everybody,
did a lot of research into
just sort of different vegetation,
and they explored all sorts of fungi
and mold spores,
-and macro-things.
-CLEMENTS: Coral.
MUSKER: Little micro-things that
they blew up to huge scale.
Yeah, and coral structures.
And tried to make it sort of
an other-worldly landscape,
and yet, vegetation.
That was a big thing.
We wanted to get some green
into the movie.
We kept green off the color palette
until we got there
to play up that there was still
a tropical island analogy
we wanted to get,
that there was something
almost tropic about this place.
And to disguise its machine origins,
that it really...
You wouldn't suspect it, first thing,
it seemed so organic
that it could be this inorganic place.
Plus, then we had to design
the alien technology.
What was this race
that built this planet?
What was their technology like?
And we didn't want it to be human stuff,
so some of the early development
on that seemed a little bit
"too much gears and sprockets,
and we said, "Well, no.
"It's got to feel more other-worldly."
It's a culture that isn't the culture
of the rest of the movie,
so that was a challenge to find
something that felt different enough
so that it stood out from that.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Oh, this is fantastic!
A carbon-based life form
come to rescue me at last!
I just want to hug you and squeeze you
and hold you close to me.
All right. Okay.
MUSKER: Martin Short,
the voice of B.E.N.,
noted from all his movies
and everything,
great improv actor. So we wrote it...
We tried to take advantage of Martin,
but certainly he added a lot
in his improv.
CLEMENTS: Yeah, we probably
have five times,
six times as much material for Martin
as anyone in this film.
MUSKER: Yeah, we have
a whole raft of material.
I am, um...
My name is, uh...
This gag here, where...
The cuckoo thing was Barry Johnson,
our head of story, his idea,
his gag, and it gets one of
the biggest laughs in the movie.
It was Barry's idea.
B.E.N., in the script,
we had a whole thing
where he leaked oil inadvertently,
and that somehow went away
eventually. It was vaguely scatological.
But somehow, I don't know why
it went away, but it went away.
CLEMENTS: And you still miss it.
MUSKER: I miss it,
I think we made a mistake.
But, hey, let's just talk about
the mistakes for a while.
CLEMENTS: This was ad-libbed,
this whole little rant here.
MUSKER: Yeah,
this rant about his therapist.
Rambling, and very funny Martin
off-the-wall shtick.
But that means... But wait.
MUSKER: Oskar Urretabizkaia was
the animator for B.E.N.,
and of Basque Spanish descent
and very difficult-to-pronounce name,
but he did a great job.
We were concerned
'cause B.E.N. is a 3-D character,
but we wanted him to integrate
with the 2-D characters,
so his animation was meant to be
as cartoony as the other characters.
And we tried to design him
so he had a line around him
so he'd fit with the other characters,
but Oskar animated him in a way
that really kept him loose,
and the guys who built the rig
and all that
made it very squashy and stretchy
so that it would integrate
with the other characters.
That was the goal here, really,
not to make him feel like he was
from another planet, so to speak.
CONLI: Yeah, the whole idea
of doing him in 3-D
was to be able to get the amount
of detail on the character
but still try and maintain
the squash-and-stretch
-of the actual...
-MUSKER: Right.
Given that he was a robot,
it seemed like a natural fit for 3-D.
I've lost my mind.
You haven't found it, have you?
My missing piece?
My primary memory circuit?
Look, B.E.N...
CLEMENTS: We get into
the missing piece idea here,
which was a little controversial
for a while,
but is actually thematic.
Wanted to sort of keep it because
it really ties into the whole movie
in that sort of every character has
a missing piece in some sense.
B.E.N.'s is fairly literal,
but Silver has one in terms of
that he lost his arm.
-Jim lost his father.
-MUSKER: Yeah.
I do. Bye-bye.
(WHINES)
CONLI: The fact that whenever you're
doing a 2-D and 3-D combination
it's, from a technical standpoint, for a...
MUSKER: The worst thing is where
they touch each other.
Touching and talking,
those are the two big no-no's.
CLEMENTS: ironically, that B.E.N.
is such a touchy-feely guy,
and that's the hardest thing to do.
MUSKER: Yeah,
every time a 2-D drawing,
something that someone drew
on a piece of paper,
interacts with something
created in a computer,
it becomes a very difficult task.
And yet, B.E.N. is a compulsive
sort of grabber and toucher
and wants to be...
ls desperate at being left alone again.
So we really wanted him
to be hanging on Jim,
so that made their jobs
much, much harder
to make that work together.
CLEMENTS: But they did a really
good job, I think, there again,
you don't really think about it.
They integrate really nicely.
GOODING: Here's another instance
of comedy being extremely difficult.
We went through such pains
with those underwear,
trying to get
the funniest possible pattern,
and something that read as underwear,
and hopefully everyone's going to be
in hysterics over that one.
CLEMENTS: Now Doppler
loses his jacket.
Every character kind of
simplifies himself a little bit
through the course of the movie.
MUSKER: Craig Elliott,
one of the layout artists,
helped design this alien language
that you see written on the walls,
and on the technology here
that built this whole planet.
This whole planet was built, of course,
as you can surmise,
by an ancient race of aliens
that abandoned it.
Who built it for scientific purposes
to explore the universe.
CLEMENTS: Once again,
we took out a lot of exposition,
so we leave that to
the audience's imagination.
But there was a whole back-story...
MUSKER: I'm sure you're all imagining.
CLEMENTS: ...with this
ancient alien culture
who built this planet,
and why they built it.
KEANE: Coordinating these kinds
of scenes was a huge challenge,
where you've got all the pirates firing,
and just how many...
Sometimes we'd have
up to 12 animators
in the director's office
on a scene handout,
and everybody's got to learn their part
and do their character.
No tricks, just a little palaver.
CLEMENTS: This is
very much from the book.
MUSKER: Yeah,
another tent-pole scene.
The negotiation scene between Silver
and in the book, the captain, actually.
And in our earlier versions,
we had him negotiating with Amelia
and Jim standing by.
But Jim is our central character,
it seemed that
the key relationship was between
Silver and Jim,
so we reworked the scene to feature,
again, their sort of challenge
between the two of them.
CLEMENTS: This was a difficult scene
to write, rewritten many times just to...
A lot is going on between the dynamics
of the two characters,
and Jim is kind of taking control,
starting to take charge,
and Silver, there's some vulnerability
here on Silver, I think,
which is what makes him
completely lose his temper
as the scene progresses.
CONLI: It's important that the audience
not be sure
whether what he's saying
is true or false.
MUSKER: Yeah, they're trying
to scope him out just as Jim is.
Is he telling the truth at all?
Can you trust him?
CLEMENTS: We adjusted this scene
a little bit in terms of the acting.
Originally, Jim didn't seem so much
like he was kind of considering
and going along with Silver's proposal.
MUSKER: And it seemed to give
more dramatics to let him seem like
he was being taken in and then
sort of throw it back in Silver's face
to kind of misdirect Silver
as well as the audience.
CLEMENTS: Once again, it has Jim sort
of gaining a little bit of the upper hand.
CONLI: (CHUCKLING) Although
he does have the eye mask on.
CLEMENTS: He does
have the eye mask.
MUSKER: He's a more
guarded guy again.
CLEMENTS: He hasn't resolved
his problems yet.
MUSKER: We do have some slight
moving camera,
although this was done
with a 2-D technique
where we're just panning
the camera behind him
just to get a feeling of point of view
of Silver as Jim circles around him.
CLEMENTS: Jim is high, Silver's low,
which, once again, is emphasizing that
Jim is gaining the upper hand here.
Try to find it without my map,
by thunder!
You still don't know how to
pick your fights, do you, boy?
Now, mark me.
MUSKER: There was the famous scene
in the movie and the book
where, "Somebody help me up,"
where Silver is sort of lame.
We wanted to get the feeling
of that moment,
even if we didn't do that literally,
but just that
there's this anger and volatility
on the part of Silver
and this sort of estrangement
of their relationship here.
Now!
Oh, blast it!
MUSKER: We went back
and sort of adjusted this end
to put back a look of regret
on Silver's part,
which we took out at one point, but it
seemed to give you a little feeling of
he didn't want things to go this way,
but that's the way it played out.
CONLI: Yeah. Finding that balance
between their relationship
and Silver's wants
was always an issue.
-Ohh.
-And what? What?
We must stay together and what?
Doctor...
MUSKER: David's line of dialogue here
involving "I'm not a doctor," we had
written that in kind of a Star Trek joke.
CLEMENTS: Second Star Trek joke
in the movie.
MUSKER: Yeah, although then
David really elaborated on it,
so it was his improv
that went into the whole,
"You can't do anything
with a doctorate."
"You just sit there and you're useless!"
That was all David's improv.
It was very funny.
CLEMENTS: His greatest ad lib,
it was written as Doppler kind of
breaking down and losing it
but he took it to something
-that was...
-MUSKER: A new level. Yeah.
It's just Jimmy
has this knowledge of things.
MUSKER: And this was
a Martin improv, with that,
"Jim, any thoughts at all?"
after the big build-up.
That was Martin's funny sort of
understated improv on that.
If we try to leave, we're dead.
CLEMENTS: And this little bit with
Morph, that was a Ken Harsha idea.
MUSKER: The "We're dead,
we're dead, we're dead," is a funny...
That Ken came up with.
RIPA: You know what's interesting, too,
is kind of
looking at Morph there a bit
and how much he actually
means to the story,
and scenes, and for the characters
to work with and play off of,
and how he works
between Silver and Jim.
KEANE: Well, to me, a villain
who's really nice to his dog,
is no real villain.
I mean, in the end,
there's a redeemable quality to him.
The fact that Silver loves Morph
is a very redeeming thing.
There's no character with a more pure,
genuine heart in this than Morph.
RIPA: Yeah, they'd always talked
about Morph almost like a puppy,
very innocent.
And they're always very watchful
as far as how much he understood
and how much he didn't,
as to what the situations were.
CONLI: There used to be a scene here
where, actually, they went out
and B.E.N. had a skiff
called The Mambo Queen
which was like the book, I mean,
'cause Ben, in the book,
did have a boat that he built.
MUSKER: Yeah,
he had a little raft that they used
and so they went to his little flivver
and flew it to the ship.
But then, as we shortened the movie,
we got rid of his Mambo Queen
and we just had them
steal this longboat
and make their way to
the Legacy to steal back the map.
Andy Gaskill story-boarded this section.
And originally,
guarding the ship was Mr. Hands
so Jim had a big fight with Mr. Hands
based, again, sort of on the archetypal
scene of the movie and the book
where he had to go back to the ship
and deal with this guy, but...
Tom Schumacher actually said,
"Hey, Scroop is a much scarier guy"
"and he's better to have as your villain.
You got too many characters,"
"so why don't you
redo this with Scroop?"
-And I think that was a good idea.
-CLEMENTS: Yeah.
MUSKER: And we went back
and redid it.
We used to have a thing,
like Mission: Impossible where
Jim tried to disguise himself
by wearing a mask over his face
so that he looked like...
No, no, Morph was the mask.
Morph was the mask.
CONLI: So he disguised himself
as Mr. Onus, using Morph as a mask.
MUSKER: Yeah, it was like
Tom Cruise in the movie.
CONLI: Kind of a fun idea.
MUSKER: Again,
we've got the virtual set here
where we can actually track
and travel down through this.
We have our homage
to Larry, Moe and Curly here.
CLEMENTS: There's a Three Stooges
aspect to Morph
played out quite a bit in this sequence.
(POWERS UP)
B.E.N.: Whoops. Okay, don't panic.
CLEMENTS: The big fear
with this sequence is
it would become too intense
with a Disney film.
CONLI: There used to be a leaking pipe
where you had the hiss coming
and another half dozen shots probably.
CLEMENTS: We actually
took out a little tension.
John added this bit with...
MUSKER: Yeah, we had variations
on that. We had a boxing glove.
We had a hammer
hitting him in the head
but we went with the poke in the eyes.
CLEMENTS: To break the tension.
CONLI: Continuing with
The Three Stooges.
CLEMENTS: Counter the tension.
MUSKER: And the idea of this whole
anti-gravity fight
actually went back to
Ted and Terry's script.
They concocted the idea
of Jim having to deal
with the gravity going off
in the middle of this thing
and B.E.N. futzing with the wires
and that was Ted and Terry's thing.
(GRUNTING)
Heh, heh.
MUSKER: There was a question at
the end, too, how we'd dispatch Scroop
and in the earlier versions,
these pistols,
some of them were freeze guns
and there was a whole sequence
where we showed
how they worked and everything
and then as Scroop attacked Jim,
he wound up shooting him
and freezing him
and he broke into a million
little ice shards as he fell to the deck.
But then we saw Atlantis
which had the villain
crystallize and freeze
and break into a million pieces,
and we're like,
"We can't do that. They just did that."
So we had to rework it.
CLEMENTS: Yeah.
There was also a question of
whether Jim should shoot Scroop...
MUSKER: And not have
the violence questioned.
CLEMENTS: Which he did at one point.
He did shoot him.
MUSKER: There did seem
to be something poetic
about seeing Scroop
sail off into the distance
à la what he did to Mr. Arrow.
Poetic justice sort of thing.
B.E.N.: Laser cannons disconnected,
Captain Jimmy, sir!
Gee, that wasn't so tough.
GOODING: The lighting in this
sequence was really interesting.
The very strong under-light
coming up from that air vent.
Fine work, Jimbo.
GOODING: That was a very, very
difficult scene to do
where Silver comes
out of the darkness.
Just the balance of what you see
and what you don't see
was hard to achieve.
And this whole sequence
had to be really dark
so it would be believable
that Jim didn't see all these pirates
when he first came in,
but not so dark that the audience
couldn't see what was going on.
You're just like me, Jimbo.
Ya hates to lose.
MUSKER: I think Glen really wanted
to do more of a tour de force scene.
This is actually animated by Jin Kim
but sort of devised by Glen, I think,
where Silver really struggles
to make this thing open
to build up his frustration with Jim
and to give Jim the upper hand here.
The fact that he can do it effortlessly
where Silver can't possibly
do it without Jim's help.
CLEMENTS: Once again,
we played this at one point
that Jim was completely demoralized
by giving the map directly to Silver
after he thought he'd won.
But that scene,
Jim seemed too passive
so we kind of tried to give him
a little more defiance here
that he's not giving up,
even though he has to.
CONLI: We had to keep him alive
through the rest of the film.
MUSKER: Yeah, he receded too much.
CONLI: Receded
into his eye mask thing.
MUSKER: Yeah.
KEANE: These are some of
the most difficult scenes to animate.
Chris Hubbard did a lot of
these scenes where Silver is in awe.
And when you animate
a character that's in awe of something,
it's the other thing
that's really amazing,
and they're just responding to it
and all you have to do is
a slow, gradual opening of the eyes
and the mouth and a fascination.
And you don't have much to work with.
It's very subtle.
And I think he did
an incredible job with it.
MUSKER: And Ian Gooding concocted
those centipede trees.
They only appear really
in that one shot,
but it was so great, we had to use it.
And this sequence was
originally much longer
and it was based, again, sort of on
the book and on the movie where
they were going through
this dark, spooky place
in anticipation of finding the treasure.
CLEMENTS: And some complicated
characters got killed.
MUSKER: We had killed off
a few people
in traps that Flint had set for people
as they were coming and it just...
We needed to get to
the treasure sooner
so we wound up
tightening this sequence.
GOODING: Of course,
we had this pulsing
lime green light in the background
that just keeps going
through the whole sequence,
and that was a continuity nightmare.
To try and get it just right.
It also changes speed
which was difficult to track.
So that the further along you go,
the faster it gets
right up to the end.
KEANE: It's at this point that you start
relying on all the pipe work
that you've laid on
how the characters relate
to each other.
That you can just,
in a very quick moment,
have a look between Jim and B.E.N.
that says enough.
You don't have to go
really far and develop it
'cause now we've got
a lot of story to tell.
RIPA: Yeah.
KEANE: But we've already
set the characters up
so we can move through it quicker.
CONLI: This whole area that
we're going into is really kind of
a testament to Ron
in terms of his persistence
on wanting to get this portal functioning
and it really came out
to be pretty brilliant.
MUSKER: Frank Nissen sort of helped
design this controller,
that little green sphere that comes up
and then gets the whole portal
opening here.
CLEMENTS: We were able to get the
dimension and the size of this thing.
CONLI: This is where we get
more into science fiction
than we had before.
MUSKER: Yeah, Andrey Brandi, one of
our Hungarian conceptual designers,
concocted a whole bunch of worlds,
which we see very much
quickly in passing here
and not in Hungarian.
And Dave Tidgwell actually,
using Bryce and other programs,
concocted some of these
3-D environments
that we see through the portal.
CONLI: We used to have
more exposition here
and actually we used to have
these zaftwing, these birds that
actually flew out of one of the worlds.
MUSKER: And interacted with
Jim and Morph and everything,
but, again, we were trying to
pace it a little more briskly
so it got shortened.
CONLI: The key idea,
which we hope is clear, is that
the planet is actually a machine
that works these portals.
CLEMENTS: We took a lot of time
working this and trying to craft it so that
-you could get a lot of exposition in...
-MUSKER: Trying to rewrite...
To get the least exposition you could
and yet get it clear.
That was a real struggle.
KEANE: I like it when Silver
starts to get frustrated.
-There's this volcano inside.
-RIPA: He looks good yelling.
Yeah, he's like one of those
few people that looks good mad.
RIPA: Yeah, he does.
GOODING: So, here we get the idea
that the planet,
which was really good on the surface
and covered with natural green stuff,
is actually quite rotten at the core.
It's filled with gold,
which you'll see in a second.
And that sort of helps to
carry through our idea
with the green
and the gold storytelling.
The loot of a thousand worlds.
This big idea here actually
was one of mine,
where the core of the planet is like
a huge spherical computer floating
at the gravitational center of the planet.
And the way it communicates
with the rest of the planet
that works the portal
is through these information beams
fired by the prongs
and fired back by the core.
I can't remember why.
B.E.N., come on.
We're getting out of here...
CLEMENTS: And this area was
reworked some I think.
-MUSKER: Some?
-(ALL LAUGHING)
CONLI: We spent a lifetime
on this one.
CLEMENTS: The whole idea,
Flint's ship and Jim...
I think Roy had
wanted to bring in that element
to keep Jim more active through this.
So he had a plan.
MUSKER: Yeah, and in earlier versions,
he didn't really try and get away
on the ship and all this.
This really came about...
CONLI: We really were starting to find
something for him to do at this point,
-to keep active and this became...
-MUSKER: Right. Right.
There used to be
a sequence here where...
I mean, B.E.N. used to have
more flashbacks
and in flashbacks we saw
what happened to Captain Flint
and the pirates, and a gunfight,
and that all went away.
CLEMENTS: The original idea was that
B.E.N. would get his missing piece back
as he's about to right now.
And when he got it back,
he would remember everything,
and basically deliver
tons of exposition that would explain
every aspect of the movie
that anyone had ever questioned.
CONLI: We had just, literally,
tons of exposition.
MUSKER: And we had a version
like that. He went through,
"Annual rainfall 7.5 inches.
Planet built over a series of years."
And he belted this story out,
as we encouraged him to do.
Five minutes of exposition.
"Billy Bones stole the map."
"What else do you need to know?
Let me tell you."
And it just got a little too much.
CLEMENTS: But it went through how
they discovered the planet.
MUSKER: There were
explosions going on.
CLEMENTS: They had stumbled
onto the planet
and had discovered the portals
and B.E.N. figured out
how to operate them.
And then the pirates stole the map.
CONLI: And all the picnics!
CLEMENTS: And Billy Bones
was the cabin boy and they deserted.
And then Flint booby-trapped
the whole system
so that if anyone ever returned,
they would find trouble.
KEANE: The way these
little pirates move,
they add such a spark
of action and movement and life.
Without their crazy way
of bouncing around...
They always add lightness to a scene,
no matter what it is.
RIPA: And just even
the layout work and the scale
of this whole area is just amazing.
This is a tragic scene.
No! No! Oh, no! Oh, no!
MUSKER: Silver was
grabbing for all the treasure.
Everything he's lived for
is going past him.
CONLI: Now this is just
phenomenal effects work.
CLEMENTS: Yeah, a combination
of 2-D/3-D. But mostly 3-D.
MUSKER: That scene of Silver
at the end was gone for a while.
We thought we didn't need it
and then we realized,
"We better have that in there."
This little sequence where Doppler
turns the tables on the pirates
used to be longer, and we had him
actually doing a little gun...
Demonstrating his nimbleness
with a gun and doing a little gunfight.
CLEMENTS: This was
going to be Doppler's moment
where he was really going to
-turn into Errol Flynn.
-MUSKER: Right.
And we had him at the end also getting
more dog-like where he was barking...
And sort of doing in the pirates
and howling.
CLEMENTS: He actually did
the sharp-shooting thing.
"You've released my inner mongrel!"
MUSKER: We had a line,
"You have released my inner mongrel."
And Amelia, herself...
(IMITATING CAT YOWLING)
-Did a little cat thing.
-CLEMENTS: Oh, yeah.
MUSKER: That all went away.
It was just too much.
CLEMENTS: We shortened it
and you still get the idea.
He basically turned the tables.
MUSKER: It seemed like we were away
from the other action too long
sort of to make it feel right, so
we said, "It's gotta be more concise."
Yeah, Adam Dykstra did that.
Emil Mitev is the layout artist who
designed a lot of these interiors here.
Emil did a great job with just
the whole devolving planet here
and the scale of these shots
owes a lot to his drawings.
CLEMENTS: This was also a scene
we struggled and struggled over, this
sort of final confrontation
with Silver and Jim.
MUSKER: Yeah, we had it longer,
we had it shorter.
We had it more friendly on Silver's part.
We had it darker and blacker.
CLEMENTS: We had Jim
lowering the sword
or Silver knocking the sword away.
MUSKER: We had a million variations
on this and just, it was...
CLEMENTS: We had
more father-son bits
where Silver said,
"You're just like me, Jim."
MUSKER: And Jim just said,
"I am nothing like you!"
And, in fact, this whole sequence
used to take place out in the snow.
In an earlier version, there was a race
back through the portals.
And Silver and Jim actually were
stranded on this sort of snowy planet
in the earliest versions.
CONLI: 'Cause the portal used to
take you from world to world.
MUSKER: They worked
in a little different way
and they went to a winter world.
CLEMENTS: And you had to go through
a sort of tunnel of worlds
to get to the center of the planet.
MUSKER: So the earlier lines all had
Silver shivering, "Hang on, Jim!"
And so we couldn't use
any of that dialogue,
so we reworked it
into this environment,
so that all got rerecorded.
CLEMENTS: So now we reach
Silver's moment of truth.
MUSKER: I mean, this was really one of
the archetypal moments
where we were trying to find
a way to stage it where, basically,
Silver has a choice here.
He can either save this treasure
he's been obsessed with his entire life,
or he can save Jim. He can't do both.
(SIGHS)
When we first talked to Glen Keane
about working on the movie,
we described a scene that
demonstrated this idea,
and that was something,
through the course of the film,
no matter what we did,
we tried to hang on to,
just that this was a pivotal moment.
CLEMENTS: There was one point
we had here
when Silver finally made the decision
to let go, he couldn't let go.
The arm was sort of clasped
on to the treasure
-and wouldn't let go.
-MUSKER: That was Glen's idea. Yeah.
CLEMENTS: So he had to
actually release his arm.
His whole arm.
CONLI: Pulled the pin
and his arm came off.
MUSKER: So we had Silver, through
the climax of the film being one-armed
and he had lost that mechanical side.
CLEMENTS: Which would
have been simpler.
It just reminded us
too much of Richard Kimble.
MUSKER: Yeah.
There was a Fugitive aspect of it
that we weren't sure
that was a good thing.
Silver, you gave up?
Just a lifelong obsession, Jim.
I'll get over it.
MUSKER: Now we're moving
into sort of this
action-adventure chock-full
of 3-D effects
and just very dense
and, again, got heavily reworked.
We had things in
at one point where Jim
remained on the ship
and piloted them to safety.
He became the captain of the ship.
CLEMENTS: It was always Jim's
sort of sequence.
MUSKER: It was.
CLEMENTS: And his chance to really
show what he could do.
MUSKER: Right,
but what he was demonstrating
went through
at least 10 different variations
before we arrived at this one.
CLEMENTS: Which ended up bringing
the solar surfer back
which seems fitting.
MUSKER: Yeah,
we sort of concocted this thing
so Jim would actually be surfing
and we had to sort of make it plausible.
And I think John Ripa felt, "it should
have some form of propulsion."
And at one point he was just
riding a piece of sheet metal
down to what was going on.
-Just kind of riding the waves.
-CLEMENTS: With a solar sail.
MUSKER: With a sail,
but that seemed too contrived
and the idea came up, use the cannon
as a form of propulsion for this thing.
And I think we reworked it to...
And then I think Glen had the idea,
it can have a certain amount of
canisters of energy
so there's sort of
a ticking clock that way.
CLEMENTS: I don't know
if everyone gets it
but basically this cannon
has these three canisters
and Jim uses them all up
in his course to try to save the day.
CONLI: Yeah, the propulsion device is
basically like a chamber for a pistol.
The little canisters go in
and shoot off the power.
CLEMENTS: It's where you get into
what has been referred to at Disney
as the "plausible impossible."
There you go.
Okay. Now, no matter what happens...
MUSKER: They used
to have a little more
dialogue between them as they left
"where they sort of said goodbye
or, "if I never come back
"tell my mother I love her."
I mean, practically like that.
And it seemed too much at this moment
so we went with
the more understated...
CLEMENTS:
There was the first canister.
So there's only two left.
Get this blasted heap turned 'round!
GOODING: This shot you actually
see the ship tacking
as a real sailing ship might,
where the sails transfer
from one side of the ship to the other.
That was animated by Ian Coony.
A nice little touch that he added.
RIPA: These scenes coming up
with Jim on the surfer,
again, went to Jin Kim,
just because of how well
he was able to do these scenes,
and how much he was
able to put into them.
I mean, they're so difficult as it is
that you can get lost in
trying to figure out how to do them.
That he was able to do them
and focus on the performance,
which is one of the hardest things to do
when you have something
that's very technical.
And he just was
the right person for that.
There were also scenes... Bobby Rubio
had done a couple of scenes in there.
Really nice match.
And John Pomeroy has some
scenes coming up
that really, I think, match the intensity
that Jin was able to get into his work.
MUSKER: And this was our attempt
to get the slight James Bond thing.
This came up fairly late
in the thing, too.
We wanted to give Jim a way
of sort of cleverly coming up with
some way of saving the day
and restarting his engine,
so we came up with this thing
of him grinding the dead engine
against this metal wall
and the sparks reigniting it
and that was our attempt
to do a little reversal
at the end of this thing
as we head toward the finish line.
DOPPLER: Three, two...
CLEMENTS: And if anyone
was keeping track
as far as B.E.N.'s countdown,
if that was all accurate, it's not.
MUSKER: This was one of the most
complicated shots we did in this ending.
This turnaround of the ship.
Trying to make the sky work behind it
because it was 2-D, it was 3-D.
I don't even know what it is now,
but it was complicated.
(CHEERING)
Amelia and Doppler used to
have a longer thing between them
where she sort of talked to him
about becoming first mate on the ship
and it was a great scene
between them.
But it seemed like it may have pulled
away from Jim a little bit too much
so we simplified that.
AMELIA: I'd be proud to recommend you
to the interstellar academy.
CLEMENTS: The proud father.
Just wait until your mother
hears about this!
Of course, we may downplay
the life-threatening parts.
MUSKER: Again with Martin's
goodbye here,
or his congratulatory thing here,
we had longer versions,
we had shorter versions,
I think we were much shorter,
but we wound up reinstating stuff
'cause Martin just did some funny stuff
with this crying bit at the end.
It just seemed kind of
comic that we liked.
CLEMENTS: And if people notice,
his eyes are now blue.
When he got his memory chip,
it turned his eyes from green to blue.
CONLI: I thought you were going to
talk about the eye mask.
CLEMENTS: Yeah,
I was going to get to it.
And Jim's eye mask is gone for good.
It's gone for good.
JIM: You never quit, do you?
MUSKER: And for us, this scene,
in this interior,
despite all the changes in the story,
most of this stayed relatively
as it was just in that
we wanted to get this sort of
moment where Jim lets Silver go,
and also, though, that Silver
beckons Jim to come with him
and Jim having found his newfound
maturity,
he really says, "No, I think
I got a future back home."
And it's, again, sort of a tent-pole
for us in the movie anyway.
KEANE: There's an emotional chord
that you know you have to hit
in these scenes.
And Morph plays such
an important moment in this,
because Morph has always
represented that inseparable
element to Silver.
And when he's given this choice
of hanging on to Morph
or giving Morph to Jim,
it's such a real gift.
RIPA: Yeah, it's really heartfelt
because by this time,
you know how much
Morph means to Silver.
I would've taken you up
on that offer in a second,
but I met this old cyborg...
MUSKER: And this shot was added
late in the game of Silver
because we felt that
we were on Jim so long
and it's really the relationship
between the two of them,
so we cut away from Jim
during part of it
to feature Silver just as he said,
"I met this guy
who kind of changed my life."
It just seemed more emotional
to be on Silver for that line.
And this line, where he says,
"I have a future,"
he used to say, "Greatness,"
alluding back to where he said,
"You have the makings of greatness,"
but it seemed a little bit comic
and it was a question,
"Does it seem too swell-headed?"
-And the future...
-CONLI: Perhaps glib.
MUSKER: Glib, and "future" tied into
his earlier line where he says,
"Yeah, what future?" and it just
seemed to round out the thing.
CLEMENTS: Beautiful music here by
James Newton Howard.
MUSKER: Yeah, the theme between
Jim and Silver that he stated earlier
really sort of comes back around here
and he added these violin overdubs,
the just really sweet, tender thing.
Again, this was Barry Johnson's idea
to sort of have
Morph dissolve into
a puddle of tears here.
But it was Tom Schumacher
who encouraged us,
toward the end of the film, to say,
"I think Jim should..."
"Or Silver should actually
give Morph to Jim as a gift."
And that was controversial
'cause it was a question,
can you give a pet away?
CLEMENTS: The pet owners in the...
CONLI: Me, being a dog person,
I seriously questioned it
because I couldn't imagine
giving my dog to somebody.
MUSKER: Right,
but me not being a dog person,
I just thought it would
really be emotional
that the thing Silver cared about most,
he actually found it
in the grace of his heart
to bestow it and it became
more powerful on Silver's part.
And I think Glen,
even though he is a dog owner,
said, "Hey, I can see that."
So we reworked this ending.
CLEMENTS: What made it work
was Silver realizing
that Morph would actually
be happier with Jim.
So then he gives him the order.
This is for your dear mother,
to rebuild that inn of hers.
Stay out of trouble, ya old scalawag.
MUSKER: Neil Eskuri was our
artistic coordinator and he really helped
the massive job of trying to relate
all the different parts of the puzzle
between effects and color models
and layout,
and really trying to make the process
as efficient and as rich as possible
on the screen
and here at the end of the film
as we go back to the space port,
he peopled that.
As we go back to the space port,
I think it's the most complicated
exposure sheet.
The exposure sheets
are the roadmap of these scenes,
and I think this one
took two weeks
just to assemble the sheet
and there's just a kajillion
characters in there.
It really has a rich feeling of
a dense, thriving metropolis.
Thanks, Neil,
for expanding that universe out there.
CLEMENTS: Yeah. Really
had a very complex job
on this movie, and did a great job.
CONLI: He came to us from Dinosaur.
So he had this rich background in 3-D
and we were using so much 3-D
in terms of the virtual sets
and deep canvas stuff,
that he became a real
instrumental part in terms of
making sure that
everything was unified
between the 2 and 3-D world.
RIPA: These scenes with Jim, with
the first time he came through the door,
and with the cops and stuff,
just showing how much he's changed
and that's really what they're there for,
even in terms of color.
His uniform color in contrast to
how he was dressed in the beginning
with the black T-shirt
and the charcoal jacket
and trying to hide,
he's got this light, white kind of...
Opposite of what he was
in the beginning.
KEANE: He had to go through the
experience to get to where he's at now.
He had to have met Silver.
He had to have a father
to help him mature.
RIPA: Yeah.
He had to get over that loss.
MUSKER: And note how amazingly
in sync all this clapping is.
CLEMENTS: People think stuff
like that's easy.
And it really was.
Not!
KEANE: So,
seeing Silver in the clouds here,
it's an image that you know
that is always gonna be with Jim.
That Silver's always
going to be watching over his shoulder.
And it says something really strong
to families,
to all of us who are growing up,
who want to reach your dreams,
and to see a young man who kind of
had the cards stacked against him,
and the most unlikely person possible
was the key to unlocking his potential.
And it's just a great message.
I feel like our films here
should have something to say.
And this is a story
that was borrowed from
Robert Louis Stevenson
hundreds of years ago,
and adapted to our time
through Ron and John's vision.
And it's just really satisfying
to see it actually up on the screen,
and for this generation
with a new message to it,
but a message that
was started a long time ago.
RIPA: Even having gone through it
and seen it like this and talked about it,
it just reminds you
of what a great opportunity
and incredible experience it was
doing a film like this.
And really feeling like
everybody worked very hard
and tried to do something
that they believed in
and hopefully, as an audience,
everybody enjoys it.
CONLI: Four years.
CLEMENTS: Four years?
Seventeen years!
CONLI: I was very lucky because
I got pulled in
in the last four and a half years.
Whereas you guys have been really
looking at this thing...
I mean, Ron,
you should talk about this.
The fact that you pitched this in 1985
is a phenomenal...
MUSKER: Same meeting
with Little Mermaid.
CLEMENTS: Yes,
I originally pitched this at
what they called a gong show,
which was sort of a meeting, actually,
with Michael Eisner
when we gathered a group of people
and pitched The Little Mermaid
and I pitched this.
Originally, they were both gonged,
although The Little Mermaid
actually got going pretty quickly
and this has been
on the back burner for a long time
so it's nice to finally see it.
CONLI: A great lesson in
persistence on this one.
But it's truly, for me,
it is a piece of literature that I loved
ever since I was a kid.
It was kind of the book
that got me into reading
and so the opportunity to work on it
and the vision that I was able
to share with these guys,
it was... These guys are brilliant.
It's been an amazing team.
CLEMENTS: It's been just
an incredible group of people.
MUSKER: In terms of the technology,
had this movie gotten going
17 years ago
when it was proposed,
both the people that worked on it,
and the technology that we used
were not necessarily available then,
so it's been to the movie's
good fortune, I would say,
that it's taken this long
to get off the ground.
CONLI: Had we started five years
earlier, we couldn't have got there.
Had we started 17 years ago,
we couldn't have dreamt of
where we would end up.
CLEMENTS: And the intention was
even like, when we were...
I mean, John and I have been working
on this for a long period of time.
Even between
Little Mermaid and Aladdin,
we worked on it a little bit.
Between Aladdin and Hercules
And even then, we conceived it
as a big action-adventure movie
and really wanted to get that
kind of action-adventure
cinematics into it,
and had no idea
how that would be possible,
and it turned out that by the time
we were actually able to do the film,
technology had developed
that actually made it possible,
but even then, a lot of stuff was
developed in the course of the movie
that didn't exist when we began.
CONLI: And that's a testament to
the team, 'cause the team was really...
Everyone embraced this film,
everyone embraced the story,
and everyone embraced
the technology that was there.
MUSKER: And took it into these
uncharted territories,
technologically speaking
and artistically speaking,
in terms of character design,
acting choices, virtual sets, 3-D, 2-D,
you name it, all the way down the line,
we were doing things
we hadn't really done before.
And, yeah, it was a testament
to the team that they really...
CLEMENTS: We decided to go for this
kind of classical look to the movie
and a very sort of dimensional,
classical look to the characters,
which really put a big emphasis,
not only on
that you needed superb acting,
but draftsmanship was so important.
And we had just such amazing
animators on this film
who were not only terrific actors,
wonderful actors,
but could draw so beautifully
and the quality of draftsmanship,
I think, is a little bit unprecedented.
CONLI: I think a nod also goes
to the performers themselves.
Because I think,
from an acting standpoint,
there are incredible performances
in this thing.
I think it's one of the best
vocal performances
I've seen in an animated film.
CLEMENTS: By the way,
Treasure Planet was a
controversial title for this movie.
There were many other
titles considered,
I think, for various reasons,
but Treasure Planet
seemed to be the title that stuck.
It was the title we always wanted to
go with because this really is
Robert Louis Stevenson's
Treasure Island
told in an outer space setting
and that title seemed to
express that probably
better than any other title.
If you don't know that
it's Robert Louis Stevenson's
story translated into science fiction,
maybe the title doesn't have
the same meaning, I don't know.
I guess that sums it up.
CONLI: Hope you loved the film.
CLEMENTS: Hope this provided
a little bit of insight
into what it's like to put
one of these things together.
MUSKER: And you children out there,
don't do this at home
because it's very dangerous.
RIPA: So, I guess, thanks for joining us.
KEANE: Stop in,
visit John some day at the studio.
RIPA: Sure, stop on by.
Thanks for listening.
GOODING: Thanks for listening.
I hope you enjoyed the film
and I hope I didn't
put anyone to sleep out there.
CONLI: And read the book.
MUSKER: Read the book, yes.
CONLI: Go read the book, kids.
MUSKER: If you come away
with anything, just read the book.
CONLI: Just remember, if it wasn't
for the book, this wouldn't be here.
CLEMENTS: Remember,
it all started with a book.