[British accent]
Forget it. It's too risky.
I'm through doing that shit.
You always say that,
the same thing every time.
"I'm through, never again,
too dangerous."
I know that's what I always say.
I'm always right, too.
But you forget about it
in a day or two.
Well, the days of me
forgetting are over...
and the days of me remembering
have just begun.
You know when you go on
like this what you sound like?
I sound like
a sensible fucking man.
You sound like a duck.
Quack, quack, quack...
Take heart, 'cause you're never
gonna have to hear it again...
since I'm never
gonna do it again...
you're never gonna
have to hear me quack...
about how I'm never
gonna do it again.
After tonight.
Correct.
I got all tonight to quack.
Can I get anyone more coffee?
Oh, yes. Thank you.
You're welcome.
I mean, the way it is now...
you're taking the same risk
as when you rob a bank.
You take more of a risk.
Banks are easier.
Federal banks
ain't supposed to stop you...
in any way during a robbery.
They're insured.
Why should they give a fuck?
You don't even need a gun
in a federal bank.
I heard about
this one bloke...
He walks into a bank
with a portable phone.
He gives the phone
to the teller...
bloke on the other end
of the phone says...
"We got this guy's little girl.
"If you don't give him
all your money...
- "we're gonna kill her."
- Did it work?
Fucking way, it works.
That's what I'm talking about!
Knucklehead walks into a bank
with a telephone...
not a pistol, not a shotgun...
a fucking phone.
Cleans the place out.
They don't even lift
a fucking finger.
Did they hurt the little girl?
I don't know. Probably never was
a girl in the first place.
The point of the story isn't the girl.
The point of the story is...
they robbed a bank
with a telephone.
You want to rob banks?
I'm not saying
I want to rob banks.
If we did, it would be easier
than what we been doing.
No more liquor stores?
What we been talking about?
Yeah, no more liquor stores.
Besides, it ain't the giggle
it used to be.
There's too many foreigners
own liquor stores.
Vietnamese, Koreans, they don't
even speak fucking English.
You tell 'em,
"Empty out the register..."
they don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
They make it too personal.
We keep on, one of these gook
fucker's gonna make us kill him.
I'm not gonna kill anybody.
I don't want to kill anybody,
either.
But they'll probably
put us in a situation...
where it's us or them.
And if it's not the gooks,
it's these old fucking Jews...
who've owned the store
for fifteen fucking generations.
You got Grandpa Irving
sitting behind the counter...
with a fucking Magnum
in his hand.
Try walking into one of those
places with nothing but a phone.
See how far that gets you.
Fuck it. We're out of it.
Yeah, well, what then?
Day jobs?
- Not in this life.
- What, then?
Garcon! Coffee!
This place.
WAITRESS: Garcon means "boy."
This place? A coffee shop?
What's wrong with that?
Nobody ever robs restaurants.
Why not?
Bars, liquor stores, gas stations...
you get your head blown off
sticking up one of them.
Restaurants, on the other hand,
you catch with their pants down.
They're not expecting
to get robbed.
Not as expecting, anyway.
I bet you could
cut down on the hero factor...
in a place like this.
Correct.
Same as banks,
these places are insured.
Manager... he don't give a fuck.
He's just trying
to get you out the door...
before you start
plugging the diners.
Waitresses? Fucking forget it.
No way they're taking a bullet
for the register.
Busboys, some wetback
getting paid $1.50 an hour...
really give a fuck
you're stealing from the owner?
Customers sitting
with food in their mouths.
They don't know
what's going on.
One minute they're
having a Denver omelette...
next minute, someone's
sticking a gun in their face.
See, I got the idea...
last liquor store we stuck up.
Remember?
All the customers
kept coming in?
Yeah.
You got the idea
taking their wallets.
- Mm-hmm.
- Now, that was a good idea.
Thank you.
Made more from the wallets
than we did from the register.
- Yes, we did.
- A lot of people come into restaurants.
A lot of wallets.
Pretty smart, huh?
Pretty smart.
I'm ready. Let's do it.
Right now, right here.
- Come on.
- All right.
Same as last time, remember?
You're crowd control.
I handle employees.
I love you, Pumpkin.
I love you, Honey Bunny.
Everybody, be cool!
This is a robbery!
Any of you
fucking pricks move...
and I'll execute every
motherfucking last one of you!
[Dick Dale & His Del-Tones play "Misirlou"]
Ha ha ha
[Radio tuning]
[Kool & The Gang
play "Jungle Boogie"]
Jungle boogie,
Jungle boogie
- Get it on
- Jungle boogie
- Get up with the boogie
- Get up with the get down
- Jungle boogie
- Get down with the boogie
- Come and shake it around
OK, so tell me again
about the hash bars.
- OK. What you want to know?
- Hash is legal there, right?
Yeah, it's legal,
but it ain't 100% legal.
You just can't walk
into a restaurant...
roll a joint,
and start puffing away.
I mean, they want you to smoke
in your home...
- or certain designated places.
- And those are hash bars?
Yeah, it breaks down like this.
It's legal to buy it,
it's legal to own it...
and if you're the proprietor
of a hash bar...
it's legal to sell it.
It's legal to carry it,
but... but that doesn't matter...
'cause, get a load of this,
all right?
If you get stopped by a cop
in Amsterdam...
it's illegal
for them to search you.
I mean, that's a right the cops
in Amsterdam don't have.
Oh, man, I'm going.
That's all there is to it.
I'm fucking going.
I know, baby.
You'd dig it the most.
But you know what the funniest
thing about Europe is?
- What?
- It's the little differences.
I mean, they got the same shit
over there that they got here...
but it's just
a little different.
Example?
You can go to a movie theater
in Amsterdam and buy a beer.
And I don't mean just, like,
in no paper cup.
I'm talking about
a glass of beer.
And in Paris, you can
buy a beer at McDonald's.
And you know what they call...
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese
in Paris?
They don't call it
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese?
No, man, they got
the metric system there.
They wouldn't know what the fuck
a Quarter-Pounder is.
What do they call it?
They call it
a "Royale with Cheese."
- "Royale with Cheese."
- That's right.
What do they call a Big Mac?
Big Mac's a Big Mac,
but they call it "Le Big Mac."
"Le Big Mac." Ha ha ha ha.
What do they call a Whopper?
I don't know.
I didn't go into Burger King.
You know what they put on
French fries in Holland...
- instead of ketchup?
- What?
- Mayonnaise.
- Goddamn!
Ha ha ha.
I've seen 'em do it, man.
They fucking drown 'em
in that shit.
Yuck.
We should have shotguns
for this kind of deal.
- How many up there?
- Three or four.
That's counting our guy?
I'm not sure.
So that means it could be
up to five guys up there?
It's possible.
We should have fucking shotguns.
- What's her name?
- Mia.
Mia. How did Marsellus
and her meet?
I don't know.
However people meet people.
She used to be an actress.
Oh, really? She do anything
I'd have seen?
I think her biggest deal
was she starred in a pilot.
Pilot? What's a pilot?
Well, you know the shows on TV?
I don't watch TV.
Yeah, but you are aware...
that there's an invention
called television...
and on this invention
they show shows, right?
Yeah.
The way they pick TV shows,
they make one show.
That show's called a pilot.
Then they show that one show
to the people who pick shows...
and on the strength
of that one show...
they decide if they want
to make more shows.
Some get chosen
and become television programs.
Some don't, become nothing.
She starred in one of the ones
that became nothing.
You remember Antwan Rockamora?
Half-black, half-Samoan...
used to call him
"Tony Rocky Horror"?
Yeah, maybe. Fat, right?
I wouldn't go so far
as to call the brother fat.
I mean, he got a weight problem.
What's the nigger gonna do,
he's Samoan.
Yeah, I think I know
who you mean. What about him?
Well,
Marsellus fucked him up good.
Word around the campfire is...
it was on account
of Marsellus Wallace's wife.
[Elevator dings]
[Elevator motor engages]
So, what'd he do, fuck her?
No, no, no, no, no.
Nothing that bad.
Well, then, what, then?
Gave her a foot massage.
- A foot massage? That's it?
- Mm-hmm.
Then what did Marsellus do?
Sent a couple of cats
over to his place.
They took him out on his patio,
threw his ass over the balcony.
Nigger fell four stories.
They had a little garden
down at the bottom...
enclosed in glass,
like a greenhouse.
Nigger fell through that.
Since then, he kind of
developed a speech impediment.
That's a damn shame.
[Elevator dings]
But still, I have to say...
you play with matches,
you get burned.
What do you mean?
You don't be giving
Marsellus Wallace's new bride...
a foot massage.
You don't think he overreacted?
Well, Antwan probably
didn't expect Marsellus...
to react the way he did,
but he had to expect a reaction.
It was a foot massage.
A foot massage is nothing.
I give my mother a foot massage.
No, it's laying hands
in a familiar way...
on Marsellus' new wife.
I mean, is it as bad
as eating her pussy out?
No, but it's
the same fucking ballpark.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
stop right there.
Eating a bitch out and giving
a bitch a foot massage...
ain't even
the same fucking thing.
It's not.
It's the same ballpark.
Ain't no fucking ballpark,
neither.
Now, look, maybe your method
of massage differs from mine...
but you know
touching his wife's feet...
and sticking your tongue
in her holiest of holies...
ain't the same fucking ballpark.
It ain't the same league.
It ain't even
the same fucking sport.
Look,
foot massages don't mean shit.
Have you ever given
a foot massage?
[Chuckles] Don't be telling me
about foot massages.
I'm the foot fucking master.
- You given a lot of 'em?
- Shit, yeah.
Got my technique down
and everything.
I don't be tickling or nothing.
Would you give a guy
a foot massage?
Fuck you.
- You given 'em a lot?
- Fuck you.
You know, I'm kind of tired.
I could use
a foot massage myself.
Yo, yo, yo, man.
You best back off.
I'm getting
a little pissed here.
- This is the door.
- There it is.
What time you got?
7:22 in the a.m.
No, it ain't quite time yet.
Come on. Let's hang back.
Just 'cause I wouldn't give
no man a foot massage...
don't make it right
for Marsellus...
to throw Antwan
off a building...
into a glass
motherfucking house...
fucking up the way the nigger
talks. That shit ain't right.
Motherfucker do that shit to me,
he better paralyze my ass...
'cause I'd kill
the motherfucker...
- you know what I'm saying?
- I ain't saying it's right.
But you're saying a foot massage
don't mean nothing...
and I'm saying it does.
I've given a million ladies
a million foot massages...
and they all meant something.
Now, we act like they don't,
but they do.
That's what's so fucking cool
about 'em.
There's a sensuous thing
going on where, you know...
you don't talk about it, but you
know it, and she knows it.
Fucking Marsellus knew it...
and Antwan should've fucking
better known better.
I mean,
that's his fucking wife, man.
This ain't a man with a sense
of humor about this shit.
You know what I'm saying?
It's an interesting point.
Come on.
Let's get into character.
What's her name again?
- Mia.
Why you so interested
in big man's wife?
Well, he's going out of town,
Florida...
and he asked me if I'd take care
of her while he's gone.
- Take care of her?
- No, man. Just take her out.
You know, show her a good time.
Make sure she don't get lonely.
You're gonna be taking
Mia Wallace out on a date?
It is not a date.
It's just like if you were going
to take your buddy's wife...
to a movie or something.
It's just good company,
that's all.
[Jules sighs]
It's not a date.
It's definitely not a date.
[Jules sighs]
Hey, kids. How you boys doing?
Hey, keep chilling.
You know who we are?
We're associates
of your business partner...
Marsellus Wallace.
You do remember your business
partner, don't you?
Let me take a wild guess here.
- You're Brett, right?
- Yeah.
I thought so.
You remember your business
partner Marsellus Wallace...
don't you, Brett?
Yeah, I remember him.
Good.
Looks like me and Vincent
caught you boys at breakfast.
Sorry about that.
What you having?
- Hamburgers.
- Hamburgers!
The cornerstone
of any nutritious breakfast.
What kind of hamburgers?
Ch-ch-cheeseburgers.
No, no, no, no.
Where'd you get 'em?
McDonald's, Wendy's,
Jack-in-the-Box, where?
Um, Big Kahuna Burger.
Big Kahuna Burger. That's
that Hawaiian burger joint.
I hear they got
some tasty burgers.
I ain't never had one myself.
How are they?
They're good.
You mind if I try one of yours?
- This is yours here, right?
- Yeah.
Mmm! This is a tasty burger.
Vincent, you ever had
a Big Kahuna Burger?
Want a bite?
They're real tasty.
I ain't hungry.
If you like burgers,
give 'em a try sometime.
Me, I can't usually get 'em...
'cause my girlfriend's
a vegetarian...
which pretty much makes me
But I do love the taste
of a good burger. Mmm.
You know what they call...
a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese
in France?
- No.
- Tell him, Vincent.
Royale with Cheese.
You know why they call it that?
Because of the metric system?
Check out the big brain
on Brett!
You're a smart motherfucker.
That's right. The metric system.
What's in this?
- Sprite.
- Sprite, good.
You mind if I have
some of your tasty beverage...
to wash this down with?
Go right ahead.
[Sucking empty]
Ahh.
That hit the spot.
You, Flock of Seagulls.
You know why we're here?
Why don't you tell
my man Vince here...
- where you got the shit hid at?
- MARVIN: It's over there.
I don't remember asking you
a goddamn thing!
- You were saying?
- It's in the cupboard.
N-no. The one by your kn-knees.
[Dishes clanging]
We happy?
Vincent? We happy?
Yeah, we happy.
Pbbbt.
Look... I'm sorry, uh,
l...I didn't get your name.
I got yours. Uh, Vincent, right?
But... but l... I never got yours.
My name's Pitt...
and your ass ain't talking
your way out of this shit.
No, no, no.
I just want you to know how...
I just want you to know
how sorry we are...
that things got so fucked up
with us and... and Mr. Wallace.
W-we got into this thing with
the best intentions. I never...
[Bang]
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I break your concentration?
I didn't mean to do that.
Please, continue.
You were saying something
about "best intentions."
What's the matter?
Oh, y-you were finished?
Oh, well, allow me to retort.
What does Marsellus Wallace
look like?
[Stammering] What?
What country are you from?
Wh-what?
Why no country
I ever heard of,
- they speak English in "What"?
- [Gasping] Wh-what?
English, motherfucker!
Do you speak it?
Yes!
- Then you know what I'm saying.
- Yes!
Describe what Marsellus Wallace
looks like!
[Whimpering] What? I...
Say "what" again!
I dare you!
I double-dare you, motherfucker!
Say "what"
one more goddamn time!
[Whimpering] H-h-he's black.
- Go on!
- [Gasping] He's bald.
- Does he look like a bitch?
- What?
- [Bang]
- Oww! Aah!
- Does he look like a bitch?
- No!
Then why you try to fuck him
like a bitch, Brett?
- I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
Yes, you did, Brett!
- You tried to fuck him.
- No.
Marsellus Wallace
don't like to be fucked...
by anybody except Mrs. Wallace.
You read the Bible, Brett?
[Gasping] Y-yes.
Well, there's this
passage I got memorized...
sort of fits this occasion.
"Ezekiel" 25:17.
"The path of the righteous man
is beset on all sides...
"by the inequities
of the selfish...
"and the tyranny of evil men.
"Blessed is he who in the name
of charity and good will...
"shepherds the weak through
the Valley of Darkness...
"for he is truly
his brother's keeper...
"and the finder
of lost children.
"And I will strike down
upon thee...
"with great vengeance
and furious anger...
"those who attempt to poison
and destroy My brothers.
"And you will know
My name is the Lord...
"when I lay My vengeance
upon thee!"
No!
[AI Green's
"Let's Stay Together" plays]
Let's stay together
MARSELLUS: I think you're gonna find...
when all this shit
is over and done...
I think
you're gonna find yourself...
one smilin' motherfucker.
Thing is, Butch,
right now you got ability.
But painful as it may be,
ability don't last.
And your days
are just about over.
Now, that's a hard
motherfuckin' fact of life...
but that's a fact of life...
your ass is gonna have
to get realistic about.
See, this business
is filled to the brim...
with unrealistic
motherfuckers...
motherfuckers who thought
their ass would age like wine.
[Chuckles]
If you mean it turns
to vinegar, it does.
If you mean it gets better
with age, it don't.
Besides, Butch...
how many fights you think
you got in you, anyway?
Hmm? Two?
Boxers don't have
an Old-timer's Day.
You came close,
but you never made it.
And if you were
gonna make it...
You would have made it
before now.
AL GREEN SINGING:
Good or bad
Or happy or sad
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Ooh, ooooh, ooh
Yeah
You my nigger?
It certainly appears so.
Night of the fight,
you may feel a slight sting.
That's pride fucking with you.
Fuck pride!
Pride only hurts.
It never helps.
You fight through that shit.
'Cause a year from now...
when you're kickin' it
in the Caribbean...
you're gonna say to yourself,
"Marsellus Wallace was right."
Ha ha ha.
I got no problem with that,
Mr. Wallace.
In the fifth,
your ass goes down.
Say it.
In the fifth, my ass goes down.
Yo, Vincent Vega,
our man in Amsterdam.
Jules Winnfield,
our man in Inglewood.
Get your asses on in here!
Goddamn, nigger!
What's up with them clothes?
You don't even want to know.
Where's the big man?
Big man's right over there
taking care of some business.
Why don't you hang back
for a second or two, you know?
You see the white boy leave,
just go on over.
[Paul sighs]
How you been?
I've been doing pretty good.
How 'bout yourself?
All right. [Sniffs]
So, I hear you're taking Mia out
tomorrow?
At Marsellus' request.
Have you met Mia?
- Not yet.
- [Laughing]
- What's so fucking funny?
- Not a goddamn thing.
[Chuckling]
I got to piss.
Look, I'm not a fucking idiot,
all right?
It's the big man's wife.
I'm gonna sit across from her...
chew my food
with my mouth closed...
laugh at her fucking jokes,
and that's it.
Hey, my name's Paul,
and this shit's between y'all.
Then what did you fucking ask me
about it for?
Asshole.
[Sighs]
Give me a pack of Red Apples.
- Filters?
- Nah.
You looking at something,
friend?
You ain't my friend, palooka.
What was that?
I think you heard me just fine,
punchy.
MARSELLUS:
Vincent Vega's in the house?
My nigger.
Get your ass over here.
AL GREEN SINGING:
You'd never do that to me
- What's up?
- I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Pack of Red Apples.
$ 1.40.
And some matches.
AL GREEN SINGING:
Here's what I want to do
Hey
We ought to stay together
WOMAN: It's as if it turns...
every part of your body
into the tip of a penis.
Wow.
I'll lend it to you.
It's a great book on piercing.
SECOND WOMAN: Well, you see
how they use that gun...
to pierce your ears?
They don't use that to pierce
your nipples, too, do they?
Forget that gun.
That gun goes against
the entire idea behind piercing.
WOMAN: All my piercing,
eighteen places on my body...
every one of 'em
done with a needle.
Five in each ear. One through
the nipple of my left breast.
Two in my right nostril.
One in my left eyebrow.
One in my belly. One in my lip.
One in my clit.
And I wear a stud in my tongue.
VINCENT: Excuse me.
I was just curious, but, um...
why would you wear a stud
in your tongue?
It's a sex thing.
Helps fellatio.
Vincenzo. Step into my office.
[Door closes]
LANCE: This is Panda,
from Mexico.
Very good stuff.
Now, that's Bava.
Different, but equally good.
And that is Choco, from
the Hartz Mountains of Germany.
Now, the first two
are the same...
300 a gram.
Those are friend prices.
But this one
is a little more expensive.
This is 500 a gram,
but when you shoot it...
you will know
where that extra money went.
Now, there's nothing wrong
with these two.
This is real, real,
real good shit.
But this one
is a fucking madman.
Remember,
I just got back from Amsterdam.
[Chuckles] Am I a nigger?
Are we in Inglewood?
No. You're in my home.
Now, white people
who know the difference...
between good shit and bad shit,
this is the house they come to.
Now, my shit,
I'll take the Pepsi Challenge...
with that Amsterdam shit
any old day of the fucking week.
That's a bold statement.
[Chuckles]
This ain't Amsterdam, Vince.
This is a seller's market.
Coke is fucking dead as... dead.
Heroin is coming back
in a big fucking way.
All right,
give me three grams of madman.
If it's as good
as you say it is...
I'll come back
and buy another thousand.
Well, I just hope that I still
have some left for you.
But... I'm giving you some
out of my own private stash.
That is what a nice guy I am.
Hey, I'm out of balloons.
Is a baggie all right?
Yeah, that's cool.
All right.
I'll just get one for you.
Honey,
will you get me some baggies...
and, uh,
twistix from the kitchen?
WOMAN: OK.
Hey, uh,
what do you think about Trudi?
She ain't got a boyfriend.
You want to, uh,
hang out, get high?
Which one is Trudi?
The one with all the shit
in her face.
No, that's Jody. That's my wife.
[Laughing together]
- I'm sorry, man.
- Thank you.
[Chuckles] No, I can't.
Um, I gotta be someplace.
All right. No problemo.
- I'll take a rain check.
- [Knock on door]
- Oh.
- Thank you, Jody.
Still got your Malibu?
Ah, man. You know what some
fucker did the other day?
- What?
- Fucking keyed it.
- Oh, man, that's fucked up.
- VINCENT: Tell me about it.
I had it in storage for 3 years.
It was out 5 days...
and some dickless piece of shit
fucked with it.
They should be
fucking killed, man.
No trial, no jury,
straight to execution.
Boy, I wish
I could've caught him doing it.
I'd have given anything
to catch that asshole doing it.
It'a been worth him
doing it...
just so I could've caught him
doing it.
- What a fucker!
- What's more chicken shit...
than fucking
with a man's automobile?
I mean, don't fuck
with another man's vehicle.
- You don't do it.
- It's just against the rules.
- Thank you.
Mind if I shoot up here?
Mi casa, su casa.
Muchas gracias.
[Car engine shuts off]
[Car door opens, closes]
Hello?
DUS TY SPRINGFIELD SINGING:
Billy Ray was a preacher's son
And when his daddy
would visit he'd come along
MIA: Vincent.
Vincent.
I'm on the intercom.
Where is it?
Where is the intercom?
It's on the wall
by the two African fellows.
To your right.
[Singing]... was the son
of a preacher man
The only boy...
Warm. Warmer. Disco.
Hello.
Push the button
if you want to talk.
- Hello.
- Go make yourself a drink...
and I'll be down
in two shakes of a lamb's tail.
The bar is by the fireplace.
DUS TY SPRINGFIELD SINGING:
Being good isn't always easy
OK.
[Singing] When he started
sweet-talkin' to me
He'd come and tell me
everything is all right
He'd kiss and tell me
Can I get away again tonight?
The only one
who could ever reach me
Was the son of a preacher man
The only boy
who could ever teach me
Was the son of a preacher man
Yes, he was, he was
- Lord knows he was,
- Ooh, yes, he was
How well I remember
The look
that was in his eyes
Stealin' kisses
from me on the sly
Takin' time to make time
Tellin' me that he's all mine
Learnin' from
each other's knowin'
Lookin' to see
how much we've grown
And the only one
who could ever reach me
Was the son of a preacher man
The only boy
who could ever teach me
Was the son of a preacher man
Yes, he was, he was
Oh, yes, he was
Let's go.
What the fuck is this place?
This is Jack Rabbit Slim's.
An Elvis man should love it.
Come on, Mia,
let's go get a steak.
You can get a steak here,
daddy-o.
Don't be a...
Oh, after you,
kitty cat.
[Motorcycle engines roaring]
[Cheering, applause]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Now, how may I help you?
There's a reservation
under Wallace.
- Wallace?
- We reserved a car.
Oh, a car. Why don't you
seat them in the Chrysler?
RICKY NELSON SINGING:
Throw a nickel in the jukebox
Then we start to rock
School gal, baby,
gonna tell you some news
You sure do look good
in them baby doll shoes
Well, it's one, two,
pull off my shoes
Three, four,
get out on the floor
Five, six, gonna get your kicks
Down at the corner
of Lincoln and 46th, yeah
All right
I've been waitin'
in school all day long
Waitin' on the bell
to ring so I can go home
Throw my books on the table,
Pick up the telephone
Come on, baby,
let's get somethin' goin'
- MAN: Decaf!
- MARILYN MONROE: Just a minute.
RICKY NELSON SINGING:
Throw a nickel in the jukebox
Then we start to rock
School's out baby,
gonna tell you some news
You sure do look good
in them baby doll shoes
Well, it's one, two,
pull off my shoes
Three, four,
get out on the floor
Five, six,
come get your kicks
Down at the corner
of Lincoln and 46th
You gotta move,
start rockin', baby
Rockin', rockin', baby,
gonna rock all night
Rock all night,
just wait and see
MAN: Ricky! Ricky!
[Music ends, cheering]
ED SULLIVAN:
Let's hear it for Ricky Nelson!
Fantastic job, Rick.
Thank you very much.
Vincent!
ED SULLIVAN:
Just so that you all know...
Ricky will be back
in the second half of our show.
So we hope you enjoy your meals
here at Jack Rabbit Slim's.
Thank you.
PAGE: Call for...
Phillip... Morris!
What do you think?
I think it's like a wax museum
with a pulse.
Hi, I'm Buddy.
What can I get you?
Let's see.
Steak, steak, steak.
Yeah, the Douglas Sirk steak.
I'll have that.
How do you want that cooked?
Burnt to a crisp,
or bloody as hell?
Bloody as hell, and oh, yeah,
look at this. Vanilla Coke.
What about you, Peggy Sue?
I'll have the Durwood Kirby
burger, bloody, and...
the $5.00 shake.
How do you want that shake?
Martin and Lewis,
or Amos and Andy?
Martin and Lewis.
Did you just order
a $5.00 shake?
Mm-hmm.
That's a shake.
That's milk and ice cream.
- Last I heard.
- That's $5.00?
You don't put bourbon in it
or nothin'?
- No.
- Just checkin'.
BUDDY: I'll be right back
with your drinks.
RICKY NELSON SINGING:
... lonesome town
To cry my troubles away...
Could you, um...
roll me one of those, cowboy?
You can have this one, cowgirl.
Thanks.
RICKY NELSON SINGING:
... with regret
Think nothin' of it.
RICKY NELSON SINGING:
... lonesome town
I can learn to forget
So... Marsellus said you
just got back from Amsterdam.
- Sure did.
- How long were you there?
[Sniffs] Just over three years.
I go there about once a year
to chill out for a month.
No kiddin'? I didn't know that.
Why would you?
I heard you did a pilot.
That was my fifteen minutes.
What was it?
It was a show about a team
of female secret agents...
called "Fox Force Five."
- What?
- "Fox Force Five."
Fox, as in we're
a bunch of foxy chicks.
Force, as in we're a force
to be reckoned with.
And Five, as in there's one,
two, three, four, five of us.
There was a blond one...
Sommerset O'Neal.
She was the leader.
The Japanese Fox
was a kung-fu master.
The black girl
was a demolition expert.
French Fox's speciality was sex.
What was your specialty?
Knives.
Character I played,
Raven McCoy...
her background was she grew up
raised by circus performers.
According to the show...
she was the deadliest woman
in the world with a knife...
and she knew
a zillion old jokes.
Her grandfather,
an old vaudevillian, taught her.
And if we would've
got picked up...
they would've worked in
a gimmick where every show...
I would've told another joke.
You know any of them old jokes?
Well, I only got the chance
to say one...
'cause we only did one show.
- Tell me.
- It's corny.
Don't be that way.
Tell me.
No. You wouldn't like it,
and I'd be embarrassed.
You'd be em...
You told 50 million people,
and you can't tell me?
I promise I won't laugh.
That's what I'm afraid of,
Vince.
That's not what I meant,
and you know it.
Well, now I'm definitely
not gonna tell you...
'cause it's been
built up too much.
What a gyp.
Martin and Lewis.
Vanilla Coke.
Mmm. Yummy.
You think
I could have a sip of that?
Be my guest.
I gotta know what a $5.00 shake
tastes like.
You can use my straw.
I don't have cooties.
- Yeah, but maybe I do.
- Cooties, I can handle.
All right.
Goddamn, that's a pretty
fuckin' good milk shake.
Told you.
I don't know
if it was worth $5.00...
but it was pretty fucking good.
Don't you hate that?
Hate what?
Uncomfortable silences.
Why do we feel
it's necessary...
to yak about bullshit
in order to be comfortable?
I don't know,
but it's a good question.
That's when you know you've
found somebody really special...
when you can just
shut the fuck up for a minute...
and comfortably share a silence.
Well, I don't think
we're quite there yet...
but don't feel bad.
We just met each other.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to go to the bathroom
and powder my nose.
You sit here
and think of something to say.
I'll do that.
OK.
[Men whistling]
[Mia inhaling]
I said goddamn! Goddamn.
[Whispering] Goddamn.
[Toilet flushes]
I need some hair spray.
[Car door slams]
Mmm. Don't you just love it...
when you come back
from the bathroom...
to find your food
waiting for you?
We're lucky
we got anything at all.
I don't think Buddy Holly's
much of a waiter.
Maybe we should've sat
in Marilyn Monroe's section.
Would you like some coffee?
Which one? There's two Monroes.
No, there's not.
That is Marilyn Monroe.
That is Mamie Van Doren.
And I don't see
Jayne Mansfield.
She must have the night off
or somethin'.
- Pretty smart.
- Yeah, I got my moments.
So, did you think
of somethin' to say?
Actually, I did.
However...
You seem like
a really nice person...
and I don't want to offend you.
Ooh. This doesn't sound like
the usual mindless, boring...
gettin'-to-know-you chitchat.
That sounds like you actually
have somethin' to say.
Well, well, I do.
I do.
But you have to promise
not to be offended.
No! No, no, no.
You can't promise
somethin' like that.
I have no idea
what you're gonna ask me...
so you can go ahead and ask me
and my natural response
could be to get offended.
Then,
through no fault of my own...
- I would've broken my promise.
- Let's just forget it.
That's an impossibility.
Trying to forget anything
as intriguing as this...
would be an exercise
in futility.
Is that a fact?
Besides,
isn't it more exciting...
- when you don't have permission?
- All right. All right.
Well, here it goes.
What did you, uh, think about
what happened to Antwan?
Who's Antwan?
Tony Rocky Horror. You know him.
He fell out of a window.
Mmm. Mmm.
Well, that is one way to say it.
Another way to say it
would be that he was thrown out.
Another way would be was he was
thrown out by Marsellus...
and yet even another way
is to say...
he was thrown of a window
by Marsellus because of you.
Is that a fact?
No, no. It's not a fact.
It's just what I heard.
- It's just what I heard.
- Who told you?
They.
They talk a lot, don't they?
[Chuckles]
They certainly do.
Don't be shy, Vincent.
What else did they say?
Well, I'm not... I'm not shy.
Um...
Did it involve the "F" word?
No. No, no, no.
They just said that Antwan
had given you a foot massage.
- And?
- And... and nothin'. That's it.
You heard Marsellus
threw Tony Rocky Horror...
out of a four-story window
for giving me a foot massage?
- Mm-hmm.
- And you believe that?
[Chuckles] Well, I mean...
at the time I was told,
it sounded reasonable.
Marsellus throwing Tony
out of a four-story window...
for massaging my feet
seemed reasonable?
No, it seemed excessive...
but that doesn't mean it didn't
happen. I mean, I understand...
that Marsellus is very,
very protective of you.
A husband being protective
of his wife is one thing.
A husband
almost killing another man...
for touching his wife's feet
is something else.
But did it happen?
Only thing Antwan
ever touched of mine...
was my hand when he shook it...
at my wedding.
Really?
Truth is,
nobody knows why Marsellus...
threw Tony out of
that four-story window...
except Marsellus and Tony.
But when you little scamps
get together...
you're worse
than a sewing circle.
Ladies and gentlemen...
now the moment
you've all been waiting for...
the world-famous Jack Rabbit
Slim's Twist Contest.
[Applause, cheering]
This is where
one lucky couple...
will win this handsome trophy
that Marilyn here is holding.
Now, who'll be
our first contestants?
Right here!
I wanna dance.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I do believe Marsellus...
my husband, your boss...
told you to take me out
and do whatever I wanted.
Now I want to dance.
I want to win.
I want that trophy,
so dance good.
All right. You asked for it.
Let's hear it
for our first contestants.
[Applause, cheering]
Let's meet our first
contestants here this evening.
Young lady, what is your name?
[High voice] Mrs. Mia Wallace.
And how about your fella here?
[Deep voice] Vincent Vega.
All right. Let's see
what you can do. Take it away!
- MAN: Yay!
- WOMAN: Go for it!
MAN: All right!
["You Never Can Tell"
by Chuck Berry starts]
CHUCK BERRY SINGING:
It was a teenage wedding
And the old folks
wished 'em well
You could see that Pierre
Did truly love the mademoiselle
And now the young
monsieur and Madame
Have rung the chapel bell
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They furnished off
an apartment
With a two-room Roebuck sale
The cooler ator was cr ammed
With TV dinners and ginger ale
But when Pierre found work
The little money comin'
worked out well
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They had a hi-fi phono
Boy, did they let it blast
700 little records
All rock, rhythm, and jazz
But when the sun went down
The r apid tempo
of the music fell
"C'est la vie,"
say the old folks
It goes to show
you never can tell
They had a teenage wedding
And the old folks
wished 'em well
You could see that Pierre
Did truly love
the mademoiselle
[Alarm beeping]
[Beeping]
Ha ha ha!
Is that what you call
an uncomfortable silence?
I don't know what you call that.
[Chuckles]
Drinks. Music.
I'm gonna take a piss.
That's a little bit
more information...
than I needed, Vince,
but go right ahead.
URGE O VERKILL SINGING:
Girl
Bow, bow, bow
You'll be a woman soon
I love you so much,
can't count all the ways
I'd die for you, girl,
and all they can say is
He's not your kind
They never get tired
of puttin' me down
And I never know
when I come around
What I'm gonna find
Don't let them
make up your mind
Don't you know, girl
Bow, bow, bow
You'll be a woman soon
One drink and that's it.
Don't be rude.
Drink your drink.
But do it quickly.
Say good night and go home.