URGE O VERKILL SINGING:
Girl
You'll be a woman soon
Soon
You'll need a woman
I've been misunderstood
for all of my life
But what they're sayin', girl,
just cuts like a knife
The boy's no good
Well, I finally have found
what I've been lookin' for
But if they get a chance,
they'll end it for sure
Sure they would
Baby, I've done...
You see, this is a moral test
of oneself.
Whether or not
you can maintain loyalty.
Because being loyal
is very important.
[Singing] They never
get tired of puttin' me down
And I never know
when I come around
What I'm gonna find
Don't let them
make up your mind
Don't you know, girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
Girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
Hello.
Girl
So, you're gonna go out there,
you're gonna say...
"Good night.
I've had a very lovely evening."
Walk out the door
and get in the car.
Go home, jerk off,
and that's all you're gonna do.
URGE O VERKILL SINGING:
Now it's up to you, girl
You'll be a woman soon
Please
Come take my hand
[Whimpers]
You'll be a woman soon
Soon
You'll need a man
[Door opens]
All right, Mia.
So, listen, I gotta go.
All right?
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ.
You f...Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, fuck me! Fuck me!
Oh, come on, girl.
We're gettin' out of here.
We gotta walk now.
[Tires screeching]
VINCEN T:
Don't fucking die on me, Mia.
Silly fuck.
[Beeping]
[Beep]
[Line ringing]
Answer!
[Telephone ringing]
MAN ON TV:
Have you got the ring?
SECOND MAN:
Why, certainly.
FIRS T MAN: Join hands,
you two love birds.
SECOND MAN: Uh-uh.
WOMAN: Please. Please.
Hurry up.
Yes, yes, yes, indeed.
Hold hands, you love birds.
[Ring]
[Indistinct chattering on TV]
[Line rings]
Fuck you, Lance! Answer!
[Ring]
[Chattering continues on TV]
WOMAN ON TV:
Now, what do you say?
MAN ON TV: I give up,
I'll marry you!
[Ring]
Lance!
The goddamn phone's ringing!
[Ring]
I can hear it.
I thought you told
those fuckin' assholes...
never to call here this late.
Yeah, I told 'em...
and that is exactly
what I'm going to tell...
this fucking asshole right now.
WOMAN ON TV:
I'll teach you a thing or two.
Don't you dare strike me!
Hello?
Lance, Vincent.
I'm in big fuckin' trouble, man.
I'm comin' to your house.
Whoa, whoa.
Hold your horses, man.
Wh-what's the problem?
I got this chick,
she's fuckin' O.D. Ing on me.
Don't bring her here.
I'm not even fucking
joking with you, man.
Don't not be bringing some
fucked-up pooh-butt to my house.
No choice.
She's O.D. In'?
She's fuckin' dyin' on me, man!
OK, well, then you bite
the fuckin' bullet...
and you take her to a hospital
and call a lawyer.
Negative.
This is not
my fuckin' problem, man!
You fucked her up,
you fuckin' deal with this!
Are you talking to me
on a cellular phone?
I don't know you.
Who is this?
Don't come here.
I'm hanging up the phone.
Prank caller! Prank caller!
[Tires screeching]
[Crash]
What the hell was that?!
Have you lost
your fucking mind?!
You were talking about drug shit
on a cellular ph...
Lance, help me.
You crashed your car
into my fuckin' house!
Grab her feet.
Hey, hey, hey!
Are you deaf?
You are not bringing this
fucked-up bitch into my house!
This fucked-up bitch
is Marsellus Wallace's wife.
Do you know
who Marsellus Wallace is?
Yeah.
If she croaks on me,
I'm a fucking grease spot!
I will be forced to tell him
that you did not help...
and that you let her die
on your fuckin' lawn.
Now, come on, help me.
Help me. Pick her up.
LANCE: Shit!
Lance!
Shit!
It's 1:30
in the goddamn morning.
What the fuck's
going on out here?
TV: Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Who's she?
Go to the fridge
and get the adrenaline shot.
What's wrong with her?
- She's O.D. Ing!
- Get her out of here!
BOTH: Get the shot!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, too!
What a fuckin' bitch.
Just keep talkin' to her.
She's gettin' the shot.
I'm gonna go get
my little black medical book.
What the fuck you need
a medical book for?
I never had to give
an adrenaline shot before.
You've never given
an adrenaline shot?
I never had to.
I don't go joypopping
with a bunch of bubblegummers.
My friends
can handle their highs.
- Get the shot!
- I am if you'll let me.
I ain't fucking stopping you!
Well, stop talkin' to me.
Start talkin' to her!
- Get the shot!
- All right!
Hurry up, Lance!
We're losin' her!
I'm lookin' as fast as I can!
What's he lookin' for?
I don't know. Some book.
What are you lookin' for?
My little black medical book!
A little black
fuckin' medical book!
It's like a textbook
they give to nurses.
I never saw no medical book.
Well, trust me, I have one.
If it's so important, why don't
you keep it with the shot?
I don't know!
Stop bothering me!
While you're lookin' for it,
she's gonna die on our carpet.
You're never gonna find anything
in this mess.
Honey, I'm going to fucking
kill you if you don't shut up!
Get in here!
Christ.
Get the fuck out of my way.
Pig.
Quit fuckin' around
and give her the shot.
While I'm doin' this...
you take off her shirt
and find her heart.
- It's got to be exact?
- Yeah, exact.
A shot in the heart,
so I guess it's gotta be exact.
I don't know exactly where
her heart is. I think it's here.
- That's it.
- This it?
What I need
is a big fat magic marker.
- You got it?
- What?
A magic marker! A felt pen!
A fuckin' black magic marker!
- All right.
- Hurry up.
Fuck. OK, OK, OK.
I think it's ready.
- Hurry up, man. Hurry up.
- I'll tell you what to do.
No, no, no.
You're gonna give her the shot.
- You're gonna give her the shot.
- I ain't givin' her the shot.
- I never done this before.
I ain't never done it before,
either. I ain't startin' now.
You brought her here, that means
you're gonna give her the shot.
The day I bring an O.D. Ing bitch
to your house...
then I give her the shot.
Give her the shot.
- Give it to me.
- Here.
Give me that.
Tell me what to do.
OK. You're giving her
an injection of adrenaline...
straight to her heart,
but she's got a breastplate.
You've got to
pierce through that.
You gotta bring the needle down
in a stabbing motion.
I gotta stab her three times?
No! You don't gotta stab her
three times. Just once.
But hard enough to get through
her breastplate into her heart.
Once you do that,
you press down on the plunger.
OK, then what happens?
I'm kind of curious
about that myself.
This ain't no fuckin' joke, man!
- Am I gonna kill her?
- No, no!
She's supposed to come
out of it like that.
All right. Count to three.
Ready?
One...
two...
Three!
[Gasping]
Aah! Aah! Aah!
[Gasping for air]
[Coughing]
[Gasping]
If you're all right,
then say something.
Something.
Ha ha. That was fuckin' trippy.
Ha ha ha ha.
VINCENT: Uhh.
LANCE: Oh, man.
[Car pulls up]
[Car door closes]
Mia. Mia.
What's...
what's your thoughts on... on...
on how to handle this?
What's yours?
Well, I'm of the opinion...
that if Marsellus
lived his whole life...
he don't need to know nothin'
about this incident.
If Marsellus knew
about this incident...
I'd be in as much trouble
as you.
I seriously doubt that.
I can keep a secret if you can.
Shake on it?
Mum's the word?
Cool.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
I'm gonna go home
and have a heart attack.
Vincent!
Do you want to hear
my "Fox Force Five" joke?
Sure.
Except that I think I'm still
a little too petrified to laugh.
No, you won't laugh
'cause it's not funny.
But if you still wanna hear it,
I'll tell it.
I can't wait.
OK.
Three tomatoes are walking
down the street...
Papa Tomato, Mama Tomato,
and Baby Tomato.
Baby Tomato
starts lagging behind...
and Papa Tomato
gets really angry...
goes back and squishes him,
and says, "Catch up."
Hmm. Hmm.
Ketchup.
See you around.
[Dog barking]
Oh, that Paddlefoot...
he funny, silly dog.
He think totem pole alive.
Hee hee hee!
KLONDIKE:
He arctic tenderfoot.
Ho ho ho ho!
That totem pole
been here forever.
BUTCH'S MOM: Butch?
[Paddlefoot barks]
[Man speaking
indistinctly on TV]
Butch,
stop watching TV a second.
Yeah?
We got a special visitor.
Now... do you
remember when I told you...
your daddy died
in a P.O.W. Camp?
Well... this here
is Captain Koons.
He was in the P.O.W. Camp
with Daddy.
[Sighs]
Hello, little man.
Boy, I sure heard
a bunch about you.
See, I was a good friend
of your dad's.
We were in that Hanoi
pit of hell together...
over five years.
Hopefully...
you'll never have to experience
this yourself...
but when two men
are in a situation...
like me and your dad were
for as long as we were...
you take on certain
responsibilities of the other.
If it had been me who'd...
not made it...
Major Coolidge would be talkin'
right now to my son... Jim.
But the way
it turned out...
I'm talkin' to you...
Butch.
I got somethin' for ya.
This watch I got here...
was first purchased
by your great-grandfather...
during the First World War.
It was bought
in a little general store...
in Knoxville, Tennessee.
Made by the first company
to ever make wristwatches.
Up till then, people just
carried pocket watches.
It was bought by Private
Doughboy Erine Coolidge...
on the day he set sail
for Paris.
This was your great-
grandfather's war watch...
and he wore it every day
he was in that war.
And when he'd done his duty...
he went home
to your great-grandmother...
took the watch off...
put it in an old coffee can...
and in that can it stayed...
Till your gr anddad,
Dane Coolidge...
was called upon
by his country...
to go overseas and fight
the Germans once again.
This time they called it
World War II.
Your great-grandfather
gave this watch...
to your granddad for good luck.
Unfortunately, Dane's luck
wasn't as good as his old man's.
Dane was a marine,
and he was killed...
along with all the other marines
at the Battle of Wake Island.
Your granddad was facing death.
He knew it.
None of those boys
had any illusions...
about ever leaving
that island alive...
so, three days before
the Japanese took the island...
your granddad asked a gunner
on an Air Force transport...
name of Winocki...
a man he had never met
before in his life...
to deliver to his infant son...
who he had never seen
in the flesh...
his gold watch.
Three days later,
your granddad was dead...
but Winocki kept his word.
After the war was over...
he paid a visit
to your gr andmother...
delivering
to your infant father...
his dad's gold watch.
This watch.
This watch
was on your daddy's wrist...
when he was shot down
over Hanoi.
He was captured,
put in a Vietnamese prison camp.
He knew that if the gooks
ever saw the watch...
they'd confiscate it...
take it away.
The way your dad looked at it,
this watch was your birthright.
He'd be damned if any slopes
put their greasy yellow hands...
on his boy's birthright,
so he hid it...
in one place he knew he could
hide somethin'... his ass.
Five long years he wore
this watch up his ass.
Then he died of dysentery,
he give me the watch.
I hid this uncomfortable hunk
of metal up my ass, two years.
Then... after seven years...
I was sent home to my family.
And...
now...
little man,
I give the watch to you.
[Bell dings]
[Gasps]
[Crowd cheering]
[Sniffs]
It's time, Butch.
[Announcer speaking
indistinctly]
[Butch blowing]
[Grunting]
... weighing 210 pounds...
Floyd Ray Wilson!
[Crowd cheering]
[Bell dinging]
SPORTSCASTER: It's official.
It's official. Wilson is dead!
SECOND SPORTSCASTER: Dan,
that had to be the bloodiest...
and the most brutal fight
this city has ever seen.
Coolidge left faster than I've
ever seen a victorious boxer...
leave the ring.
Do you think he knew
Wilson was dead?
DAN:
My guess would be yes, Richard.
I could see
the frenzy in his eyes...
give way to the realization
of what he was doing.
I think any man would have
left the ring that fast.
RICHARD:
Do you feel this tragedy...
is gonna have an effect
on the world of boxing?
DAN: Such a tragedy can't help
but shake the boxing world...
to its very foundations...
but par amount importance is
during the sad weeks ahead...
the eyes of the WBA remain...
[Horn honks]
[Tires squeal]
[Knocks on door]
Mia.
Marsellus?
I didn't do it, man.
How you doin'?
Great.
I never thanked you for dinner.
What you got?
He booked.
His trainer?
Says he don't know nothin'.
I believe him.
Think Butch surprised
his ass same as us.
No, we don't wanna think,
we wanna know.
Take him to the kennel,
sic the dogs on his ass.
We'll find out for goddamn sure
what he knows and what he don't.
Butch's search...
how do you want it done?
I'm prepared to scour the earth
for that motherfucker.
If Butch goes to Indochina...
I want a nigger hidin'
in a bowl of rice...
ready to pop a cap
in his ass.
I will take care of it.
[Car driving]
[Colombian accent]
Mister?
ESMARELDA: Hey, mister?
What?
You were in that fight.
ESMARELDA:
The fight on the radio.
You're the fighter?
Now, what gave you that idea?
No, ho, come on.
You're him.
I know you're him.
Tell me you're him.
I'm him.
You killed
the other boxing man.
He's dead?
The radio said he was dead.
[Sighs, sniffs]
Sorry about that, Floyd.
[Butch sniffs]
What does it feel like?
What does what feel like?
Killing a man.
Beating another man to death
with your bare hands.
Are you a weirdo?
[Chuckles]
No.
It is a subject
I have much interest in.
You are the first person
I've met...
who has killed somebody.
So...
what does it feel like
to kill a man?
[Sniffs, exhales]
I'll tell you what.
You give me one of them
cigarettes you got up there...
and I'll tell you all about it.
[Butch sighs]
So...
Esmarelda...
Villalobos.
Is that Mexican?
The name is Spanish,
but I am Colombian.
That's some handle
you got there, honey.
Thank you.
And what is your name?
Butch.
What does it mean?
I'm an American, honey.
Our names don't mean shit.
So, moving right along,
Esmarelda.
What is it you wanna know?
I want to know what it
feels like to kill a man.
I couldn't tell ya.
I didn't know he was dead
until you told me he was dead.
Now that I know he's dead...
you wanna know
how I feel about it?
I don't feel the least bit bad
about it.
[Speech inaudible]
What the fuck I tell ya, huh?
As soon as the word got out
the fix was in, man...
the odds went through the roof.
I know. I know.
Unbelievable.
Hey, fuck him, Scotty.
If he was a better boxer,
he'd still be alive.
He never laced up his gloves...
which he never shoulda done
in the first fuckin' place...
he'd still be alive.
[Spits]
Yeah, well...
who gives a fuck?
It's over now.
Well, enough about the poor
unfortunate Mr. Floyd.
Let's talk about the rich
and prosperous Mr. Butch.
How many bookies
you lay it around on?
All eight?
How long to collect?
[Sniffs] So you'll have it all
by tomorrow night?
No, I understand,
a few stragglers aside.
Oh, fuck, Scotty,
that is good news...
that is great news, man.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
No, me and Fabienne
are gonna leave in the morning.
It'll probably take us a couple
of days to get to Knoxville.
OK, my brother.
[Chuckles]
You're right.
You're goddamn right.
All right, Scotty.
Next time I see you,
we'll be on Tennessee time.
Be cool, brother.
[Tires squeal]
[Engine running]
45.60.
And, uh, here's a little...
somethin' for the effort.
Now...
if anybody asks you
who your fare was tonight...
what are you gonna say?
The truth.
Three well-dressed,
slightly toasted Mexicans.
Bonsoir,
Esmarelda Villalobos.
Buenas noches, Butch.
[Sighs]
FABIENNE: [French accent]
Keep the light off.
Is that better,
sugar pop?
Oui.
Hard day at the office?
Pretty hard.
I got in a fight.
Poor baby.
Can we make spoons?
You know what? I was thinkin'
about takin' a shower.
I'm stinkin' like a dog
over here.
Mmm. I like the way you stink.
Let me take this jacket off.
I was looking at myself
in the mirror.
Uh-huh.
I wish I had a pot.
You were lookin' at yourself
in the mirror...
and you wish you had some pot?
A pot.
A pot belly.
Pot bellies are sexy.
Well, you should be happy...
'cause you have one.
[Chuckling]
Shut up, fatso!
I don't have a pot.
I have a bit of a tummy...
like Madonna
when she did "Lucky Star."
It's not the same thing.
I didn't know
there was such a difference...
between a pot belly and a tummy.
The difference is huge.
[Kisses]
Would you like it
if I had a pot belly?
No. Pot bellies make a man...
Iook either oafish
or like a gorilla.
But on a woman,
a pot belly is very sexy.
The rest of you is normal.
Normal face, normal legs,
normal hips, normal ass...
but with a big perfectly
round pot belly.
If I had one, I'd wear a T-shirt
two sizes too small...
to accentuate it.
You think men
would find that attractive?
I don't give a damn
what men find attractive.
It's unfortunate what we
find pleasing to the touch...
and pleasing to the eye
is seldom the same.
[Sighs]
If you had a pot belly...
I would punch you in it.
- You'd punch me in my belly?
- Right in the belly.
Ah! I'd smother you.
I'd drop it right on your face
till you couldn't breathe.
[Butch laughing]
You'd do that?
Yes. Yes.
[Moans]
[Moaning]
[Both moan, both laugh]
Did you get everything?
Yes, I did.
Good job, sugar pop.
Did everything go as planned?
You didn't listen to the... Ow!
[Fabienne chuckles]
You didn't listen to the radio?
I never listen to your fights.
Were you the winner?
I won, all right.
Are you still retiring?
Sure am.
So, it all worked out
in the finish?
We're not at the finish yet,
baby.
Mmm.
We're in a lot of danger,
aren't we?
If they find us,
they'll kill us, won't they?
But they won't find us,
will they?
Do you still want me
to go with you?
I don't want to be a burden
or a nuisance, it's...
[Exhales]
Say it.
Fabienne...
I want you to be with me.
Forever?
Forever and ever.
Do you love me?
Very, very much.
[Sighs]
Mmm.
Butch?
Yes.
Will you give me oral pleasure?
Will you kiss it?
But you first.
OK.
Mmm.
Butch.
Mon amour.
L'aventure commence.
Mmm.
[Fabienne moans]
[Shower running]
[Butch groaning]
I think I cracked a rib.
Giving me oral pleasure?
No, retard. From the fight.
Don't call me retard.
[Mongoloid voice]
My name is Fabby.
My name is Fabienne.
Stop it. Stop it.
Shut up, fuckhead!
I hate that mongoloid voice.
OK, OK. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
[Shuts off water]
I take it back.
Would you hand me a dry towel,
Miss Beautiful Tulip?
Oh, I like that.
I like being called a tulip.
Tulip is much better
than mongoloid.
I didn't call you a mongoloid.
I called you a retard,
and I took it back.
Uhh. [Sniffs]
Butch?
Yes, lemon pie.
Where are we going to go?
Well, I'm not sure yet.
Wherever you want.
We're gonna get
a lot of money from this...
but it ain't gonna be
the kinda money...
that we can live like hogs
in the fat house forever.
I was thinkin' maybe
we could go down...
someplace
in the South Pacific.
The kinda money
we're gonna have...
is gonna carry us
a long way down there.
If we wanted,
we could live in Bora Bora?
You betcha.
And if after a while
you didn't dig that...
go someplace else,
maybe Tahiti. Mexico.
But I do not speak Spanish.
Well, you do not speak
Bora Boran, either.
Besides, Mexican is easy.
? Donde esta el zapateria?
What does that mean?
Where is the shoe store?
? Donde esta...
Spit, please.
[Spits]
? Donde esta el zapateria?
Excellent pronunciation.
Mmm.
You'll be my little mamacita
in no time.
[Yawning]
? Que hor a es?
What time is it?
Time for bed.
Sweet dreams, jellybean.
[Spits]
Butch?
Never mind.
[Fabienne brushing teeth]
[Motorcycle driving on TV]
Ohh!
Merde.
You startled me.
Did you have a bad dream?
Shit.
What is this you're watching?
A motorcycle movie.
I'm not sure the name.
Are you watchin' it?
In a way.
It's a little early
in the morning...
for explosions and war.
What was it about?
How should I know, Fabienne?
You were the one
who was watchin' it.
No, imbecile,
what was your dream about?
I don't know. I don't remember.
It's really rare
that I remember my dreams.
Well, let's look
at the grumpy man...
in the morning.
- Mmm.
Why don't you get up
and we'll get some breakfast?
One more kiss,
and I'll get up.
Mmm.
Satisfied?
[Inhales, exhales]
Yep.
Then get up, lazy bones.
Ohh.
[Chuckles]
God. Unh.
What time is it?
Almost 9:00 in the morning.
What time does our train arrive?
11:00.
You know what I'm gonna
have for breakfast?
What, lemon pie?
I'm gonna order a big plate...
of blueberry pancakes
with maple syrup...
eggs over easy,
and five sausages.
Anything to drink with that?
Ah, that looks nice.
[Chuckles]
To drink...
a tall glass of orange juice
and a black cup of coffee.
After that, I'm going to
have a slice of pie.
Pie for breakfast?
Any time of the day
is a good time for pie.
Blueberry pie
to go with the pancakes.
And on top, a thin slice
of melted cheese...
Where's my watch?
It's there.
No, it's not.
Have you looked?
Yes, I fucking looked.
What the fuck
do you think I'm doing?
You sure you got it?
Yes. Bedside table drawer.
On the little kangaroo?
Yes.
It was on the little kangaroo.
Yeah, well, it's not here now.
Well, it should be.
It most definitely should be,
but it's not here now.
So where the fuck is it?
Fabienne...
that was my father's
fucking watch.
Do you have any idea
what he had to go through...
to get me that watch?
I don't have time to go into it,
but he went through a lot.
All this other shit
you could set on fire...
but I specifically reminded you
not to forget the fucking watch!
Now think.
Did you get it?
I believe so.
You believe so?
What the fuck does that mean?
You either did,
or you didn't get it!
Then I did.
Are you sure?
No.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Motherfucker!
- Motherfucker!
- Aah!
Do you know how
fucking stupid you fucking are?
No!
It's not your fault.
If you left it
at the apartment...
If you left it at the apartment,
it's not your fault.
I had you bring
a bunch of stuff.
[Exhales]
I reminded you about it,
but I didn't illustrate...
how personal the watch
was to me.
If all I gave a fuck about
was the watch...
I should've told you that.
You're not a mind reader,
are you?
[Sniffles]
L... I'm sorry.
Don't be.
It just means
I can't have breakfast with you.
Why does it mean that?
Because I got to go back to
my apartment and get my watch.
Won't the gangsters
be looking for you there?
Well...
that's what I'm going
to find out.
If they are and I don't think
I can handle it...
Then I'll split.
I saw your watch.
I thought I brought it.
I'm so sorry.
Here's some money.
Go out and get those pancakes.
Have a nice breakfast.
I'll take your Honda.
I'll be back before
you can say blueberry pie.
Blueberry pie.
Maybe not that fast...
but pretty fast, OK?
OK.
Bye.
Shit! Of all the fucking things
she could fucking forget...
she forgets my father's watch!
I specifically reminded her.
"Bedside table,
on the kangaroo."
I said the words, "Don't forget
my father's watch."
[Tires squeal]
[Woman talking]
[Horn honks "La Cucaracha"]
[Neighbors chattering]
[Dog barking]
Lookin' good, Butch.
[Toilet flushes]
Aah!
[Glass shatters]
[Alarm beeping]
[Child chattering]
[Starts engine]
["Flowers on the Wall"
playing]
THE S TATLER BRO THERS SINGING:
Flowers on the wall
That don't bother me at all
Playin' solitaire till dawn
With a deck of 51
That's how you're going
to beat 'em, Butch.
They keep underestimating you.
THE S TATLER BRO THERS SINGING:
Kangaroo
Now, don't tell me
[Singing along]
Countin' flowers on the wall
That don't bother me at all
Playin'...
THE S TATLER BRO THERS SINGING:
Solitaire till dawn
With a deck of 51
Smoking cigarettes
And watching "Captain Kangaroo"
Now, don't tell me
I've nothin' to do
It's good to see you,
I must go
I know I look a fright
Motherfucker.
Huhh!
He's dead.
Oh, my God.
If you need someone to go
to court, I'll be glad to help.
That guy was a drunken maniac.
He hit you, and then he
crashed into that car.
Who?
Him.
I'll be damned.
[Crowd yells]
Uhh.
Aah! Aah! Uhh!
WOMAN: Aah!
I'm shot!
Uhh!
[Woman screaming]
[Fires gun]
[Grunting]
[Catches breath]
- [Fires gun]
- Uhh!
[Man whistling on radio]
[Marsellus shouts]
[Door opens, bells ring]
- Can I help you with something?
- Shut the fuck up.
MAYNARD: Now, you just wait
a goddamn minute now.
What the fuck are you up to?
Come here, motherfucker!
- Uhh!
MARSELLUS: Uhh!
You feel that sting,
big boy, huh?
That's pride
fucking with you, see?
You got to fight
through that shit.
Uhh! Huh?
You better kill me.
Yeah,
somebody's going to get killed.
Somebody's going to get their
motherfucking head blown to...
Hold it right there,
God damn it.
This ain't none
of your business, mister.
I'm making it my business.
Toss the weapon.
You don't understand, man.
[Woman singing on radio]
Take your foot off the nigger.
Put your hands behind your head.
Approach the counter right now.
This motherfucker's
trying to kill me.
Shut up.
Keep a-comin'. Come on.
Uhh!
[Man whistling on radio]
Zed, it's Maynard.
Yeah. The spider
just caught a couple flies.
[Woman singing on radio]
[Maynard hangs up phone]
[Both groaning]
[Butch spits]
[Maynard sets down container]
[Butch gags]
Nobody kills anybody in my place
of business except me or Zed.
[Doorbell rings]
That's Zed.
ZED: I thought you said
you waited for me.
I did.
So how come
they're all beat up?
They did that
to each other, man.
They came in fighting.
Now, this one right here,
he was going to shoot that one.
Is that right?
You going to shoot him, boy?
Huh?
Hey, is Grace all right
out front?
Yeah. It ain't Tuesday, is it?
No. It's Thursday.
She ought to be fine.
Mm-hmm.
Ahh. Well...
Bring out The Gimp.
I think The Gimp's sleeping.
I guess you'll just have to go
wake him up, now, won't you?
[Maynard unlocks lock]
[Unlocks lock]
Get up.
Get down.
[Zed taps The Gimp's head]
Which one of 'em
you want to do first?
[Zed sighs]
[Zed taps The Gimp's head]
I ain't for sure yet.
[Whispering]
Eenie, meenie, minie, mo.
ZED:
Catch a nigger by the toe.
If he hollers...
let him go.
Eenie, meenie...
minie, mo.
My mother said...
ZED: To pick the perfect one...
and you are...
ZED: It.
ZED: I guess that means you,
big boy.
[Muffled speech]
Shh.
[Marsellus stops]
You want to do it in here?
No. Let's do it back there
in Russell's old room.
Sounds good to me.
[Muffled speech]
[Muffled yelling]
Uhh. Uhh.
You keep an eye on this one.
[Music playing]
[Maynard and Zed chattering]
ZED: Yeah!
Uhh!
[Zed grunting rhythmically]
[The Gimp giggling]
ZED: Yeah!
ZED: Yeah, go!
Come on, motherfucker!
Now, motherfucker!
[Zed slaps]
ZED: Come on!
Yeah!
THE GIMP: Uhh! Uhh! Aah!
Aah!
ZED: Yeah!
[Zed grunting]
ZED: Yee!
Yee-haw!
Go!
[Bells ring]
Come on, motherfucker!
Aah!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Come on!
[Bells ring]
ZED: Yeah!
Yeah!
Uhh!
Now, motherfucker!
Aah!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Come on!
Now!
Yeah!
ZED: Yeah!
Yeah, baby!
[Muffled moaning]
MAYNARD:
Shut the fuck up!
[Muffled moaning continues]
MAYNARD: Fuck!
Come on!
Yeah.
[Muffled moaning]
Haah!
[Maynard moaning]
Aah!
Ohh!
Ohh! Uhh!
BUTCH: You want that gun,
don't you, Zed?
Go ahead and pick it up.
Go ahead, pick it up.
Come on. Atta boy.
I want you to pick it up...
Zed.
[Cocks rifle]
MARSELLUS:
Step aside, Butch.
Uhh!
[Zed wheezes]
Fuck!
You OK?
No, man.
[Zed moans]
I'm pretty fucking far from OK.
ZED: Uhh!
ZED: Aah!
[Zed moans]
What now?
ZED: Uhh!
Let me tell you what now.
[Zed groans]
I'm going to call a couple
of hard pipe-hitting niggers...
to go to work
on the homes here...
with a pair of pliers
and a blow torch.
You hear me talking,
hillbilly boy?
MARSELLUS: I ain't through
with you by a damn sight.
I'm going to get
medieval on your ass.
I meant, what now
between me and you?
[Zed whimpers]
Oh, that what now.
I tell you what now
between me and you.
There is no me and you...
not no more.
[Zed groans]
So are we cool?
Yeah, we cool.
[Zed groans]
Two things...
Don't tell nobody about this.
This shit is between me, you...
and Mr. Soon To Be Living...
The Rest Of His Short-Ass Life
In Agonizing Pain...
rapist here.
It ain't nobody else's business.