[Sally] Customers.
Customers!
Customers, everyone! Customers!
- [Sally] OK!
- Customers?
[Sally] Been a long time.
Remember what we rehearsed.
Make sure your
"Open, please come in" signs are out.
You all know what to do.
All right, nobody panics. Here we go!
Van, I just don't see
any on-ramp anywhere.
- Minny, I know exactly where we are.
- Yeah, we're in the middle of nowhere.
- Honey, please.
- [Sally] Hello.
Welcome to Radiator Springs,
gateway to Ornament Valley.
Legendary for
its service and hospitality.
How can we help you?
- We don't need anything, thank you.
- Ask for directions to the Interstate.
There's no need to ask for directions.
I know where we're going.
He did the same thing
on our trip to Shakopee.
We were headed over there
for the Crazy Days, and we...
- OK. Really. We're just peachy, OK?
- What you really need
is the sweet taste
of my homemade, organic fuel.
No, it doesn't agree with my tank.
- Just trying to find the Interstate.
- Good to see you, soldier!
Come on by Sarge's Surplus Hut
for your government surplus needs.
- Honey, surplus!
- We have too much surplus.
I do have a map
over at the Cozy Cone Motel.
And if you stay, we offer a free
Lincoln Continental breakfast.
- Honey, she's got a map.
- I don't need a map! I have the GPS.
- Never need a map again, thank you.
- How 'bout somethin' to drink?
Stop at Flo's V-Eight Cafe.
Finest fuel on Route 66.
No we just topped off.
And if you need tires,
stop by Luigi's Casa Della Tires,
home of the Leaning Tower of Tires.
- We're trying to find the Interstate.
- But you do need a paint job.
Ramone will paint you up right.
Hey, anything you want!
- You know, like a flame job.
- No thanks...
Maybe ghost flames!
You like old school pinstripin'?
Von Dutch style?
- [Both gasp]
- Oh, honey, look. Von Dutch.
[Chuckling] OK, no.
We're gonna be going now, OK?
Ow!
[Laughs] A little somethin'
to remember us by, OK?
- OK!
- Come back soon, OK?
I mean, you know where we are!
Tell your friends!
[Van] OK! Yes. You bet.
Thanks again, folks.
Bye-bye now.
Psst! Psst!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
- I know how to get to the Interstate!
- Do ya?
- Minny, no.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, not really. But listen.
I'm Lightning McQueen, famous racecar.
I'm being held against my will.
I need you to call my team,
so they can come rescue me
and get me to California in time for me
to win the Piston Cup. Understand?
- [Locks beeping]
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, it's the truth! I'm telling you!
You gotta help me! Don't leave me here!
I'm in hillbilly hell!
My IQ's dropping by the second!
I'm becoming one of them!
- [Lightning echoes]
- [Sighing]
OK, don't worry.
They know where we are now.
They'll tell friends. You'll see.
[Male DJ] We'll be back
for our Hank Williams marathon...
- That's good.
...after a Piston Cup update.
[Kori] Still no sign of Lightning
McQueen. Chick arrived in California
and today became the first car
to spend practice time on the track.
[Chick] It's nice to get out here
before the other competitors.
You know, get a head start.
Gives me an edge.
[Electronic music]
[Laughing]
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
Ha-ha!
Yeah!
[Crowd shouting and cheering]
[Girls chattering and giggling]
Hey, McQueen...
Eat your heart out.
[Gasping] Oh!
Let me get this straight.
I can go when this road is done.
That's the deal, right?
- That's what they done did said.
- OK. Outta my way.
I got a road to finish.
[Grunting and revving]
- He's done!
- Done?
- Uh-huh.
- It's only been an hour.
- [Bessie groans]
- Ah, I'm done. Look, I'm finished.
Say thanks, and I'll be on my way.
That's all you gotta say.
[Mater] Whee-hoo!
I'm the first one on the new road!
Oh!
[Vibrating] It rides purty smooth.
- It looks awful!
- Well, it matches the rest of the town.
- Oh!
- [Blubbering]
Red.
Who do you think you are?
Look, Doc said when I finish,
I could go. That was the deal.
The deal was you fix the road,
not make it worse.
Now, scrape it off!
Start over again.
Hey, look, grandpa,
I'm not a bulldozer. I'm a racecar.
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
Is that right? Then why don't we
just have a little race? Me and you.
- What?
- [Chuckling] Me and you. That a joke?
If you win, you go and I fix the road.
If I win, you do the road my way.
Doc, what're you doin'?
I don't mean to be rude here,
but you probably go zero to sixty in,
like, what? Three-point-five years?
Then I reckon
you ain't got nothin' to worry about.
You know what, old-timer?
That's a wonderful idea. Let's race.
[Sheriff] Gentlemen,
this will be a one-lap race.
You will drive to Willy's Butte,
go around Willy's Butte and come back.
There will be no bumpin',
no cheatin', no spittin',
no bitin', no road rage, no maimin',
no oil slickin', no pushin', no shovin',
no backstabbin', no road-hoggin',
and no lollygaggin'.
Speed. I'm speed.
Float like a Cadillac,
sting like a Beemer.
[Luigi laughs]
My friend Guido, he dream to give
a real racecar a pit stop.
- Peet stop!
- Uh... [chuckles]
The race is only one lap, guys.
Uno lappo! Don't need any help.
- I work solo mio.
- Fine. Race your way.
- No pit stoppo. Comprendo?
- OK.
Gentlemen...
...start your engines!
[Engine sputters]
[Revving furiously]
- IHijole! Check that out!
- Whoa.
Great idea, Doc.
Now the road will never get done.
Luigi?
[Chuckling] On your mark, get set...
Uno for the money,
due for the show,
tre to get ready, and quattro
to... I can't believe it. Go!
[Giggling]
[Cheering]
Huh?
Doc... the flag means go.
Remember the fl...
Here we go. Go.
Doc, what are you doing, man?
Oh, dear. It would seem
I'm off to a poor start.
Well, better late than never.
Come on, Mater.
- Might need a little help.
- Uh... OK.
You got your tow cable?
Well, yeah,
I always got my tow cable. Why?
[Doc] Oh, just in case.
[Yelling] Ow! Ow!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
No, no, no, no, no!
- Oh, man!
- Whoa.
- Ow!
- [Fillmore] Bad trip, man.
[Revving]
Hey! Was that floatin' like a Cadillac
or was that stingin' like a Beemer?
- I'm confused.
- [Chuckling]
[Doc] You drive like you fix roads.
Lousy! Have fun fishin', Mater.
[Gasps] Ah!
I'm startin' to think he knowed
you was gonna crash!
Thank you, Mater. Thank you.
I can make a little turn on dirt.
You think?
No. And now I'm a day behind.
I'm never gonna get outta here!
Hey, ese!
You need a new paint job, man!
- [Lightning] No, thank you.
- How 'bout some organic fuel?
- That freak juice?
- [Lightning] Pass.
Whoo! Watchin' him is makin' me thirsty.
Anybody else want somethin' to drink?
Nah, not me, Flo.
I'm on one of them there special diets.
I'm a precisional instrument
of speed and aero-matics.
"You race like you fix roads."
[Grunting] I'll show him.
[Grunting] I will show him!
- [Tar splattering]
- Oh, great! I hate it!
- Hate, hate, hate, hate it!
- [Chuckles] Music. Sweet music.
Maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
[Lightning]
Radiator Springs, a happy place!
OK, Bessie, you think that's funny?
Great! I'm talking to Bessie now!
I'm talking to Bessie!
Wow.
[Mater] Mornin', Sally!
Hey, look at this here fancy new road
that Lightnin' McQueen done just made!
Yes! Uh, amazing!
Whoa-ho! Yeah! [sighing]
Oh, Ramone! Mama ain't
seen you that low in years.
I haven't seen a road like this
in years.
- Well, then let's cruise, baby.
- Low and slow.
[Italian] E bellissima! It's beautiful!
Guido, look, it's-a like
it was paved by angels.
Boy, I tell you what.
I bet even the roads on the moon
ain't this smooth.
Doc, look at this!
Shoulda tossed him into
the cactus a lot sooner, huh?
Well, he ain't finished yet.
Still got a long way to go.
Guido, look at Luigi!
This is fantastico!
That looks like fun!
Mater, I got dibs, next turn!
Hey, Luigi, this new road
makes your place look like a dump.
That crazy old devil woman.
[Sighs] Oh!
She's right!
- Ah!
- Guido!
Huh. That punk actually did a good job.
Well, now... where the heck is he?
Sheriff!
Is he makin' another run for it?
No, no. He ran outta asphalt
in the middle of the night,
and asked me if he could
come down here.
All he's tryin' to do
is make that there turn.
[Lightning] No, no, no, no! Oh, great.
Perfect turns on every track
I've ever raced on.
Sheriff, why don't you go get yourself
a quart of oil at Flo's.
I'll keep an eye on him.
Well, thanks, Doc.
I've been feelin' a quart low.
[Engine revving]
[Screaming]
[Spitting]
This ain't asphalt, son. This is dirt.
Oh, great. What do you want?
You here to gloat?
You don't have three-wheel brakes,
so you got to pitch it hard,
break it loose and then
just drive it with the throttle.
Give it too much, you'll be
outta the dirt and into the tulips.
So you're a judge,
a doctor and a racing expert.
I'll put it simple.
If you're goin' hard enough left,
you'll find yourself turnin' right.
Oh... Right. That makes perfect sense.
Turn right to go left! Yes! Thank you!
Or should I say, "No, thank you"?
Because in Opposite World,
maybe that really means, "Thank you"!
Crazy grandpa car. What an idiot!
[Groans]
[Lightning] Turn right to go left.
Hmm...
Whoa!
- Oh!
- [Car crashing]
- Ow! Oh, that...
- [cactus crashing]
[Screaming] Ow!
Turn right to go left.
Guess what. I tried it.
You know what? This crazy thing
happened... I went right!
You keep talkin' to yourself,
people'll think you're crazy.
- Thanks for the tip.
- What? I wasn't talkin' to you!
- Oh, Guido, e bellissimo!
- Che cosa?
- It looks great! This is great!
- Ti piace, eh? Si, si, bellissimo.
[Grunts, passes gas]
Oh, Lord.
- [Chuckles]
- [Sheriff] Mater!
I need you
to watch the prisoner tonight.
Well, dad-gum! Wait a minute.
What if he tries to run again?
Just let him run outta gas
and tow him on back.
- But keep an eye on him.
- Yes, sir!
[Groaning] Oh...
While I'm stuck here
paving this stinkin' road,
Chick's in California schmoozing Dinoco.
My Dinoco. Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Who's touching me?
You have a slow leak. Guido, he fix.
You make-a such a nice new road.
You come to my shop.
Luigi take-a good care of you.
Even though you not a Ferrari.
You buy four tires,
I give you a full-a size spare
- absolutely free!
- Look, I get all my tires for free.
[Chuckling] I like your style, eh?
You drive the hard bargain.
OK. Luigi make you a new deal.
You buy one tire,
I give you three for free!
[Flo] Oh, would you look at that?
Ramone, Ramone!
[Luigi] Then Luigi make you
a new new deal.
[Lightning] No, no, no, no.
Deal me out. Pass. No, thank you.
- No, no, no, no. No.
- This is it. My last offer.
You buy one tire, I give you
seven-a snow tires for free!
Done. You interested, you call me.
You know where I am.
[Exhales deeply]
Ah!
Stop! Let me...
Oh, Red, you missed a spot.
See it right there?
- No! No!
- On the hood right there.
Stop, stop! That's cold!
Help! Please! Stop!
- [Coughing, sputtering]
- Thanks, Red.
What was that for?
- Do you want to stay at the Cozy Cone?
- Huh?
If you do, you gotta be clean.
'Cause even in hillbilly hell
we have standards.
What, I? I don't get it.
I thought I'd say thank you
for doin' a great job.
So I thought I'd let you stay with me.
I mean, not with me!
But there. Not with me there,
but there in your own cozy cone.
- And I'd be in my cone, and it's...
- Wait. Wait, you're being nice to me.
If you want to stay
at the dirty impound, fine.
- I understand you criminal types.
- No, no, no, no. That's OK.
- Yeah, the Cozy Cone.
- [Sally] It's newly refurbished.
[Lightning chuckles] Yeah,
it's like a clever little twist.
The motel's made out of caution cones,
which, of course, cars try to avoid.
But now we're gonna stay in them.
That's funny.
Figure that all out on your own,
did you?
Cone number one, if you want.
Oh...
Hey, do I spy a little
pinstriping tattoo back there?
Oh... [chuckles]
That's just a... Oh!
[Both chuckle]
Oh, you saw that? Yeah.
Just gonna be going.
Gonna... Yeah.
- You know, I knew this girl Doreen.
- [Gasps]
Good-lookin' girl.
Looked just like a Jaguar,
only she was a truck!
You know, I used to crash into her,
just so I could spoke to her.
- What are you talking about?
- I don't know.
Hey, I know somethin' we can do tonight,
'cause I'm in charge of watchin' you!
No, Mater, I gotta finish this road,
and I have to get out of here.
Well, that's all right,
Mr. I Can't Turn On Dirt.
You probably couldn't handle it anyway.
Whoa, whoa, easy now, Mater.
You know who you're talkin' to?
This is Lightning McQueen.
I can handle anything.
- [Whispering] I'm not doin' this.
- Come on. You'll love it! [chuckles]
- [Mater] Tractor-tippin's fun.
- [Lightning] This is ridiculous.
- [Tractors snore]
- [Mater] All right, listen.
When I say go, we go.
But don't let Frank catch you. Go!
Whoa! Wait! Who's Frank?
[Lightning whispering] Mater!
Wait, Mater!
OK, here's what you do.
You just sneak up in front of 'em,
and then honk.
And they do the rest. Watch this.
- [Honking loudly]
- Oh!
Oh... Oh! Oh... [mooing]
[Gas sloshing, backfiring]
[Laughing loudly]
I swear, tractors is so dumb!
I tell you what, buddy,
it don't get much better than this.
Yep, you're livin' the dream, Mater boy.
- [Honking]
- Oh!
Oh! Oh... [mooing]
[Gas sloshing, backfiring]
[Laughing] I don't care who you are,
that's funny right there.
Oh, your turn, bud.
Mater, I can't.
I don't even have a horn.
- Baby.
- I'm not a baby.
[Clucking]
Fine. Stop! Stop, OK?
All right. I'll do something.
That's Frank.
- [Bellowing angrily]
- [Shouting]
- [Mooing]
- [Engine revving]
[Mater laughing]
Run!
- Here he comes, look out!
- [Bellowing]
[Laughing] Whoa!
[Screaming]
Run! He's gonna get ya!
[Mater laughing]
Oh! Customers!
Oh!
Ah, no, no, no.
Oof! Oh!
[Mater] Tomorrow night we can
go look for the ghostlight!
- I can't wait, Mater.
- Oh, yeah, I'm tellin' ya!
Oh, boy,
you gotta admit that was fun!
Oh, yeah... yeah.
Well, we better get you
back to the impound lot.
You know, actually,
Sally's gonna let me stay at the motel.
Oh...
- Gettin' cozy at the Cone, is we?
- Oh, come... No. No, are you kidding?
Besides, she can't stand me.
And I don't like her, to be honest.
Yeah, you probably right.
Hey, look, there's Miss Sally!
- Where, where?
- [Laughing]
- You're in love with Miss Sally.
- No, I'm not.
- [Mater] Yes, you do.
- [Lightning] No way.
- Way.
- Come on, look...
- You're in love with Miss Sally!
- Real mature.
- You're in love!
- Real grown up.
- You love her. You love her.
- Wait...
You love her!
You love her. You love her.
All right. OK. Mater, enough!
- Will you stop that?
- Stop what?
Driving backwards. It's creeping me out.
You're gonna wreck.
Wreck? Shoot!
I'm the world's best backwards driver!
You just watch this right here,
lover boy. Wee-hee!
[Lightning] What are you doing?
Watch out! Look out!
Mater? Mater!
- Mater!
- [Laughing]
Hey, take it easy, Mater!
[Screaming happily]
Oof!
[Blubbering] Yee-hee!
[Chuckling] He's nuts.
No need to watch where I'm goin'.
Just need to know where I've been.
Whoa, that was incredible!
How'd you do that?
Rearview mirrors. We'll get you some,
and I'll teach you if you want.
[Chuckling] Yeah,
maybe I'll use it in my big race.
What's so important
about this race of yours, anyway?
It's not just a race.
We're talking about the Piston Cup!
I've been dreaming about it
my whole life!
I'll be the first rookie in history
ever to win it.
And when I do,
we're talkin' big new sponsor,
with private helicopters.
No more medicated bumper ointment.
No more rusty old cars.
What's wrong with rusty old cars?
Well, I don't mean you, Mater.
I mean other old cars. You know?
- Not like you. I like you.
- It's OK, buddy.
Hey, you think maybe one day I can
get a ride in one of them helicopters?
I mean, I've always wanted to ride
in one of them fancy helicopters.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure, sure.
- You mean it?
Oh, yeah. Anything you say.
I knew it. I knowed
I made a good choice!
In what?
My best friend.
See you tomorrow, buddy!
McQueen and Sally
parked beneath a tree,
K-i-s-somethin'-somethin'-somethin'-t!
[Laughing]
[Revving engine] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Chuckling]
Number one. Number one...
Ah, number one!
- Ah, this is nice.
- Hey, Stickers.
[Both scream]
- I'm sorry.
- You scared me. You gotta be careful.
I scared myself
scaring you scaring me.
- I mean, I wasn't like scared scared.
- No, of course not. No.
- I was more...
- I overheard you talkin' to Mater.
When? Just now?
What, what did, what did you hear?
Something about a helicopter ride.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, he got
a kick out of that, didn't he?
- Did you mean it?
- What?
- That you'll get him a ride.
- Who knows?
First things first. I gotta
get outta here and make the race.
Uh-huh.
You know... Mater trusts you.
Yeah, OK.
- Did you mean that?
- What?
Was it just a "Yeah, OK",
or "Yeah... OK" or "Yeah, o-OK"?
Look, I'm exhausted.
It's kinda been a long day.
Yeah, OK. G'night.
[Groans] Oh...
Hey, thank you.
What did you just say?
You know,
thanks for lettin' me stay here.
It's nice to be out of the impound,
and this is... It's great.
- Newly refurbished, right?
- Yeah.
- G'night.
- Good night.
Hmm.
[Reveille plays]
[~ Jimi Hendrix: Star Spangled Banner]
Will you turn
that disrespectful junk off?
Respect the classics, man.
It's Hendrix!
[Groaning]
[Breathing rapidly]
[Muttering]
[Fast-paced electronic music]
Ah!
- [Mooing loudly]
- [Screaming]
No!
[Yelling loudly]
[Mooing]
- No! [gasping]
- [Alarm beeping]
I gotta get outta here!
Hey, have you seen the Sheriff?
Oh! Oh, my gosh.
- Hey, what are you doin'?
- Get a good peek, city boy?
[Stuttering] I just need my
daily gas ration from the Sheriff.
Wait for him at Flo's.
Get outta here.
I've been trying
to get outta here for three days!
[Sheriff] Hope you enjoyed the show!
[Groaning]
Whoa, Doc.
Time to clean out the garage, buddy,
come on.
What?
He has a Piston Cup?
Oh, my gosh.
Three Piston Cups?
- [Doc] Sign says stay out.
- [Gasps]
You have three Piston Cups.
How could you have...
I knew you couldn't drive.
I didn't know you couldn't read.
- You're the Hudson Hornet!
- Wait at Flo's, like I told ya!
Of course. I can't believe
I didn't see it before.
You're The Fabulous Hudson Hornet!
You used to hold the record for most
wins in a season. Oh, we gotta talk.
- You gotta show me your tricks. Please.
- I tried that.
You won three times!
Look at those trophies!
You look.
All I see is a bunch of empty cups.
[Country music]
You know, some automotive yoga
could really lower your RPM's, man.
Oh, take a car wash, hippie.
Yeah, look at my husband, y'all!
Whoo! That's your color!
- [Ramone] Yellow, baby.
- Mmm. You smokin' hot!
There he is.
Oh, my gosh!
Did you know Doc is a famous racecar?
- Doc? Our Doc?
- Not Doc Hudson.
No, no, no, no, it's true!
He's a real racing legend.
He's The Fabulous Hudson Hornet!
Fabulous? I never seen Doc
drive more than 20 miles an hour.
I mean, have you ever seen him race?
No, but I wish I could have.
They say he was amazing!
- He won three Piston Cups!
- He did what in his cup?
I think the heat's
startin' to get to the boy!
Well, I'll say! Look how red he is.
[Ramone] I think he needs
a new coat of poly, man.
- [Mater] Are you sick, buddy?
- You are lookin' peaked.
He needs a new coat of poly for sure!
[Gas bell rings]
- [Sheriff] Hey! What are you doin'?
- It's OK. You can trust me, right?
I trust you, all right.
It's him I'm worried about.
Hmm... I trust him.
- Come on, let's take a drive.
- A drive?
Yeah, a drive.
Don't you big city racecars
ever just take a drive?
Ah... No. No, we don't.
[Gas pump stops]
Hey, Stickers! You comin' or what?
[Flo] Mm-hm!
- And you thought he was gonna run.
- Hey, can you believe it, man?
He actually thought
Doc was a famous racecar!
That's so too much!
OK, you got me out here.
Where are we goin'?
I don't know.
Whoa! Yes.
- [Sputtering]
- [Laughing]
Oh! Ah-ha-ha!
- Bleah!
- [Chuckling]
- [Grunts]
- [Laughs]
[Sputtering]
[Laughing]
[Chuckles] Oh!
[Spitting]
[Lightning] Wow. What is this place?
Wheel Well.
Used to be the most popular stop
on the mother road.
This place?
[Horns beeping]
[Sally sighing] Yeah, imagine.
Oh, imagine what
it must have been like to stay here.
You know, I don't get you.
How does a Porsche
wind up in a place like this?
Well, it's really pretty simple.
I was...
...an attorney in LA
livin' life in the fast lane, and...
Oh, you were, were you?
Were you rich?
- What?
- Just... clues to the puzzle.
Yeah, OK.
Well, that was my life.
And you know what?
It never felt... happy.
Yeah. I mean... really?
Yeah. So I left California.
Just drove and drove
and finally broke down right here.
Doc fixed me up, Flo took me in.
Well, they all did. And I never left.
Yeah. You know, I understand.
You need a little R and R.
Recharge the old batteries.
But you know, after a while,
why didn't you go back?
[Inhaling heavily] I fell in love.
- Oh.
- Yep.
- Corvette?
- No.
I fell in love with this.
Whoa. Look at that.
Look, they're drivin' right by.
They don't even know
what they're missing!
[Sally] Well,
it didn't used to be that way.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. Forty years ago,
that Interstate down there didn't exist.
Really?
[Sally] Yeah. Back then,
cars came across the country
a whole different way.
How do you mean?
The road didn't cut through the land
like that Interstate.
It moved with the land, you know?
It rose, it fell, it curved.
- Mornin'!
- Nice day, huh?
Cars didn't drive on it
to make great time.
They drove on it to have a great time.
[~ James Taylor: Our Town]
Well, what happened?
The town got bypassed
just to save ten minutes of driving.
[Lightning] How great would it have been
to see this place in its heyday!
Oh, I can't tell you how many times
I've dreamed of that.
But one of these days we'll
find a way to get it back on the map.
Yeah. Hey, listen, thanks for the drive.
I had a great time.
It's kinda nice to slow down
every once in a while.
You're welcome.
Hey, listen, listen!
If anybody asks you,
we was out smashin' mailboxes, OK?
[Chuckling] Wha... what?
[Rumbling]
[Mooing]
Oh, man, the paint's still wet!
- [Honking loudly]
- [Mooing]
No, no, no, no!
Get out of the store!
Hey! Don't eat the radial!
Here, take-a the snow tires.
- [Sheriff] Mater!
- I wasn't tractor-tippin'!
Then where did all these
gol-durn tractors come from?
- Whoa, boy!
- Hey! Hey, guys!
There's one goin' this way.
I got it.