(splutters lips,
sings descending notes)
(singing up and down scale):
Mah, mah, mah, mah...
mah, mah, mah, mah, mah.
-(singing descending scale)
-DIRECTOR: And we're on
in four, three, two, one.
What if I told you that even the
worst neighborhood in America
could be made completely safe,
and what if I told you
that this could be accomplished
without risking the life of one
single law enforcement officer?
How do I know this?
Because it's happening right now
in every country in the world
but this one.
I'm Pat Novak, and welcome
to “The Novak Element."
In tonight's
State of the Union segment
we'll be joined
by General Curtis Monroe,
live from the War Room
in the Pentagon.
General Monroe, welcome back.
- Good to see you, Pat.
- Uh, thank you
for this unprecedented
access to your operation.
Could you walk us through
what we're seeing here?
Well, this is a, uh,
a routine operation.
We found that random patrols
helped the local population
to feel safer and to trust us.
It's amazing.
And what are these colored dots
that we're seeing here, General?
These are our assets
on the ground.
Uh, in green,
we got the ED-2093.
They're the big boys,
they secure the perimeter.
Purple are the smaller EM-2083.
They sweep and mop up.
And the red dots, Pat,
that's your film crew.
(laughs)
It is great to see
American machines
helping to promote peace
and freedom abroad.
All right, you guys, this is
just standard op, all right?
There's no opposition expected.
I'm gonna set your
markers to code red.
(bopping)
All our drones are gonna give
top priority to your safety.
No red assets
have ever been lost.
- Okay.
- Okay?
That make you feel better?
- (woman chuckles)
- But, listen,
you keep those bracelets on,
you're completely safe.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay, enjoy the show.
All right, let's go.
ED-209:
May peace be upon you.
Please exit your homes
with your arms raised
for a noninvasive
scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Please exit your homes
with your arms raised
for a noninvasive
scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
As-salaamu alaikum.
- May peace be upon you.
- Scott, get me a shot of this.
Your cooperation is appreciated.
We apologize for
any inconvenience.
As-salaamu alaikum.
May peace be upon you.
Incredible.
In... credible!
Not long ago, that would have
been American men and women
risking their lives
to pacify these people.
Uh, General, you care
to comment on this?
Well, Pat, we had
Vietnam, we had Iraq,
we had Afghanistan...
Never again.
From a military perspective,
this has been invaluable.
We can accomplish our objectives
without any loss
to American lives,
and I think
the honest people over there
really appreciate it.
A-And why wouldn't they?
For the first time
in their lives,
they get to watch
their children grow up
in an environment
of safety and security.
Navid!
Get away from the window!
Mom! They're here! They're coming!
Come here! Come here right now!
Arash!
Navid! You stay with your mom and sisters!
But he's just a kid.
Say eh'.!
Stay here with your mom and the kids!
What do you think you're doing?
You heard me!
Arash, please don't go! Don't do this!
Navid! My dear! Come back here!
Navid!
Shut the door!
We're not here to kill any of them.
Got it?
The goal is to die on television.
Let's go!
NOVAK (voice-over):
Kelly,
can you hear me out there?
Loud and clear, Pat.
I'm here in sunny Tehran
where locals have clearly
embraced these routine scans.
As you can see behind me,
they're working
in collaboration
with the robots,
and obviously their safety is
everyone's top priority.
♪♪
Don't make a move before I say...
I wanna make sure they're recording.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
We're ready.
You'll notice children
in the streets as well.
This is everyday life happening
in perfect harmony...
(startled shout)
KELLY:
Oh, my God!
Oh, great.
Here, come here, come here.
Stay put, stay put, stay put.
It's fine, don't worry,
my guy's got it.
(grunts)
(Kelly screams)
Navid! It's dangerous here!
Come away! Come...
Navid, where are you going?
Navid!
Look at me! Navid! Navid!
What are you looking for? Navid!
Navid! Navid! What are you...
Navid! Don't go! Navid!
Navid!
(shouts in Farsi)
(gasps)
(Kelly screams)
Oh!
Oh, my God!
(mother screaming)
(screaming in Farsi)
Drop your weapon.
KELLY:
No, no!
- No!
- NOVAK (over com): Kelly?
Kelly, are you all right?
- Kelly!
- We're okay, Pat, our robots
- have just repelled some suicide bombers.
- Hold on, Kelly.
But, uh...
I'm sorry, Kelly, but
for security reasons,
the Pentagon's going to
cut our feed to Tehran,
but please be careful.
Yeah, I'll continue to stand by.
Now you see how fundamental
these robots are
to our foreign policy.
So then tell me,
why can't we use these machines
here at home?!
Why is America so robophobic?
On the one hand,
we have Raymond Sellars,
an entrepreneur
and true American
whose product just saved
my colleague's life,
and on the other,
Hubert Dreyfus...
a man with both feet
planted firmly in the past,
whose bill prohibits the use
of drones on US. soil.
The American people support
the Dreyfus Act
because they haven't experienced
this technology
and they fear
what they don't understand.
We at “The Novak Element“
support Mr. Sellars' efforts
to make our country
and our viewers safer.
After all...
what's more important than the
safety of the American people?
♪♪
(siren wailing)
- Hey, Murphy.
- Hey.
How's Jack?
We don't know yet.
...Murphy.
- Rick.
...How's it going?
—Good.
What the hell are
they doing here?
Six in the morgue,
Lewis in the hospital.
This was the mother
of all bad ideas.
We got a lead
on Antoine Vallon, we took it.
What lead?
Not in front of them.
This is bullshit.
Yeah?
Yeah, you got something
to say, Murphy?
Vallon's our case.
Yeah, two years
without no arrest, no nothing?
You've got to be dumb or dirty.
You got something on us,
or is this personal?
No, it's nothing personal...
Although I don't like you
as a person.
KAREN:
Okay, you two, out.
No problem.
Maybe if you hadn't gone
off the reservation,
your partner would
still be standing.
- What'd you say to me?
- Hey, that's enough!
Okay, Alex.
Just you and me now.
80, me and Jack, we've been
doing some street buys.
We get a line on some guns.
(voice-over): We meet up with
this low-level G called Jerry
who ends up having a piece
he's not supposed to have.
Where the hell you get
a gun like that, Jerry?
I can get you two
whole crates full, man.
Two crates?
No disrespect, J,
but how a clown like you
get so much product, man?
Yo, what's it matter
where it comes from?
Why it matters—— we don't want
no dirty guns, Jerry.
These guns got bodies
on 'em, Jerry?
Yo, look, they're clean,
all right?
- You gonna buy this shit or not?
- Hey, hey,
why you acting so nervous, man?
You fishing on us, Jerry?
What'd you say?
- You think he fishing, D?
- I think he's fishing on us.
Yo, what the hell are
they talking about, man?
Hey, let me see your phone.
- Let me see your phone.
- I'm not showing you
- my phone, man!
- You recording this?
- What?
- I think you're a goddamn cop.
What the hell
are you talking about, man?!
- Don't even try that!
- Hey, put your gun down!
We're not cops, all right?
- We work for Antoine Vallon.
- Put your phones on the table!
What?
Hey, hey, hey, shut up, shut up.
What'd you say?
Ends up he works for Vallon.
Before the meet we ran the
serial numbers on the rifles.
The guns were supposed to be
in our evidence room.
(voice-over):
Not out on the street.
Intake papers blank,
no signatures.
- What do you got?
- Nothing.
How do you think that happened?
I'm telling you, Murphy,
this is a mistake.
These guys'll shoot you
just to see if they gun work.
We need backup.
We call for backup, word's
gonna get around the station,
he's gonna disappear.
It's gonna be all right.
(voice-over): We told Vallon
we were gun buyers,
and he bought it.
What do you two need
with that much product?
You plotting a coup?
Man, don't trip.
We ain't gonna bust
a single shot in your town.
We got some problems back home
with Chicago PD.
(phone rings)
Yeah, I heard
you don't like cops.
Hey, boss.
What do you got for me?
Really?
MURPHY (voice-over): We were
just about to close the deal,
but someone tipped him off.
Gentlemen,
I got to deal with this.
-(tires screech)
—Two minutes.
Make sure you kill 'em both!
I got two handguns,
one automatic.
(engine roaring,
tires screeching)
We gotta get out of here.
I'm gonna take the automatic.
You sure about this?
(gunfire continues)
You ready?
Move.
♪♪
(grunting)
(grunts)
Lewis?
Lewis!
Officer down!
Officer down... 331 Hamilton.
This is Detective Alex Murphy
in need
of immediate medical assistance.
331 Hamilton Road.
Jack.
Jack, come on.
Jack, can you hear me?
Jack, stay with me.
(thunder rumbles)
Jack.
KAREN (voice-over): Alex, you
don't do something like this...
- Come on, Jack!
- ...unless you bring it
to me first.
Vallon's connected.
I'm warning you, don't
make any more moves
until I vet this.
If officers are supplying him
with guns...
That's up to IAD.
I'll handle it.
MAN (voice-over):
I don't care how sophisticated
these machines are,
Mr. Sellars.
A machine does not know
what it feels like to be human.
It can't understand
the value of human life.
Why should it be
allowed to take one?
To, to, to legislate
over life and death,
we need people who understand
right from wrong.
What do your machines feel?
Well, uh, they feel no anger.
They feel no prejudice.
They feel no fatigue,
which makes them ideal
for law enforcement.
Putting these machines
on the streets
will save
countless American lives.
- You're evading the question.
- No, I'm not.
Yes, you're evading
the question.
I asked, what do
these machines feel?
If one of them...
killed a child,
what would it feel?
- Nothing.
- And that's the problem.
That's why 72% of Americans
will not stand
for a robot pulling the trigger.
(applause)
MAN (voice-over): The world's
most valuable market,
and we can't touch it.
With a domestic expansion,
we'd clear $600 billion
per annum.
In other words, every second
that law is in existence,
we are hemorrhaging money.
What do you want me to do?
We've thrown cash at senators
at both sides of the aisle.
Nobody's budging.
They don't want to vote
against their constituents,
so, unless we sway public
opinion, the battle's lost.
Now, to that effect,
my team have come up
with a pretty aggressive
new campaign.
Wow factor off the charts.
We need to give Americans
a product they can love,
a figure they can rally behind.
Sir, I have dissected this bill.
There are no loopholes.
We can't put a machine
on the streets.
Forget machines.
You saw the polls.
Americans don't want a machine.
They want a product
with a conscience.
They want something
that knows...
...what it feels like
to be human.
We're gonna put a man
inside a machine.
DOCTOR (voice-over):
You're not you
because of your legs,
your arms, your hands.
You're you
because of your brain.
It's your, your brain's capacity
to process information
that makes you who you are.
Relax and just do
what you've always done.
I've never played with these.
The music doesn't come
from your fingers, Michael,
it comes from your mind.
All you have to do
is let it out.
Please.
♪♪
- ♪♪
- (gentle laugh)
(voice breaking):
Oh, my God.
(laughs quietly)
(stumbles over chords)
(groans in frustration)
No, it's okay. Easy.
His emotions are peaking.
The readings are
getting clouded.
NORTON:
It's okay.
Relax.
If you get too emotional,
it'll change
the chemistry in your brain.
It'll throw the system out.
You're doing great.
Come on.
♪♪
(fumbling)
I need emotion to play.
SELLARS: "Concierto de
Aranjuez, “ second movement.
Beautiful piece.
Dennett, when you have a moment.
Thank you.
NORTON (voice-over):
We agreed on this
a long time ago, Raymond.
I, I, I wouldn't be asked to
develop combat applications.
My, my work here is driven
by its own questions.
And your work is brilliant,
but your ideas
are being underutilized.
Look, I think I found a way
to put real revenue stream
behind your research and save
thousands of lives
in the process.
(tires screech)
You're not keeping up your end,
leaving me exposed like that.
Detective Murphy's just
a little impulsive.
So put him on the payroll.
Why are we talking about this?
It won't work, and now
that his partner got hit,
he's never gonna let it go.
What is that?
Lewis's hospital.
Alex is dropping
by this afternoon,
in case you want
to send flowers.
(scoffs)
Yeah.
I kill a cop,
looking over my shoulder
the rest of my life.
That's not good for business.
Who do you think's
gonna be investigating you?
I'm gonna go hard
after Lake and Daniels.
Gonna have 'em in bracelets
within a month, man.
Hey, Vallon,
I'm walking up right now.
Cameras off?
Clear.
MURPHY (voice-over):
You were right.
We should've had backup.
I'm sorry.
You're not really
sleeping, are you?
(both chuckle)
Asshole.
Sergeant Thomas Fry, NYPD.
Paralyzed from the waist down.
He has let himself go
a little since the accident.
Pass.
Yeah, yeah, fair enough.
Officer Alfred Miller, Denver.
Severe cere... cerebellar...
Cerebellar ataxia.
That's why you're
the doctor, Doctor.
He scored through the roof
with our urban demos.
Let's keep this one in mind;
I like this guy.
Very good, sir, leaved
the best for last.
I give you Sergeant Jack
Freeman, masculinity incarnate.
Led Pittsburgh SWAT
for five years,
now confined to a wheelchair.
I... think I can
seethe appeal.
NORTON:
No.
What? Why?
Well, check
the psych evaluation.
He's far too unstable.
He's trying to say
that he has a temper.
Have you any idea what we'd
be putting him through?
The psychological
strain requires
someone emotionally balanced.
We have to be scientific.
I mean, we're not selling
a soft drink here, are we?
He's right.
Okay, keep looking.
WOMAN:
David, what did I say?
Not until you're finished.
Hey, guys.
Hi, Dad.
Hey.
Hey, little monkey.
How's the game, buddy?
Damon got ejected, but we
got a two-man advantage.
Oh, yeah?
- That's fantastic.
- Hey, D,
why don't you head upstairs,
start getting ready for bed?
But he just got home.
I'll be up in a second.
Tuck you in, okay?
All right?
(Alex grunts)
Now give your mom a kiss.
Good night, baby.
Too slow, boy.
You're just too slow.
How's Jack holding up?
They said a week
till he's back on his feet.
It's my fault.
He shouldn't even
have been there.
Here.
(sighs)
(kisses gently)
(both panting)
(both moaning quietly)
(car alarm blaring in distance)
Oh, shit, I thought
I fixed that.
It'll stop.
(alarm continues)
(moans)
It's gonna wake up David.
(alarm continues)
(remote chirps,
alarm continues blaring)
(alarm continues)
(remote chirps,
alarm continues blaring)
♪♪
NORTON (voice-over):
He suffered fourth-degree burns
over 80% of his body.
Lower spine has been severed.
If he survives,
he'll be paralyzed
from the waist down
and confined to a wheelchair.
Mrs. Murphy...
we, we don't have to do this.
I need to know everything
before I make a decision.
(Clara sighs)
Please continue.
Vestibulocochlear,
optical nerves
have been critically damaged.
He'll be blind in one eye,
most likely deaf.
Frankly, Dr. Norton
and the Omni Foundation
are the leaders in this field.
In my opinion, this is the only
chance your husband has.
I'd seriously consider
their offer.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I need time to think.
LIZ: I'm afraid,
Mrs. Murphy,
time is one thing
you don't have.
You say you can save him,
but what does that mean?
What kind of life will he have?
♪ Fly me to the moon ♪
♪ Let me play
among the stars... ♪
Thanks.
Thanks, buddy.
You know she's gonna
make me dance again.
Now, that I've got to see.
You don't want to see that.
Here she comes now.
Hold on to that.
Get out there, partner.
♪ Hold my hand... ♪
Every time.
♪ In other words... ♪
LEWIS:
Get her, boy!
♪ Baby, kiss me ♪
♪ Fill my heart with song ♪
♪ And let me sing for evermore ♪
♪ You are all I long for ♪
♪ All I worship and adore... ♪
Subject is still dreaming.
♪ In other words... ♪
He's retrieving memories,
trying to make sense
of sensorial stimulation
package 37.
Perfect, Kim.
♪ In other words... ♪
Let's reconnect the spine.
♪ I love you... ♪
Time to wake him up.
♪ Fill my heart with song ♪
Let me sing for evermore ♪
♪ You are all I long for ♪
♪ All I worship and adore ♪
♪ in other words ♪
♪ Please be true... ♪
Excuse me?
What are you doing here?
Baby, where you going?
♪ In other words... ♪
Lewis.
♪ I... love... ♪
♪ You. ♪
Subject regaining
cognitive functions.
What's happening?
Where am I?
You were in an explosion, Alex.
Y-You're in a hospital.
Where's, where's Clara?
My wife, wh-where's my wife?
I want you to calm down, Alex.
Listen to me... you're okay
and your family's fine,
both your wife and your son.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Dr. Dennett Norton.
I'm treating you.
- (monitor beeping rapidly)
- Heart rate rising.
I can't move.
- What the hell is all that?
- Visual input unstable.
I want you to relax, Alex.
Subject's dumping
too much epinephrine.
- Should we purge it?
- Not yet.
Unlock vertebrae.
(clicking, whirring, hissing)
Go ahead, Kim.
Unlock upper, lower extremities.
What kind of suit is this?
It's not a suit, Alex, it's...
it-it's you.
This was the only option.
We're here...
All of us... to make
you whole again.
- Full body unlock.
- (clank, thud)
I want you to walk now, Alex.
You can do that.
(footsteps thudding)
(whirring, thudding)
This seems so real.
Alex, it's, it's very important
you understand
what is happening.
This is real.
It's not a dream,
it's not drugs or anesthetics.
I know I'm dreaming
because I can feel all of this.
Alex, amputees can often feel
their missing appendages.
It's called phantom
limb sensation.
What do you mean "amputees"?
- What the hell did you do to me?
- Alex, you need to relax.
Take this off me now.
I need to get out of this thing.
You need to relax.
Alex, Dr. Norton
saved your life.
What did you do to me?!
What have you done to me?!
Your body was beyond
biological repair!
KIM:
Alex... hey!
Shut him down.
NORTON:
Uh, no! Let him run!
Let him run!
(whirring, thudding)
(startled shouts, gasping)
(crew speaking Mandarin)
(man shouting in Mandarin)
Where am I?!
(man shouts in Mandarin)
(whirring, thudding)
(workers murmuring)
NORTON (over radio):
Alex, please.
Stop.
Alex, you have to stop.
Please.
Alex.
Please stop.
Stay where you are and,
and we'll come and pick you up.
(thudding)
(thud, whirring)
Okay, Kim.
Shut him down.
(power whirring down)
(workers murmuring,
birds chirping)
Alex... you can't
run from this.
You have to understand the
reality of the situation.
Show me.
Kim.
(whirring)
(whirring and clanking)
No.
Holy Christ.
Holy Christ,
there's nothing left.
(sobbing)
(heart beating quietly)
Your body may have gone,
but you're still here.
That's not even my brain.
We had to repair
the damaged areas,
but we didn't interfere
with your emotion
or your intellect.
Do you un... you
understand me, Alex?
You're, you're in control.
I'm in control?
Yes.
Okay.
If I'm in control...
then I want to die.
Just unplug whatever it is
keeping me alive
and end this nightmare.
Now, say I did that,
which, as a doctor,
would almost be impossible
for me, but, but say I did.
What, what, what do
I say to your wife?
What does she say to your son?
That it didn't work,
that you tried.
Something went wrong.
You did everything
you could, but...
I died.
So, after all
they've been through,
all the pain,
all their hope restored,
we would just rip that away?
Your wife loves you, Alex.
She signed
the consent forms herself.
Otherwise, y-you couldn't have
undergone the procedure.
She loves you,
and she gave you
a second chance.
I need you
to take it.
I don't want to see myself
like this again.
Ever.
And the same goes for my family.
Just put me back in.
(quiet whirr, click)
(phone ringing)
ROBOCOP:
Zoom in.
Stop.
(ringing continues)
Zoom in.
Stop.
(ringing continues)
Accept the connection.
(beeping)
(sighs)
It's so good to finally see you.
I was gonna say the same thing.
I'm sorry.
I know how I must look to you.
I think you look beautiful.
(Clara laughs gently)
Are they treating you okay,
baby?
So far. Dr. Norton,
he seems like a nice guy.
Does David know you're calling?
He misses you.
...I can go get him. I just...
—No.
I don't want him to
see me like this.
Not yet.
Sure.
(crying)
We're gonna get
through this, baby.
We're gonna make it like it was.
When are you coming home?
Well, they still got some tests,
but they're saying it's
going really well.
The minute they let me.
I gotta go.
I love you.
- End the connection.
- (beeping)
(whirring)
Okay, blood cleansing initiated.
Viral and bacterial
screening activated.
Releasing proteins, fats,
minerals and carbs.
Energy inflow
is at 1,320 kilocalories.
Now starting
anti-inflammatory corticoids,
hormones
and antibiotic protocols.
Standard daily intake.
Release antidepressants.
Let's give him a nice dream.
(switches clanking)
MATTOX (voice-over):
All right,
here's what you're dealing with.
Modified M2 battle rifle.
.50-caliber Beowulf ammunition
at 30-round clips.
Three shot bursts or full auto.
Heavy-duty.
TSR 66.
Cartridge-driven taser pistol.
Each projectile releases
up to 200,000 volts.
It can stun,
it can kill,
and it's nasty shit.
Your armor, state-of-the-art,
but not invulnerable.
.50-caliber or larger
can penetrate and kill.
Multiple hits, and guess who
ends up in the recycling bin?
If you sense you need a weapon
or are threatened...
(whirring, clicking)
...the visor goes down
and the system makes
the weapons available.
But you got to remember,
it's not the weapons that count.
It's who's handling them,
or in your case, what.
You think you can do this?
Oh, just stick to your job.
Just stick to my job?
Combat robots are my job, Doc.
Rio, Congo, you name it,
I was there.
Our machines run perfectly.
You ask me, sticking organics
into the system
is a huge step backwards.
I don't care how well
you designed this thing.
Without my sign-off,
it better start learning Chinese
'cause it ain't never
going home.
It's nice to meet you, too.
Let's do this...
Tin Man.
Quality control,
EM-208 versus Tin Man.
Rendering scenario one now.
- (blips)
- Hey, Doc, hope you don't mind.
I like a little music
while I'm working.
(“ If I Only Had a Heart“
begins playing)
All right.
All right, let's, uh,
let the games begin.
Let's rock and roll.
Commence scenario.
♪♪
- (gunshots)
- MATTOX: Lagging on the corners.
Ah, no, there, did you see that?
What my robot did,
that's how you do it.
(gunshots continue)
New product's afraid.
2.3 seconds behind.
Great.
(gunshots continue)
ROBOCOP:
Drop the weapon!
- Let the kid go.
- MATTOX: Oh, well,
Drop the gun.
He's worried that the
kid is gonna get hurt.
...Let the kid go.
—Too bad.
(gunshots)
Well, there you have it.
5.6 seconds behind.
Scenario failure.
I wouldn't buy
that for a dollar.
Let's do it again.
Your funeral.
Detective Alex Murphy.
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Search results:
“ Detective Murphy
making a speedy recovery."
"Alex Murphy, man or machine?"
“Thrust into the spotlight,
Clara Murphy won't talk."
Antoine Vallon.
Search results:
"DPD says Antoine Vallon
"no longer a suspect
due to lack of evidence."
(sighs)
"Detroit Free Press."
DANIELS: Unfortunately,
Murphy's investigation
into Antoine Vallon wasn't
authorized in the first place.
Look, Detective Murphy
was simply overzealous, okay?
We have absolutely no evidence
linking Vallon to the attempt
on his life.
All I'm gonna say
is my partner's a great cop,
and I won't rest until the men
who tried to kill him
are brought to justice.
SELLARS (voice-over):
What's that?
What's wrong with him?
NORTON:
No, nothing, nothing.
Watch the procedural bars
on the 208.
A machine assesses the threat
and acts, all right?
That's it.
It's two steps.
N-Now watch Alex.
The software assesses
the threat,
...just like the robot.
—Yeah.
And it sends the information
to the brain.
Alex's brain receives
the information
and decides what to do with it
based on his emotional...
- Right.
- Cognitive abilities,
like any man would.
-Right.
—Then the brain
relates this to the AI module,
- Yeah.
- And, uh...
Like, you know, a year later.
And our computers
finish the job.
Raymond, you-you wanted
a man inside a machine,
and that's what you've got,
but the human element
will always be present...
Fear, instinct, bias,
compassion-— they will always
interfere with the system.
Okay, but, Dennett...
I've got to give
the American people
something they can root for.
Something aspirational, right?
They have to believe
in this thing.
"Pretty good," that's not...
I don't know how to sell "okay."
We, you and I, have
got a release date,
and we've got to make it, okay?
So I don't care how you do it.
I'm asking you,
come on, can you help me?
Just get him to do that.
...Get him to do that.
—That is a machine.
I know, but it's a man
inside a machine.
No, that's a man
inside a machine!
- Right there!
- Right! And his life depends on it.
And the future
of Omnicorp depends on it.
So get your ass back to China,
and get it fixed.
I don't care how you do it,
just go do it.
♪♪
(scoffs)
It tastes like...
peanut butter.
I can't get it out of my mouth.
NORTON: And you don't
like peanut butter?
- No.
- (chuckles)
You like peanut butter, Kim?
I love it.
Mm.
Okay.
I'm gonna put you to
sleep now, Alex, okay?
Okay.
Now, put him under, Kim.
(computer beeps,
machinery hisses)
What are you planning to do?
Consciousness...
is nothing more...
than the processing
of information.
I'm gonna fix him,
and he won't know
the difference.
♪♪
...Raymond?
—Yeah?
We just ran focus groups
at Ryan Correctional Facility.
Yeah?
We call this Combat Mode.
It really put the fear of
God into the prisoners.
Yeah, that's okay.
And get a load of this.
What's that?
He transforms.
Kids love it.
Really?
Focus group numbers
through the roof.
- (chuckles) Really?
- Oh, yeah.
That's really embarrassing.
What is this?
You know what, people really
don't know what they want
until you show it to them
most of the time.
(sighs)
Make him more, uh...
tactical.
Make him look, uh...
Let's go with black.
Yeah.
♪♪
(brakes squeaking)
(thud)
(thudding, whirring)
(thudding, whirring continue)
...Alex. —He looks like
a billion dollars.
2.6 billion.
Raymond Sellars.
I've looked forward to
meeting you, Detective.
I really appreciate everything
you've done for me.
Well, we funded this program
to give men like you
a second chance.
You just do your best today.
...Shall we?
—Let's.
Mr. Sellars,
we're ready for you.
...Okay. Great.
—Chief Technician Shuman.
Morning, folks.
MATTOX (over radio): Okay,
so this is how it's gonna be.
We're going toe-to-toe.
Last man standing wins.
(over radio): I hit you, you go
back to the drawing board.
You hit me,
you get a ticket back home.
My guys are gonna be shooting
.47-caliber rounds.
Do a little damage,
but they can't take you out.
But make no mistake,
Tin Man, my gun will.
(guns clicking)
Alex, listen to me.
(over radio): The EM-2083
will try to maneuver you
so Mattox can get a clear shot.
Do not let that happen.
If Mattox hits you,
everything but your life support
will shut down.
You'll feel more pain than
you've ever felt in your life.
I don't know about that.
I've been through a lot.
All right.
I say we go on three.
Three.
♪♪
How's it going down there?
Whatever you do,
don't get shot in the face.
Wow.
♪♪
LIZ (voice-over):
Dr. Norton,
how-how is he doing this?
NORTON:
His software is faster,
His hardware is stronger.
He's a better machine.
LIZ: But you said
humans hesitate.
Only when they're
making decisions.
He's not making decisions?
Well, yes and no.
In his everyday life,
man rules over machine.
Alex makes his own decisions.
Now, when he engages in battle,
the visor comes down,
and the software
takes over, and, uh,
the-the machine does everything.
Alex is, uh,
he's a passenger,
just along for the ride.
LIZ: But if the machine
is in control,
then how is Murphy accountable?
Who's pulling the trigger?
When the machine fights,
the system releases a signal
into Alex's brain,
making him think he's doing
what our computers
are actually doing.
I mean, Alex believes,
right now, he is in control,
but he's not.
It-It's the illusion
of free will.
Crap.
♪♪
LIZ:
So you've circumvented the law
by creating a machine
that thinks it's a man,
but that's illegal.
- The...
- No... no, no, no.
It's a machine
that thinks it's Alex Murphy,
and in my book, that's legal.
Well done.
SELLARS:
Hey, Doctor,
what happens if I tase
an exoskeleton
with a little asshole inside?
(echoing over ♪.A.):
I, uh,
I think we're all curious
to find out.
Go ahead.
(groaning, grunting)
(groaning continues)
(grunts)
(whirring)
(sighs)
(crickets chirping, dog barking)
If I had a pulse,
it'd be racing.
She's been waiting four months.
I'm sure hers is, too.
(whirrs)
You're gonna do fine.
(footsteps approaching)
I love your sign, D.
Hey...
...there's nothing
to be nervous about.
(gentle laugh)
Thank you, Dennett.
It's been a privilege.
(whirrs)
(footsteps thud)
(thudding, whirring)
(doorbell rings)
♪♪
(footsteps thudding)
(sighs)
(whirrs)
(footsteps thudding)
Hi, Dad.
You know I missed you, buddy.
Me, too.
Want to feel it?
What is it?
It's okay, sweetie.
I saved all the Red Wings
games on my computer.
You did?
-How'd they do?
—I don't know.
I've been waiting to
watch them with you.
You know I'd love to, kiddo.
But I-I can't tonight.
You know, 'cause Daddy's suit
needs some...
some special handling.
Do you understand?
(tires squealing)
(whirring, thudding)
Thanks for coming, Jack.
Heard you went home already.
I know Clara
must be thrilled
to have you back.
I saw Clara.
And David.
That ain't my home right now.
It's in a damn lab
across the hall.
I'm sorry, Alex.
Starting tomorrow,
I'm gonna take down Vallon
and his whole damn crew.
I was waiting
to hear you say that.
Least I know you're
the right color now.
(chuckles)
(thudding, whirring)
♪♪
KELLY: Pat, the cooler
temperatures here today
certainly have not
stopped people from showing up.
We're expecting people
from every corner of the city
here in Detroit to come out
and show their support
for Detective Alex Murphy.
You know, a lot of questions
on people's minds today is:
What will he look like?
Is he a changed man?
Rumor has it he is
in the building,
preparing to come out.
Alex...
we're gonna upload
the entire DPD database
into your brain.
That means you'll have
instantaneous access
to criminal records plus
an archive of CCTV footage
from 2011 to the present.
All right.
Hit me.
Okay.
Kim, it's all yours.
KIM: Archive footage
uploading successfully.
Your system draws connections
automatically.
It will link perpetrators
to their crimes and give you
their exact locations
whenever available.
ROBOCOP: I got evidence
to make 138... no, no...
166 arrests.
KIM:
His emotions are stable.
This is incredible.
KELLY (voice-over):
You will notice
his family is here
in the building as well.
The mayor is
standing onstage behind me.
Also, Raymond Sellars
from Omnicorp.
They seem like great friends,
obviously echoing
the partnership
that they've brought together.
LIZ: How much longer
will this take?
KAREN: Well, the feed from
the database is almost done,
so we're approaching
present day.
634 pending arrests.
We're gonna need
a bigger prison.
ROBOCOP:
He's on top of her.
KIM: Dr. Norton,
he's getting too emotional.
...I got to do something...!
—Alex...
Alex, ca-calm down.
Take a breath; R-relax.
Kim, what are the readings?
I haven't seen him
- at levels like this.
- He's gonna shoot 'em. -Alex.
Alex, Alex, r-relax.
Relax.
Alex...
- What is this?
- This just a computer glitch?
KAREN:
No, that's his own crime scene.
- Alex.
- KIM: He's spiking
...all over the place.
—Alex!
- Alex!
- The system is crashing, Doctor.
Alex, can you hear me?
Alex? Alex?
KIM: I'm not sure
he can handle this.
ROBOCOP:
I gotta do something.
He's emotionally ovefloaded.
Unlock me!
Alex, stop! Stop!
He's having a seizure!
Kim, shut him down! Alex!
...Get me a live feed.
—I can't do it.
...Dr. Norton's with the patient.
—Do it now!
Jesus Christ!
...Dr. Norton... Dr. Norton...
- What?!
The press is waiting.
We have to get him
- up there now.
- What do you want me to do?!
I don't know... fix him!
Do what you have to do.
Your reputation is on the line
every bit as much as ours.
We're running out of time.
Okay.
Everybody out.
Out!
Mayor Durant is about to take
to the stage and introduce
Detroit's newest weapon
in the war on crime.
I'm, I'm actually getting word
that he's ready to go right now.
(car alarm blaring)
KIM:
Heart rate rising.
He might start spiking, Doctor.
NORTON: Set modules to absorb
dopamine and noradrenalin.
But you'll be taking
away his emotions.
Drop the levels
until I tell you to stop.
Doctor, you'll be taking away
- his ability to feel anything.
- Now, please.
Pull the footage.
Put it on a loop.
Dopamine level's at 20%.
More.
KIM: Dopamine level's
at ten percent.
NORTON:
More.
KIM:
Dopamine level's
...at five percent.
—Lower...
...You're flattening him out.
—Lower.
KIM:
Two percent.
Hold it there.
Alex...
Alex, how do you feel?
I feel fine, Dr. Norton.
MAYOR (voice-over):
Well, today
I'm not here to talk
about crime prevention.
I am here to give you the cure!
That's right!
Hi, Dad.
(whirring, footsteps thudding)
Dad?
MAYOR:
Ladies and gentlemen,
the revolution begins right now
with Detective Alex Murphy.
(cheering, whistling, applause)
♪♪
SELLARS:
Detective.
(whirring)
POPE:
He looks like a zombie.
I think he's accessing
criminal data.
Thomas King,
you are under arrest.
(crowd screaming)
(whirring)
Until today, Thomas King
was a convicted felon
wanted for rape,
arson, and murder.
This man has torn apart
American families.
On the loose for six years.
And where was
this criminal mastermind hiding?
Right in front
of the police headquarters.
Here he is, just steps away
from two of Detroit's finest.
These two officers
are completely unaware
of the monster in their midst.
(crowd screaming)
And then, in 60 seconds...
I repeat, just 60 seconds...
Detective Murphy
brings him down.
ROBOCOP: If you cannot
afford an attorney,
one will be provided for you.
This, my friends, is the future
of American justice.
How many like Thomas King
will pay for their crimes
now that RoboCop is here?
Yes, let's not shy away
from what this means, people.
Men weren't up to the task,
but Alex Murphy...
A robot cop... was.
We can't take him
off the street.
This, this is what I'm saying.
He's a hit,
a big, fat, stinking hit.
Yeah, until he breaks down
in front of everyone.
Hey, we all knew
there would be issues.
Uh, it's inevitable.
Dennett, you're my guy.
I just need you to
get a handle on this.
I know, but I need more time.
Scientifically,
w-w-we're in uncharted water.
We need to take him back to
the lab and do more tests.
I mean, it was like something
was interfering with our system,
something beyond
chemistry or physics.
Like what, his soul?
Hey, look, this train
has already left the station.
I can't exactly go out
to the world and say,
“ Sorry, I released
a defective product,"
so, no matter what we do,
we just need to keep him
on the streets.
Uh, what about the interviews?
Cancel 'em.
Cancel all of 'em... everything.
In fact, Dennett, let's, uh,
let's keep the wife
at a distance for now as well.
CLARA (voice-over):
I'd like to see him.
Can you arrange that?
Look, I won't lie to you.
Alex was so nervous,
we had to sedate him.
I looked in his eyes
and I couldn't see my husband,
and then he just shoots
a man in front of our son.
That's not sedation.
He's responding to drugs
differently now.
We both knew, from day one...
there would be complications.
Just give me a little more time.
I promise...
you'll have your husband back.
(elevator bell dings)
KAREN: This goes for every
squad in every department.
Detective Murphy
will have full access
to all investigations...
Robberies, narcotics, homicides.
If he requests
to take over a case,
the case will be handed to him.
No arguments, no complaints.
MAN:
This is bullshit.
I said no complaints,
and I mean it.
Now...
ROBOCOP:
Good morning, Chief Dean.
Good morning, officers.
I've selected 13 targets for
today, all wanted for murder.
John Biggs is target number one.
I'll be taking over this case.
Ambulances, detention
vehicles, and coroners
should be ready
to move in on my request.
I wish you all a very good day.
Murphy...
you okay, man?
I'm fine, Sergeant.
Can't wait to get back to work.
Lake and Daniels are in there
shitting their pants.
Excuse me, I have casework.
(engine roaring)
(crowd cheering)
(cheering)
(engine roaring)
Brother.
So what's this do?
(yelling)
Don't shoot, don't shoot,
don't shoot, don't shoot!
(tires screech)
Walter Karrel, look at me.
You have two options.
Option one:
I shoot you with 50,000 volts,
which may cause respiratory
failure, organ malfunction,
internal burns, and loss of
bowel and bladder control,
and then I arrest you.
Option two: You tell me
where John Biggs' drug lab
is located,
and then I arrest you.
You have two seconds to decide.
♪♪
(grunts)
(bopping)
♪♪
(grunts)
Totally justifiable.
We are going to make
a lot of money.
Nothing, no fear,
no increase in heart rate,
no traces of anger whatsoever.
LIZ:
Congratulations, Doctor.
You did it.
Yes, I did.
MATTOX (voice-over):
I told you, sir.
Norton clearly never had
control of the product.
SELLARS: I agree,
that's why I called you here.
I just want a second pair of
eyes on this thing, that's all.
Okay, I'll need a feed
from the Tin Man's head...
plus full surveillance
of the lab and...
You're gonna have full access
to everything.
If anything comes up,
I'm gonna be in Washington.
NOVAK (voice-over):
He brought peace
to this country's
most violent city.
He showed us all
that Detroit and America
can have a brighter future...
A future of economic growth,
freedom, and happiness.
On tonight's show,
a visionary and true patriot:
The CEO of Omnicorp,
Raymond Sellars.
(applause)
- Hello, Pat.
- Raymond.
Thanks for having me.
You must be doing a
victory lap about now.
- Well...
- Two weeks ago,
Omni's stock went
through the roof,
and the Senate
has finally agreed
to vote on the repeal
of the Dreyfus Act.
Well, look, I mean,
the tide is definitely turning.
I, I just feel certain
that, soon,
we'll be keeping
all Americans safe.
I certainly hope so,
but I think
our next guest will have
a different point of view.
SELLARS:
Mm-hmm.
Hubert Dreyfus.
Senator, thank you
for joining us.
Hello, Pat. Mr. Sellars.
Senator, do you know
what this is?
The American public is divided
on the Dreyfus Act.
Our polls at NovakElement.com
are tight at 50-50.
There is no doubt Omnicorp
created a sensation,
but this bill is not
about Alex Murphy.
It's about whether America
is willing to give robots
the authority over human lives.
No, no, no, no,
look, look, look.
This, uh, sea change
we're witnessing...
And it is a sea change... shows
that Americans don't really care
if our law enforcement systems
are manned or unmanned.
What they care about
is efficiency
and they care about safety.
You're clouding the issue.
This is clearly an attempt
to sway public opinion
- with a marketing stunt.
- No, what's clear is
that with just one system
in place,
we've cut crime by 80%.
Just imagine if we put,
I don't know,
let's say
a hundred systems in place.
And then I want you
to ask yourself,
why are you holding us back?
- Is that your plan?
- Thank you, Senator.
- And thank you, Raymond.
- Thank you, Pat.
Well, there you have it.
Who could argue with that?
Which begs the question:
Has the US. Senate
become pro-crime?
(phone ringing)
(phone rings, then beeps on)
Yeah, hi.
No, no, $5,000.
Yeah, call me tomorrow.
Hey, guys.
Vallon's waiting for you inside.
What, you too busy
to walk us in?
- I'm out here making money.
- Yeah, no, I know.
VALLON:
Where are my trip wires?
I gotta do this myself?
What took you so long?
DANIELS: What the hell
is all this shit?
I can't move any product
with this thing on the streets.
What are you doing
to protect me?
Relax, the guy's
a walking zombie.
Tell me your phones are off.
He's not going after you.
We covered our tracks.
He can't manufacture evidence
out of thin air.
If he does, I'm ready for him.
(thudding, whirring)
Well?
I've been getting calls.
From whom?
Well, Clara.
You need to let her
see her husband.
She has rights.
That's not your decision.
That's Legal's call.
Yeah, but it's only
a question of time
before she turns up
on television.
Well, she can try.
I'll issue a gag order before
I let her see her husband.
- I'd hop to it.
- CLARA (voice-over): Alex.
Alex, Alex!
Alex.
You need to come home.
Clara, please stand aside.
- You need to speak to your son.
- Right now,
I see three crimes in progress.
- My objective...
- Alex, listen to me.
I know you're in there.
David won't show
his face at school.
He's having nightmares.
He's falling apart.
I'm falling apart.
(gasping)
Please.
I can't do this on my own.
He's been scared
ever since that night.
- (clamoring)
- Come on, brother...!
LIZ (voice-over): What do you
think she's gonna do?
Hm. What's he gonna do?
(crowd clamoring)
Are you okay? David...?
(car horn honks)
(tires screech)
(tires screeching,
engine roaring)
KIM (voice-over): He's supposed
to be watching this.
Instead he's accessing
images of Clara and David
arriving at school,
over and over again.
Somehow he's overriding
the system's priorities.
KIM (voice-over):
Want me to shut him down?
NORTON (voice-over):
No.
Not yet.
I want to see what happens.
♪♪
KIM:
What's he doing at his house?
Look, he's disobeying protocol.
You have to shut him down.
As far as I can tell,
he's still doing his job.
♪♪
(deep whirring, topping)
(car alarm blaring)
(whirring, footsteps thudding)
Adrian, give me an image
of his brain.
He's undoing what we did to him.
His dopamine levels are
coming back to normal.
How is that even possible?
I haven't the faintest idea.
NORTON (over radio):
Alex.
(whirring)
(engine roaring)
Alex, please return
to the station.
I want to run some tests.
Well, this should
be interesting.
(engine roaring)
ALEX (recorded):
And your phone on the table!
We're not cops, all right?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
- Wh at?
- Whoa!
What'd you say?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
(engine roaring)
(dog barking in distance)
(groans)
(screaming)
My hand, man!
...Where's Antoine Vallon?
- You broke
my hand, man!
I know you remember me, Jerry.
- (bones crackling)
- (screaming)
Where's Vallon?
JERRY: Aah!
Wait, wait, man, wait, man!
If I tell you where Vallon is,
he'll kill my wife and kid, man.
Your wife left you
in 2019 after filing charges
for domestic abuse,
and you don't have a kid.
But I do.
(screams, bones crackle)
I'm not asking again!
Look, I swear, man,
I don't know
where Vallon is, okay?
The only guy I talk to is
his driver Marcus.
That's it, man, that's it!
Does he have a phone number?
(engine roaring)
We have a problem.
Alex is breaking protocol.
What's he doing?
He's off solving his own murder.
Oh, that is genius.
Why didn't I think of that?
VALLON (voice-over):
How long till he gets here?
All right.
Johnny, you stay
on these monitors.
What happened?
Some idiot used
an unencrypted phone.
Shit.
VALLON:
All right, everyone, listen up!
He's coming.
He leaves alive, you don't.
MAN:
How do we stop him?
.50-caliber and above.
Aim for the head.
(beep)
This one's set!
Go! Go!
(beeping)
(man yells in distance)
Come on. Come on!
Ready to go!
They're all set.
(power whirrs off)
(switch clicks)
(guns cocking)
(motorcycle engine decelerates)
(engine idling)
(engine revving)
♪♪
(grunts)
Finish it!
(RoboCop groans)
(whirring)
Freak! Die!
(groans)
(whirring, footsteps thudding)
(whirring, thudding)
(blipping, whirring)
♪♪
Watch out.
Need me to call a doctor?
Come on, Jack.
You're gonna like this.
What's going on?
What the hell you doing here?
Y'all gonna play
good cop, bad cop?
Nah, Daniels, bad cop, RoboCop.
ROBOCOP:
I've recovered 26 guns
from Vallon's warehouse.
13 serial numbers
match weapons missing
from Evidence,
and I got your prints
all over them.
This is bullshit.
I also have
CCTV footage of you and Vallon
the same day he
tried to kill me.
VALLON:
So put him on the payroll.
...Why we talking about this?
- DANIELS: It won't work.
Now that his partner got hit,
he's never gonna let it go.
- What is that?
- Lewis's hospital.
Murphy's dropping by
this afternoon.
If I kill a cop, I'm looking
over my shoulder.
I kill a cop,
I'm looking over...
LEWIS:
You know what they do to cops
in prison, man?
Being locked up
with the same dudes
you put in there?
VALLON: I kill a cop,
I'm looking over my shoulder
the rest of my life.
If I kill a cop...
How long you think
before he gives you up?
(people screaming)
Don't shoot me.
Okay?
I swear to Christ, it was Dean.
She helped pull those guns.
Just don't shoot me.
Thank you for your cooperation.
(Lake groaning)
You can cuff him now, Jack.
Now, I know why
we couldn't get an arrest.
'Cause Vallon was protected
from up on high.
Alex, I can explain.
You tipped him off today.
Come on, man.
Don't do this.
You tried to kill me twice.
I trusted you,
and you destroyed my family.
Confess.
Now, in front of everyone.
Confess!
(power whirrs off)
What happened?
MATTOX (over radio):
Tin Man is down.
Had to be done.
Why?
Product shot a corrupt cop.
Two more seconds,
the chief's brains
would've been splattered
across the 6:00 News.
- We got anything on her?
- Well, she's, uh,
the Chief of the Detroit
Police Department.
What do you think?
You know what?
This might actually tip
this thing right into the net.
NOVAK: Alex, I don't know
if you can hear me,
but tonight,
you uncovered a nest of vipers
inside the Detroit
Police Department.
And in so doing, you shed light
on an invaluable truth.
Even the police,
the men and women
who swore to keep us safe,
they can be bribed.
They... can be bought.
Machines, however,
are corruption-free.
Americans could be living
in a country
where law enforcement
is not only efficient,
but incorruptible.
Thank you, Alex,
for all you've done,
and for all that you are.
Detective Murphy is currently
in critical condition.
Our doctors are
working ceaselessly
but, at this time, it is
unclear if he will survive.
(reporters clamoring)
KELLY: Ms. Kline,
how do you think the attempt
on Detective Alex Murphy's life
will affect tomorrow's vote
for the Dreyfus Act?
LIZ: At this time,
Omnicorp's sole concern
is the full recovery
of Detective Murphy.
NOVAK: How many times
does Detective Murphy
have to give his life
for his country?
I sincerely hope
the Senate makes
the right vote tomorrow,
so that Alex Murphy's sacrifices
will not have been in vain.
OHIO SENATOR (voice-over):
Senator Dreyfus is my friend.
He has been
my mentor and my strength
in times of difficulty
on this floor.
But despite all that,
I work for the state of Ohio
and the safety of its citizens
is my top priority.
So I vote yes.
The Dreyfus Act
must be repealed.
That's us ahead, 39 to 10.
Yeah, I spoke to
the Senate liaison,
and it looks like
it's in the bag.
But we still have to tread
carefully with the politicians.
We're here live
at DPD headquarters
where moments ago, Clara Murphy
made a shocking statement.
POPE:
What the hell?
Omnicorp has denied me
and my son
access to Alex for weeks.
I demand to know why.
This treatment is inhuman,
and somebody needs
to be held accountable.
- CLARA: Thank you.
- Oh, we're fucked.
No, we only need 12 votes.
She shouldn't make
much difference.
Yeah, but what about
after the vote?
We... I mean,
those two should not
be allowed contact.
If-if she starts putting ideas
in his head...
Bring her in.
I'll handle the explanation.
And what about Alex?
You know, unfortunately,
we can't just keep him on ice.
LIZ: The shooting
at the station
spooked some of the politicians.
They're our clients;
We have to take care of them.
They're fine when a machine
is lowering the murder rate,
but when a man
is investigating city politics,
they get nervous.
All right, first off,
it's not a man, okay?
It's property of Omnicorp.
And politics are the
least of your concern.
I mean, this thing
solved its own murder.
How long till it realizes
you haven't been
on the level with it?
POPE: If that happens,
every journalist
in this country
is dying to speak to him.
I mean, we-we created a hero.
What happens
when he opens his mouth?
What's bigger than a hero?
A dead hero.
Get me Dr. Norton.
What is this, Raymond?
You have Mattox spying on me
and now this bullshit
about a "critical condition"?
You know and I know
Alex is fine!
Calm down.
What... Dennett.
Your work is so good, I don't...
Well, now,
this is not about my work!
You saw the woman on TV!
This has to stop!
You're right.
But let me
ask you something, Dennett.
What kind of life have we really
given Alex Murphy?
He's never gonna be
a normal man,
a father, a husband.
By the time we put
the other units on the street,
he's just... Dennett...
(sighs)
Let's face it.
We failed him.
We failed Alex Murphy.
But I want you to think
about the bigger picture
because that's
what we're talking about.
The work you've done with him
is gonna be studied for decades.
You've changed
the face of history, Dennett.
No policeman
is ever going to die
in the line of duty again
because of you.
Think about that.
I want that family
taken care of
beyond their wildest dreams.
We owe them that.
I agree.
I want full funding
for ten years.
New staff, all my own people.
Fantastic.
Deal.
Hey, what's going on?
Security's here.
They're clearing everyone out.
They're not waking him up.
Whatever you do,
don't leave him alone.
What do you mean
they're not waking him up?
SENATE LEADER:
The voting period has ended.
The clerks have
tabulated the results.
The yeas are 63.
The nays are 22.
A majority of senators
have voted in the affirmative.
The Dreyfus Act
has been repealed
by Congress.
(applause over TV)
(phone rings)
God, you guys are slow,
like a bunch of girls.
This is Mattox.
SELLARS:
Bennett's on board.
It's about time.
Call it.
Get it done.
My pleasure.
(doorbell rings)
Mrs. Murphy...
You can come here
as much as you want.
You can threaten me.
You can sue me.
You can take my home.
But I am not gonna stop
till I see my husband.
Do you understand that?
Mr. Sellars would
very much like to see you.
Is Alex okay?
He has important information
to share with you.
Will you accompany me?
David.
We gotta go.
Can you grab your coat?
(phone rings)
Hey.
NORTON: I'm in the elevator,
on my way down.
I need access to the lab.
That's insane;
They're still here.
NORTON:
Distract them.
Okay.
|cannot...!
There's a lady in here
going hysterical.
She will not let us in;
She's got the code for the door.
I repeat:
She will not let us in.
Lady, you need to let us
in there now.
We have to get in there.
Are you not understanding
what I'm saying?
Do you want to be responsible
for the deaths
of everyone in this building?
Hey! Stop!
(panting)
Don't shoot.
Step outside.
Unlock the transmitter!
KIM:
Transmitter unlocked.
Send in Mrs. Murphy, please.
WOMAN (over intercom):
Right away, sir.
NORTON (voice-over):
Wake him up!
Alex! Alex!
Alex, it's Dr. Norton.
You have to wake up!
Alex, can you hear me?
These men are here to kill us.
They're here to kill us,
for Christ sakes!
SELLARS (voice-over):
Mrs. Murphy, last night,
Alex had a psychotic break.
He killed an unarmed colleague
and later suffered a seizure.
We did everything...
Everything... we could,
but the doctors
couldn't save him.
Very sorry, Mrs. Murphy.
We're going to be making
the announcement shortly.
ROBOCOP (voice-over):
You shut me down.
I was about to get a confession.
Mattox shut you down.
I've removed your transmitter,
so he won't do it again.
Sellars can't afford
to wake you up.
He sent these guys
to pull the plug.
He wants you dead, Alex.
You understand?
SELLARS (voice-over):
Sorry. If there's anything
we can do for you and
David, we'll do it.
I want nothing from you.
I understand.
You stay out of our lives.
You and your company.
If that's what
you think is best.
There's one more thing.
I think it would be to
the benefit of everyone,
especially David,
if we kept this matter private.
We don't want to damage
Alex's legacy.
NORTON (voice-over):
Alex.
Alex!
I can fix this!
You lied to me.
You lied to my wife.
You're working for the people
that are trying to kill me.
You want me to
trust you, Doctor?
Alex, I can go to the press!
Alex, I can tell them
the whole story!
Alex!
Listen to me, please!
Alex...!
(engine roaring)
What the hell...?
(tires squealing)
(passing car honking horn)
(engine revving)
Keep all our systems
at green light,
and for Christ sakes,
get Sellars on the phone.
MAN:
Roger that.
Damn, damn, damn, damn, damn!
Look at this city.
So beautiful.
It's become so peaceful.
I wish...
I had some good news
for Detroit.
I have very sad news.
Despite our best efforts
to save him,
Alex Murphy passed away
just hours ago.
Alex Murphy was...
SECURITY OFFICER:
Mr. Sellars.
- What is it?
- Mattox just called.
We need to you to come
with us now.
(elevator bell dings)
Ma'am, I need you to turn around
and go the other way, please.
What are you talking about?
We have
a security situation here.
I need you to turn around
and go the other way.
Sir, there's a car
outside that's...
That area is locked down.
- Now go.
- What's happening?
I said go!
I want to talk to Mr. Sellars.
Mr. Sellars.
- How close is that helicopter?
- About ten minutes, sir.
♪♪
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
I need to speak with
Sergeant Jack Lewis.
- Yes.
- It's an emergency.
SECURITY OFFICER:
Stand by.
Mr. Sellars.
Apparently there's
a Clara Murphy
in the lobby.
Uh, Raymond, if she sees him,
- we are dead in the water.
- What do you want to do?
Bring Mrs. Murphy up here.
Yes, sir.
(sirens wailing,
tires squealing)
LEWIS (voice-over):
Norton said they may be
using drones for protection.
So whatever you do,
do not draw your weapons.
They won't shoot
if we're unarmed.
...Clear?
—Clear. —Clear.
(siren wailing)
(engine decelerating)
OFFICER:
Hold it right there!
OFFICER 2 (over radio):
...coming your way.
Don't move!
This is private property.
You are not authorized
to be here!
(electricity crackling,
officer groans)
ROBOCOP:
I'd put those guns down now
if I were you.
OFFICER:
Stand down. Stand down.
OFFICER 2: All right, man,
we're good We're good!
Let's go! Back it up!
(whirring)
(thudding)
(sirens wailing)
Head to the lower level.
-GUARD: Hold up! Hold up!
—Ram it!
(thudding)
(grunting, groaning)
(grunting with effort)
(sirens wailing)
(tires squealing)
(grunting)
Gun it!
Go, go, go, now!
(groaning)
Alex, run!
Omnicorp Security!
- Drop your weapons!
- ED-209: Drop your weapon.
Keep your hands above your head,
and no one will be harmed.
(sirens wailing in distance)
What's going on?
Mrs. Murphy, I want you
to listen to me carefully.
The organic part
of your husband Alex is dead.
The robotic part of him
is malfunctioning,
and he's shooting up
the building.
So we've got to get you
and your son
out of here right away.
I've got to take this call.
He just left the lobby,
and he's headed our way.
MATTOX:
Roger that, sir.
Don't shoot.
My robot. You just flank.
...Got it.
—Tin Man!
Tin Man?
Tin Man.
Oh, there it is.
You look like crap.
What's the matter?
Can't shoot?
Huh?
What were you thinking?
This isn't a drill.
You're a robot.
I'm a red asset.
Wrote that myself.
What do you think?
Come on, Tin Man,
just pull the trigger.
Pull it.
You can run.
Go on.
Run.
Run!
There you go.
Run.
Run. Run!
(yells)
(whoops)
- Stings like a bitch, don't it?
- (groaning)
Aren't you lucky I didn't have
my gun set to "kill"?
Hey, listen...
this isn't personal.
Well, maybe a little.
I'm gonna put you
out of your misery.
(gunshot)
SECURITY OFFICER:
Helicopter's approaching.
Mr. Sellars boards first.
No, no, no. Mrs. Murphy,
you and your son
can get on first.
(groaning, gasping)
Officer down.
Mechanical room.
Omnicorp Building.
OFFICER (over radio):
Roger that. EMS on the way.
You're gonna be okay, Jack.
Nonfatal.
Go. Go.
PILOT: Omni-LZ Helo One
on approach to deck.
(whirring, footsteps thudding)
CO-PILOT:
What's that?
- CO-PILOT: He's got a gun.
- PILOT: What?
CO-PILOT:
Pull up! Pull up!
What the hell's he doing?
Sorry, sir. I don't know.
Alex?
Dad?
(gasping)
Clara, David.
No, wait-wait-wait. Wait.
Get out of the way.
- Alex, put down the gun.
- Clara,
take David
and get out of the way now!
Raymond Sellars,
you're under arrest
for the attempted murder
of a police officer.
Are you here to cuff me?
All right.
Go ahead, cuff me.
You can't.
You're not programmed that way.
If you go against the program,
the entire system
shuts down, so...
You don't even have a warrant.
- We'll overlook this little...
- Get down on the ground and put
- your hands behind your back.
- I-I'm just from Marketing.
- Now!
- Okay, yep, yep, yep.
Yep.
Alex, we need
to work together here.
Because I'm the only one
with the technology
to keep you alive.
Dead or alive,
you're coming with me.
(whirring)
- (clank)
- (groaning)
All right.
Weapon.
Alex, honestly,
I mean you no harm.
If I wanted to,
I could have killed you
along time ago.
I just aim this right
at your head and blow it off.
CLARA:
Sellars, please!
Don't!
I mean, if I wanted to,
I could just
aim this at your little family,
and I could just kill them too.
And really, there's nothing
you could do about it,
because, let's face it...
you're a robot.
Do you understand that?
Alex...
Dad!
CLARA (whispering):
Baby.
(whirring)
Hey...
Hey... everything's
gonna be all right.
(Clara and David crying)
Everything's gonna be all right.
(sirens wailing in distance)
♪♪
(heart beating quietly)
How are you feeling, Alex?
I'm ready.
(clanking, whirring)
(clicking, whirring)
(heart beating steadily)
- He's ready.
- (Clara sighs)
♪♪
NOVAK:
There's still no word
from Omnicorp
parent company, OCP.
And although the government says
they are rebuilding Alex Murphy,
rumors continue to swirl
about his condition.
But we have obtained
exclusive video
taken by cell phone
that shows the people of Detroit
may have Alex Murphy
back on the streets
sooner than they think.
The real tragedy here is that
our president chose
to uphold the Dreyfus Act.
Now, I have no doubt
he was manipulated
by our biased media
and by whistle-blower
Dennett Norton.
I acknowledge we know
less than we thought.
But I do believe
my research program is sound.
What I did With it...
...was wrong.
The fact that
this mother (bleep)
Is not serving time
in some Federal penitentiary
is a huge, hot, heaping pile
of horse (bleep)!
Now I know some of you may think
that this kind
of thinking is dangerous
and these machines violate
your civil liberties.
Some of you even believe that
the use of these drones overseas
makes us the same kind
of bullying imperialists
that our forefathers
were trying to escape.
To you, I say,
stop whining!
America is now,
and always will be,
the greatest country
on the face of the Earth!
I'm Pat Novak.
Good night.
♪♪
(music ends)