What if I told you that even in the
... America's worst neighborhoods safer
will become completely safe?
How do I know that?
Because it is happening now...
all over the states
... but the world
this country
... It's greatness
to see the machinery of American
help in promoting peace abroad
! So, tell me
Why would not appreciate the use of
these machines here in our country?
... Why has America
machinery phobia?
We have to give the Americans
appreciate the product to be loved
Personal rally around
We will not appreciate the situation in the street machine
Forget about the machine they want...
product awareness by
... knows something
'What is the sense of
to be a human being
= = give your mom a kiss -
Good night, my dear -
a withering oh boy
We will put a man inside the machine
It's time to wake him up
make it more tactical
Let's make it in black
Power Control
EMC - 208
against ten men
! Stunning
yields an a lot of money
in February
It's coming
Do you want to play the role of good cop bad cop or
?
Cop bad cop and automated
some creatures
It does what we did do -
Damn -
can not control it
close the
cop automated
Thank you for your cooperation with us