And we're on in four, three,
two, one.
What if I told you that even
the worst neighborhood in America
could be made completely safe?
And what if I told you
that this could be accomplished
without risking the life
of one single law enforcement officer?
How do I know this?
Because it's happening right now
in every country in the world
but this one.
I'm Pat Novak,
and welcome to The Novak Element.
In tonight's State of the Union segment
we'll be joined by General Curtis Monroe
live from the War Room in the Pentagon.
General Monroe, welcome back.
Good to see you, Pat.
Thank you for this unprecedented access
to your operations.
Could you walk us
through what we're seeing here?
Well, this is a routine operation.
We found that random patrols
helped the local population
to feel safer and to trust us.
It's amazing.
And what are these colored dots
that we're seeing here, General?
These are our assets on the ground.
In green, we got the ED-209s.
They're the big boys.
They secure the perimeter.
Purple are the smaller EM-208s.
They sweep and mop up.
And the red dots,
Pat, that's your film crew.
It is great to see American machines
helping to promote
peace and freedom abroad.
All right, you guys,
this is a standard op, all right?
There's no opposition expected.
I'm gonna set your markers to code red.
All our drones are gonna
give top priority to your safety.
No red assets have ever been lost.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Does that make you feel better?
But, listen,
keep those bracelets on,
you're completely safe.
Okay?
Good. Enjoy the show.
All right. Let's go.
May peace be upon you.
Please exit
your homes with your arms raised
for a noninvasive scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Please exit
your homes with your arms raised
for a noninvasive scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Scott, get me a shot of this.
Your cooperation is appreciated.
We apologize for any inconvenience.
As-Salaam-Alaikum.
May peace be upon you.
Incredible.
Incredible!
Not long ago,
that would have been
American men and women
risking their lives
to pacify these people.
General, you care to comment on this?
Well, Pat, we had Vietnam,
we had Iraq, we had Afghanistan.
Never again.
From a military perspective,
this has been invaluable.
We can accomplish our objectives
without any loss to American lives
and I think the honest people
over there really appreciate it.
And why wouldn't they?
For the first time in their lives
they get to watch their children grow up
in an environment of safety and security.
Kelly! Can you hear me out there?
Loud and clear, Pat.
I'm here in sunny Tehran
where locals have clearly
embraced these routine scans.
As you can see behind me, they're working
in collaboration with the robots
and obviously their safety is
everyone's top priority.
You'll notice children
in the streets as well.
This is everyday life
happening in perfect harmony.
Oh, great. Here, come here.
Stay put, stay put, stay put.
It's fine. Don't worry. My guys got it.
Oh, my God!
Drop your weapon.
Kelly?
Kelly! Are you all right? Kelly!
We're okay, Pat.
- Our robots have just repelled...
- Hold on, Kelly.
...some suicide bombers.
I'm sorry, Kelly, but for security reasons
the Pentagon's going
to cut our feed to Tehran.
But, please, be careful.
Yeah. I'll continue to stand by.
Now you see how fundamental
these robots are to our foreign policy.
So then tell me.
Why can't we use
these machines here at home?
Why is America so robophobic?
On the one hand, we have Raymond Sellars.
An entrepreneur and true American
whose product just
saved my colleague's life.
And on the other.
Hubert Dreyfus.
A man with both feet
planted firmly in the past
whose bill prohibits
the use of drones on US soil.
The American people
support the Dreyfus Act
because they haven't
experienced this technology,
and they fear what they don't understand.
We at The Novak Element
support Mr. Sellars' efforts
to make our country and our viewers safer.
After all,
what's more important
than the safety of the American people?
- Hey, Murphy.
- Hey.
How's Jack?
We don't know yet.
- Murphy.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
- Good.
What the hell are they doing here?
Six in the morgue. Lewis in the hospital.
This was the mother of all bad ideas.
We got a lead on
Antoine Vallon, we took it.
What lead?
Not in front of them.
- This is bullshit.
- Yeah?
Yeah, you got something to say, Murphy?
Vallon's our case.
Yeah, two years
without no arrest, no nothing?
You've gotta be dumb or dirty.
You got something on us?
Or is this personal?
No, it's nothing personal.
Although, I don't like you as a person.
Okay, you two, out.
No problem.
Maybe if you hadn't
gone off the reservation,
your partner would still be standing.
- What'd you say to me?
- Hey, that's enough!
Okay, Alex.
It's just you and me now.
So me and Jack,
we've been doin' some street buys.
We get a line on some guns.
We meet up with this low-level G
called Jerry,
who ends up havin' a piece
he's not supposed to have.
Where the hell
you get a gun like that, Jerry?
I can get you two whole crates full, man.
Two crates?
No disrespect, J,
but how a clown like
you get so much product, man?
What's it matter where it comes from?
Why it matters,
we don't want no dirty guns, Jerry.
These guns got bodies on 'em, Jerry?
Yo, look, they're clean, all right?
You gonna buy this shit or not?
Hey, hey, why you acting so nervous, man?
You fishin' on us, Jerry?
What'd you say?
- You think he fishin', D?
- I think he's fishin' on us.
Yo, what the hell are
they talkin' about, man?
Hey, let me see your phone.
- Let me see your phone.
- I'm not showing you my phone, man!
You recordin' this?
I think you're a goddamn cop!
What the hell are you talkin' about, man?
I'm not showing you my phone!
Hey! Put your gun down!
Put your phones on the table.
We're not cops, all right?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
What?
Shut up! Shut up! What'd you say?
Ends up he works for Vallon.
Before the meet,
we ran the serial numbers on the rifles.
The guns were supposed
to be in our evidence room.
Not out on the street.
Intake papers blank. No signatures.
- What do you got?
- Nothin'.
How do you think that happened?
I'm telling you,
Murphy, this is a mistake.
These guys'll shoot
you just to see if they gun work.
We need backup.
If we call for backup,
word's gonna get around the station.
He's gonna disappear.
It's gonna be all right.
So we told Vallon
we were gun buyers,
and he bought it.
What do you two need
with that much product?
You plotting a coup?
Man, don't trip, we ain't gonna bust
a single shot in your town.
We got some problems
back home with Chicago PD.
Yeah, I heard you don't like cops.
Hey, boss.
What do you got for me?
Really?
We were
just about to close the deal
but someone tipped him off.
Gentlemen,
I gotta deal with this.
Two minutes.
Make sure you kill 'em both!
I got two handguns, one automatic.
We gotta get out of here.
I'm gonna take the automatic.
You sure about this?
You ready?
Move.
Lewis!
Officer down! Officer down, 331 Hamilton.
This is Detective Alex Murphy
in need of immediate medical assistance.
331 Hamilton Road.
Jack.
Jack, come on. Jack. Can you hear me?
Jack. Stay with me.
Jack.
Alex,
you don't do something like this
unless you bring it to me first.
Vallon's connected.
I'm warning you,
don't make any more moves
until I vet this.
If officers are supplying him with guns...
That's up to IAD.
I'll handle it.
I don't care how sophisticated
these machines are, Mr. Sellars.
A machine does not know
what it feels like to be human.
It can't understand
the value of human life.
Why should it be allowed to take one?
To legislate over life and death,
we need people who understand
right from wrong.
- What do your machines feel?
- Well, they feel no anger.
They feel no prejudice.
They feel no fatigue,
which makes them
ideal for law enforcement.
Putting these machines on the streets
will save countless American lives.
- You're evading the question.
- No, I'm not.
Yes,
you're evading the question.
I asked what do these machines feel?
If one of them killed a child...
what would it feel?
- Nothing.
- And that's the problem.
That's why 72% of Americans
will not stand for
a robot pulling the trigger.
America is the world's
most valuable market,
and we can't touch it.
With a domestic expansion,
we'd clear 600 billion dollars per annum.
In other words, every second
that law is in existence,
we are hemorrhaging money.
What do you want me to do?
We've thrown cash at senators
at both sides of the aisle.
Nobody's budging.
They don't want to vote
against their constituents.
So unless we sway public opinion,
the battle's lost.
Now, to that effect,
my team have come up with
a pretty aggressive new campaign.
Wow factor off-the-charts.
We need to give Americans
a product they can love.
A figure they can rally behind.
Sir, I have dissected this bill.
There are no loopholes.
We can't put a machine on the streets.
Forget machines.
You saw the polls.
Americans don't want a machine.
They want
a product with a conscience.
They want...
something that knows...
what it feels like...
to be human.
We're gonna put a man inside a machine.
You're not you
because of your legs,
your arms, your hands.
You're you because of your brain.
It's your brain's capacity
to process information
that makes you who you are.
Relax, and just do
what you've always done.
I've never played with these.
The music doesn't come
from your fingers, Michael,
it comes from your mind.
All you have to do is let it out.
Please.
Oh, my God.
No, it's okay. Easy.
His emotions are peaking.
The readings are getting clouded.
It's okay.
Relax. If you get too emotional,
it'll change the chemistry in your brain.
It'll throw the system out.
You're doing great. Come on.
I need emotion to play.
Concierto de Aranjuez,
second movement.
Beautiful piece.
Dennett, when you have
a moment. Thank you.
Now, we agreed on this
a long time ago, Raymond.
I-I wouldn't be asked
to develop combat applications.
My-my work here
is driven by its own questions.
And your work is brilliant.
But your ideas are being underutilized.
Look, I think I found a way
to put real revenue stream
behind your research
and save thousands
of lives in the process.
You're not keeping up your end,
leaving me exposed like that.
Detective Murphy's
just a little impulsive.
So put him on the payroll.
Why are we talkin' about this?
It won't work.
And now that his partner got hit,
he's never gonna let it go.
- What is that?
- Lewis' hospital.
Alex is dropping by this afternoon,
in case you want to send flowers.
Yeah.
I kill a cop,
lookin' over my shoulder
the rest of my life.
That's not good for business.
Who do you think's
gonna be investigating you?
I'm gonna go hard after Lake and Daniels.
I'm gonna have 'em in
bracelets within a month, man.
Hey, Vallon,
I'm walking up right now.
Cameras off?
Clear.
You were right.
We should've had backup.
I'm sorry.
You're not really sleeping, are ya?
Asshole.
Sergeant Thomas Ryan, NYPD.
Paralyzed from the waist down.
He has let himself go
a little since the accident.
Pass.
Yeah. Yeah, fair enough.
Officer Alfred Miller, Denver.
"Severe Cerebellar..."
Cerebellar ataxia.
That's why you're the doctor, Doctor.
He scored through the roof
with our urban demos.
Let's keep this one in mind.
I like this guy.
Very good, sir. I saved the best for last.
I give you Sergeant Jack Freeman,
masculinity incarnate.
Led Pittsburgh SWAT for five years,
now confined to a wheelchair.
I...
think I can see the appeal.
No.
What? Why?
Well, check the psych evaluation.
He's far too unstable.
He's trying to say that he has a temper.
Have you any idea
what we'd be putting him through?
The psychological strain
requires someone emotionally balanced.
We have to be scientific.
I mean, we're not selling
a soft drink here, are we?
He's right. Okay. Keep looking.
David, what did I say?
Not until you're finished.
- Hey, guys.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey.
- Hey, little monkey.
How's the game, buddy?
Damon got ejected,
but we got a two-man advantage.
Oh, yeah? That's fantastic.
Hey, D, why don't you head upstairs
and start getting ready for bed.
But he just got home.
I'll be up in a second.
Tuck you in, okay? All right?
- Now give your mom a kiss.
- Good night, baby.
Too slow, boy.
You're just too slow.
How's Jack holding up?
They said a week
till he's back on his feet.
It's my fault.
We shouldn't even have been there.
Here.
Oh, shit, I thought I fixed that.
It'll stop.
It's gonna wake up David.
He suffered
fourth-degree burns
over 80 percent of his body.
Lower spine has been severed.
If he survives...
he'll be paralyzed
from the waist down
and confined to a wheelchair.
Mrs. Murphy...
we don't have to do this.
I need to know everything
before I make a decision.
Please continue.
Vestibulocochlear,
optical nerves have
been critically damaged.
He'll be blind in one eye.
Most likely deaf.
Frankly, Dr. Norton
and the Omni Foundation
are the leaders in this field.
In my opinion, this is
the only chance your husband has.
I'd seriously consider their offer.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I need time to think.
I'm afraid, Mrs. Murphy,
time is one thing you don't have.
You say you can save him,
but what does that mean?
What kind of life will he have?
- Thanks.
- Thanks, buddy.
You know she's gonna make me dance again.
Now that I've gotta see.
You don't want to see that.
Here she comes now.
Hold on to that.
Get out there, partner.
Every time.
Get her, boy.
Subject is still dreaming.
He's retrieving memories,
trying to make sense of
sensorial stimulation package 37.
Perfect, Kim.
Let's reconnect the spine.
Time to wake him up.
Excuse me?
What are you doing here?
Baby, where you going?
Lewis.
Subject regaining cognitive functions.
What's happening?
Where am I?
You were in an explosion, Alex.
You're in a hospital.
Where's...
Where's Ciara? My wife. Where's my wife?
I want you to calm down,
Alex. Listen to me.
You're okay. And your family's fine.
Both your wife and your son.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Dr. Dennett Norton. I'm treating you.
Heart rate rising.
I can't move.
I can't move. What the hell is all that?
Visual input unstable.
I want you to relax, Alex.
Subject's dumping too much epinephrine.
- Should we purge it?
- Not yet.
Unlock vertebrae.
Go ahead, Kim.
Unlock upper, lower extremities.
What kind of suit is this?
It's not a suit, Alex. It's...
It's you.
This was the only option.
We're here, all of us,
to make you whole again.
Full body unlock.
I want you to walk now, Alex.
You can do that.
This seems so real.
Alex, it's very important
you understand what is happening.
This is real.
It's not a dream,
it's not drugs or anesthetics.
I know I'm dreaming
'cause I can feel all of this.
Alex, amputees can often
feel their missing appendages.
It's called phantom limb sensation.
What do you mean "amputees"?
- What the hell did you do to me?
- You need to relax.
Take this off me now.
I need to get out of this thing.
What did you do to me?
What have you done to me?
Alex? Hey!
Shut him down.
No! Let him run! Let him run!
Where am I?
Alex, please.
Stop.
Alex, you have to stop.
Please.
Alex.
Please stop.
Stay where you are
and we'll come and pick you up.
Okay, Kim.
Shut him down.
Alex...
you can't run from this.
You have to understand
the reality of the situation.
Show me.
Kim.
Oh!
No.
Holy Christ.
Holy Christ, there's nothing left.
Your body may have gone,
but you're still here.
That's not even my brain.
We had to repair the damaged areas.
But we didn't interfere with
your emotion or your intellect.
Do you understand me, Alex?
You're... You're in control.
- I'm in control?
- Yes.
Okay.
If I'm in control...
then I wanna die.
Just unplug whatever it is
keepin' me alive and end this nightmare.
Now, say I did that,
which as a doctor would
almost be impossible for me,
but say I did.
What do I say to your wife?
What does she say to your son?
That it didn't work. That you tried.
Somethin' went wrong.
You did everything you could...
but I died.
So after all they've been through,
all the pain, all their hope restored,
we would just rip that away?
Your wife loves you, Alex.
She signed the consent forms herself.
Otherwise, you couldn't
have undergone the procedure.
She loves you
and she gave you a second chance.
I need you to take it.
I don't wanna see myself like this again.
Ever.
And the same goes for my family.
Just put me back in.
Zoom in.
Stop.
Accept the connection.
It's so good to finally see you.
I was gonna say the same thing.
I'm sorry.
I know how I must look to you.
I think you look beautiful.
Are they treating you okay, baby?
So far. Dr. Norton,
he seems like a nice guy.
Does David know you're calling?
He misses you.
- I can go get him.
- No.
I don't want him to see me like this.
Not yet.
Sure.
We're gonna get through this, baby.
We're gonna make it like it was.
When are you comin' home?
Well, they've still got some tests.
But they're sayin' it's goin' really well.
The minute they let me.
I gotta go.
I love you.
End the connection.
Okay, blood cleansing initiated.
Viral and bacterial screening activated.
Releasing proteins, fats,
minerals and carbs.
Energy inflow is at 1320 kilocalories.
Now starting
anti-inflammatory corticoids, hormones
and antibiotic protocols.
Standard daily intake.
Release antidepressants.
Let's give him a nice dream.
All right,
here's what you're dealin' with.
Modified M2 battle rifle.
.50 caliber Beowulf
ammunition at 30 round clips.
Three-shot bursts or full auto.
Heavy-duty.
TSR 66. Cartridge-driven taser pistol.
Each projectile
releases up to 200,000 volts.
It can stun,
it can kill and it's nasty shit.
Your armor,
state-of-the-art, but not invulnerable.
.50 caliber or larger
can penetrate and kill.
Multiple hits,
and guess who ends
up in the recycling bin?
If you sense you need
a weapon or are threatened
the visor goes down and the system
makes the weapons available.
But you gotta remember,
it's not the weapons that count.
It's who's handling them.
Or, in your case, what.
- You think you can do this?
- Oh, just stick to your job.
Just stick to my job?
Combat robots are my job, Doc.
Rio, Congo,
you name it, I was there.
Our machines run perfectly.
You ask me, stickin' organics
into the system
is a huge step backwards.
I don't care how well
you designed this thing.
Without my sign-off,
it better start learnin' Chinese,
'cause it ain't never goin' home.
It's nice to meet you, too.
Let's do this,
Tin Man.
Quality control, EM-208 versus Tin Man.
Rendering scenario one now.
Hey, Doc, hope you don't mind.
I like a little music while I'm workin'.
All right.
All right, let's let the games begin.
Let's rock 'n' roll.
Commence scenario.
Laggin' on the corners.
No, there, do you see that?
What my robot did, that's how you do it.
New product's afraid.
2.3 seconds behind. Great.
Don't shoot! He has a gun!
Drop your gun!
Drop the weapon. Let the kid go!
Oh, well, it's worried
that the kid's gonna get hurt.
- Let the kid go!
- Too bad.
Well, there you have it.
5.6 seconds behind. Scenario failure.
I wouldn't buy that for a dollar.
- Let's do it again.
- Your funeral.
Detective Alex Murphy.
Search results.
"Detective Murphy
making a speedy recovery."
"Alex Murphy. Man or Machine?"
"Thrust into the spotlight,
Ciara Murphy won't talk."
Antoine Vallon.
Search results.
"DPD says Antoine Vallon
no longer suspect
due to lack of evidence."
Detroit Free Press.
Unfortunately,
Murphy's investigation into Antoine Vallon
wasn't authorized in the first place.
Look, Detective Murphy
was simply overzealous, okay?
We have absolutely no evidence
linking Vallon to the attempt on his life.
All I'm gonna say is
my partner's a great cop.
And I won't rest until the men
who tried to kill him
are brought to justice.
What's wrong with him?
No, nothing, nothing.
Watch the procedural bars on the 208.
The machine assesses the threat and acts.
- All right.
- That's it.
It's two steps. Now watch Alex.
The software assesses the threat,
just like the robot.
And it sends the information to the brain.
Alex's brain receives the information
and decides what to do with
it based on his emotional...
Right.
...cognitive abilities like any man would.
Then the brain relates this
to the AI module and, uh...
Yeah, like, you know, a year later.
And our computers finish the job.
Raymond, you wanted
a man inside a machine.
And that's what you've got.
But the human element
will always be present.
Fear, instinct, bias, compassion,
they will always interfere with
- the system!
- Okay, but, Dennett...
I've gotta give...
the American people
something they can root for.
Something aspirational, right?
They have to believe in this thing.
"Pretty good"? That's not...
I don't know how to sell "okay."
We, you and I, have got a release date,
and we've gotta make it, okay?
So I don't care how you do it.
I'm askin' ya, come on, can you help me?
Just get him to do that.
- Get him to do that.
- That is a machine.
I know, but it's a man inside a machine.
No, that's a man
inside a machine right there!
And his life depends on it.
And the future of OmniCorp depends on it
so get your ass back
to China and get it fixed.
I don't care how you do it, just go do it!
It tastes like peanut butter.
I can't get it out of my mouth.
And
you don't like peanut butter?
No.
You like peanut butter, Kim?
I love it.
Okay.
I'm gonna put you to sleep now, Alex.
Now, put him under, Kim.
What are you planning to do?
Consciousness is nothing more
than the processing of information.
I'm gonna fix him.
And he won't know the difference.
- Raymond?
- Yeah?
We just ran focus groups
at Ryan Correctional Facility.
We call this Combat Mode.
It really put the fear of God
into the prisoners.
Yeah, that's okay.
And get a load of this.
- What's that?
- He transforms. Kids love it.
- Really?
- Focus group numbers through the roof.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, that's really embarrassing.
What is this? You know what?
People really don't know what they want
until you show it to 'em most of the time.
Make him more, uh...
tactical.
Make him look, uh...
Let's go with black.
Yeah.
Alex.
He looks like a billion dollars.
2.6 billion.
Raymond Sellars.
I've looked forward
to meeting you, Detective.
I really appreciate
everything you've done for me.
Well, we funded this program
to give men like you a second chance.
You just do your best today.
- Shall we?
- Let's.
- Mr. Sellars, we're ready for you.
- Okay, great.
Chief Technician Shuman.
Morning, folks.
Okay,
so this is how it's gonna be.
We're goin' toe-to-toe.
Last man standing wins.
I hit you, you go
back to the drawing board.
You hit me, you get a ticket back home.
My guys are gonna be shootin'
.47 caliber rounds.
Do a little damage,
but they can't take you out.
But make no mistake, Tin Man,
my gun will.
Alex, listen to me.
The EM-208s will try to maneuver you
so Mattox can get a clear shot.
Do not let that happen.
If Mattox hits you,
everything but your life support
will shut down.
You'll feel more pain
than you've ever felt in your life.
I don't know about that.
I've been through a lot.
All right.
I say we go on three.
Three.
How's it going down there?
Whatever you do,
don't get shot in the face.
Wow.
Dr. Norton,
how, how is he doing this?
His software is faster.
His hardware is stronger.
He's a better machine.
But you said humans hesitate.
Only when they're making decisions.
He's not making decisions?
Yes and no.
In his everyday life,
man rules over the machine.
Alex makes his own decisions.
Now, when he engages in battle,
the visor comes down
and the software takes over.
Then the machine does everything.
Alex is, he's a passenger,
just along for the ride.
But if the machine is in control,
then how is Murphy accountable?
Who's pulling the trigger?
Well, when the machine fights,
the system releases
signals into Alex's brain
making him think he's doing
what our computers are actually doing.
I mean, Alex believes
right now he is in control.
But he's not.
It's the illusion of free will.
Crap!
So you've circumvented the law
by creating a machine
that thinks it's a man.
But that's illegal.
No. No, no, no.
It's a machine
that thinks it's Alex Murphy.
And in my book...
that's legal.
Well done.
Hey, Doctor, what happens
if I tase an exoskeleton
with a little asshole inside?
I, uh, I think we're
all curious to find out.
Go ahead.
If I had a pulse, it'd be racing.
She's been waiting four months.
I'm sure hers is, too.
You're gonna do fine.
I love your sign, D.
Hey.
There's nothin' to be nervous about.
Thank you, Dennett.
It's been a privilege.
Hi, Dad.
You know I missed you, buddy.
Me, too.
Wanna feel it?
What is it?
It's okay, sweetie.
I saved all the Red Wings games
on my computer.
You did?
- How'd they do?
- I don't know.
I've been waiting to watch them with you.
You know I'd love to, kiddo.
But I can't tonight.
You know, 'cause
Daddy's suit needs some...
Some special handling.
Do you understand?
Thanks for coming, Jack.
I heard you went home already.
I know Ciara must be
thrilled to have you back.
I saw Ciara...
and David.
That ain't my home right now.
It's in a damn lab across the hall.
I'm sorry, Alex.
Startin' tomorrow,
I'm gonna take down
Vallon and his whole damn crew.
I was waitin' to hear you say that.
Least I know you're the right color now.
Pat, the cooler
temperatures here today
certainly have not stopped
people from showing up.
We're expecting people
from every corner of the city
here in Detroit
to come out and show their support
for Detective Alex Murphy.
You know, a lot of questions
on people's minds today
is what will he look like.
Is he a changed man?
Rumor has it he is in the building
preparing to come out...
Alex, we're gonna upload
the entire DPD database into your brain.
That means you'll have
instantaneous access to criminal records
plus an archive of CCTV footage
from 2011 to the present.
All right.
Hit me.
Okay. Kim, it's all yours.
Archive footage
uploading successfully.
Your system draws
connections automatically.
It will link perpetrators to their crimes
and give you their exact locations
whenever available.
I got evidence to make 138... No, no.
166 arrests.
His emotions are stable.
This is incredible.
You will notice his family
is here in the building as well.
The mayor is standing on stage behind me.
Also, Raymond Sellars from OmniCorp.
They seem like great friends
obviously echoing
the partnership that they've
brought together.
How much longer will this take?
Well, the feed
from the database is almost done, so.
We're approaching present day.
634 pending arrests.
We're gonna need a bigger prison.
He's on top of her.
Dr. Norton,
he's getting too emotional.
- I gotta do something!
- Alex.
Alex, calm down.
Take a breath.
Relax.
Kim, what are the readings?
I haven't seen him at levels like this.
- He's gonna shoot 'em!
- Alex!
Alex, Alex, relax.
Relax.
Alex?
- What is this?
- This just a computer glitch?
No. That's his own crime scene.
- Alex!
- He's spiking all over the place.
Alex!
- Alex?
- The system is crashing, Doctor.
Alex, can you hear me?
Alex! Alex!
- I'm not sure he can handle this.
- I gotta do something!
He's emotionally overloaded.
Unlock me!
Alex! Stop!
Stop! He's having a seizure!
Kim, shut him down! Alex!
Get me a live feed!
I can't do it.
- Dr. Norton's with the patient.
- Do it now!
Jesus Christ!
Dr. Norton! Dr. Norton!
- What?
- The press is waiting!
We have to get him up there now!
What do you want me to do?
I don't know! Fix him!
Do what you have to do!
Your reputation is on the line
every bit as much as ours.
We're running out of time.
Okay.
Everybody out!
Out!
Mayor Durant is about to take to the stage
and introduce Detroit's
newest weapon in the war on crime.
I'm actually getting word
that he's ready to go right now.
Heart rate rising.
He might start spiking, Doctor.
Set modules to absorb
dopamine and noradrenalin.
But you'll be taking away his emotions.
Drop the levels until I tell you to stop.
Doctor, you'll be taking away
- his ability to feel anything.
- Now, please!
Pull the footage. Put it on a loop.
- Dopamine level's at 20 percent.
- More.
- Dopamine level's at 10 percent.
- Dopamine level's at five percent.
- Lower.
- You're flattening him out.
- Lower!
- Two percent.
- Hold it there.
Alex?
Alex, how do you feel?
I feel fine, Dr. Norton.
Well, today I'm not here
to talk about crime prevention.
I am here to give you the cure.
That's right!
Hi, Dad!
Dad?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the revolution begins right now
with Detective Alex Murphy!
Detective.
- What's he doing?
- He looks like a zombie.
I think he's accessing criminal data.
Thomas King! You are under arrest!
Until today, Thomas King was
a convicted felon
wanted for rape, arson, and murder.
This man has torn apart American families.
On the loose for six years.
And where was this
criminal mastermind hiding?
Right in front of the police headquarters.
Here he is, just steps
away from two of Detroit's finest.
These two officers are completely unaware
of the monster in their midst.
And then, in 60 seconds...
I repeat, just 60 seconds,
Detective Murphy brings him down.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be provided for you.
This, my friends,
is the future of American justice.
How many like Thomas King
will pay for their crimes
now that RoboCop is here?
Yes,
let's not shy away
from what this means, people.
Men weren't up to the task.
But Alex Murphy,
a robot cop,
was.
We can't take him off the street.
This is what I'm saying. He's a hit.
A big, fat, stinking hit.
Yeah, until he breaks down
in front of everyone.
Hey, we all knew there would be issues.
It's inevitable.
Dennett, you're my guy.
I just need you to get a handle on this.
I know, but I need more time.
Scientifically, we're in uncharted water.
We need to take him back
to the lab and do more tests.
I mean, it was like something
was interfering with our system.
Something beyond chemistry or physics.
Like what? His soul?
Hey, look, this train
has already left the station.
I can't exactly go
out to the world and say,
"Sorry, I released a defective product."
So, no matter what we do,
we just need to keep him on the streets.
What about the interviews?
Cancel 'em. Cancel all of 'em.
Everything.
In fact, Dennett.
Let's, uh...
Let's keep the wife
at a distance for now, as well.
I'd like to see him.
Can you arrange that?
Look, I won't lie to you.
Alex was so nervous, we had to sedate him.
I looked in his eyes
and I couldn't see my husband.
And then he just shoots a man
in front of our son.
That's not sedation.
He's responding to drugs differently now.
We both knew from day one...
there would be complications.
Just give me a little more time.
I promise...
you'll have your husband back.
This goes for every squad
in every department.
Detective Murphy will have
full access to all investigations.
Robberies, narcotics, homicides.
If he requests to take over a case,
the case will be handed to him.
No arguments, no complaints.
This is bullshit!
I said no complaints!
And I mean it. Now...
Good morning, Chief Dean.
Good morning, officers.
I've selected 13 targets for today,
all wanted for murder.
John Biggs is target number one.
I'll be taking over this case.
Ambulances,
detention vehicles, and coroners
should be ready to move in on my request.
I wish you all a very good day.
Murphy.
You okay, man?
I'm fine, Sergeant.
Can't wait to get back to work.
Lake and Daniels are in there
shittin' their pants...
Excuse me, I have casework.
That's him!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Walter Karrel, look at me.
You have two options.
Option one.
I shoot you with 50,000 volts
which may cause respiratory failure,
organ malfunction,
internal burns, and loss
of bowel and bladder control.
And then I arrest you.
Option two. You tell me where
John Biggs' drug lab is located.
And then I arrest you.
You have two seconds to decide.
Totally justifiable.
We are going to make a lot of money.
Nothing. No fear.
No increase in heart rate.
No traces of anger whatsoever.
Congratulations, Doctor.
You did it.
Yes, I did.
I told you, sir.
Norton clearly never
had control of the product.
I agree.
And that's why I called you here.
I just want a second pair of eyes
on this thing, that's all.
Okay.
I'll need a feed from the Tin Man's head
plus full surveillance of the lab, and...
You're gonna have
full access to everything.
If anything comes up...
I'm gonna be in Washington.
He brought peace
to this country's most violent city.
He showed us all
that Detroit and America
can have a brighter future.
A future of economic growth,
freedom, and happiness.
On tonight's show,
a visionary and true patriot.
The CEO of OmniCorp, Raymond Sellars.
- Hello, Pat.
- Raymond.
Thanks for havin' me.
You must be doing a victory lap about now.
Well...
Two weeks ago,
Omni's stock went through the roof.
And the Senate has finally agreed
to vote on the repeal of the Dreyfus Act.
Well, look, I mean,
the tide is definitely turning.
I just feel certain that
soon we'll be keeping all Americans safe.
I certainly hope so.
But, I think
our next guest will
have a different point of view.
Mmm-hmm.
Hubert Dreyfus.
Senator, thank you for joining us.
Hello, Pat. Mr. Sellars.
Senator, do you know what this is?
The American public is divided
on the Dreyfus Act.
Our polls at Novakelement.com
are tight at 50-50.
There is no doubt
OmniCorp created a sensation
but this bill is not about Alex Murphy.
It's about whether
America's willing to give robots
- the authority over human lives.
- No. Look, look, look.
This sea change we're witnessing,
and it is a sea change,
shows that Americans don't really care
if our law enforcement systems
are manned or unmanned.
What they care about is efficiency
and they care about safety.
You're clouding the issue.
This is clearly an attempt
to sway public opinion
- with a marketing stunt.
- No. What's clear is
that with just one system in place,
we've cut crime by 80 percent.
Just imagine if we put,
I don't know,
let's say 100 systems in place.
And then, I want you to ask yourself,
why are you holding us back?
- Is that your plan?
- Thank you, Senator.
- And thank you, Raymond.
- Thank you, Pat.
Well, there you have it.
Who could argue with that?
Which begs the question.
Has the US Senate become pro-crime?
Yeah, hi.
No, no, 5000.
Call me tomorrow.
Hey, guys.
Vallon's waitin' for you inside.
What, you too busy to walk us in?
- I'm out here makin' money.
- Yeah, yeah, I know.
Where are my trip wires?
I gotta do this myself?
- What took you so long?
- What the hell is all this shit?
I can't move any product
with this thing on the street.
What are you doing to protect me?
Relax. The guy's a walkin' zombie.
And tell me your phones are off.
He's not going after you.
We covered our tracks.
He can't manufacture
evidence out of thin air.
If he does, I'm ready for him.
Well?
I've been getting calls.
From whom?
Well, Ciara.
You need to let her see her husband.
She has rights.
That's not your decision.
That's Legal's call.
Yeah, but it's only a question of time
before she turns up on television.
Well, she can try.
I'll issue a gag order
before I let her see her husband.
I'd hop to it.
Alex. Alex!
Alex, you need to come home.
Ciara, please stand aside.
You need to speak to your son.
Right now, I see three crimes in progress.
Alex, listen to me.
I know you're in there.
David won't show his face at school.
He's having nightmares.
He's falling apart. I am falling apart.
Please.
I can't do this on my own.
He's been scared ever since that night.
What do you think she's gonna do?
What's he gonna do?
Are you okay?
David? David.
Stand back. Come on, stand back!
He's supposed to be watching this.
Instead, he's accessing
images of Ciara and David
arriving at school.
Over and over again.
Somehow, he's overriding
the system's priorities.
- Do you want me to shut him down?
- No.
Not yet.
I wanna see what happens.
What's he doing at his house?
Look, he's disobeying protocol.
You have to shut him down.
As far as I can tell,
he's still doing his job.
Adrian, give me an image of his brain.
He's undoing what we did to him.
His dopamine levels
are coming back to normal.
How is that even possible?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Alex.
Alex, please return to the station.
I wanna run some tests.
Well, this should be interesting.
And your phone on the table!
We're not cops, all right?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
- Whoa!
- What'd you say?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
My hand, man!
- Where's Antoine Vallon?
- You broke my hand, man!
I know you remember me, Jerry.
Where's Vallon?
Wait, man.
If I tell you where Vallon is,
he'll kill my wife and kid, man.
Your wife left you in 2019
after filing charges for domestic abuse.
And you don't have a kid.
But I do.
I'm not askin' again!
Look, I swear, man.
I don't know where Vallon is, okay?
The only guy I talk to
is his driver Marcus.
That's it, man. That's it!
Does he have a phone number?
We have a problem.
Alex is breaking protocol.
What's he doing?
He's off solving his own murder.
Oh, that is genius.
Why didn't I think of that?
How long till he gets here?
- Five minutes.
- All right.
Johnny, you stay on these monitors.
What happened?
Some idiot used an unencrypted phone.
Shit.
All right, everyone, listen up!
He's coming.
He leaves alive, you don't.
How do we stop him?
.50 caliber and above. Aim for the head.
This one's set.
Let's go. Go!
All right, move! Let's go!
Come on. Come on!
Ready to go!
They're all set.
Finish it!
Freak, die!
Watch out.
Need me to call a doctor?
Come on, Jack. You're gonna like this.
What's going on?
What the hell you doin' here?
Y'all gonna play good cop, bad cop?
Nah, Daniels. Bad cop, RoboCop.
I've recovered 26 guns
from Vallon's warehouse.
13 serial numbers
match weapons missing from Evidence.
And I got your prints all over 'em.
This is bullshit.
I also have
CCTV footage of you and Vallon
the same day he tried to kill me.
So put him on the payroll.
Why we talkin' about this?
It won't work.
Now that his partner got hit,
he's never gonna let it go.
- What is that?
- Lewis' hospital.
Murphy's dropping by this afternoon.
I kill a cop,
I'm lookin' over my shoulder...
You know what
they do to cops in prison, man?
Being locked up with
the same dudes you put in there?
How long you think before he gives you up?
Don't shoot me. Okay?
I swear to Christ. It was Dean.
She helped pull those guns.
Just don't shoot me.
Thank you for your cooperation.
You can cuff him now, Jack.
Now I know why we couldn't get an arrest.
'Cause Vallon was
protected from up on high.
Alex, I can explain.
You tipped him off today.
- Come on, man. Don't do this.
- You tried to kill me twice.
I trusted you.
And you destroyed my family.
Confess.
Now, in front of everyone.
Confess!
What happened?
Tin Man is down. Had to be done.
Why?
Product shot a corrupt cop.
Two more seconds, the chief's brains
would've been splattered
across the 6:00 news.
We got anything on her?
Well, she's the Chief of
the Detroit Police Department.
What do you think?
You know what?
This might actually tip
this thing right into the net.
Alex,
I don't know if you can hear me.
But tonight,
you uncovered a nest of vipers
inside the Detroit Police Department.
And in so doing,
you shed light on an invaluable truth.
Even the police,
the men and women
who swore to keep us safe,
they can be bribed.
They can be bought.
Machines, however, are corruption-free.
Americans could be living in a country
where law enforcement
is not only efficient,
but incorruptible.
Thank you, Alex, for all you've done.
And for all that you are.
Detective Murphy is
currently in critical condition.
Our doctors are working ceaselessly
but, at this time,
it is unclear if he will survive.
Ms. Kline,
how do you think the attempt
on Detective Alex Murphy's life
will affect tomorrow's vote
for the Dreyfus Act?
At this time,
OmniCorp's sole concern
is the full recovery of Detective Murphy.
How many times does Detective Murphy
have to give his life for his country?
I sincerely hope...
the Senate makes the right vote tomorrow
so that Alex Murphy's sacrifices
will not have been in vain.
Senator Dreyfus is my friend.
He has been my mentor and my strength
in times of difficulty on this floor.
But despite all that,
I work for the state of Ohio,
and the safety of
its citizens is my top priority.
So I vote yes.
The Dreyfus Act must be repealed.
That's us ahead, 39 to 10.
Yeah, I spoke to the Senate liaison
and it looks like it's in the bag,
but we still have to tread
carefully with the politicians.
We're here live
at DPD headquarters
where moments ago, Ciara Murphy
- made a shocking statement.
- What the hell?
OmniCorp has denied me and my son
access to Alex for weeks.
I demand to know why.
This treatment is inhuman and somebody
needs to be held accountable.
Oh, we're fucked.
No, we only need 12 votes.
She shouldn't make much difference.
Yeah,
but what about after the vote?
I mean, those two
should not be allowed contact.
If she starts putting ideas in his head...
Bring her in. I'll handle the explanation.
And what about Alex?
You know, unfortunately,
we can't just keep him on ice.
The shooting at the station
spooked some of the politicians.
They're our clients.
We have to take care of them.
They're fine when a machine
is lowering the murder rate,
but when a man is investigating
city politics, they get nervous.
All right. First off,
it's not a man, okay?
It's property of OmniCorp.
And politics are
the least of your concern.
I mean, this thing solved its own murder.
How long till it realizes
you haven't been on the level with it?
If that happens,
every journalist in this country
is dying to speak to him.
I mean, we created a hero.
What happens when he opens his mouth?
What's bigger than a hero?
Dead hero.
Get me Dr. Norton.
What is this, Raymond?
You have Mattox spying on me and now this
bullshit about a "critical condition"?
You know and I know Alex is fine!
Calm down.
Dennett.
Your work is so good, I don't...
Well, now, this is not about my work!
You saw the woman on TV!
This has to stop!
You're right.
But let me ask you something, Dennett.
What kind of life have
we really given Alex Murphy?
He's never gonna be a normal man,
a father, a husband.
By the time we put the other units
on the street, he's just...
Dennett.
Let's face it.
We failed him.
We failed Alex Murphy.
But I want you to think
about the bigger picture
'cause that's what we're talking about.
The work you've done with him
is gonna be studied for decades.
You've changed
the face of history, Dennett.
No policeman is ever going to die
in the line of duty again
'cause of you.
You think about that.
I want that family taken care of
beyond their wildest dreams.
- We owe them that.
- I agree.
I want full funding. 10 years.
New staff, all my own people.
Fantastic.
Deal.
Hey. What's going on?
Security's here.
They're clearing everyone out.
They're not waking him up.
Whatever you do, don't leave him alone.
What do you mean
they're not waking him up?
The voting period has ended.
The clerks have tabulated the results.
The yeas are 63.
The nays are 22.
A majority of senators
have voted in the affirmative.
The Dreyfus Act has
been repealed by Congress.
God, you guys are slow,
like a bunch of girls.
This is Mattox.
Dennett's on board.
It's about time.
Call it.
Get it done.
My pleasure.
- Mrs. Murphy...
- You can come here as much as you want.
You can threaten me.
You can sue me. You can take my home,
but I am not gonna stop till I see
my husband. Do you understand that?
Mr. Sellars would
very much like to see you.
Is Alex okay?
He has important information to share
with you. Will you accompany me?
David.
We gotta go. Can you grab your coat?
Hey!
I'm in the elevator, on my way down.
I need access to the lab.
That's insane. They're still here.
Distract them.
Okay.
I cannot...
There's a lady in here going hysterical.
She will not let us in.
She's got the codes for the door.
I repeat, she will not let us in.
Lady, you need to let us in there now.
We have to get in there.
Are you not understanding what I'm saying?
Do you wanna be responsible for
the deaths of everyone in this building?
Hey! Stop!
Don't shoot!
Step outside.
Unlock the transmitter!
Transmitter unlocked!
Send in Mrs. Murphy, please.
Right away, sir.
Wake him up!
Alex! Alex!
Alex, it's Dr. Norton,
you have to wake up!
Alex, can you hear me?
These men are here to kill us!
They're here to kill us, for Christ sakes!
Mrs. Murphy, last night,
Alex had a psychotic break.
He killed an unarmed colleague
and later suffered a seizure.
We did everything,
everything we could,
but the doctors couldn't save him.
Very sorry, Mrs. Murphy.
We're going to be
making the announcement shortly.
You shut me down.
I was about to get a confession.
Mattox shut you down.
I've removed your transmitter
so he won't do it again.
Sellars can't afford to wake you up.
He sent these guys to pull the plug.
He wants you dead,
Alex. Do you understand?
Sorry.
If there's anything we can do
for you and David, we'll do it.
I want nothing from you.
I understand.
You stay out of our lives.
You and your company.
If that's what you think is best.
There's one more thing.
I think it would be to the benefit
of everyone, especially David,
if we kept this matter private.
We don't wanna damage Alex's legacy.
Alex! Alex!
I can fix this!
You lied to me.
You lied to my wife.
You're working for
the people that are trying to kill me.
- You want me to trust you, Doctor?
- Alex, I can go to the press!
Alex, I can tell them the whole story!
Alex!
Listen to me, please!
Alex! Alex!
What the hell?
Keep all our systems at green light,
and for Christ sakes,
get Sellars on the phone.
Roger that.
Damn, damn, damn, damn, damn!
Look at this city.
So beautiful.
It's become so peaceful.
I wish...
I had some good news for Detroit.
I have very sad news.
Despite our best efforts to save him,
Alex Murphy passed away just hours ago.
Alex Murphy...
Mr. Sellars.
- What is it?
- Mattox just called.
We need you to come with us now.
Ma'am, I need you to turn around
and go the other way, please.
- What are you talking about?
- We have a security situation here.
I need you to turn around
and go the other way.
Sir, there's a car outside...
That area is locked down. Now go.
- What's happening?
- I said go!
I wanna talk to Mr. Sellars.
Mr. Sellars.
How close is that helicopter?
About 10 minutes, sir.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
I need to speak with Sergeant Jack Lewis.
It's an emergency.
Stand by. Mr. Sellars.
Apparently there's
a Ciara Murphy in the lobby.
Raymond, if she sees him,
we are dead in the water.
What do you wanna do?
Bring Mrs. Murphy up here.
Yes, sir.
Norton said they may be
using drones for protection.
So whatever you do,
do not draw your weapons.
They won't shoot if we're unarmed. Clear?
Clear.
Hold it right there.
Don't move.
This is private property.
You are not authorized to be here!
I'd put those guns down now if I were you.
- Stand down.
- All right, man, we're good, we're good.
Go, back it up!
Head to the lower level.
Hold up, hold up!
Ram it!
Gun it.
Go, go, go! Now!
Alex, run!
OmniCorp Security!
Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapon.
Keep your hands above your head
and no one will be harmed.
What's going on?
Mrs. Murphy,
I want you to listen to me carefully.
The organic part of
your husband Alex is dead.
The robotic part of him is malfunctioning,
and he's shooting up the building.
So we've gotta get you and your son
out of here right away.
I gotta take this call.
He just left the lobby
and he's headed our way.
Roger that, sir.
Don't shoot. My robot.
- You just flank.
- Got it.
Tin Man.
Oh, there it is.
You look like crap.
What's the matter?
Can't shoot?
Huh?
What were you thinking?
This isn't a drill.
You're a robot.
I'm a red asset. Wrote that myself.
What do you think?
Come on, Tin Man, just pull the trigger.
Pull it.
You can run.
Go on.
Run.
Run!
There you go. Run.
Run. Run!
Whoo!
Stings like a bitch, don't it?
Aren't you lucky I didn't
have my gun set to "kill"?
Hey, listen.
This isn't personal.
Well, maybe a little.
I'm gonna put you out of your misery.
Helicopter's approaching.
Mr. Sellars boards first.
No, no, no. Mrs. Murphy,
you and your son can get on first.
Officer down.
Mechanical room.
OmniCorp Building.
Roger that. EMS on the way.
You're gonna be okay, Jack.
It's nonfatal.
Go. Go.
Omni-LZ Helo-1
on approach to deck.
What's that?
- He's got a gun!
- What?
Pull up! Pull up!
- What the hell is he doing?
- Sorry, sir. I don't know.
Alex?
Dad?
Ciara, David.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait.
- Get out of the way.
- Alex, put down the gun.
Ciara, take David
and get out of the way now!
Raymond Sellars, you're under arrest
for the attempted murder
of a police officer.
Oh, you're here to cuff me? All right.
Go ahead, cuff me.
You can't. You're not programmed that way.
If you go against the program,
the entire system shuts down, so.
You don't even have a warrant.
We'll overlook this little...
Get down on the ground and
put your hands behind your back.
- I'm just from marketing.
- Now!
Okay, yep, yep, yep. Yep.
Alex, we need to work together here.
Because I'm the only one with
the technology to keep you alive.
Dead or alive, you're coming with me.
All right.
Weapon.
Alex, honestly, I mean you no harm.
If I wanted to, I could
have killed you a long time ago.
I just aim this right at
your head and blow it off.
Sellars, please! Don't!
I mean, if I wanted to, I could
just aim this at your little family...
and I could just kill them too.
And really, there's
nothing you could do about it
because, let's face it,
you're a robot.
Do you understand that?
Alex.
Dad!
Baby.
Hey.
Everything's gonna be all right.
How are you feeling, Alex?
I'm ready.
He's ready.
There's still no word
from OmniCorp parent company, OCP.
And although the government
says they are rebuilding Alex Murphy,
rumors continue to
swirl about his condition.
But we have obtained
exclusive video taken by cell phone
that shows the people of Detroit
may have Alex Murphy back on the streets
sooner than they think.
The real tragedy here
is that our president
chose to uphold the Dreyfus Act.
Now, I have no doubt he was
manipulated by our biased media
and by whistle-blower Dennett Norton.
I acknowledge
we know less than we thought.
But I do believe
my research program is sound.
What I did with it...
was wrong.
The fact that this mother
is not serving time in
some federal penitentiary
is a huge, hot,
heaping pile of horse.
Now I know some of you may think
that this kind of thinking is dangerous
and these machines
violate your civil liberties.
Some of you even believe
that the use of these drones overseas
makes us the same
kind of bullying imperialists
that our forefathers
were trying to escape.
To you, I say...
stop whining!
America is now
and always will be
the greatest country
on the face of the Earth!
I'm Pat Novak.
Good night.