Navid!
Get away from the window!
Mom! They're here! They're coming!
Come here! Come here right now!
Arash!
Navid! You stay with your mom and sisters!
But he's just a kid.
Seven!
Stay here with your mom and the kids!
What do you think you're doing?
You heard me!
Arash, please don't go! Don't do this!
Navid! My dear! Come back here!
Navid!
Shut the door!
We're not here to kill any of them.
Got it?
The goal is to die on television.
Let's go!
Don't make a move before I say...
I wanna make sure they're recording.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
We're ready.
Navid! It's dangerous here!
Come away! Come...
Navid, where are you going?
Look at me! Navid! Navid!
What are you looking for? Navid!
Navid! Navid! What are you...
Navid! Don't go! Navid!