What if I told you that even the worst
neighborhood in America
could be made completely safe.
What if I told you that
this can be accomplished
without risking the life of one
single law enforcement officer.
How do I know this? Because
this is happening now.
In every country in
the world but this one
I'm Pat Novak, and
welcome to Novak Element.
In tonight's State of the Union segment,
we'll be joined by
General, "Curtis Monroe"
live from the war room at the Pentagon.
General "Monroe", Welcome back.
Good to see you, "Pat".
Thank you for this unprecedented
access to your operations.
Can you walk us through
what we're seeing here.
This is a routine
operation, We found that
random patrols help
the local population.
Feel safer, and to trust us.
It's amazing.
And, what are these colored dots
that we're seeing here general?
These are our assets on the ground.
In green we got the "ED209s"
They're the big boys.
They secure the perimeter.
Purple are the smaller "EM
208s" They sweep and mop up.
And the red dots Pat
that's your film crew.
It's great to see
American machines helping
to promote peace and freedom abroad.
This is standard Op alright,
there is no opposition expected.
I'm gonna set your markers to code red.
All our drones are going to
give top priority to your safety.
No red assets have ever been lost.
OK
Does this make you feel better?
But listen, keep those
bracelets on you completely safe.
Okay? Good.
Enjoy the show!
Alright, let's go.
(Robotic voice) May peace be upon you.
Please exit your homes
with your arms raised.
For a non-evasive scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Please exit your homes
with your arms raised.
For a non-evasive scanning procedure.
Scott, get me a shot of this.
Incredible. Incredible!
Not long ago that
would have been American
men and women risking their lives.
To pacify these people.
General, care to comment on this?
Well, Pat, We had Vietnam, we
had Iraq we had Afghanistan,
Never again. From a military
perspective this has been invaluable.
We can accomplish our objectives
without any loss to American lives.
And I think the honest people
over there really appreciate it.
Why wouldn't they?
For the first time in their lives, they
get to watch their children grow up.
In an environment of
safety and security.
Let's go
Kelly, can you hear me out there?
Loud and clear Pat.
I'm here in Sunny Tehran.
Where locals have clearly
embraced these routine scans.
As you can see behind me, they are
working in collaboration with the robots.
And obviously their safety
is everyone's top priority.
You'll notice children in the streets
as well, this is every day life.
Happening in perfect harmony.
Oh great, here here, stay put, stay put.
It's fine don't worry my guys got it.
Drop your weapon.
"Kelly, Kelly," Are you alright?
"Kelly."
We're okay, Pat.
I'm sorry Kelly but
for security reasons the Pentagon
is going to cut our feed to Tehran.
But Please be careful.
Yeah, I'll continue to stand by.
Now you see how fundamental these
robots are to our foreign policy.
So then tell me, why can't we
use these machines here at home?
Why is America so robophobic?
On the one hand, we
have Raymond Sellers.
An entrepreneur,
And true American, who's product
just saved my colleague's life.
On the other, "Hubert Dreyfuss".
A man with both feet
planted firmly in the past
who's bill prohibits the
use of drones on US soil.
The American people
support the Dreyfuss act.
Because they haven't
experienced this technology.
And they fear what
they don't understand.
We at the Novak Element
support Mr. Seller's
to make our country
and our viewers safer.
After all, what's more important then
the safety of the American people?
Hey "Murphy".
Hey.
How is Jack?
We don't know yet.
How's it going?
Good.
What the hell are they doing here?
Six in the morgue, Louis in hospital.
This was the mother of all bad ideas.
We got a lead on Anton
Vallon, we took it.
What lead?
Not in front of them.
This is bullshit.
Yeah?
Yeah, you got something to say Murphy?
Vallon's our case.
You got two years without
no arrests, no nothin.
He's got to be dumb or dirty.
You got something on
us? Or is this personal?
No, it's nothin personal.
Although I don't like you as a person.
Okay, you two, out.
No problem.
Maybe if you hadn't
gone off the reservation
your partner would still be standing.
What did you say to me? That's enough!
Okay, "Alex".
It's just you and me now.
Me and jack, we've been
doing some street buys.
We get a line on some guns.
And we met with this low
level G called Jerry who
ends up having a peace
he's not suppose to have.
Where the hell you get
a gun like that, Jerry
I can get you two
whole crates full, man.
Two crates?
No disrespect Jay, but how a clown
like you get so much product, man?
What's it matter where it comes from?
It matters, we don't
want no dirty guns Jerry.
These guns got bodies on them Jerry?
They're clean alright. You
gonna buy this shit or not?
Why you acting so nervous man?
You fishin on us Jerry?
What'd you say?
You think he's fishin D'?
I think he's fishin on us.
What the hell are they talkin about man?
Let me see your phone,
let me see your phone
I'm not showing you my phone, man.
Are you recording this?
What?
I think you're a God Damn cop.
What the hell are you
talking about, man?
Lie down to the ground.
Put your gun down.
We're not cops alright,
we work for, "Anton Vallon".
Hey, Hey, Hey!
Shut up, shut up, what did you say?
Ends up he works for "Vallon".
Before the meeting we ran the
serial numbers on the rifles.
They were supposed to
be in our evidence room.
Not out on the street. The intake
papers were blank, no signatures.
What have you got?
Nothing.
How do you think that happened?
I tell you Murphy this is a mistake.
These guys will shoot you
just to see if they gun work.
We need backup.
We call for backup words going
to get around the station.
And he's going to disappear.
It's gonna be alright.
We told Vallon we were gun
buyers, and he bought it.
What do you two need
with that much product?
You plotting a coup?
Hey, don't trip. We ain't gonna
bust a single shot in your town.
We got some problems
back home with Chicago PD.
Yeah,
I heard you don't like cops.
Hey, boss.
What do you got for me?
Really.
Just about to close the deal.
Someone tipped him off.
Gentlemen I gotta deal with this.
Few minutes.
Make sure you kill them both.
I've got two handguns, one automatic.
You've gotta get out of here,
I'm going to take the automatic.
You sure of this?
You ready?
Move
Louis.
Officer down, officer down,
331 Hamilton.
This is detective Alex Murphy in
need of immediate medical assistance.
331 Hamilton Road.
"Jack."
"Jack," come on "Jack," Do you hear me?
"Jack," Stay with me.
"Jack."
"Alex," you don't do something like
this unless you bring it to me first.
Vallon's connected. I'm warning you don't
make any more moves until I vet this.
If officers are supplying them guns.
That's up to IAD.
I'll handle it.
Washington, DC
I don't care how sophisticated
these machines are Mr. Sellers.
A machine does not know what
it feels like to be human.
Can't understand the value of human life.
Why should it be aloud to take one?
To legislate over life and death, we need
people who understand right from wrong.
What do your machines feel?
Well, they feel no anger, the feel
no prejudice, they feel no fatigue.
Which makes them ideal
for law enforcement.
Putting these machines on the streets
will save countless American lives.
Your evading the question. No I'm not.
Yes, your evading the question. I
asked "What do these machines feel?"
If one of them, uh, killed a child.
What would it feel?
Nothing.
That's the problem.
That's why 72 percent of Americans will
not stand for a robot pulling the trigger.
America is the world's most valuable
market, and we can't touch it.
With a domestic expansion we'd
clear 600 billion dollars per annual.
In other words, every second that law is
in existence we're hemorrhaging money.
What do you want me to
do? We've thrown cash at
senators on both sides of
the isle. Nobody's budging.
They don't want to vote against their
constituents, so unless
we sway public opinion.
The battles lost. Now to that effect.
My team have come up with a
pretty aggressive new campaign.
Wow factor off the charts.
We need to give the Americans
a product they can love.
A figure they can rally behind.
Sir, I have dissected this bill.
There are no loop holes. We
can't put a machine on the street.
Forget the machine, you saw the polls.
Americans don't want a machine.
They want a product with a conscious.
They want.
Something that knows.
What it feels like to be human.
We're gonna put
a man inside the machine.
You're not you because of your
legs, your arms, your hands.
You're you because of your
brain. It's your brain's
capacity to process information
that makes you who you are.
Relax, and just do
what you've always done.
I've never played with these.
The music doesn't come from your fingers
Michael, it comes from your mind.
All you have to do is let it out.
Please.
Oh my God.
That's okay.
His emotions are peaking, the
readings are getting clouded.
It's okay.
Relax, if you get too
emotional, it'll change the
chemistry in your brain.
It'll throw the system out.
You're doing great. Come on.
I need emotion to play.
(Speaking french)
It's a beautiful piece,
Dennett can we have a moment?
Thank you.
We have agreed on this
a long time ago Raymond.
I, I, I wouldn't be asked to
develop combat application.
My work here is driven
by it's own question.
And your work is brilliant, but
your ideas are being underutilized.
Look, I think I found a way.
To put real revenue stream
behind your research,
and to save thousands
of lives in the process.
You're not keeping up your end,
making me exposed like that.
Detective Murphy's
just a little impulsive.
So, put him on the payroll,
Why are we talking about this?
It won't work. And now that his partner
got hit he's never going to let it go.
What is that?
Louis' hospital. Alex is
dropping by this afternoon.
In case you want to send flowers.
Yeah.
Kill a cop, look over my
shoulder the rest of my life.
It's not good for business.
Who do you thinks going
to be investigating you"?
I'm going to go hard after them, Dennis.
And have them in
bracelets within a month.
Hey, Vallon I'm locking up right now.
Camera's off?
Clear.
You were right, we should've had backup.
I'm sorry.
You're not really sleeping are you?
Asshole.
Sergeant, "Thomas Ryan," NYPD,
paralyzed from the waist down.
He has let himself go a little.
Since the accident.
Pass Yep, yeah,
fair enough.
The officer "Alfred Miller", Denver.
Severe...
Seri, cerebellerd..
Cerebellum ataxia.
That's why you're the Doctor, Doctor.
He scored through the
roof with our urban demos.
Lets keep this one in
mind, I like this guy.
Very good sir, I saved
the best for last.
I give you Sargent "Jack
Freeman" Masculinity incarnate.
Led Pittsburgh Swat for five years, now.
Confined to a wheel chair.
I think I can see the appeal.
No.
What? Why?
I checked the Psych evaluations.
He's far too unstable.
He's trying to say,
that he has a temper.
Have you any idea what
we'd be putting him through?
The psychological strain requires
someone emotionally balanced.
We have to be scientific.
We're not selling a
soft-drink here are we?
You're right, okay, Keep looking.
"David," What did I say?
Not until you're finished.
Hey guys.
Hi dad.
Hey little monkey.
How's the game buddy?
Dane got rejected, but we
have a two man advantage.
Oh yeah? That's fantastic.
Hey D, why don't you head upstairs,
start getting ready for bed?
But he just got home.
I'll be up in a second
to tuck you in okay?
Alright?
Now give your Mom a kiss.
Good night baby.
Too slow boy.
You're just too slow.
How is Jack holding up?
They said a week till
he's back on his feet.
It's my fault, we shouldn't
have even been there.
Here.
(Car alarm) Somebody's gotta fix that.
Stop.
Let's not wake up David.
He's suffering 4th degree burns
over 80 percent of his body.
Lower spine has been severed.
If he survives.
He'll be paralyzed from the waist
down, confined to a wheel chair.
Mrs. Murphy.
We don't have to do this.
I need to know everything
before I make a decision.
Please continue.
Consider the cochlear optic
nerves have been critically damaged.
He'll be blind in one eye.
And most likely deaf.
Frankly, Dr. Norton and the Omni
foundation are the leaders in this field.
In my opinion, this is the
only chance your husband has.
I'd seriously consider their offer.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I need time to think
I'm afraid Mrs. Murphy, time
is one thing you don't have.
You say you can save him,
but what does that mean?
What kind of life will he have?
Thanks.
Thanks buddy.
You know this is going
to make me dance again.
Now that I gotta see.
You don't wanna see that.
Here she comes now.
Hold on to that.
Good idea partner.
Every time.
Get er' boy!
Subject is still dreaming.
He's retrieving memories, trying to make
sense of sensory stimulation package 37.
Perfect Kim.
Let's reconnect the spine.
Time to wake him up.
Excuse me?
What are you doing here?
Babe, where are you going?
"Louis."
Subject regaining cognitive functions.
Whats happening?
Where am I?
You were in an explosion, Alex.
You're in a hospital.
Where?
Where's "Claire" My
wife? Where is my wife?
I want you to calm down Alex, listen to
me, you're okay. You're family's fine.
Both your wife and your son.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Dr. Dennett Norton
I'm treating you.
Heart rate rising.
I can't move.
I can't move. What the hell is all that?
Visual input, unstable.
I want you to relax.
Subject's dumping too much
epinephrine, should we purge him?
Not yet.
Unlock vertebrate.
Go ahead, Kim. Unlock
Upper, Lower extremities.
What kind of suit is this?
It's life.
Your suit "Alex".
It's You.
This was the only option, We're here,
all of us, to make you whole again.
Full body
I want you to walk, now Alex.
You can do that
seems so real
Alex it's very important you
understand what's happening.
This is real. It's not a dream,
it's not drugs, or anesthetics.
I know I'm dreaming, because
I can feel all of this.
Alex, Amputees can often
feel their missing appendages.
It's called Phantom Limb sensation.
What do you mean amputee?
What the hell did you do to me?
Alex you need to relax.
Take this off of me now.
Alex you need to relax
I need to get out of this
thing. What did you do to me?
What have you done to me?
Alex, HEY!
Shut him down!
No! Let him run, Let him run!
Where am I?
"Alex," Please.
Stop.
"Alex," you have to stop.
Please.
"Alex."
Please stop.
Stay where you are, and
we'll come and pick you up.
Okay, "Kim".
Shut him down.
"Alex."
You can't run from this.
You have to understand the
reality of the situation.
Show me.
"Kim."
No.
Holy Christ.
Holy Christ!
Holy Christ there's nothing left!
Your body may have gone,
but your still here.
That's not even my brain.
We had to repair the damaged areas.
But we didn't interfere with
your emotion, or your intellect.
You understand me, Alex.
You're, You're in control
I'm in control?
Yes.
Okay,
If I'm in control.
Then, I want to die.
Just unplug what ever it is keeping
me alive and end this nightmare!
Let's say I did that, which as a doctor
would be almost impossible for me.
But, say I did.
What do I say to your wife?
What does she say to your son?
That it didn't work.
That you tried, but
something went wrong.
You did everything you could but...
I died.
And so, after all they've
been through all the pain.
All their hope restored,
we just rip that away?
Your wife loves you Alex. She
singed the consent forms, herself.
Otherwise you couldn't have
undergone the procedure.
She loves you and she
gave you a second chance.
I need you to take it.
I don't want to see
myself like this again.
Ever.
The same goes for my family.
Put me back in.
Zoom in.
Stop.
Accept the connection.
It's so good to finally see you.
I was gonna have to say the same thing.
I'm sorry
I know how I must look to you.
I think you look beautiful.
Are they treating you okay, babe?
So far.
Dr. Norton seems like a nice guy.
Does David know you're calling?
He misses you. I can go get him, I just.
No
I don't want him to see me like this.
Not yet.
Sure.
We're going to get through this baby.
We're going to make it like it was.
When are you coming home?
We still got some tests.
But they are saying
it's going really well.
The minute they let me
I gotta go
I love you.
End the connection.
Okay, blood cleansing initiated.
Viral, and bacterial
screening activated.
Releasing proteins.
Fats, Minerals, and Carbs.
Energy in-flow is
at 1320 Kilo-Calories.
Now starting Anti-inflammatory corticoid,
hormones and antibiotic protocols.
Standard daily intake.
Who has Anti-depressants?
Let's give him a nice dream.
Alright, here's what
you're dealing with.
Modified M2 Battle Rifle.
50 caliber Beowulf
ammunition, and 30 round clips.
3 Shot burst or full auto.
Heavy Duty.
TSR-66 Cartridge driven taser pistol.
Each projectile releases
up to 200,000 volts.
It can stun, it can
kill, it's nasty shit.
Your armor. State of the
art but not invulnerable.
50 caliber or larger can
penetrate and kill, multiple
hits and guess who ends
up in the recycling bin.
If you sense you need a
weapon, or are threatened.
The visor goes down, and the
system makes the weapon available.
Gotta remember, it's not
the weapons that count.
It's who's handling them.
Or in your case .. What..
Do you think you can do this?
Just stick to your job.
Just stick to my job?
Combat robots are my job
doc. Rio, Congo, you name it.
I was there. Our machines run perfectly.
You ask me, sticking an organic in
the system is a huge step backwards.
I don't care how well you
design this thing, without
my sign off it better
start learning chinese.
Because it ain't never going home.
It's nice to meet you too.
Lets do this, Tin man.
Quality control EM208, Vs. Tin man..
Rendering Scenario one, now.
Hey, Doc. I hope you don't mind. I
like a little music while I'm working.
Alright, Alright, lets
uh, let the games begin.
Rock and roll.
Commence scenario.
Lag in the corners.
Did you see that? What my
robot did. That's how you do it.
Your products afraid.
2.3 seconds behind.
Great.
Drop your gun!
Drop your weapon let the kid go.
He's worried that the
kids going to get hurt.
Let the kid go!
Well, there you have it 5.6
seconds behind. Scenario failure.
I wouldn't buy that for a dollar.
Let's do it again.
It's your funeral.
Detective, "Alex Murphy".
Search results: Detective Alex
Murphy making a speedy recovery.
"Alex Murphy" Man or machine.
Thrust into the spotlight,
Clair Murphy won't talk.
"Anton Vallon."
Search Results: DPD says Anton
Vallon is no longer suspect.
Due to lack of evidence
Detroit free press.
Unfortunately Murphy's
investigation into
Anton Vallon wasn't
authorized in the first place.
Murphy was simply over zealous, Okay?
We have absolutely no evidence linking
Vallon to the attempt on his life.
All I'm gonna say is that my
partner's a great cop. And I won't
rest until the men who tried to
kill him are brought to justice.
What's wrong with him?
No, Nothing, Nothing.
Watch the procedure bar on the 20A.
Our machine assesses
the threat and acts.
That's it, two steps. Now watch Alex.
The software assesses the
threat just like robots.
And it sends the information to
the brain. Alex's brain receives.
The information and then
decides what to do with
it based on his emotional
and cognitive abilities.
Then the brain relates
this to the AI module.
And...
Yeah, like a year later.
Computers finish the job, a brain...
You wanted a man inside a machine!
That's what you've got, but the
human element will always be present.
Fear, instinct, bias, compassion. They
will always interfere with the system.
Okay, but Dennett
I've gotta give the
American people something
they can root for. Something
aspirational. Right?
They have to believe in
this thing. Pretty good,
that's not.
I don't know how to sell okay.
We, you and I, have got a release
date. We've gotta make it, okay"?
I don't care how you do it, I'm asking you.
Come on can you help me? Just get him -
to do that. Him to do that.
He's a machine
I know but it's a man
inside of a machine.
That's a man inside a machine.
His life depends on it, and the
future of Omnicorp depends on it.
So, get your ass back to
China and get it fixed.
I don't care how you
do it, just go do it.
Tastes like peanut butter
I can't get it out of my mouth.
You don't like peanut butter?
No.
You like peanut butter Kim?
I love it.
OK
I'm gonna put you to sleep now Alex.
Put him under, Kim.
What are you planning to do?
Consciousness is nothing more
then the processing of information.
I'm going to him.
He won't know the difference
Raymond.
Yeah.
We just ran focus groups at
Ryan Correctional facility.
We call this combat mode.
It really put the fear
of God into the prisoners.
Yeah, that's okay.
Get a load of this.
What is that?
He transforms. Kids love it.
Really?
Focus group numbers, through the roof.
That's really embarrassing.
What is this?
You know what,
People don't really know what they want
until you show it to them most of the time.
Make him more uh.. tactical
Make him look uhh...
Let's go with black.
Yeah.
"Alex."
He looks like a billion dollars.
$2.6 billion.
"Raymond Sells"
I've looked forward to
meeting you detective.
I really appreciate
everything you've done for me.
Well, We've found this program to
give men like you a second chance.
You just do your best today.
Shall we?
Alright.
Mr. Sellers We're ready for you.
Okay great.
This is a detective "Sherman".
Good morning folks.
Okay, so this is how it's gonna be.
We're going toe to toe.
The last man standing wins.
If I hit you, you go
back to the drawing board.
You hit me You get a ticket back home.
My guys are going to
be shooting.47 rounds.
Do a little damage, but
they can't take you out.
But make no mistake,
Tin Man. My gun will.
Alex, listen to me.
The EM208s will try to maneuver you.
So Mattox can get a clear shot.
Do not let that happen.
If Mattox hits you everything but
your life support will shut down.
You will feel more pain then
you've ever felt in your life.
I don't know about that
I've been through a lot.
Alright.
I say we go on Three.
Three.
How's it going down there?
Whatever you do, don't
get shot in the face.
Dr. Norton, how is he doing that?
His software is faster,
his hardware is stronger.
He is a better machine.
But you said that humans hesitate.
Only when there making decisions.
He's not making decisions?
Yes and no.
In his every day life
man rules over machine.
Alex makes his own decisions.
When he engages in battle
the visor comes down
and the software takes over and,
uh, the machine does everything.
Alex is a passenger,
just along for the ride.
But, if the machine is in control how is
Murphy accountable?
Who's pulling the trigger?
When the machine fights the system
releases signals into Alex's brain.
Making him think he's doing what
our computers are actually doing.
I mean, Alex believes
right now he is in control.
But, he's not. It's the
illusion of free will.
Crap.
You circumvented the law by creating
a machine that thinks it's a man.
- But that's illegal.
- No, no.
It is a machine that
think it's Alex Murphy.
And in my book - That's legal.
Well done.
Hey Doctor what happens if I tase an
exoskeleton with a little
asshole on the side?
I think We're all curious to find out.
Go ahead.
If I had a pulse, it would be racing.
She's been waiting for months.
I'm sure hers is too.
You're gonna do fine.
I love your sign D.
Hey.
There's nothin to be nervous about.
Thank you, Dennett.
It's been a privilege.
Hi, Dad.
I missed you, buddy. Me too.
Want to feel it?
What is it?
It's okay, sweety.
Saved all the redwings
games on my computer.
You did?
- How'd they do?
- I don't know.
I've been waiting to
watch them with you.
I'd love to kiddo.
But I can't tonight.
Daddy's suit needs some.
Special handling.
You understand?
Thanks for coming, Jack.
I heard you went home already.
Clara should be
thrilled to have you back.
I saw Clara.
And David.
That ain't my home right now.
It's in a damn lab across
the hall I'm sorry, Alex.
Starting tomorrow, I'm gonna take
down Vallon and his whole damn crew.
I was waiting to hear you say that.
At least I know you're
the right color now.
Cooler temperatures here today certainly
have not stopped people from showing up.
We're expecting people from every
corner of the city here in detroit.
To come out and show their
support for Detective Alex Murphy.
You know, a lot of questions on people's
minds today is "What will he look like?"
"Is he a changed man?" Rumor
has it he is in the building.
Preparing to come out.
Alex, We're going to upload the
entire DPD database into your brain.
That means you'll have instantaneous
access to criminal records.
Plus an archive of CCTV footage
from 2011 to the present.
Alright, Hit me.
Kim, it's all yours.
Archive footage uploading successfully.
You're system draws
connections automatically.
It will link perpetrators
to the crimes and
give you exact locations,
whenever available.
I have evidence to make 138
I don't know.
166 arrests.
His emotions are stable.
This is incredible.
You will notice his family is
here in the building as well.
The mayor is standing on stage
behind me, also Raymond Sellers,
from Omnicorp. They seem
like great friends. Obviously
echoing the partnership
they brought together.
How much longer will this take?
Well the
feed from the database is almost done.
We're approaching present day.
634 pending arrests.
We're gonna need a bigger prison.
He's on top of her..
Doctor Norton he's getting to emotional.
I've gotta do something.
Alex, calm down.
Take a breath. Relax.
Kim, what are the readings?
I haven't seen them at levels like this.
He's gonna shoot him! Alex, relax.
Relax.
Alex... What is it?
A computer glitch?
No that's his own crime scene.
He's spiking all over the place Alex!
Alex!
The system is crashing
Doctor. Alex, can you hear me?
Alex, Alex.
I'm not sure he can handle this.
Do something.
He's emotionally Overload! Unlock Me!
Stop it! Stop it! He's having a seizure.
Kim, shut it down. Alex!
Give me a live feed I
can't do it. Doctor Norton..
- Now!
- Jesus Christ!
Dr. Norton? What?
The press is waiting. We
have to get him up there now.
What do you want me to
do? I don't know, fix him.
Do what you have to do.
Your reputation is on the
line every bit as much as ours.
We're running out of time.
Okay.
Everybody out.
OUT!
Mayor Duran Is about
to take to the stage
and introduce Detroit's newest
weapon in the war on crime.
I'm actually getting word that
he's ready to go right now.
Heart rate rising, he
might start spiking Doctor.
To absorb dopamine and noradrenaline.
But you'll be taking away his emotions.
Drop the levels until I tell you to stop.
Doctor you'll be taking away
his ability to feel anything.
Now, please.
Hold the footage, put it on a loop.
- Dopamine levels 20 %.
- More.
- Dopamine levels 10 %.
- Dopamine levels 5 %
- Lower.
You're flatting him out. Lower!
2 %. Hold it there.
Alex?
Alex, how do you feel?
I feel fine, Dr. Norton.
Today, I'm not here to
talk about crime prevention.
I am here to give you the cure.
Hi, Dad.
Dad?
NO DANGER
Ladies and gentlemen, the
revolution begins right now,
with Detective Alex Murphy.
What's he doing?
He looks like a Zombie.
I think he accessing Criminal data.
Thomas King! You're under arrest.
Until today, Thomas King
was a convicted felon
wanted for rape, arson, and murder.
This man has torn
apart American families.
On the loose for 6 years.
And where was this
criminal mastermind hiding?
Right in front of the
police headquarters.
Here he is just steps away
from two of Detroit's finest.
These two officers
are completely unaware
of the monster in their midst.
And then, in 60 seconds..
I repeat, just 60 seconds.
Detective Murphy brings him down.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you can not afford an attorney.
One will be provided for you.
This, my friends, is the
future of American justice.
How many like Thomas King
will pay for their crimes now
that RoboCop is here.
Yes!
Let's not shy away from
what this means people.
Men weren't up to the task.
But Alex Murphy, a robot cop was.
We can't take him off the
street. This is what I'm saying.
He's a hit. A big fat stinking hit.
Until he breaks down
in front of everyone.
Hey we all knew
there would be issues.
It was inevitable. Dennett You're my guy.
I just need you to get a handle on this.
I need more time. Scientifically,
we're in uncharted water.
We need to take him back to
the lab and do more tests,
It was like, something was
interfering with our system.
Something beyond chemistry or physics.
Like what? His soul?
Hey look this train
has left the station.
We can't exactly go
out to the world and say.
"Sorry, we released
a defective product."
So no matter what we do, we just
need to keep him on the streets.
What about the interviews?
Cancel them, cancel all of them.
Everything. In fact, Dennett...
Let's uh...
Let's keep the wife at a
distance for now as well.
I would like to see him.
Can you arrange that?
Look, I won't lie to you
Alex was so nervous
we had to sedate him.
I looked in his eyes and
I couldn't see my husband.
And then he just shoots
a man in front of our son.
That's not sedation.
He's responding to
drugs differently now.
We both knew from day one
there would be complications.
Just give me a little
more time. I promise...
You'll have your husband back.
This goes for every
squad in every department.
Detective Murphy will have
full access all investigations.
Robberies, narcotics, homicide.
If he requests to take over a case,
the case will be handed to him.
No arguments, No complaints.
This is Bullshit!
I said "no complaints"!
And I mean it!
Good morning, chief Dean.
Good morning, officers.
I selected 13 targets
today, all wanted for murder.
John Biggs is? 1. I will
be taking over this case.
Ambulances detention vehicles and coroners
should be ready to move in on my request.
I wish you all a very good day.
Murphy...
You okay man?
I'm fine sargent.
Can't wait to get back to
work Thinkin Daniels is -
Excuse me, I have casework.
Don't shoot!
Walter Karrel, look at me.
You have two options Option 1:
I shoot you with 50,000 volts.
Which can cause respiratory failure.
Organ malfunction, internal burns,
and loss of bowl and bladder
control. And then, I arrest you.
Option 2: You tell me where
John Biggs drug lab is located.
And then I arrest you.
You have two seconds to decide.
Totally justifiable.
We are going to make a lot of money.
Nothing. No fear, no
increase heart-rate,
no traces of anger, whatsoever.
Congratulations, Doctor. You did it.
Yes, I did.
I told you, sir. Norton clearly
never had control of the product.
I agree. And that's
why I called you here.
I just want a second pair of
eyes on this thing, that's all.
Okay, I'll need a feed
from the Tin Man's head.
Plus full surveillance of the lab.
You're gonna have full
access to everything.
If anything comes up
I'll be in Washington.
He brought peace to this
country's most violent city.
He showed us all that
Detroit and America
can have a brighter future
a future of economic growth.
Freedom and happiness.
On tonight's show, a
visionary and true patriot.
The CEO of Omnicorp, Raymond Sellers.
Hello, Pat - Raymond.
Thanks for having me.
You must be doing a
victory lap about now.
Two weeks ago, Omni stock
went through the roof.
And the Senate finally agreed to vote
on the repeal of the Dreyfuss act.
Well, look, I mean the
tide is definitely turning.
I just feel certain that soon
we'll be keeping all Americans safe.
I certainly hope so. But I think our next
guest will have a different point of view.
Hubert Dreyfuss. Senator,
thank you for attending.
Hello, Pat. Mr. Sellers.
Senator, do you know what this is?
The American public is
divided on the Dreyfuss act.
Our polls at Novakelement.com are tight.
50 % to 50 %.
There is no doubt Omnicorp
created a sensation,
But this bill is not about Alex Murphy.
It's about weather America's
willing to give robots
the authority over human lives.
Look.
This uh C-change we're
witnessing. And it is a C-change.
Shows that Americans don't really
care if our law enforcement systems
manned or unmanned. What they care about
is efficiency, and they care about safety.
You're clouding the issue.
This is clearly an attempt to sway
public opinion with a marketing stunt.
What's clear is, with
just one system in place.
We've cut crime by 80 %.
Just Imagine if we put...
I don't know, lets say
100 systems in place.
And then I want you to ask yourself.
Why are you holding us back?
Is that your pla.
Thank you, Senator.
And thank you, Raymond. Thank you, Pat.
Well, there you have it.
Who could argue with that?
Which begs the question.
Has the US Senate become Pro-Crime?
Yeah Hi No. 5000.
Call me tomorrow.
Hey guys. Vallons
waiting for you inside.
What, you're too busy to walk us in?
I'm out here making money.
Where are my trip wires?
I gotta do this myself?
- What took you so long?
- What the hell is all this shit?
I can't move any product with
this thing on the streets.
What are you doing to protect me?
- Relax, the guys a walking zombie.
- Tell me your phones are off.
He's not going after you,
we've covered our tracks.
Can't manufacture
evidence out of thin air.
If he does, I'm ready for him.
Well?
I've been getting calls.
From whom?
Clara. We need to let her see
her husband. She has rights.
That's not your decision.
That's legal's call.
But it is only a question of time
until she turns up on television.
She can try.
I'll issue a gag order before
I'll let her see her husband.
I'd hop to it.
Alex. Alex!
Alex.
You need to come home.
Clara, please stand aside.
Need to speak to your son.
Right now I see 3 crimes in progress.
Alex, listen to me.
I know your in there.
David won't show his face at school.
He's having nightmares.
He's falling apart I'm falling apart.
Please...
I can't do this on my own.
He's been scared ever since that night.
What do you think she's
gonna do? What's he gonna do?
You Okay? David?
He's supposed to be watching this.
Instead, he's accessing
images of Clara and David
arriving at school over and over again.
Somehow he's overriding
the system's priorities.
You want me to shut him down?
No.
Not yet.
I want to see what happens.
What's he doing at his house?
Look, He's disobeying protocol.
You have to shut him down.
As far as I can tell
he's still doing his job.
Adrian, give me an image of his brain.
He's undoing what we did to him.
His Dopamine levels it
are coming back to normal.
How is that even possible?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Alex?
Alex, please return to the station.
I want to run some tests.
Well this should be interesting.
We're not cops alright,
we work for Antoine Vallon!
What did you say?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
My hand, man!
Where is Antoine Vallon?
You broke my hand man!
I know you remember me, Jerry.
Where's Vallon? Wait!
If I tell you where Vallon is
he'll kill my wife and kid man.
Your wife left you in 2019 after filing
charges on you for domestic abuse.
And you don't have a kid.
But I do.
I'm not asking again!
Look, I swear man, I don't
know where Vallon is okay?
The only guy I talk to
is his driver Marcus.
That's it man that's it!
Does he have a phone number?
We have a problem. Alex
is breaking protocol.
What's he doing?
He's off solving his own murder.
That is genius. Why
didn't I think of that?
How long until he gets here?
- 5 minutes.
- Alright.
Johnny, you stay on these monitors.
What happened?
Some idiot used an unencrypted phone.
Shit!
Alright, everyone listen up!
He's coming.
If he leaves alive, you don't!
How do we stop him?
With 50 caliber and
above. Aim for the head.
This one's set.
Go! Go!
Run!
Come on!
Ready to go!
They're all set.
Finish it!
Free shot!
Watch out.
Need me to call a doctor?
Come on Jack you're gonna like this.
What's going on? What
the hell you doin here?
Y'all gonna play good cop bad cop?
No, Daniels. Bad cop, RoboCop
I've recovered 26 guns
from Vallon's warehouse
13 serial numbers match
weapons missing from evidence, and
I got your prints all over them.
- This is bullshit!
- I also..
I also have CCTV footage of
you and Vallon the same day
he tried to kill me.
Why don't we talk about this?
It won't work, now that his partners
hit he's not gonna let it go.
His hospital.
Murphy's dropping by this afternoon.
If I kill a cop I'm
looking over my shoulder..
You know what they do
to cops in prison man?
You get locked up with the
same doods you put in there.
Think before he gives you up.
Don't shoot me.
I swear to Christ it was dean.
He helped pull those
guns. Just don't shoot me.
Thank you for your cooperation.
You can cuff him now, Jack.
Now I know why we
couldn't get an arrest.
Vallon was protected from up on high.
Alex, I can explain.
- You tipped him off today.
- Come on, man don't do this.
You tried to kill me twice!
I trusted you, and you
destroyed my family.
Confess. Now
in front of everyone.
Confess!
What happened? Tin man is down.
Had to be done. Why?
Product shot a corrupt cop.
2 more seconds the
Chief's brains would have
been splattered across
the 6 O'clock news.
We got anything on her?
No, she's Chief of the
Detroit Police Department.
What do you think?
You know what?
This might actually tip this
thing right into the net.
Alex, I don't know if you can hear me
but tonight you uncovered
a nest of vipers,
Inside the Detroit Police Department.
And in so doing, you shed
light on an invaluable truth.
Even the police,
the men and women sworn to keep us safe,
they can be bribed.
They can be bought.
Machines, however, are corruption free.
Americans could be living in
a country where law enforcement
is not only efficient,
but incorruptible.
Thank you Alex for all you've done.
And for all that you are.
Detective Murphy is currently
in critical condition.
Our Doctors are working ceaselessly.
But this time, it is
unclear if he will survive.
Mrs. Klein how do you think
the attempt on Detective
Alex Murphy's life will effect
tomorrow's vote for the Dreyfuss act?
At this time Omnicorp's soul concern is.
The full recovery of
Detective Alex Murphy.
How many times does Detective Murphy
have to give his life for his country?
I sincerely hope the
Senate makes the right vote
so that Alex Murphy's sacrifices.
Will not have been in vain.
Senator Dreyfuss is my friend
he has been my mentor and my strength
in times of difficulty on this floor.
But despite all that, I
work for the state of Ohio
and the safety of It's
citizens is my top priority.
So, I vote yes. The Dreyfuss
act must be repealed.
That's us ahead 39 to 10
I spoke to the senate liaison.
It looks like it's in the
bag, but we still have to tred
carefully with the politicians.
We're here live at DPD headquarters.
Where moments ago Clara Murphy
made a shocking statement.
Omnicorp as denied me and my son
access to Alex for weeks.
I demand to know why.
This treatment is inhumane
and someone has to be held accountable.
We're fucked.
No, you only need 12 votes. She
shouldn't make much difference.
What about after the vote?
Those two should not be aloud contact.
If she starts putting ideas in his head..
Bring her in. I'll
handle the explanation.
What about Alex? Unfortunately
we can't just keep him on ice.
The shooting at the station
spooked some of the politicians.
They're our clients we
have to take care of them.
They're fine when a machine
is lowering the murder rate
when a man is
investigating city politics
they get nervous.
Alright. First, it's not a man okay?
It's property of Omnicorp.
And politicians are the
least of your concern.
I mean this thing
solved it's own murder.
How long until it realizes you
haven't been on the level with it.
If that happens, every
journalist in this country
is dying to speak with him
I mean We created a hero.
What happens when he opens his mouth?
What's bigger then a hero?
A dead hero.
Get me Doctor Norton.
What is this, Raymond?
You have Mattox spying on me
and now this bullshit
about critical condition?
You and I know that Alex is fine!
Calm down, Dennett.
- Your work is so good that...
- It is not my work!
You saw the woman on TV!
This has to stop!
You're right, but Let
me ask you something.
What kind of life have we
really given Alex Murphy?
He's never going to be a
normal man, a father, a husband.
By the time we put the other units
on the street he's just Dennett...
Face it. We failed him.
We failed Alex Murphy.
But I want you to think
about the bigger picture.
Because that's what we're talking about.
The work you've done with him is
going to be studied for decades.
You've changed the
face of history Dennett.
No Policeman is ever going to
die in the line of duty again.
Because of you.
Think about that!
I want that family taken care of.
Beyond their wildest
dreams. We owe them that.
I agree.
I want full funding. 10 years.
New staff. All my own people.
Fantastic. Deal!
Hey, what's going on?
Security's here their
clearing everyone out.
Their not waking him up. What
ever you do don't leave him alone.
What do you mean their
not waking him up?
The voting period has ended. The
clerks have tabulated the results.
The yeas are 63 The neighs are 22.
The majority of senators
have voted in the affirmative.
The Dreyfuss act has
been repealed by congress.
God, you guys are slow.
Like a bunch of girls.
This is Mattox.
Dennetts on board.
It's about time.
Call it.
Get it done.
My pleasure.
Mrs. Murphy.
You can come here as much as you want
you can threaten me, you can
sue me, you can take my home
but I'm not going to stop
until I see my husband.
Do you understand that?
Mr. Sellers would very
much like to see you.
Is Alex okay?
He has important
information to share with you.
Will you accompany me?
David...
We gotta go, can you grab your coat?
Hey!
I'm in the elevator on my way
down. I need access to the lab.
That's insane, they're still here.
Distract them.
Okay.
- I can not...
- There's a lady in here going hysterical.
She will not let us in, she's
got the codes for the door.
I repeat she will not let us in.
Lady, you need to let us in there
now. We have to get in there.
Are you not understanding
what I'm saying?
Do you want to be responsible for the
death of everyone in this building?
Hey! Stop!
- Don't shoot!
- Step outside.
Unlock the transmitter!
Transmitter unlocked.
Send in Mrs. Murphy please.
Right away sir.
Wake him up
Alex!
Alex, it's Doctor Norton.
You have to wake up!
Alex, can you hear me?
These men are here to kill us!
They're here to kill
us for Christ sakes!
Ms. Murphy, last night,
Alex had a psychotic break.
He killed an unarmed colleague
later suffered a seizure.
We did everything, everything, we could
but the doctors couldn't save him.
Very sorry Mrs Murphy.
We're going to be making
the announcement shortly.
You shut me down. I was
about to get a confession.
Mattox shut you down.
I removed your transmitter so
that he wouldn't do it again.
Sellers can not afford to wake you up.
He sent these guys to pull the plug.
He wants you dead Alex. You understand?
Sorry, if there is anything we can
do for you and David, we'll do it.
I want nothing from you.
I Understand.
You stay out of our lives.
- You and your company.
- If that's what you think is best.
There's one more thing, I think it
will be to the benefit of everyone
especially David, if we
kept this matter private.
We don't want to damage Alex's legacy.
Alex... Alex
Alex I can fix this.
You lied to me You lied to my wife.
You're working for the people
that are trying to kill me?
You want me to trust you Doctor?
Alex I can go to the press!
Alex, I can tell them the whole story!
Alex!
Listen to me, please!
Alex! Alex!
What the hell?
Give all of our systems a green light.
For Christ sakes get Sellers on the phone.
Roger that Damn, Damn, Damn...
Look at this city.
So beautiful.
It's become so peaceful.
I wish I had good news for Detroit.
I have very sad news.
Despite our best efforts to save him.
Alex Murphy passed away just hours ago.
- Alex Murphy...
- Mr. Sellers.
What is it? Mattox just called.
We need you to come with us now.
Ma'am, I need you to
turn around and go the
other way please -What
are you talking about?
We've got a security situation here. I need
you to turn around and go the other way.
Sir, there is a car outside...
That area is locked down, now go!
- What's happening?
- I said go!
I want to talk to Mr. Sellers.
- Mr. Sellers.
- How close is the helicopter?
About 10 minutes sir.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
I need to speak with
with Sergeant Jack Lewis.
It's an emergency.
Stand by. Mr. Sellers, apparently
there is a Clara Murphy in the lobby.
- What?
- Raymond...
If she sees him we are dead in the water.
What do you want to do?
Bring Ms. Murphy up here. Yes, sir.
Norton said that they may be
using drones for protection.
So, what ever you do,
do not draw your weapons.
They won't shoot if we're unarmed.
Clear? Clear!
Hold it right there!
Don't move!
This is private property!
You are not authorized to be here!
I would put those guns
down now if I were you.
Stand down, stand down.
Alright, okay..
Head to the lower level!
- Hold up! Hold up!
- Ram it!
Gun it!
Go, go, go!
Alex, run!
Omnicorp security! Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapons.
Keep your hands on your head
and no one will be harmed.
What's going on?
Mrs Murphy I want you
to listen to me carefully.
The organic part of your
husband, Alex, is dead.
The robotic part of
him is malfunctioning.
And he's shooting at
the building. So we gotta
get you and your son
out of here right away.
I gotta take this call.
He just left the lobby.
He's headed our way.
Roger that Sir.
Don't shoot my robot, you just flank.
Got it.
Tin Man.
Tin Man!
There it is.
You look like crap.
What's the matter? Can't shoot?
What were you thinking?
This isn't a drill.
You're a robot. I am a Red asset.
I wrote that myself.
What do you think?
Come on Tin Man just pull the trigger.
Pull it.
You can run. Go on.
Run!
Run.
There you go Run!
Run! Run!
Stings like a bitch, don't' it?
Lucky, lucky, I didn't
have my gun set to kill.
Listen, this isn't personal.
Well, Maybe a little.
I'm gonna put you out of your misery.
Helicopters approaching
Mr. Sellers boards first.
No, no. Mrs. Murphy. You and
your son can get on first.
Officer down, mechanical
room, Omnicorp Building.
Roger that, EMS on the way.
You're going to be okay Jack. Non fatal.
Go, go!
Omni LZ - Helot-1
on approach to deck.
What's that?
He's got a gun! What?
Pull up! Pull up!
What the hell is he doing?
Sorry, sir, I don't know.
- Alex?
- Dad?
Clara, David...
Wait...
Get out of the way.
Alex put down the gun.
Clara, take David and
get out of the way now!
Raymond Sellers, you're under arrest for
the attempted murder of a police officer.
You're here to cuff me? Alright.
Go ahead. Cuff me.
You can't, you're not
programmed that way.
If you go against the program
the entire system shuts down.
You don't even have a warrant.
We'll overlook this little...
Get down on the ground and put
your hands behind your back.
- I'm just from marketing.
- NOW!
Okay, Yep, yep yep yep...
Alex, we need work together.
Because I'm the one with the
technology to keep you alive.
Dead or alive, you're coming with me.
Right.
Weapon
Alex, honestly, I mean you no harm.
If I wanted to I could have
killed you along time ago.
I just aim this right at
your head and blow it off.
Sellers, please Don't!
I mean if I wanted to, I could
just aim this at your little family.
And I could just kill them too.
And really there's nothing you can
do about it because lets face it.
You're a robot.
You understand that?
Alex.
Dad!
Hey,
Everything's gonna be alright.
How you feeling, Alex?
I'm ready.
He's ready.
There's still no word from
Omnicorp parent company OCP.
And although the government says
they are rebuilding Alex Murphy.
Rumors continue to swirly
about his condition.
But we have obtained exclusive
video taken by a cell phone.
That shows the people
of Detroit may have Alex
Murphy back on the street
sooner then they think.
The real tragedy here
is that our President
chose to uphold the Dreyfuss act.
I have no doubt that he was
manipulated by bias media.
And by whistle blower Dennett Norton.
I acknowledged we know
less then we thought.
But I do believe my
research program is sound.
What I did with it.
Was wrong.
The fact that this mother F
is not serving time in
some federal penitentiary
is a huge hot heaping pile of horse sh
I know some of you may think that
this kind of thinking is dangerous.
And these machines violate
your civil liberties.
Some of you even believe that
the use of these drones overseas
makes us the same kind
of bullying imperialist
that our forefathers
were trying to escape.
To you I say: Stop whining!
America is now, and always will be
the greatest country on
the face of the earth!
I'm Pat Novak.
Good night.