Are you here to kill me?
I know what this is.
I have seen one before.
Many, many years ago.
It belonged to a man I met
in a half-remembered dream.
A man...
possessed of some radical notions.
What is the most resilient parasite?
A bacteria?
A virus?
An intestinal worm?
What Mr. Cobb is trying to say...
An idea.
Resilient. Highly contagious.
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain
it's almost impossible to eradicate.
An idea that is fully formed,
fully understood, that sticks.
Right in there somewhere.
For someone like you to steal?
Yes. In the dream state,
your conscious defenses are lowered
and that makes your thoughts,
vulnerable to theft.
It's called extraction.
Mr. Saito, we can train
your subconscious to defend itself,
from even the most skilled extractor.
How can you do that?
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
I know how to search your
mind and find your secrets.
I know the tricks.
And I can teach them to you,
so that even when you are asleep,
your defense, is never down.
Look if you want my help,
you are gonna have to be
completely open with me.
I need to know my way around your
thoughts better than your wife,
better than your therapist,
better than anyone.
If this is a dream,
and you have a safe full of secrets.
I need to know what's in that safe.
In order for this all to work,
you need to completely let me in.
Enjoy your evening gentlemen,
as I consider your proposal.
He knows.
What's going on up there?
Saito knows.
He is playing with us.
Doesn't matter.
I can get it here, trust me.
The information is in the safe.
He looked right at it
when I mentioned secrets.
What's she doing here?
Just head back to the room.
Alright? I will take care of this.
Ok, make sure you do.
We are here to work.
If I jumped...
would I survive?
With a clean dive, perhaps.
Mal, what are you doing here?
I thought you might be missing me.
You know that I am.
But, I can't trust you anymore.
So what?
Looks like Arthur's taste.
Actually the subject is partial
to postwar British painters.
Please, have a seat.
Tell me...
Do the children miss me?
You can't imagine.
What are you doing?
Just getting some fresh air.
Stay where you are Mal.
Goddammit.
Turn around.
The gun Dom.
Please.
Now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
Did she tell you?
Or have you known all along?
That you are here to steal from me or,
that we are actually asleep?
I want to know the name of your employer.
There is no use threatening him
in a dream, right Mal?
That depends on what you are threatening.
Killing him would just wake him up.
But pain...
Pain is in the mind.
And judging by the decor.
We are in your mind,
are not we Arthur?
What are you doing it's too soon.
I know, but the dream is collapsing.
I am gonna try to keep Saito
under a little bit longer.
We are almost there.
He was close.
Very close.
Stop him!
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
He won't wake.
Give him the kick.
What?
Sunk him.
He is out.
You came prepared?
Not even my head of security knows
this apartment.
How did you find it?
It's very difficult for a man of your
position to keep a love nest like this secret
particularly where there is
a married woman involved.
She would never...
Yet, here we are.
With a dilemma.
They are getting closer.
You got what you came for.
Well, that's not true.
You left out a key piece
of information, didn't you?
You held something back because
you knew what we were up to.
Question is why did you let us in at all?
An audition.
An audition for what?
Doesn't matter. You failed.
We extracted every bit of
information you had in there.
But your deception was obvious.
So...
leave me and go.
You don't seem to understand, Mr. Saito.
That corporation that hired us,
they won't accept failure.
We won't last two days.
Cobb?
Looks like I am gonna have to do this
a little more simply.
Tell us what you know!
Tell us what you know, now!
I have always hated this carpet.
It's stained...
and frayed in such distinctive ways.
But very definitely made of wool.
Right now,
I am lying on polyester.
Which means,
I am not lying on my carpet,
in my apartment.
You have lived up to your reputation.
Mr. Cobb.
I am still dreaming.
How did it go?
Not good.
Dream within a dream?
I am impressed.
But in my dream,
you play by my rules.
Yes, but you see Mr. Saito,
We are not in your dream.
We are in mine.
Asshole.
How do you mess up the carpet?
It was not my fault.
You are the architect.
I didn't know he was gonna
rub his cheek on it!
That's enough.
You.
What the hell was all that?
I have it under control.
I would hate to see you out of control.
We don't have time for this.
I am getting off at Kyoto.
He has not gonna check every compartment.
Yeah, well. I don't like trains.
Listen.
Every man for himself.
Yes, hello?
Hi Daddy.
Hi Dad.
Hey, guys. Hey.
How are you? How you doing?
Good. Ok, I guess.
Ok?
Who is just ok? Is that you James?
Yeah.
When are you coming home, Dad?
Well. I can't sweetheart, I can't.
Not for a while, remember?
Why?
Look.
I told you, I am away,
because I am working, right?
Grandma says you are never coming back.
Phillipa, is that you?
Put Grandma on the phone for me, will you?
She is shaking her head.
Well, I just hope she is wrong about that.
Daddy?
Yeah. James?
Is Mommy with you?
James, we talked about this.
Mommy is not here anymore.
Where?
That's enough, kids.
Say bye-bye.
Listen. I am gonna send some presents
with Grandpa, alright?
And you be good, you be...
Our ride is on the roof.
Right.
Hey, are you ok?
Yeah. Yeah. I am fine. Why?
Well, down in the dream.
Mal showing up.
Look. I am...
sorry about your leg.
Won't happen again.
It's getting worse, isn't it?
One apology is all you are getting, alright?
Where is Nash?
He has not shown. You wanna wait?
We were supposed to deliver
Saito's expansion plans
to COBOL Engineering two hours ago.
By now, they know we failed.
It's time we disappear.
Where you gonna go?
Buenos Aires.
I can lie low there, maybe sniff out
a job when things quiet down.
You?
Stateside.
Send my regards.
He sold you out.
Thought to come to me
and bargain for his life.
So, I offer you the satisfaction.
It's not the way I deal with things.
What will you do with him?
Nothing.
But I can't speak for COBOL Engineering.
What do you want from us?
Inception.
Is it possible?
Of course not.
If you can steal an idea
from someone is mind,
why can't you plant one there instead?
Ok, here is me planting
an idea in your head.
I say you. Don't think about elephants.
What are you thinking about?
Elephants.
Right.
But it's not your idea.
Because you know I gave it to you.
The subject's mind can always trace
the genesis of the idea.
True inspiration is impossible to fake.
That's not true.
Can you do it?
Are you offering me a choice?
Because I can find my own way
to square things with COBOL.
Then you do have a choice.
Then I choose to leave, sir.
Tell the crew where you want to go.
Hey, Mr. Cobb.
How would you like to go home?
To America.
To your children.
You can't fix that.
No one can.
Just like inception.
Cobb, come on.
How complex is the idea?
Simple enough.
No idea is simple, when you need
to plant it in somebody else's mind.
My main competitor
is an old man in poor health.
His son will soon inherit control
of the corporation.
I need him to decide to break up
his father's empire.
Cobb, we should walk away from this.
Hold on.
If I were to do this...
If I even could do it,
I would need a guarantee.
How do I know you can deliver?
You don't.
But I can.
So...
do you want to take a leap of faith,
or become an old man.
Filled with regret,
waiting to die alone?
Assemble your team, Mr. Cobb.
And choose your people more wisely.
I know how much you wanna go home.
This can't be done.
Yes, it can.
Just have to go deep enough.
You don't know that.
I have done it before.
Who did you do it to?
Why are we going to Paris?
We are gonna need a new architect.
You never did like your office, did you?
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
Is it safe for you to be here?
Extradition between France
and the United States,
is a bureaucratic nightmare,
you know that.
I think they might find a way
to make it work in your case.
Look, I...
brought these for you to give
to the kids when you have a chance.
It will take more than
the occasional stuffed animal,
to convince those children
they still have a father.
I am just doing what I know.
I am doing what you taught me.
I never taught you to be a thief.
No, you taught me
to navigate people's minds.
But after what happened...
there were not a whole lot of legitimate
ways for me to use that skill.
What are you doing here, Dom?
I think I found a way home.
It's a job for some very,
very powerful people.
People who I believe,
can fix my charges permanently.
But I need your help.
You are here to corrupt
one of my brightest and best.
You know what I am offering.
Let them decide for themselves.
Money.
Not just money.
You remember.
It's,
the chance to build cathedrals.
Entire cities things that never existed,
things that could not
exist in the real world.
So, you want me to let someone else,
follow you into your fantasy?
They don't actually come into the dream,
they just...
they just design the levels
and teach them to the dreamers. That's all.
Design it yourself.
Mal won't let me.
Come back to reality Dom.
Please.
Reality.
Those kids,
your grandchildren,
they are waiting for their father
to come back home, that's their reality.
And this job, this last job.
That's how I get there.
I would not be standing here
if I knew any other way.
I need an architect
who is as good as I was.
I have got somebody better.
Ariadne?
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
Pleased to meet you.
If you have a few moments,
Mr. Cobb has a job offer
he would like to discuss with you.
A work placement?
Not exactly.
I have a test for you.
You are not gonna tell me anything first?
Before I describe the job.
I have to know you can do it.
Why?
It's not, strictly speaking legal.
You have,
two minutes,
to design a maze
that it takes one minute to solve.
Stop.
Again.
You are gonna have to do better than that.
That's more like it.
They say we only use a fraction
of our brain's true potential.
Now, that's when we are awake.
When we are asleep.
Our mind can do almost anything.
Such as?
So imagine you are designing a building,
You consciously create each aspect.
But sometimes, it feels like it's almost
creating itself,
if you know what I mean.
Yeak.
Yeah, like I am...
discovering it.
Genuine inspiration, right?
Now in a dream.
Our mind continuously does this.
We...
create and perceive
our world simultaneously.
And our mind does this so well
that we don't even know it's happening.
That allows us to get right
in the middle of that process.
How?
By taking over the creating part.
Now, this is where I need you.
You create the world of the dream.
We bring the subject into that dream.
And they fill it with their subconscious.
How could I ever...
acquire enough detail
to make them think that it's reality?
Well, dreams...
they feel real
while we are in them, right?
So it's only when we wake up that
we realize something was actually strange.
Let me ask you a question.
You...
you never really,
remember the
beginning of a dream, do you?
You always wind up,
right in the middle of what's going on.
I guess, yeah.
So how did we end up here?
Well, we just came from the...
Think about it. Ariadne.
How did you get here?
Where are you right now?
We are dreaming?
You are in the middle of the workshop,
right now, sleeping.
This is your first lesson in shared dreaming.
Stay calm.
If it's just a dream. Then why are you...
Because it's never just a dream, is it?
And a face full of glass hurts like hell.
When you are in it,
it feels real.
That's why the military developed
dream sharing it was a training program,
for soldiers to shoot stab and strangle
each other and then wake up.
How did architects become involved?
Well, someone had to design
the dreams, right?
Why don't you give us
another five minutes?
Five minutes?
What...
We were talking for like at least an hour.
In a dream, your mind
functions more quickly therefore...
time seems to feel more slow.
Five minutes in the real world
gives you an hour in the dream.
Why don't you see what you
can get up to in five minutes?
You have got the basic layout.
Bookstore, cafe.
Almost everything else is here too.
Who are the people?
Projections of my subconscious.
Yours?
Yes.
Remember, you are the dreamer.
You build this world.
I am the subject.
My mind populates it.
You can literally...
talk to my subconscious.
That's one of the ways we extract
information from the subject.
How else do you do it?
By creating something secure.
Like a...
like a bank vault or a jail.
The mind automatically fills it
with information it's trying to protect.
You understand?
Then you break in and steal it?
Well...
I guess I thought that...
the dream space would be
all about the visual but...
it's more about the feel of it.
My question is, what happens when you
start messing with the physics of it all?
It's something, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Why are they all looking at me?
Because my subconscious feels that
someone else is creating this world.
The more you change things,
the quicker the projections start
to converge on you.
Converge?
They sense the foreign nature
of the dreamer.
They attack, like white blood cells
fighting an infection.
What, they are gonna attack us?
No.
Just you.
This is great, but I am telling you.
If you keep changing things like this...
Jeez, mind telling your subconscious
to take it easy?
It's my subconscious.
Remember? I can't control it.
Very impressive.
I know this bridge.
This place is real, isn't it?
Yeah. I cross it every day
to get to the college.
Never re-create places from your memory.
Always imagine new places.
You draw from stuff you know, right?
Only use details...
A streetlamp
or a phone booth.
Never entire areas.
Why not?
Because building a dream from your memory
is the easiest way to lose your grasp
on what's real and what is a dream.
Is that what happened to you?
Listen to me.
This has nothing to do with me, understand?
That why you need me to build your dreams?
Hey, get off of her.
Back up. Back up.
Hey!
Cobb! Cobb!
Get off of her!
Let me go! Let me go!
Mal!
Cobb! Wake me up!
Wake me up! Wake me up!
Mal! No!
Let me go! Let me go!
Mal, no! No!
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me.
You are ok. You are ok.
Hey.
Why...
Why would not I wake up?
There was still time on the clock.
You can't wake up from
within the dream unless you die.
She will need a totem.
What?
A totem, it's a small personal...
That's some subconscious
you have got on you, Cobb!
She is a real charmer.
I see you met Mrs. Cobb.
She is his wife?
Yeah. So a totem.
You need a small object, potentially heavy.
Something you can have on you
that no one else knows.
Like a coin?
No.
It needs to be more unique than that, like...
this is a...
loaded die.
I can't let you touch it.
That would defeat the purpose.
Dee, only I know the balance and
the weight of this particular loaded die.
That way.
When you look at your totem...
you know beyond a doubt that
you are not in someone else's dream.
I-I-I-I don't know,
if you can't see what's going on,
or if you just don't want to...
but Cobb has some serious problems
that he has tried to bury down there.
And I am not about to just,
open my mind,
to someone like that.
She will be back.
I have never seen anyone pick
it up that quickly before.
Reality is not gonna be enough for her now.
And when she comes back...
When she comes back.
You are gonna have her building mazes.
Where are you gonna be?
I got to go visit Eames.
Eames?
No, he is in Mombasa.
It's Cobol's back yard.
It's a necessary risk.
Well, there is plenty of good thieves.
We don't just need a thief.
We need a forger.
Rub them together all you want.
They are not gonna breed.
You never know.
I am gonna get you a drink.
You are buying.
Your spelling has not improved.
Piss off.
How is your handwriting?
It's versatile.
Good.
Thank you very much.
Inception.
Now, before you...
bother telling me it's impossible,
No, it's perfectly possible.
It's just bloody difficult.
Interesting.
Because Arthur keeps
telling me it can't be done.
Arthur.
You still working
with that stick in the mud?
He is good at what he does, right?
Oh, he is the best.
But he has no imagination.
Not like you.
Listen, if you are gonna perform inception.
You need imagination.
Let me ask you something.
Have you done it before?
We tried it.
We got the idea in place.
But it didn't take.
You didn't plant it deep enough?
No, it's not just about depth, you know.
You need the simplest version of the idea
in order for it to grow
naturally in your subject's mind.
It's a subtle art.
So, what is this idea
that you need to plant?
We need the heir of...
a major corporation
to dissolve his father's empire.
Right there you have
various political motivations...
and anti-monopolistic sentiments
and so forth.
But all of that stuff, it's...
It's really at the mercy of your
subject's prejudice, you see?
What you have to do is
start at the absolute basic.
Which is what?
The relationship with the father.
Do you have a chemist?
No, not yet.
Right. Ok, well.
There is a man here.
Yusuf. He...
He formulates his own versions
of the compounds.
Why don't you take me there?
Once you have lost your tail.
The man at the bar.
COBOL Engineering.
That price on my head.
Was that dead or alive?
Don't remember.
Let's see if he starts shooting.
Run interference, I will meet you
downstairs in the bar in, say...
half an hour?
Back here?
This is the last place they would suspect.
Alright.
Freddy?
Freddy Simmonds.
My God, it's you, isn't it?
No, it isn't you.
Not dreaming now, are you?
Get him!
There!
Cafe.
One-one cafe.
One cafe.
Care for a lift, Mr. Cobb?
What are you doing in Mombasa?
I am here to protect my investment.
So this is your idea of losing a tail?
Different tail.
Cobb said you would be back.
I tried not to come, but...
But there is nothing quite like it.
It's just...
pure creation.
Shall we take a look
at some paradoxical architecture?
You are gonna have to master a few tricks,
if you are gonna build three
complete dream levels.
Excuse me.
What kind of tricks?
In a dream, you can cheat architecture
into impossible shapes.
That lets you create closed loops.
Like the Penrose Steps.
The infinite staircase.
See.
Paradox.
So a closed loop like that,
will help you disguise the boundaries
of the dream you create.
But how big do these levels have to be?
It could be anything from the floor
of a building to an entire city.
They have to be complicated enough,
that we can hide from the projections.
A maze?
Right, a maze.
And the better the maze...
Then the longer we have
before the projections catch us?
Exactly.
My subconscious seems polite enough.
You wait, they will turn ugly.
No one likes to feel someone else
messing around in their mind.
Cobb can't build anymore, can he?
I don't know if he can't, but he won't.
He thinks it's safer
if he doesn't know the layouts.
Why?
He won't tell me.
But I think it's Mal.
His ex-wife?
No, not his ex.
They are still together?
No.
She is dead.
What you see in there
is just his projection of her.
What was she like in real life?
She was lovely.
You are seeking a chemist?
Yes.
To formulate compounds for a job?
And to go into the field with us.
No. I rarely go into the field, Mr. Cobb.
Well, we would need you there to tailor
compounds specific to our needs.
Which are?
Great depth.
A dream within a dream?
Two levels?
Three.
Not possible.
That many dreams within
dreams is too unstable.
It is...
possible.
You just have to add a sedative.
A powerful...
sedative.
How many team members?
Five.
Six.
The only way to know
you have done the job...
is if I go in with you.
There is no room for tourists
on a job like this, Mr. Saito.
This time, it seems there is.
This. I think, is a good place to start.
I use it every day.
What for?
Here. I will show you.
Perhaps you will not want to see.
After you.
Ten.
Twelve. All connected. Bloody hell.
They come every day to share the dream.
You see?
Very stable.
How long do they dream for?
Three, four hours,
each day.
In dream time?
With this compound?
About 40 hours.
Each and every day.
Why do they do it?
Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
After a while, it becomes
the only way you can dream.
Do you still dream, Mr. Cobb?
They come here every day to sleep?
No.
They come to be woken up.
The dream, has become their reality.
Who are you to say otherwise, sir?
Let's see what you can do.
You know how to find me.
You know what you have to do.
Sharp, no?
Are you alright,
Mr. Cobb?
Yeah, yeah.
Everything is just fine.
Robert Fischer,
heir to the Fischer Morrow
energy conglomerate.
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
That's not your concern.
Mr. Saito this...
this isn't your typical corporate espionage.
You-you asked me for inception.
I do hope you understand,
the gravity of that request.
Now,
the seed that we plant
in this man's mind will grow into an idea.
This idea will define him.
It may come to change...
Well, it may come to change
everything about him.
We are the last company standing
between them and total energy dominance.
And we can no longer compete.
Soon, they will control the energy supply
of half the world.
In effect,
they become a new superpower.
The world needs Robert Fischer
to change his mind.
That's where we come in.
How is Robert Fischer's relationship
with his father?
Rumor is...
the relationship is quite complicated.
Well, we can't work based
solely on rumor, can we?
Can you get me access to this man here?
Browning.
Fischer Senior's right-hand man.
Fischer Junior's godfather.
It should be possible.
If you can get the right references.
References are something
of a specialty for me, Mr. Saito.
I am not smelling settlement here.
Take them down.
Mr. Browning!
Maurice Fischer's policy
is always one of avoiding litigation.
Well,
shall we voice your concerns
with Maurice directly?
Not sure that's necessary.
No, no, no. I-I think we should.
How is he?
I don't want to bother him
unnecessarily, but...
Robert, I told you...
keep out the damn.
Wait.
So do it. Get...
Mr. Fischer.
Put it through.
Never, never.
Never do the same as I asked.
Leave that.
Here.
Must be a cherished memory of his.
I put it beside his bed.
He has not even noticed.
Robert...
we need to talk about a power of attorney.
I know this is hard, but...
Not now.
But it's imperative we start...
Uncle Peter.
The vultures are circling.
And the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes,
the more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
I have had ample opportunity
to observe Browning...
and adopt his physical presence,
study his mannerisms, and so on and so forth.
So now in the first layer of the dream.
I can impersonate Browning.
And suggest concepts
to Fischer's conscious mind.
Then,
when we take him
a level deeper his own...
projection of Browning should
feed that right back to him.
So he gives himself the idea.
Precisely.
That's the only way it will stick.
It has to seem self-generated.
Eames.
I am impressed.
Your condescension,
as always, is much appreciated.
Arthur thank you.
Were you going under on your own?
No, no. I was just...
running some experiments.
I didn't realize anyone was here.
Yeah. I was just...
I was working on my totem, actually.
Here, let me take a look.
So you are learning?
An elegant solution
for keeping track of reality.
Was it your idea?
No, it was...
It was Mal's actually. This...
This one was hers.
She would spin it in the dream
and it would never topple.
Just...
spin and spin.
Arthur told me she passed away.
How are the mazes coming along?
Each level relates to the part of the subject's
subconscious that we are trying to access.
So,
I am making the bottom level a hospital.
So Fischer will bring his father...
You know, I... I actually.
I have a question about this layout.
No, no, no. Don't...
Don't show me specifics.
Only the dreamer should know the layout.
Why is that so important?
In case one of us brings in our projections.
We don't want them knowing
the details of the maze.
You mean in case you bring Mal in.
You can't keep her out, can you?
Right.
You can't build because
if you know the maze.
Then she knows it.
Well, she would sabotage the whole operation.
Cobb, do the others know?
No.
No, they don't.
You have got to warn them
if this is getting worse.
No one said it's getting worse.
I need to get home.
That's all I care about right now.
Why can't you go home?
Because they think I killed her.
Thank you.
For what?
For not asking whether I did.
I will split up my father's empire.
Now, this is obviously an idea that
Robert himself would choose to reject...
which is why we need to plant it deep
in his subconscious.
The subconscious...
is motivated by emotion, right?
Not reason. We need to find
a way to translate this,
into an emotional concept.
How do you translate business strategy
into emotion?
That's what we are here
to figure out right?
Robert's relationship with his father
is stressed, to say the least.
Can we run with that?
We suggest breaking up his father's
company as a screw you to the old man.
No, because I think positive emotion...
trumps negative emotion every time.
We all yearn for reconciliation.
For catharsis.
We need Robert Fischer to have
a positive emotional reaction to all this.
Alright, well try this.
My father accepts that I want to create
for myself, not follow in his footsteps.
That might work.
Might?
We need to do a little better than might.
Thank you for your contribution Arthur.
Forgive me for wanting
a little specificity Eames.
Specificity?
Inception's not about being specific.
When we get inside his mind, we are
gonna have to work with what we find.
On the top level,
we open up his relationship
with his father...
and say,
I will not follow in my father's footsteps.
Then the next level down, we feed him,
I will create something for myself.
Then,
by the time we hit the bottom level,
we bring out the big guns.
My father doesn't want me to be him.
Exactly.
Three layers down,
the dreams are gonna collapse,
with the slightest disturbance.
Sedation.
For sleep,
stable enough to create
three layers of dreaming
we will have to combine it with
an extremely powerful sedative.
Good night.
The compound we will be
using to share the dream
creates a very clear connection
between dreamers whilst,
actually accelerating brain function.
In other words, more time on each level.
Brain function in the dream will be
about 20 times normal.
And when you enter a dream within
that dream,
the effect is compounded.
It's three dreams.
That's 10 hours times 20...
Math was never my strong subject.
How much time is that?
It's a week, the first level down.
Six months the second level down.
And the third level...
That's 10 years.
Who would want be stuck
in a dream for 10 years?
Depends on the dream.
So once we have made the plant.
How do we get out?
I am hoping you have something more
elegant than shooting me in the head.
A kick.
What's a kick?
This.
Ariadne, would be a kick.
It's that feeling of falling you get
that jolts you awake.
Snaps you out of the dream.
How we gonna feel a kick
with this sedation?
That's the clever part.
I customized the sedative to leave
inner-ear function unimpaired.
That way,
however deep the sleep.
The sleeper still feels falling.
Or tipping.
The trick is to synchronize a kick,
that can penetrate all three levels.
We could use a musical countdown
to synchronize the different kicks.
He has not got any surgery scheduled,
no dental, nothing.
Was not he supposed to have
a knee operation?
Nothing.
Nothing that they will put him
under for, anyway we need...
We need at least a good 10 hours.
Sydney to Los Angeles.
One of the longest flights in the world.
He makes it every two weeks.
He must be flying private, then.
Not if there were unexpected
maintenance with his plane.
It would have to be a 747.
Why's that?
On a 747, the pilot's up top,
the first-class cabin's in the nose.
So no one would walk through.
Wait you would have
to buy out the entire cabin
and the first-class flight attendant.
I bought the airline.
It seemed neater.
Well, looks like we have our 10 hours.
Ariadne?
Terrific work, by the way.
You know how to find me.
You know what you have to do.
You remember when you asked me
to marry you?
Of course I do.
You said you had a dream.
That we would grow old together.
And we can.
You should not be here.
Just wanted to see what kind of tests
you are doing on your own every night.
This has nothing to do with you.
This has everything to do with me.
You have asked me
to share dreams with you.
Not these.
These are my dreams.
Why do you do this to yourself?
It's the only way I can still dream.
Why is it so important to dream?
In my dreams, we are still together.
These are not just dreams.
These are memories.
And you said never to use memories.
I know I did.
You are trying to keep her alive.
You can't let her go.
You don't understand.
These are moments I regret.
They are memories that I have to change.
Well, what's down there that you regret?
Listen, there is only one thing
you need to understand about me.
This is your house?
Mine and Mal's, yes.
Where is she?
She is already gone.
That's my son, James.
He is digging for something.
Maybe a worm.
That's Phillipa.
See I thought about calling out,
so they would turn and smile
and I could see this...
those beautiful faces of theirs but...
it's all too late.
Right now, or never Cobb.
Then I start to panic.
I realize I am gonna regret
this moment that...
I need to see their faces one last time.
James!
Phillipa!
Come on in!
But the moment has past.
And whatever I do,
I can't change this moment.
As I am about to call out to them...
they run away.
I am ever gonna see their faces,
again I have got to get back home.
The real world.
What are you doing here?
My name is...
I know who you are.
What are you doing here?
I am just trying to understand.
How could you understand?
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
To be half of a whole?
No.
I will tell you a riddle.
You are waiting for a train.
A train that will take you far away.
You know where you hope
this train will take you...
but you don't know for sure.
But it doesn't matter.
How can it not matter to you
where that train will take you?
Because you will be together.
How could you bring her here Dom?
What is this place?
This is a hotel suite where we
used to spend our anniversary.
What happened here?
You promised!
You promised, we would be together!
Please. I need you to stay here
just for now!
You said we would be together!
You said we would grow old together!
I will come back for you.
I promise.
Do you think,
you can just build a prison
of memories to lock her in?
Do you really think that
that's gonna contain her?
It's time.
Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
When is the funeral?
Thursday. In Los Angeles.
Robert should accompany
the body no later than Tuesday.
We should move.
Alright.
Cobb. I am coming with you.
I promised Miles. No.
The team needs someone,
who understands what
you are struggling with.
And it doesn't have to be me...
but then you have to show Arthur,
what I just saw.
Get us another seat on the plane.
If I get on this plane and
you don't honor our agreement,
when we land I go to jail
for the rest of my life.
Complete the job en route,
I make one phone call from the plane,
you have no trouble
getting through Immigration.
I am sorry.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Thank you.
Excuse me. I think this is yours?
You must have dropped it.
Would you care for a drink?
Oh. Water, please.
Oh... same, please.
Thank you.
You know I could not help but notice but...
you would not happen to be related to...
the Maurice Fischer, would you?
Yes, he...
He was my father.
Well, he was a very inspiring figure.
I am sorry for your loss.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Hey.
To your father.
May he rest in peace?
You could not have peed before you went under?
Sorry.
A bit too much free champagne
before take off, hey Yusuf?
Ha, ha, bloody ha.
We know he is going to be looking
for a taxi in this weather.
Asshole!
Hey man, why don't you try...
Walk away.
Just have him ca...
I got to go.
Alright. Taxi!
Thank you.
Alright.
Third and Market. Snappy.
What are you doing?
Oh sorry, I thought it was free.
It's not.
Maybe we could share.
Maybe not.
Can you pull over and get this...
Great.
Come on.
There is $500 in there.
The wallet is worth more than that.
So you might at least drop me at my stop.
I am afraid that it doesn't...
Book!
Cover him!
Down! Down! Down!
What the hell is going on?
What the fuck!
This was not in the design.
Cobb?
Get him!
Are you alright?
Yeah. I am ok. I am ok.
Fischer is ok, unless he gets carsick.
Saito?
Get Fischer in the back room now.
Get him in the back room.
Move.
What the hell happened?
Has he been shot? Is he dying?
I don't know.
Jesus Christ.
Where were you? What happened to you?
Blocked by a freight train.
Why did you put a train cross
in the middle of a downtown intersection?
I didn't.
Where did it come from?
Let me ask you a question,
why the hell were we ambushed?
Those were not normal projections.
They have been trained for God's sakes!
You are right.
How could he be trained?
Fischer has
had an extractor,
teach his subconscious to defend itself, so...
his subconscious is militarized,
it should have shown in the research.
I am sorry.
Why the hell didn't it?
Calm down.
Don't tell me to calm down!
This was your job, goddamn it!
This was your responsibility!
You were meant to check
Fischer's background thoroughly!
We are not prepared
for this type of parody!
We have dealt with sub-security before!
We will be more careful
and we are gonna be fine!
This was not a part of the plan!
He is dying.
God!
So we put him out of his misery.
Cobb!
Don't do that!
Don't do that.
Cobb, hey, hey.
He is in agony.
I am waking him up.
No.
It won't wake him up.
What do you mean, it won't wake him up?
We won't wake him up?
When we die in a dream, we wake up.
Not from this.
We are too heavily sedated
to wake up that way.
Right. So, what happens when we die?
We drop into limbo. Are you serious?
Limbo?
Unconstructed dream space.
Well, what the hell is down there?
Just...
raw, infinite subconscious.
Nothing is down there,
except for what might have been left behind
by anyone sharing the dream
who is been trapped there before.
Which in our case,
is just you.
How long could we be stuck there?
Don't even think about trying
to escape until the sedation...
How long?
Jesus.
Decades. It could be infinite, I don't know.
Ask him, he is the one who is been there.
Let's get him upstairs.
Great.
Thank you.
So, now we are trapped in Fischer's mind,
battling his own private army,
and if we get killed,
we will be lost in limbo
till our brains turn to scrambled egg?
Someone got first aid?
So you knew these risks,
and didn't tell us?
There were not meant to be risks
I didn't know we would be dealing
with a load of gunfire.
You had no right.
It's the only way
you can go three layers deep.
And you?
You knew about this
and went along with it?
I trusted him.
You trusted him? And what did
he promised you half his share?
No.
His whole share.
Besides he said he had done it before.
You done it before. What with Mal?
Because that worked so good?
That has nothing to do with it.
I did what I had to to get to my children.
So you led us into a war
zone with no way out?
There is a way out.
We continue on with the job,
and we do it as fast as possible
and we get out using the kick.
Just like before.
Forget it. We go any deeper.
We just raise the stakes.
I am sitting this one out on this level.
Fischer's security is surrounding
this place as we speak.
Ten hours of flight time
is a week at this level.
That means each and every one of us
will be killed.
That I can guarantee you.
We have no other choice but to continue on
and do it as fast as possible.
Downwards is the only way forwards.
Get ready.
You, come on. Let's go shake him up.
I am insured against kidnapping
for up to 10 million.
This should be very simple.
Shut up! It won't be.
In your father's office below the
bookshelves is his personal safe.
We need the combination.
I don't know any safe.
That doesn't mean
you don't know the combination.
Tell us what it is.
I don't know.
We have it on good authority you do know.
Yeah?
Whose authority?
Five hundred dollars this cost.
What's inside it?
Cash, cards, ID...
and this.
Useful?
Maybe.
You are on.
You have got an hour.
An hour?
I was supposed to have all night
to crack this.
And Saito was not supposed
to be shot in the chest.
You have got one hour.
Now get us something useful, please.
What's that?
Good authority.
Uncle Peter.
Just make, just make them stop.
The combination.
I don't know it.
Why does Browning say you do?
I don't know.
Just let me. Let me talk to him
and I will find out.
You have one hour.
Start talking.
You alright?
You ok?
Those bastards have had at me for two days.
They have someone with access
to your father's office.
They are trying to open his safe.
Yeah.
They thought I would know the combination.
But I don't know it.
Yeah well, neither do I, so...
What?
Maurice told me that when he passed.
You were the only one able to open it.
No, he never gave me any combination.
Maybe he did.
I mean, maybe you just didn't know
it was a combination.
Well, what then?
I don't know, some meaningful
combination of numbers...
based on your-your...
your experiences with Maurice.
We didn't have very many...
Meaningful experiences together.
Perhaps after your mother died.
After my mother died.
You know what he told me?
Robert.
There is really...
nothing...
to be said.
Well, he was bad with emotion.
I was 11.
Uncle Peter.
How is he doing?
He is in a lot of pain.
When we get down to the lower levels.
The pain will be less intense.
And if he dies?
Worst case scenario?
When he wakes up.
His mind is completely gone.
Cobb.
I will still honor the arrangement.
I appreciate that Saito but...
when you wake up, you won't even
remember that we had an arrangement.
Limbo is gonna become your reality.
You are gonna be lost down there so long
that...
you are gonna become an old man.
Filled with regret?
Waiting to die alone.
No.
I will come back.
And we will be young men together again.
Breathe.
These people are gonna kill us
if we don't give them the combination.
They just wanna ransom us.
I heard them.
They are gonna lock us in that van.
And then drive it into the river.
Alright. What is in the safe?
Something for you.
Maurice always said
it was his most precious gift to you.
A will.
Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
That's an alternate.
This would supersede the other
if you want it to.
It splits up the component businesses
of Fischer Morrow.
It would be the end
of the entire empire as we know it.
Destroying my whole inheritance?
Why would he suggest such a thing?
I just don't know.
He loved you Robert.
In his own way.
At the end...
he called me in to his deathbed.
He could barely speak.
But he took the trouble...
to tell me one last thing.
He pulled me close.
And I could only make out...
one word.
Disappointed.
When were you in limbo?
You might have the rest of the team
convinced to carry on with this job.
But they don't know the truth.
Truth? What truth?
The truth that, at any minute,
you might bring a freight train
through the wall.
The truth that,
Mal is bursting through your subconscious.
And the truth that.
As we go deeper into Fischer...
we are also going deeper into you.
And...
I am not sure
we are gonna like what we find.
We were working together.
We were exploring the concept
of a dream,
within a dream.
I kept pushing things.
I wanted to go deeper and deeper.
I wanted to go...
further.
I just didn't understand the concept
that hours could turn into years down,
that we could get trapped so deep only...
when we wound up on the shore
of our own subconscious...
we lost sight of what was real.
We created.
We built the world for ourselves.
We did that for years.
We built our own world.
How long were you stuck there?
Something like 50 years.
Jesus.
How could you stand it?
It was not so bad at first.
Feeling like gods.
The problem was knowing
that none of it was real.
Eventually,
it just became impossible
for me to live like that.
And what about for her?
She had locked something away,
something deep inside her.
A truth that she had once known but...
chose to forget.
Limbo became her...
reality.
What happened when you woke up?
Well, to wake up from that after,
after years,
after decades...
to become old souls thrown
back into youth like that?
I knew something was wrong with her.
She just would not admit it.
Eventually, she told me the truth.
She was possessed...
by an idea.
This one very simple idea,
that changed everything.
That our world was not real.
That she needed to wake up
to come back to reality that...
in order to get back home...
we had to kill ourselves.
What about your children?
She thought they were projections,
that our real children were waiting
for us up there somewhere.
I am their mother!
Calm down.
I can tell the difference.
If this is my dream.
Why can't I control this?
Because you don't know you are dreaming!
She was certain
there was nothing I could do...
no matter how much I begged.
No matter how much I pleaded.
She wanted to do it.
But she could not do it alone.
She loved me too much so...
she came up with a plan...
on our anniversary.
Sweetheart, what are you doing?
Join me.
Just,
just step back inside.
Alright?
Just step back inside now, come on.
No.
I am going to jump and
you are coming with me.
No. I am not.
Now, you listen to me.
If you jump,
you are not gonna wake up, remember?
You are gonna die. I am just...
just step back inside.
Come on.
Step back inside
so we can talk about this.
We have talked enough.
Mal.
Come out onto the ledge
or I will jump right now.
Ok.
We are gonna talk about this.
Alright?
I am asking you to take a leap of faith.
No, honey.
No. I can't.
You know I can't do that.
Take a second, think about our children.
Think about James.
Think about Phillipa now.
If I go without you.
They will take them away anyway.
What does that mean?
I filed a letter with our attorney,
explaining how I am fearful
for my safety.
How you have threatened to kill me.
Why did you do this?
I love you Dom.
Why did you?
Why-why would you do this to me?
I have freed you from the guilt
of choosing to leave them.
We are going home,
to our real children.
Oh, no, no, no, Mal, you listen to me.
Alright?
Mal, look at me, please?
You are waiting for a train.
Mal, goddamn it, don't do this!
A train that will take you far away.
James and Phillipa,
are waiting for you!
You know where you hope,
this train will take you,
They are waiting for us!
But you can't know for sure.
Mal, look at me!
But it doesn't matter.
Mal, goddamn it!
Because you will be together.
Mal, listen to me!
Sweetheart!
Look at me!
Mal, no!
Jesus Christ!
She had herself declared sane
by three different psychiatrists.
It made it impossible for me,
to try to explain the nature of her madness.
So I ran.
Right now, or never Cobb.
James! Phillipa!
Come on in! Come on!
Alright, let's go.
I left my children behind and I have been
trying to buy my way back ever since.
Your guilt, defines her.
It's what powers her.
But you are not responsible
for the idea that destroyed her.
And if we are gonna succeed in this,
you have to forgive yourself.
And you are gonna have to confront her.
But you don't have to do that alone.
No, you are not...
I am doing it for the others.
Because they have no idea,
the risk they have taken
coming down here with you.
We have to move.
Time is up.
Alright.
I don't know any combination.
Not consciously, anyway.
How about instinctively?
I got somebody in your father's office
right now ready to tap in the combination.
Give me the first six numbers
that come to your head right now.
I have no idea.
Right now!
I said, right now! Right now!
Five, two, eight, four, nine, one.
You will have to do better than that.
Alright. Bag them.
You are going for a ride.
We are worth more to you alive.
You hear me?
What did you get?
That boy's relationship with his father
is even worse than we imagined.
This helps us how?
The stronger the issues.
The more powerful the catharsis.
How are you going to reconcile
them if they are so estranged?
I am working on that, are not I?
Work faster.
The projections are closing in quick.
We got to break out of here
before we are totally boxed in.
Damn it.
You must not be afraid to dream
a little bigger, darling.
We need to shift his animosity
from his father to his godfather.
Destroy his one positive relationship?
No, we repair his relationship
with his father,
whilst exposing his godfather's
true nature.
We should charge Fischer a lot more
than Saito for this job.
What about his security is gonna
get worse as we go deeper.
No I think we run with Mr. Charles.
No.
Who is Mr. Charles? Bad idea.
The second we get into
that hotel and approach Fischer
his security is gonna be all over us.
We run with Mr. Charles
like on the Stein job.
You have done it before?
Yeah and it didn't work.
The subject realized he was dreaming
and his subconscious tore us to pieces.
Excellent but you learned a lot, right?
I need some kind of distraction.
No problem.
How about a lovely lady
that I have used before?
Listen to me.
You drive carefully, alright?
Everything down there is
gonna be unstable as hell.
Don't jump too soon.
We only got one shot at that kick.
We got to make it.
I will play the music to let you know
it's coming.
The rest is on you.
You ready?
Ready!
Sweet dreams.
Am I boring you?
I was telling you my story.
I guess it was not to your liking.
I have a lot on my mind.
There goes Mr. Charles.
Mr. Fischer,
right?
Pleasure to see you again.
Rod Green from marketing, I...
And you must be?
Leaving.
In case you get bored.
Must have blown you off.
That is, unless her phone number
really is only six digits.
Funny way to make friends.
Someone stealing your wallet like that.
Goddamn it. The wallet alone
is worth at least...
500 dollars right?
Listen don't worry about it.
My people are already on it as we speak.
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer
against his own subconscious.
And why don't you approve?
Because it involves telling the mark
that he is dreaming,
which involves attracting
a lot of attention to us.
Didn't Cobb say never to do that?
So now you have noticed how much time Cobb
spends doing things he says never to do.
Mr. Saito, can I have a moment?
I am sorry, but...
Hold on! Wait!
You look a bit perkier.
Very amusing, Mr. Eames.
Turbulence on the plane?
No, it's much closer.
That's Yusuf's driving.
I am sorry.
Who did you say you were?
Rod Green from marketing.
But that's not true at all, is it?
My name is Mr. Charles.
You remember me, don't you?
I am the head of your security down here.
Get out on a different floor.
Keep moving.
Dump the wallet.
Security will be looking for that.
Ok.
We need to buy Cobb a little more time.
Security?
You work for the hotel?
No, no.
I specialize in a very specific type
of security.
Subconscious security.
You are talking about dreams?
Are you talking about...
extraction?
I am here to protect you.
Mr. Fischer I am here to protect you,
in the event that someone
tries to access your mind
through your dreams.
You are not safe here.
They are coming for you.
Strange weather, isn't it?
You feel that?
What's happening?
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention
to the strangeness of the dream,
which is making his subconscious
look for the dreamer.
For me.
Quick, give me a kiss.
They are still looking at us.
Yeah, it was worth a shot.
We should probably get out of here.
You feel that?
You have actually been trained
for this, Mr. Fischer.
Pay attention to the strangeness
of the weather, the shift in gravity.
None of this is real.
You are in a dream.
Now, the easiest way for you
to test yourself
is to try and remember how
you arrived at this hotel.
Can you do that?
Yeah, I...
No, breathe, breathe.
Remember your training.
Accept the fact that you are in a dream.
And I am here to protect you.
Go on.
You are not real?
No.
I am a projection of your subconscious.
I was sent here to protect you in the event
that extractors tried to pull you into a dream.
And I believe that's what's
going on right now, Mr. Fischer.
Yeah.
Ok.
Can you get me out of here?
Right away.
Follow me.
Hold on a second.
Jesus Christ! What are you doing?
These men were sent here
to abduct you, alright?
If you want my help.
You have to remain calm.
I need you to work with me, Mr. Fischer.
If this is a dream.
I should just kill myself
to wake up, right?
I would not do that if I were you.
Mr. Fischer.
I believe they have you sedated.
And if you pull that trigger...
you may not wake up.
You may go into a further
dream state, now...
you know what I am talking about.
You remember the training.
Remember what I said to you.
Give me the gun.
This room should be directly below 528?
Yeah.
Think, Mr. Fischer, think.
What do you remember,
from before this dream?
There was...
there was a lot of gunfire.
rain.
Uncle Peter.
Oh, my God, we have been kidnapped.
Where were they holding you?
They had us in the back of a van.
That explains the gravity shifts.
You are in the back of a van right now,
keep going.
It had something to do with...
Something to do with a safe.
God, why is it so hard to remember?
It's like trying to remember a dream
after you have woken up.
Listen, it takes years of practice.
You and Browning,
have been pulled into this dream
because they are trying to steal
something from your mind.
I need you to focus and try
and remember what that is.
What is it, Mr. Fischer? Think!
A combination.
They demanded the first
numbers to pop into my head.
They are trying to extract a number
from your subconscious.
It can represent anything.
We are in a hotel right now.
We should try hotel rooms.
What was the number, Mr. Fischer?
Try and remember for me,
this is very important.
Five.
Five, two.
It was something.
It was a long number.
That's good enough we can start there.
Fifth floor.
Yep.
So do you use a timer?
No. I have to judge it for myself.
Or while you are all asleep in 528.
I wait for Yusuf's kick.
Well, how will you know?
His music warns me.
And then when the van hits
the barrier of the bridge,
that should be unmistakable.
So we get a nice,
synchronized kick.
If it's too soon.
We won't get pulled out.
But if it's too late.
I won't be able to drop us.
Well, why not?
Because the van will be in free fall.
Can't drop you without gravity.
Right.
They are with me.
Go on.
Mr. Charles.
Do you know what that is, Mr. Fischer?
Yeah. I think so. Yeah.
They were trying to put you under.
I am already under.
Under again.
What do you mean.
A dream within a dream?
Hey.
I see you have changed.
I am sorry?
Oh. I am sorry.
I mistook you for a friend.
Good-looking fellow. I am sure.
No, no, no.
That's Fischer's projection of Browning.
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
Why?
Because how he acts will tell us,
if Fischer is starting to suspect
his motives the way we want him to.
Uncle Peter.
You said you were kidnapped together?
Well, well, not exactly.
They al-They already had him.
They were torturing him.
And you saw them torture him?
The kidnappers are working for you?
Robert.
You are trying to get that safe open?
To get the alternate will?
Fischer Morrow has been my entire life.
I can't let you destroy it.
I am not gonna throw away
my inheritance, what would I?
I could not let you rise
to your father's last taunt.
What taunt?
The will Robert.
That will?
That's his last insult.
A challenge for...
you to build something for yourself,
by telling you, you are not worthy
of his accomplishments.
What, but that he was...
disappointed?
I am sorry.
But...
he is wrong.
You can build a better company
than he ever did.
Mr. Fischer?
He is lying.
How do you know?
Trust me, it's what I do.
He is hiding something.
And we need to find out what that is.
I need you to do the same thing to him
that he was going to do to you.
We will enter his subconscious and find out
what he doesn't want you to know.
Alright.
He is out.
Wait.
Whose subconscious are
we going into exactly?
We are going into Fischer's.
I told him it was Browning
so he would be a part of our team.
He is gonna help us break
into his own subconscious.
That's right.
Security is gonna run you down hard.
And I will lead them on a merry chase.
Just be back before the kick.
Go to sleep, Mr. Eames.
You good?
Hey. You ready?
Yes, yes. Some...
I am fine. I am ready.
Cobb?
What's down there?
Hopefully, the truth we want Fischer to learn.
I mean, what's down there for you?
Did you see that?
Eames, this is your dream.
I need you to draw the security away
from the complex, you understand?
Who guides Fischer in?
Not me.
If I know the route.
Everything could be compromised.
I designed the place.
No, you are with me.
I could do it.
Alright. You brief him on the route
into the complex.
Fischer,
you will be going with him.
Alright.
What about you?
You keep this live.
I will be listening in the whole time.
The windows on that upper floor,
are big enough for me to cover
you from that tower, you see?
You are not coming in?
In order to find out the truth
about your father,
you are gonna need to break
into Browning's mind on your own.
Come on Fischer!
Sound the alarm!
Go, go, go!
Move!
Go!
Sod it.
I hope you are ready.
No, it's too soon.
Cobb, do you hear that?
I first noticed it about 20 minutes ago.
I thought it was the wind up here.
Yeah, I hear it.
It's music.
So, what do we do?
We move fast.
Yusuf is 10 seconds from the jump.
Which gives Arthur three minutes.
Hey!
That's him!
Which gives us what?
Sixty minutes.
Can they make that route in an hour?
They have to climb to the terrace.
Then they need a new route.
A more direct route.
It's designed as a labyrinth.
There must be access routes
that cut through the maze, right?
Eames?
Did Eames add any features?
I don't think I should tell you.
If Mal was after...
We don't have time for this.
Did he add anything?
He added an air-duct system
that can cut through the maze.
Good. Explain it to them.
Saito?
Go ahead.
Paradox.
What was that?
The kick.
Cobb!
Cobb, did we miss it?
Yeah, we missed it.
Man.
Could not someone...
have dreamt up...
a goddamn beach?
What the hell do we do now?
We finish the job before the next kick.
What next kick?
When the van hits the water.
If you would like to make a call,
please hang up and try again.
If you need help, hang up...
How do I drop you without gravity?
Arthur has a couple minutes.
And we have about 20.
You ok?
Run! Turn around!
Move to base!
There is something wrong.
They are heading your way.
Like they know something.
Just buy us more time, alright?
Come on!
On my way.
Come on! Move!
Alright.
Ok. That's the antechamber
outside the strong room.
Does the strong room have windows?
It would not be very strong if it did.
Let's hope Fischer likes
what he finds in there.
Are those projections his subconscious?
Yes.
Are you destroying parts of his mind?
No. They are just projections.
We are here.
You are clear, but hurry there is
an entire army headed your way.
I am in.
There he is.
There is someone in there.
Fischer, it's a trap. Get out.
Come on. Come on, a little lower.
Cobb.
No she...
She is not real.
How do you know that?
She is just a projection.
Fischer. Fischer is real.
Hello.
Eames!
Eames, get to the antechamber now!
What happened?
Mal killed Fischer.
I could not shoot her.
There is no use in reviving him.
His mind is already trapped down there.
It's all over.
So that's it then, we failed?
We are done.
I am sorry.
Well, it's not me that doesn't get back
to my family, is it?
It's a shame, I really wanted to know
what was going to happen in there.
I swear we had this one.
Let's set the charges.
Wait, there is still another way!
We just have to follow Fischer down there.
Not enough time.
No, but there will be enough time
down there.
And we will find him.
Ok, as soon as Arthur's music kicks in.
Just use the defibrillator to revive him.
We can give him his own kick
down below.
Look, you get him in there.
As soon as the music ends.
You blow up the hospital...
and we all ride the kick
back up the layers.
Hope it's worth a shot,
if Saito can hold the guards
off while I set the charges.
Saito will never make it, will he?
Cobb, come on.
We have got to try this.
Go for it.
If you are not back before the kick.
I am gone with or without you.
She is right.
Come on. Let's go.
Can I trust you to do
what needs to happen here?
I mean, Mal is gonna be down there.
I know where to find her.
She will have Fischer.
How do you know?
Because...
she wants me to come after him.
She wants me back down there with her.
Alright?
This is your world?
It was.
And this is where she will be.
Come on.
Saito.
I need you...
I need you to take care of Fischer
while I go set some charges, ok?
No room for tourists on these jobs.
Don't be silly.
You built all this?
This is incredible.
We built for years.
Then we started in on the memories.
This way.
This was our neighborhood.
Places from our past.
That was our first apartment.
Then we moved to that building
right there.
After Mal became pregnant.
That became our home.
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
Like I told you, we had lots of time.
What is that?
That's the house Mal grew up.
Well, will she be in there?
No.
Come on.
We both wanted to live in a house.
But we loved this type of building.
In the real world.
We would have to choose but not here.
How are we gonna bring Fischer back?
We are gonna have to come up
with some kind of a kick.
What?
I am gonna improvise.
Listen, there is something
you should know about me.
About inception.
An idea is like a virus.
Resilient.
Highly contagious.
And the smallest seed
of an idea can grow.
It can grow to define...
or destroy you.
A smallest idea such as,
Your world is not real.
Simple little thought,
that changes everything.
So certain of your world...
of what's real.
Do you think he is?
Or do you think he is as lost as I was?
I know what's real, Mal.
No creeping doubts?
Not feeling persecuted Dom?
Chased around the globe by anonymous
corporations and police forces,
the way the projections
persecute the dreamer?
Admit it.
You don't believe in one reality anymore.
So choose.
Choose to be here.
Choose me.
You know what I have to do.
I have to get back to our children
because you left them.
Because you left us.
You are wrong.
I am not wrong.
You are confused.
Our children are here.
And you would like to see their faces again.
Would not you?
Yes, but I am gonna see them up above Mal.
Up above?
Listen to yourself.
These are our children.
Watch.
James? Phillipa?
Don't do this Mal. Please.
Those are not my children.
You keep telling yourself that.
But you don't believe it.
No. I know it.
What if you are wrong?
What if I am what's real?
You keep telling yourself what you know.
But what do you believe?
What do you feel?
Guilt.
I feel guilt, Mal.
And no matter what I do. No...
No matter how hopeless I am.
No matter how confused.
That guilt...
is always there,
reminding me of the truth.
What truth?
The idea,
that caused you to question
your reality came from me.
You planted the idea in my mind?
What is she talking about?
The reason I knew inception was possible,
was because I...
did it to her first.
I did it to my own wife.
Why?
We were lost in here.
I knew we needed to escape but...
she would not accept it.
She had locked something away,
something...
something deep inside.
A truth that she had once known but...
chose to forget.
And she could not break free.
So I decided to search for it.
I went deep into the recess of her mind,
and found that secret place.
And I broke in...
and I planted an idea.
A simple little idea
that would change everything.
That her world was not real.
That death was the only escape.
You are waiting for a train.
A train that will take you far away.
You know where you hope
this train will take you...
but you can't know for sure.
Yet it doesn't matter.
Now, tell me why!
Because you will be together!
But I never knew that,
that idea would grow in her mind like
a cancer that even after she woke.
That even after
you came back to reality...
that you would continue to believe
your world was not real.
That death was the only escape.
Mal, no! Jesus!
You infected my mind.
I was trying to save you.
You betrayed me.
But you can make amends.
You can still keep your promise.
We can still be together,
right here...
in the world we built together.
Cobb.
We need to get Fischer.
You can't have him.
If I stay here, will you let him go?
What are you talking about?
Fischer is on the porch.
Go check he is alive Ariadne.
Cobb, you can't do this.
Go check he is alive right now.
Do it.
He is here! And it's time.
But you have to come now!
You take Fischer with you, alright?
You can't stay here to be with her.
I am not.
Saito is dead by now.
That means he is down here somewhere.
That means I have to find him.
I can't stay with her anymore.
Because she doesn't exist.
I am the only thing
you do believe in anymore.
No.
I wish.
I wish more than anything but...
I can't imagine you with
all your complexity,
all your perfection, all your imperfection.
You alright?
Yeah.
Look at you.
You are just a shade.
You are just a shade of my real wife.
And you were the best that I could do but...
I am sorry, you are just not good enough.
Does this feel real?
What are you doing?
Improvising.
No, no, no!
In there, now. Go, go, go, go.
I was...
dis...
I was dis...
disap...
I know Dad.
Dis...
I know you were disappointed...
I could not be you.
No.
No, no, no, no.
I was disappointed...
that you tried.
What?
Come on, come on.
Dad?
That's the kick Ariadne!
You have to go now!
Don't lose yourself!
Find Saito and bring him back!
I will!
You remember when you asked me
to marry you?
Yes.
You said you dreamt
that we would grow old together.
But we did.
We did. You don't remember?
I miss you more than I can bear...
but we had our time together.
And I have to let you go.
I have to let you go.
I am sorry Robert.
You know, the will means that Dad
wanted me to be my own man...
not just to live for him.
That's what I am gonna do Uncle Peter.
What happened?
Cobb stayed.
With Mal?
No, to find Saito.
He will be lost.
No, he will be alright.
Have you come to kill me?
I am waiting for someone.
Someone from a half-remembered dream.
Cobb?
Impossible.
We were young men together.
I am an old man.
Filled with regret.
Waiting to die alone.
I have come back for you.
To remind you...
of something.
Something you once knew.
That this world is not real.
To convince me to honor
our arrangement?
To take a leap of faith, yes.
Come back...
so we can be young men together again.
Come back with me.
Come back.
Hot towel sir?
We will be landing in Los Angeles
in about 20 minutes.
Do you need immigration forms?
Thank you.
Hot towel sir?
No.
Do you need immigration forms?
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
Thank you, sir.
Welcome.
This way.
James?
Phillipa?
Look who is here.
Hey.
Hey, guys!
Hey! How are you?
Daddy! Daddy!
Daddy!
How are you?
Look what I have been building!
What are you building?
We are building a house on the cliff!
On the cliff? Come on.
I want you to show me.
Can you show me?
Let's go. Come on.
Daddy!
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections August 2022