An American, Colonel.
He was at the gate,
impersonating an Officer.
Take him upstairs.
A moment. Please!
Stop! I must speak to the Commander.
Colonel. I found it!
Do as he says. Open it.
The Lance of Longinus.
The blade that drew Christ's blood.
The Holy Lance.
Double the guard.
This is the prize the Führer seeks.
Colonel, we need to talk.
No time, Doctor.
The train to Berlin is waiting.
Search the woods!
Take the dogs.
Do you think that spy was alone?
Go! Go! Go! We're moving out!
On the double!
This man was with the American.
This is the American's bag.
What have I done?
Bring him to my carriage.
Careful.
This is the Führer's special relic!
Stay seated.
So...
you are a birdwatcher?
Yes. Because of the bombing,
the wagtails are following
a completely different trajectory.
We caught your accomplice.
The American.
There is a problem.
I must speak to the Colonel.
It's urgent.
I must speak with the Colonel.
It's about the Lance.
I only had a moment to look at it.
Of course, my training is in physics,
For God's sake, spit it out!
The Lance...
It's a fake.
A fake?
The blade is an alloy.
Fifty years old,
the engravings recent. It's a replica.
We're dead.
There is another relic on this train.
One with real power.
What are you talking about?
The Antikythera.
The Antikythera?!
Enough about that old dial!
Colonel, the Führer has lost the war...
and his mind!
Let me explain.
The Antikythera's
power is not supernatural.
It is mathematics.
Whoever harnesses it...
will not be King...
nor Emperor...
or Führer.
He will be God.
And how do you propose we tell him this?
My Führer,
I'm sorry the Lance of Christ is fake.
But here is...
half of something you've never heard of.
Tell me,
have you ever MET HITLER?!!
A saboteur aboard.
And Hitler's Lance is gone.
That way!
What are you doing here?!
Who are you?
They have the Antikythera!
Drop the gun.
Give me the Antikythera.
Time to destination?
60 seconds.
30 seconds.
20 seconds.
15 seconds.
10 seconds.
9!
8!
7!
6!
Turn around!
Abort!
ABORT!!!
We're being pulled in!
What are you doing?!
This is my plane!
You're flying my plane!
We're going to DIE!!!
We need to pull up!
Restart engines!
Setting coordinates for Munich.
Master...
The Romans are getting closer.
They have dragons!
Master...
Don't ride out there, Master!
The dragons!!
We must take down their dragons!
Change course!
The portal closes in minutes!
I have to go back!
I can't be here!
I CAN'T STAY HERE!!
The plane won't make it!!
We're losing altitude!
We're going down!
I've lost control!
Eureka.
Master!
We have to leave, Master.
Two thousand years.
We've come...
two thousand years.
But we didn't expect to meet...
the great...
Archimedes.
You...
were always...
going to...
meet me.
Apologies, Archimedes.
I'm a fan...
but we need to leave. He's hurt.
I want...
to stay...
with you.
You are a brilliant man...
a wise man...
a genius...
a hero to your people.
But he can't help you.
This is your time.
He must be in his own time!