Subtitle by Sailor420
Hope you enjoy the show
That's them in there just like that?
Just like that.
I wouldn't go in there for a day or two.
Heard the expression kick the hornet's nest?
I'll stay right here. Thank you.
Those things scare me to death.
They been killing my honey bees.
A few days unchecked,
they'll wipe out the whole colony.
What are you gonna do with them?
Well, that's between me and them,
if you don't mind.
That's okay.
I understand these things.
I just wanted to thank you
for putting up with me,
and all of my bees.
This place was crabgrass and weeds,
and you brought it back to life.
You're a blessing.
No one's ever taken care of me before.
I'll, uh...
Mr. Clay...
Come back at suppertime. Let me feed you.
Boss.
- (man) You got something, yeah?  - I got one.
I want it. I need it.
Hey, put it in my ear.
Get this fucking hippie shit down, please.
United Data Group. Good afternoon. This is Boyd.
How may I help you?
Boyd.
Uh, hello. I just got a message saying
that there's a problem with my computer.
Don't you worry. The message you received
is from our United Data Group antivirus software.
It's part of the software package
that you pre-installed on your computer.
I'm sorry. I'm not a computer person.
What did you say the name of your product is again?
Now, our records show that you actually
have an older version on your account.
So what I'm going to need you to do is uninstall that
and install the latest version.
Well, I have no idea how to do that.
My daughter set up everything for me.
Well, I would recommend
you take your computer to an IT specialist.
However, keep in mind
that you will lose all your data,
since they'll have to replace the hard drive.
I'm pretty remote out here.
Everything I have is on the computer.
Okay. There is actually
a software package that you can download
that would allow me to reinstall remotely.
All right. Tell me what to do.
It's okay. Can you, uh, can you type this,
Friendly friend dot net?
Spelled just how it sounds.
Okay. I'm there.
And there should be a button
on your screen that says "install."
Can you click on that button?
I clicked the button.
So you're about to see some windows
open, close on your desktop,
as I reinstall the virus shield for you.
Okay.
I hope you fucking clowns are paying attention.
You stick to the script,
but not so much that you sound like a goddamn robot.
All right?
Boyd: She has got 10K checking,
life insurance annuity, Roth IRA,
teacher's pension and...
Holy fucking shit!
All right.
She is a signatory
on a $2 million dollar account.
Some, uh... It's some fucking charity.
All right, kids, let the strip mining begin.
Ooh. My computer's going crazy.
Totally normal.
Just do not touch your keyboard.
Because of this inconvenience,
I'm going to credit back your subscription fees.
How about that?
I've gone ahead and deposited $500
into the account ending 020.
Oh, that's not my account.
That's an account that I manage.
Can you log into that account
and verify the transfer, please, Miss Parker?
Just hold on.
Yes, there's...
There's a transfer for $50,000?
Set the hook with sympathy.
Miss Parker, I...
I made a terrible mistake.
I was supposed to credit you 500,
but I don't know, I got a stuck key here.
I'm gonna lose my job here.
I got kids.
I ain't got fucking kids.
Oh, I don't want you to get in trouble, but...
I could wire the amount back.
I will need a different password though.
One second.
This is the master password for all her accounts.
Okay, so the second we get it, we zero out everything.
Um...
You know, I, um...
I think I should call the bank. Hm?
You know what? You're probably right.
But there goes my job,
and there goes all your data.
All my kids' pictures are on this computer.
Okay.
Boom! Fucking yes!
That is what I am talking about! Come on!
Let me fucking hear it! I fucking love you people!
I fucking love you!
Hello?
Hello? You still there?
Uh-oh.
Oh.
What did I do?
Stupid...
Mrs. Parker?
Don't move.
Don't you fucking move.
Drop the knife.
Hands behind your back.
Slowly get on your knees one knee at a time.
Now, who the fuck are you...
and what are you doing in my mother's house?
Verona...
I'm so sorry.
How do you know my...
Mom.
(agent) Until we can clear him, he's our best and only perp.
Clear him?
Agent Parker, I know that's your mother.
I understand.
But there's a world where she committed suicide.
Suicide? You can't be serious.
That woman loved life more than anybody I know.
But by all means, let's just completely ignore
the big white dude in her house with a knife.
Get him up.
Come on.
(agent 2) It's Clay, right?
Adam Clay?
I don't have much to say.
Mr. Clay, we just got a couple of questions.
Like, what the fuck were you doing
in my mother's house?
I was bringing her a jar of honey.
A jar of honey.
Who the fuck are you? Winnie-the-Pooh?
I keep bees.
How do you know my mother?
I rent some space in the barn from her.
I have a signed lease.
But what the fuck were you doing in her house?
She didn't answer when I knocked.
I noted her car in the driveway.
I heard the smoke alarm and I entered.
You "noted"?
You got a law enforcement background?
I told you, I take care of bees.
Oh, my God.
(agent 2) His hands tested negative for gunshot residue.
But the prints on the gun were your mother's.
It seems, sadly, it was suicide.
Mr. Clay, I need to apologize for last night.
I realize I may have been a little aggressive.
That's understandable.
Could I interest you in something a bit stronger?
No.
But I'll sit with you if you like.
No, thank you.
I wanted to thank you
for taking care of my mom.
I tried to stay in her life as much as I could.
Obviously, I could have done a better job.
Being old can be a lonely thing.
Turn a certain age, you cease to exist. Cease to matter.
Used to be a part of life, of the family.
Part of the hive, I guess you could say.
There's some British Isles hiding in your accent.
I was born there.
I hated that she was out here alone.
She wouldn't leave.
There's too many memories.
You know, I think I know why she liked you.
You're just like my brother.
He was in MARSOC, a Marine Raider.
He was killed a few years ago kicking doors.
She loved him.
He'd mow the lawn
and you'd think he invented fire.
You know, while I graduated the FBI Academy
and she said, "Oh, that's nice."
She got scammed.
Somebody emptied out all her accounts,
her savings, her retirement.
Got every penny. Maxed out all her cards.
She was an educator,
director of a charity for kids.
They got two million out of that account.
You know who did it?
I talked to an agent in our cyber-crimes office.
This crew's been operating for two years
and we don't even have names.
And even if we did, good luck building an indictment
that would stand up in court.
Some defense attorney would just argue that
the elderly victim agreed
to wire a complete stranger his entire life savings.
Taking from an elderly person
is as bad as stealing from a child.
Maybe worse.
Someone hurts a child,
there are parents.
People who care, ready to step in.
Someone hurts an older person...
sometimes they're left to face the hornets alone.
Because either it goes unnoticed...
or no one cares.
I care.
And I'm stubborn.
And so help me God,
I'm going to get these motherfuckers who did this.
I need to take care of the hive.
You've been up all night.
Clay: The hive is more important.
What are you doing?
- I thought you retired.  - Clay: I did.
I need a favor.
What kind of favor?
A name and address.
- Easy.  - Not easy.
Even the FBI can't find these people.
Well, we're not the FBI, are we?
Shoot me the deets and stand by.
Yeah.
You weren't kidding. This one kicked my butt.
They're routing all over the world.
But you found them?
Sure. But who are these people?
I'm gonna find out.
(guard) Whoa, whoa, whoa!
The hell you think you're going, pal?
This United Data Group?
Don't know nothing about that.
This is private property, and you're trespassing.
I'm going inside.
I'm going to burn it down.
Yeah, that's not happening, buddy.
You're not going any-fucking-where
except right the fuck back the way you came.
Do you know what they do here?
Buddy, I'm counting to three.
One, two, three.
There. I did it for you.
You aware this is a criminal outfit?
Scamming the weakest in our society.
Stealing everything they have.
Do you know that's who you work for?
Clay: I'm looking for the call center.
Yeah, you're in the right place.
You just have to sign in here.
Tell any other companies in the building
to evacuate now.
- There's going to be a fire.  - Okay. Th...
Thanks.
Hang up the phone.
Nah, I'm good, buddy. I'm just doing my thing here.
Uh, Miss Perkins, so sorry, I'll have to
- call you right back.  - Everyone...
I need your attention, please.
Repeat after me.
I will never steal from the weak
and the vulnerable again.
(man) I sent you a department download,
and we'll find out what's going on...
Repeat after me.
I will never steal from the weak
and the vulnerable again.
(scammers) I will never steal from the weak
To help you keep that promise,
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
Might be a good time to go home.
(man 2) Oh, my God!
- (man 3) It's gas!   - (man 4) Fucking psycho.
It's gas!
It's gas! It's gas!
Boyd: Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What the fuck, bro?
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
I'm a beekeeper.
I protect the hive.
Sometimes I use fire to smoke out hornets.
This a multi-million dollar operation, asshole.
Okay, so you can't come up here,
white-knighting shit.
Will you stomp his ass out, please?
I got it. You fucking get him.
You fucking get him!
Bet you feel really proud of yourself.
Mister...?
Uh...
- Uh, uh, Garnett.  - Mr. Garnett.
I don't care if your friends here live or die.
The next call from your little phishing scam
to this call center
will make a spark across these wires.
Given all of the gasoline fumes in here,
I promise you...
anything alive in here won't be.
Uh, guys, we might want to dip out.
Hey. What's going on?
Uh, let me get flat white, oat milk, of course,
and, uh, extra shot of espresso.
- Of course, sir.  - Thank you.
Good morning. Did we get the otoro and the uni in?
- Yes, sure.  - We did?
- Yes.  - Fucking finally. Great.
- Hey, Michaela.  - Yes.
It... it came back. The whole thing. Yeah.
And it's like I can barely fucking move.
It's all tweaked.
- Oh, those are nice.  - (woman) Mmm-hmm.
- Those the new bowls?  - Yeah.
- That's perfect. Thank you.  - (woman) Mmm-hmm.
What? I'm in a meeting.
Garnett: You said hit me on voice
if there's an emergency.
Okay. Right. Well, uh...
It seems we had a disgruntled customer.
Uh, I just can't comprehend why you're bothering me.
Just get in touch with the attorney
and start shoving back.
Well, yeah, I don't think that legal's gonna help much.
Okay, tell me what the fuck is going on right now.
This dude just strolls in
saying we're stealing from people,
and he just tears through all my security guys,
like, fucking tissue paper and, um...
And what?
And he burns the place to the ground.
Yeah. The call center is gone.
I'm standing here staring at a $30 million building,
it's now a giant fucking ashtray.
Four people didn't get out.
You're telling me that this asshole
burnt the entire building down
and dropped four fucking bodies?
Yeah, that's not exactly a disgruntled customer, is it?
Who did this? Give me a name right now.
Sir, I don't have it.
All the cameras and the drives burned up in the fire.
He had a hat.
Oh, he had a hat. Okay.
I'm gonna hit you back. All right?
I got to go big-dog this shit for a minute.
- Hey, I need to talk to you.  - About what?
What? What? No, nothing.
I mean, if I had a friend who, like, had a call center
and someone burned it down, maybe killed some people,
you could get him, right?
Get him?
Yeah, like disappear the problem.
Come on.
I'll be an hour.
That's way above my pay grade.
You literally ran the CIA,
and you're telling me you can't just find
some guy in Massachusetts?
Listen, this sounds like a job for the police.
I just need a name.
Well, you won't get it from me.
And you keep me a million miles away
from your metaverse meth lab
or whatever it is.
Yup.
So check it out.
Daddy can't hold your hand on this one.
Uh, this is clearly some kind of crime of passion,
spur of the moment,
someone snapped, like, whatever.
But, uh, what we're going to do is
I'm going to send you some credentials,
you're going to log into our cloud
and you're going to look at anyone connected
to the last few deals you closed. All right?
Just, I don't know, start there.
And, like, what if I find this guy?
Then what?
You get a wrecking crew together
and you go Goodfellas on him.</font>
I mean, come on, you're a connected guy, right?
Do you understand?
Yeah. No, I understand. I, uh...
I'll get it done.
It's called a day off.
(man) V, you good?
Yeah, I'm great. Why?
I mean, you did lose your mother yesterday.
Yeah.
What do you want, Wiley?
Are you leaving? Please don't go.
(woman) I'm going to yoga.
Remember United Data Group?
Go on.
You sober enough to drive?
Yeah.
Give us a few seconds, thank you.
Where's mine?
It's an old cup from my car
with instant and gas station hot water.
Ew.
- You want a sip?  - No.
So the fire fried all the CCTV footage.
Receptionist said she saw some jacked dude in his 40s,
manhandled security and walked in
with a couple gas cans.
This clown car saw everything, but no one's talking.
They're all frequent fliers with perjury,
fraud and cyber BeEFs.
Fucking scumbags. I want IDs on all of them.
You know, this is just the tip of, like, 20 spears, right?
Can I just have this moment?
Eloise Parker.
Yeah, I took her for over two million yesterday.
She's, uh... she's Black,
widow, just has a daughter in Boston.
I don't think this is it, but, you know.
You said your boy has an old-ass pickup truck.
That's him.
What the hell are those?
Fucking beehives.
Yeah, dickhead was talking about them.
I guess he's a, like, bee lover.
You know what?
He breaks my shit, you break his shit.
Where you at, bee boy?
You fucking hiding, bitch?
Come out and fucking face us!
Bye, bitch, now!
Let's go!
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
Can someone, like, fucking help me?
Fuck.
No! I'm okay.
We can talk about this.
Let's just work this out, me and you. We can fix...
No, no!
Oh, fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Verona: So, help me understand because I'm a little confused.
What's the nature of your business?
Don't know nothing about no business.
So then why are people just wiring you
their entire life savings?
Must be your winning personality.
They got us lawyers,
so maybe you want to talk to them.
You know, this is a really nice shirt, by the way.
Did you steal it out of a casket, you dog fucker?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Uh...
Verona, if you're done shitting all over
this gentleman's civil rights,
can I speak to you for a moment?
That's a nice shirt.
- V.  - Yeah, I know. I know.
I'm an asshole.
Oh, so you like fires?
Yeah, today I do.
Good, 'cause, uh, today's your lucky day.
'Cause apparently, your mother's house
is on fire, too, and some other shit.
- Let's go.  - Wait. What?
Wiley: Yeah. Shit's on fire. Let's go.
You good?
V, you okay?
Yeah.
- That's a new one.  - Jesus Christ.
Where's Maggie? Hey, Maggie, ID?
- United Data Group.  - Wiley: Well, he's handsome.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, Wiley, I'm good. I'm good.
You think there's even the remotest chance
that the dude who burned down United Data Group
is the same guy renting this spot
from your mother?
The beekeeper.
I lost my virginity in that barn.
Fucking shit.
The universe is going to have to wait.
I gotta take this.
Yo, what's up, playa?
This is the part where you tell me
what a good job you did,
and I put you on a G6 to Hawaii to chill for a week.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Danforth.
Did you fuck this up?
Are you fucking crying right now?
I'm not crying. I'm bleeding.
Bleeding? Why are you bleeding?
What do you mean, bleeding?
My fingers on my right hand.
He cut them off.
Okay. Fuck off. Go. Go.
He? Who the fuck is he? Tell me who he is right now.
I don't know. A fucking beekeeper.
Makes honey and fucks with beehives.
He fucks with beehives? What's he saying about bees?
I don't know. He said he was, like,
protecting the hive or something.
Oh, fuck, man. What the...
Oh, Jesus Christ!
No, no, no! Bro, bro, bro!
What do you want from me?
You want money? You want crypto? NFTs?
I got fucking NFTs.
What are you fucking... What?
No! Dude, what the fuck is this, man?
Don't move.
I fucking can't move!
You're fucking crazy, man.
What the fuck, bro?
What the fuck! No, no, no, no! No, no, no!
Fucking stop the fucking car! No! No!
Who do I have the pleasure of speaking with?
Fuck you. That's who.
You burned down my million-dollar
fucking call center.
Now I'm going to burn you down.
You haven't told me your name.
I told you my name.
It's fuck you. Mr. Fuck You.
You better fucking remember it.
Because you don't burn me down.
I burn you down. You understand me?
You are fucking with forces that you cannot comprehend.
You sound young.
I bet you don't have estate planning.
I'm fucking 28 years old. Why would I need that?
I'm about to show you.
(reporter) Breaking news in Springfield,
where three bodies have been discovered
following an arson fire at a small farm.
There was an office building explosion...
- And you say one guy did this?  - (man) Yup.
Killed seven armed men without firing a shot.
Yup. And he said he was going to kill me.
And this is your
data mining consumer service business, right?
Yes, something like that.
Pulling in 9 million a month in one office.
I've got, like, 20.
Yeah.
And the only thing you know about him
is he says he's a beekeeper.
Yeah, it's like his whole brand or whatever.
Jesus.
What?
For someone who has elevated fucking up into an art form,
this might well be your Mona Lisa.
How did I fuck up?
I don't know. You've done something.
You've disturbed a Beekeeper.
Oh.
Oh, okay. So fucking what?
Why'd I care if the guy keeps bees?
If a Beekeeper says you're gonna die,
you're gonna die.
There's nothing I can do or anybody else to stop it.
So, like, what do you even do here, then?
What good are you?
Yeah.
I did 35 years of loyal government service,
culminating as director of the world's
premier intelligence agency.
I could have done anything,
but I chose this job as a favor to your mother.
I keep Danforth Enterprises safe.
Keep her reputation safe, her name safe.
It's my fucking name too, all right?
Oh, sit down.
I put up with you.
I've put up with your tantrums,
kept you out of the tabloids, kept you out of jail.
The endless stream of sex workers.
You're a drowning man. Do you know that?
Mm.
You're scared.
Dead right I'm scared.
Terrified. So should you be.
Wallace, just tell me what the fuck this guy is.
He's probably the last pair of eyes
that you're going to sneer at.
Verona: Okay, listen.
Remember our favorite burning building?
United Data Group.
The guys who work there are hackers,
con men, fraudsters, et cetera, et cetera.
Guy who ran it. Garnett.
He's in the book. He's a known mob associate.
He's missing, but I've got PD chasing him down.
Okay, so I had some analysts run some shit,
and I think I'm starting to get the shape of the animal.
Dude, I think United Data Group
is one of several call centers.
So there's got to be like a central office
that's controlling all of them,
and that's what we got to find.
Wiley, this could be like
a billion-dollar-a-year operation.
- Hello?  - Hey!
Did you hear a single word I just said?
Yeah.
And?
I was just thinking you come in here,
hungover on your day off,
and gain more yardage on this thing
than the whole squad has in two years.
Yeah, well, they fucked with my family.
What'd you get on Clay?
- Your beekeeper?  - Yeah.
He's a ghost.
What?
Yeah, all I have is a birth certificate
and a social.
The guy's never even -
had a bank account,
credit card, flown on a plane.
I ran his prints through every database
I can think of, no hits.
That's bullshit.
This dude is former military all day.
No hits. I'm telling you.
Either he's never been printed,
or Adam Clay doesn't exist.
Which is terrifying to me
because he's probably in a classified program.
Special Agent Wiley.
Okay.
- Let's go.  - What?
- They found the guy, Garnett.  - What?
- They found him. Let's go.  - Oh, shit.
Jessica.
Jessica: I think you know why I'm calling.
You know, I'd do anything for you.
Anything for you.
Derek's scared shitless.
I've never seen him this scared.
Well, he's made his bed.
I'll give you a board seat on the holding company.
That's another million a year.
Plus you promised you'd take care of him.
Look, I don't need that. I have enough.
So you got this?
Yeah. You have my word.
Wallace...
I still think of you...
sometimes.
Sometimes.
Why are you calling me
on the "never call this line" line?
This is priority one, Janet.
Well, if it was priority one, I would know about it.
Look, I'm heading downtown to a POTUS brief.
Just hear me out.
Now, you know who I work for, don't you?
Oh, yeah. God help you, Wallace.
Exactly.
Well, Director Harward,
my young friend, seems to have caught
the unwanted attentions of...
I don't know how else to say this.
Of a Beekeeper.
Wait, a Beekeeper Beekeeper?
As in.
- Well, that's not good.  - No, it's not.
- What's the body count?  - Seven today.
You busy making funeral arrangements?
I need help, Janet. Not jokes.
Is that Garnett?
He was strapped to an old pickup.
Check this out.
Does this mean you've taken pity on an old man?
So your problem? He's retired from the program.
No longer active.
Well, that changes everything.
The current active Beekeeper is aware of the issue
and is going to be taking things from here.
You can rest easy, old friend.
Oh, no. Janet.
The current active Beekeeper is a fucking lunatic
who should have been removed months ago.
God help us now.
(man) Get out of here!
Shit!
- Excuse me.  - You're cool.
You've been a busy bee.
You're supposed to be retired.
I'm assuming you're my replacement.
Fuck you!
I need your keys.
Janet: There's an issue.
The problem has not been solved.
Well...
That is a surprise.
The Beekeepers have studied the situation
and have decided to remain neutral.
How can they do that?
He was their man, for fuck's sake!
I'm sorry, Wallace.
You're on your own.
I thought you could fucking handle this.
I can handle this!
Verona: Thank you.
Wiley: What you got for us, Detective?
That's her vehicle,
registered to a Anisette Landress.
The ATF are en route inbound to take care of it.
We're way cooler than ATF.
I'll show you why I called them.
That's a Minigun.
They use those on military vehicles.
Did you know that puppy shoots 6,000 rounds a minute?
Wiley: I know.
Did you know that's 100 rounds a second?
Yep, I know.
Did you know that you know a lot?
Yes, I do.
It's because I minored in math.
I'm a pretty smart guy actually.
Okay, then, do you know who Anisette Landress is?
- Yes, I do.  - Go ahead and tell me.
Someone who doesn't exist
in any commercial or government database.
Someone who's a ghost.
Like our good friend Adam Clay.
"Beekeeping for Beekeepers."
Here's another reason
that Anisette Landress
is like our good friend Adam Clay.
Do you know what's that way?
Springfield...
where the call center was torched.
And that way where Adam Clay's headed?
Boston.
Let's go.
Wiley: Thank you.
How are you, my friend?
- Good to see you, sir.  - Good to see you.
Wallace: Yeah, come on,
leave them alone. Leave them alone.
Don't play with those things. They go off.
Sit down. Make yourself comfortable.
When I was sworn in as director,
I was read into programs I never imagined existed.
Well...
there are programs even I wasn't privy to.
Like the Beekeepers.
The honeybee has always
had a special relationship with humanity.
A sacred relationship.
Why? No bees, no agriculture.
No agriculture, no civilization.
Our nation is not unlike a beehive,
with its complex systems of workers,
caretakers, even royalty.
If any of the beehive's complex mechanisms
are compromised,
the hive collapses.
Someone a long time ago decided
that a mechanism was needed
to keep our nation safe.
A mechanism outside the chain of command,
outside the system.
Its one mission, to keep the system safe.
Beekeepers are given all resources,
empowered to act on their own judgment.
For decades, they have quietly worked
to keep the hive safe.
That is, until now.
It appears that a retired Beekeeper
has gone off program
and is acting in what he mistakenly believes
is the hive's best interest.
(man) Can't somebody just pick up the phone
and tell this yahoo to stand-the-fuck down?
That's the one thing Beekeepers don't do.
Stand down.
Not unlike bees themselves,
Beekeepers keep working until they die.
So he's basically one of us.
No. He's not like you.
You're tier one operators,
former SEAL Team Six, Delta Group.
You are, in other words, pussies.
If you were in the same room,
he would kill you.
With enough of you, then maybe you just might
in fact be able to kill him
before he accomplishes his goal.
What would that be?
To kill his way to the top of the hive.
Mr. Pettis, you should get your people moving.
Dude, bees are interesting little shits.
Did you know that?
I know they pollinate a bunch of shit
and we'd be fucked without them.
Listen.
"Some bees are queen slayers,
"which will rise up and kill their queen
"if she fails to produce
"the right kind of male offspring."
Fascinating.
- No.  - Hm. Nope.
- No.  - No!
- It's your turn. You can't...  - No!
Special Agent Parker.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
What?
The deputy director is flying up from DC to see us.
Oh, fuck. This is your fault.
Here's another interesting factoid.
Thank fuck.
You know, I was getting sick of enjoying
my peaceful thoughts.
Sir.
Sir, this is Special Agent Parker,
Special Agent Wiley.
They'll be briefing you.
This is Deputy Director Prigg
and Amanda Munoz, special counsel.
Mr. Deputy Director,
my colleague and I believe
that three major crime scenes in our area
are connected to a single subject.
Adam Clay.
He killed six people today.
Based on the extensive use of tradecraft
and the nature of his alias,
we believe that Mr. Clay is connected
to a classified program named Beekeeper.
A program that none of our partner agencies
seem willing to acknowledge.
Let's stick to what we know, Special Agent Parker.
Yes, sir.
In any event, this individual is highly capable
and extremely motivated,
and we believe that he's on his way to Boston,
if not already here.
And we believe that this is his next target,
Nine Star United,
which appears to be the entity
operating the regional call centers,
like the one that Mr. Clay burned down.
Why is Adam Clay on this rampage?
He's, um, protecting the hive, sir.
It's what Beekeepers do.
I have enough to brief the director.
- What's your ask?  - Verona: My ask?
Uh, well, a SWAT team, for starters.
Surveillance support, additional agents, analysts.
That shouldn't be a problem.
Thank you.
- Did that just happen?  - Yeah.
All right. Everybody, listen up.
It's roll call time.
I'm getting ready for my dick to get hard
with some wonderful, beautiful numbers.
Let's start with Phoenix. Where we at?
Phoenix is up 201K.
200K, I'm gonna suck your dick. I love you.
New Orleans, show me,
tell me. Where we at?
It's down 93K, boss.
Down? You're a fucking loser.
You give me a fucking headache.
You give me fucking cancer.
New York, make me happy. I beg you.
New York City's up 64 ASCOT.
Yeah! I love you, New York!
Gather around!
I want all weapons front on entry.
- Everybody give me an oos!  - (swat team) Oos!
Let's go!
Power down, my federal friend. Power down.
Private security here on the orders of the Governor.
State Department certified to carry weapons
in all 50 states.
Feel free to call the highlighted numbers
to verify.
You're not welcome here. Get the fuck out.
All right, boys, let's go!
Set up a perimeter outside.
Your goals, they mean bonuses.
Money, money, money, we fucking love it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What the fuck?
Who the fuck are you? You can't be in here.
We're the guys keeping you alive.
Shut it down now.
Everybody, listen up.
Anyone who's not carrying a weapon,
get the fuck out!
Shouldn't you be killing bin Laden or something?
Listen to me, my friend. This place prints money.
No one's shutting down.
Anybody so much as puts a phone down, they're fired!
I'm sorry to break it to you,
but bin Laden's been dead for a while.
So I'm going to say this one last time.
Shut it down.
The fuck I am.
Call your fucking boss.
You want me to call my boss?
I'll do that.
And you'll be so fucked, it's gonna be beautiful.
Don't be shy. Come on.
Agent Kim: What about the parking garage?
Closed and locked. Steel gate.
I want a body on comms watching it.
- Delivery dock?  - Same deal.
- Station an agent there too.  - Yes, sir.
Sure there's no back entrances into this place?
Hey, there're no other entrances.
Federal law enforcement operation in progress.
Move along at a minimum retreat
to a safe distance. Thank you.
Someone scout the service tunnel.
The other option, instead of going in
is to smoke them out.
Excuse me?
I figured I'd give the firefighters a break.
I've put them through enough already.
What'd you say your name was?
Currently I go by Adam Clay.
Trust me, if there was a back entrance,
I would've used it.
I don't want to injure anyone
who's innocent and non-involved.
But it is what it is.
Somebody detain this guy!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Oh, wow, if it isn't the fucking
golden goose himself.
Sir, I got Captain Caveman here
telling me to send everyone home.
If we do that,
we're walking away from a lot of money.
Mm. Put him on.
It's for you.
Why are you fucking with my business?
Because Mr. Westwyld hired me
to kick some fucking Beekeeper's ass.
Mr. Westwyld works for me,
which means that you work for me.
Now, listen, that place
is the crown jewel of my kingdom.
I'm not gonna let some crash test dummy
with a fucking gun fuck it up.
Is that clear, Mr. Pettis?
Didn't this character already burn
one of your centers to the ground?
Well, you know, they didn't have you,
and that's why.
So maybe you just do your fucking job
and don't tell me how to do mine, please.
- We got it?  - Copy that.
Fall out. Set up a perimeter outside.
Let's go. Move!
Round of applause.
Let's say goodbye to our good friends.
Bye-bye, Admiral. Go join fucking Space Force.
You are beautiful. Now get the fuck out!
Keep walking.
Anzalone: Bye-bye, dickhead.
What a bunch of jackoffs.
Yeah, we love you!
One time amnesty.
Whoever doesn't want to die this evening,
can in an orderly fashion leave now.
Uh, uh, uh. No fucking way. It's not happening.
Anybody moves, you're fired.
- No bonus, vesting, two weeks.  - Come on, boys! Move, move!
Nada. Zero!
Are you fucking nuts?
Each one of these pricks is worth
30 to 40 million a year in profit.
So no one is shooting no guns.
Not a good day to drag innocent people into this.
These assholes? They're not innocent.
For either one of us to close that distance,
some of them will get hurt.
Let's start with this prick right here.
On me!
Take right!
Pettis, we got a man down.
(emergency PA) Fire. Fire.
Fire. Fire.
You know who you're working for?
None of my fucking business.
I'm just the guy they call when there's a problem.
And you are our problem.
Goddamn right, I'm a problem.
(emergency PA) Fire. Fire.
Fire. Fire.
Dan, what the hell happened?
Any dead?
Not dead, but we got our asses kicked.
- Our guy. What do we know?  - (swat 1) He's in the building.
I'm waiting more men to roll in.
I don't know what this guy is,
but nobody can do what he's done.
He's just a Beekeeper.
Bad idea.
I'm not waiting.
- Wiley: V, wait!  - Move!
Come on, Wiley, keep up.
Wiley: Fuck.
(swat 2) We got him!
- You done?  - Reload.
Everybody out!
You're done.
We should take the stairs.
Smart.
(swat 4) Subject is in the hallway.
(swat 5) Command, report back. Anybody on comm?
Please, please don't kill me.
I'm just a middle manager. I never hurt nobody.
I'd respect you more if you look people
in their eyes when you steal from them.
Clay: Now, you're making a lot of money here.
Tell me where it's all going.
I don't know, man.
I know you're the middle man.
- Who's above you?  - No. They'll kill me.
I'll torture you, then kill you.
Come on, guys. You got it.
Verona: Wiley, get your ass up here!
Yeah, well, I'm not an Olympian.
Clay: Make it stop.
You can make it stop.
You've stolen hundreds of millions
from people who've done nothing
but work hard all their lives.
She was an educator, a mom.
Dedicated her whole life to helping people.
Yesterday, she shot herself
because you took two million from a charity she ran.
She was the only person who ever took care of me.
Who and where, Mr. Anzalone?
- Tell me who and where.  - I can't.
Look, these people,
they're untouchable. I can't...
No, please! Please! Stop! I will! I will!
Let me show you. Let me show you.
I told you they were untouchable.
Nobody's untouchable.
Sometimes when the hive's out of balance...
you have to replace the queen.
Clay!
That man is directly responsible
for your mother's death.
I believe you.
But we have laws for these things.
You have laws for these things until they fail.
Then you have me.
Arrest him!
On your feet before I blow your fucking head off.
I just been thrown through a plate glass window.
Shut your fucking mouth!
Whoa. I have four kids.
I know. Three boys and a girl.
Wiley? You okay?
- Yeah. He went that way.  - Verona: You okay?
- Have you been hit?  - My wife thinks
I'm doing computer nerd shit.
Well, I won't tell her if you don't.
- Have you been hit?  - No, I'm good, Mom.
Did you get him?
- Did you?  - No, he's tricky.
- Get up. You okay?  - Almost, but...
I guess that's just evidence.
- Can I borrow your gun?  - Yeah. Let's go.
- On me. On me. On me. On me.  - (swat) Clear!
I want interviews with all of them.
We're going to talk.
Get him out of here.
Wiley.
Holy shit.
(woman) Do you mind if I ask you
a really boring question?
Do you actually prefer the money or the power?
Mm.
That's deep.
Oh, I'm so sorry. Excuse me.
Oh, God. Uh...
Would you excuse me for a moment? Come upstairs.
Derek: You said these guys were the fucking best. Uh...
Why are they all dead?
You kicked the beehive
and now we have to reap the whirlwind.
- Unless...  - Unless.
Unless, unless, unless fucking what?
Maybe now is the time to call your mother.
I'm paying you so much fucking money
and your advice is to call my mother?
He can't make his move on us
if we're in her proximity, can he?
Her people.
You're a fuck.
- You're scared...  - I certainly am scared.
And you want to use my mother
as a human shield.
Just call her. Just call her. Come on.
It's not a game now.
Oh, it's all a game.
Come on.
Yes, Derek. What do you want?
Derek: Hey, Mom. No, nothing.
I was just, you know, thinking about you.
I miss you. I was hoping to maybe see you this weekend.
I'm at the beach house.
You're welcome to join if you behave.
I would love to. And, hey, I actually was going to,
you know, get together with some of my
tech homies and stuff, if that's, uh,
if that's cool with you.
Fine. No drugs.
Give Kelly the details. Love you. Have to go.
Derek's joining me this weekend.
Help me keep him sober.
Yes, ma'am. I love babysitting.
Madame President, Funmi Lawal.
Hello. Good to meet you.
Sola Oyemade.
Sola, thank you so much for coming.
Susan Aneno.
Thank you so much for coming all this way.
Kelly: Oli Ray-Imanuel.
- Oli, how good to meet you.  - Great to meet you, ma'am.
You don't have to do this, you know?
Why not let Clay do his thing?
Your mom is dead because of these people.
Wherever it's headed...
I swore an oath.
I can't stand by and watch it happen.
Even if he's right?
Even if he's right.
Apologies. Damn plane was delayed.
What have you got?
We think we have a sense of Mr. Clay's true intentions.
He seems to be following the money.
What money is that?
Usually it's from people with no heirs, no family.
Nine Star United uses data mining software
to identify these people and then target their assets.
There's another company involved, sir,
a company who is a vendor to the intelligence community
and to the Justice Department.
In fact, we use this company's software
in this very office
to identify financial fraud.
Are you going to tell me the name of this company?
Danforth Enterprises.
With an annual revenue of $10 billion,
founded and operated by Jessica Danforth,
who recently stepped down because she was sworn in
as President of the United States.
She self-financed her campaign.
Yeah. None of that money was clean.
Who else knows this?
Us three.
I have a really bad memory, sir.
Prigg: Let's, uh, keep the circle small,
until I can brief the director and the attorney general.
Not a word of this to anyone. Understood?
Yes, sir.
And, Mr. Clay, I see his kill count
is steadily rising.
In a beehive, there is something
called a "queen slayer."
It's a bee that will rise up and kill the queen
if she produces defective offspring.
I thought we were sticking to the known knowns.
Right. Yes. Not that Beekeepers exist.
But Mr. Clay does keep honey bees.
He admires their willingness
to sacrifice themselves for the greater good.
Our concern is that Clay believes that Derek Danforth
is the defective offspring of a queen,
thereby Clay will strike at the heart of the problem
and become a queen slayer.
Adam Clay's next victim is Derek Danforth's mother?
President Danforth, sir.
You have a blank check. Good luck.
Thank you.
(agent 1) Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa. This is a private event.
I'm gonna need you to turn around, go away.
Federal Bureau of something or another.
We're good. We have invites right here.
All right. You'll need to excuse my partner.
He's recently concussed and hasn't slept in two days.
We're on the access list.
(agent 2) We're good, boss.
Get the Secret Service out of the house.
I don't want them here.
They're C team. B team at best.
Uh, Mom's detail is not going to like that.
Well, if Mom's detail gets in the way
of what's coming for us,
they're dead men and so are we.
Tell them they can stay in the kitchen.
Yes, sir.
He has a little talent, doesn't he?
He's absolutely fucking terrifying.
Wallace: Yeah.
(man) Good men, but clearly not good enough.
- Wallace: Hm.  - Fuck, bruh!
How'd you piss this oak off, huh?
I...
- You're looking at me?  - Wallace: Mm-hmm.
How is any of this my fault?
Wasn't your supersecret CIA
data mining software supposed to,
I don't know, maybe filter out
un-fucking-stoppable killing machines?
Don't you fuck with me, young man!
Any other life, you'd be in jail.
Hey, this is the fucking Beekeeper!
Yeah, you know I killed one once.
Oh, you see?
Yeah. Only 'cause I was lucky.
- And un-fucking-lucky.  - Wallace: Oh, jeez.
Yeah, don't piss your pants, bruh.
My team will be out shortly.
If anyone can knock
this guy's dick in the dirt, it's them.
Ain't that right, money man?
Yeah.
I'm supposed to be at a kids' birthday party
with my wife.
You are at a kids' birthday party.
And I'm your work wife.
Madam President, you look spectacular.
When the fuck are you going to tell me
what's going on, Wallace?
Good. Go through.
(agent 1) Tell that guy to hurry up.
I want every manhole on this street welded shut.
(agent 2) Six up.
Good to go.
Let's go. Let's go.
(agent 3) Come on. Move it up.
(agent 3) Put your head on a swivel, gentlemen.
Go!
(agent 1) We got eyes on the second floor.
All right, you're good. Coming through.
Oh.
Hey. When, uh, did you get in? What a surprise.
You didn't hear the giant Marine helicopter
land on the front lawn?
Ah, I guess not. Hm.
Is this, uh, nicotine or a carnival ride?
Uh, I wouldn't unless you want to go
talk with the machine elves.
Hey, you look fucking great, by the way.
I mean, power, it just looks so good on you.
Doing blow on your father's desk.
God, how I wish he was still alive
so I could kill him.
Stop picking your face.
Why does Wallace Westwyld look nervous as a burning cat?
What have you done to the man?
Mm, I wouldn't know, Mother.
Well, he's there to protect you
if you'll let him.
You're a good looking kid. You really are. You know that?
What does that mean?
It means that God doesn't give with both hands.
Uh, okay. I love you too, Mom.
Hm.
Gotta go run the free world.
Don't burn it down.
Fucking fantastic!
Verona: Wiley, look.
Oh, shit.
Verona: Danforth looks like she wants to throw up.
Look at her body language. Bad vibes.
She got caught riding dirty.
What have we done?
Derek: Are you, uh, fucking with crypto at all, right now?
It's gonna pop.
They're minting next week, so just hit me up on Insta.
- Okay.  - I'll connect your wallet.
- May I borrow my son?  - Of course.
Speak to you a moment in private?
Sorry.
Uh, who's this?
Jackson Prigg. He's number two at the FBI.
Have a seat.
Uh, I'm cool. I'll stand. What is this, like,
an ambush or something? This feels weird. I don't like it.
No, you'll sit.
I'll sit.
Kelly, would you give us a moment?
It's okay, ma'am. I can take notes.
I need you to step outside.
The deputy director has flagged his, uh, concerns
about some uncomfortable things
happening inside the family company.
Like what?
Uncomfortable things about
the source of my campaign funds.
Sounds serious. What's up?
Deputy Director.
Mr. Danforth, are you familiar with, uh, United Data Group?
United Data Group.
Yeah. Yeah, I, uh...
I invested in that.
I invest everywhere.
I mean, there's... It's everywhere.
- It's very diverse.  - Uh-huh.
How about, uh, Nine Star United?
Yeah, that was, uh...
that's more of, like, a consulting type role.
It's block chain issues. And you probably...
I don't want to bore you with all that.
What do you know about a classified algorithmic
data mining software package
developed by the intelligence community?
He's here.
All stations, target's in the building. East wing.
Give me everything you got.
He's in the house!
Assault team, saddle up!
(agent 2) Let's move, boys! Get a move on!
Let's move! Come on!
- Go! Come on. Move!  - Go! Go!
Break-break! Package is in the house!
Level three, side four.
Blue over blue, you see him, you fucking get him!
Verona: Hey! Put your fucking hands up.
Now turn the fuck around.
- Fuck.  - Wiley: Fuck.
He's outside. Target's outside.
Move! Move!
Let's get this fucking guy!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Easy, killer. You see him?
Negative.
- Clay!  - That's right.
That's right. Now, on your knees!
On your knees!
Lace your fingers behind your head.
Down on your knees now!
Do it now!
Beekeeper, huh? God's right hand?
You aren't shit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Lazarus: Hey, take a step back.
I'm putting this asshole's brains on the lawn.
What are you doing? He's not even armed.
Armed?
As long as this motherfucker's breathing, he's armed.
You're not fucking executing him.
Nice crowd you're rolling with.
Watch me.
V, what the fuck is going on?
To "bee" or not to "bee"?
Isn't that the bloody question?
I think I'll take
to "bee."
- Wiley?  - Yeah, you good?
- Yeah.  - Go.
Get off me!
He's fucking mine!
Talk to me, people. I need news.
(agent) He's here!
(agent 2) Go! Go! All stations!
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Go with the flow.
(agent 3) Not clear. He's not clear.
(agent 4) Hang tight.
On me.
(agent 6) Get on the ground. Get on the ground.
You understand you did this, right?
You broke the rules.
You corrupted an imperfect but functioning system.
I was just trying to get you into office, Mom.
How else do you think you got elected?
I was going to win with or without your help.
We were already rich. Your father built an empire.
Yeah. And you were going to fucking
break it up into pieces and sell it off.
Well, in the name of public service
because I care and I want to leave a better world.
Okay. Right.
Yeah, because you hate the fact
that being the president
is just like an endless cocktail party.
You realize that you were behind
in 15 of 20 counties you needed to win.
15 of 20 counties!
I taught CIA software to hunt money
and not terrorists.
You didn't hear that.
You got elected because of me, and you know that.
Yeah, I know it. Everyone knows it.
Now I know where the money came from...
and all the people you hurt.
Okay, whatever. It's computer data, Mom.
Somebody in this family has to have their fucking feet
on the ground to actually get shit done. You understand that?
Mom, the wolves are at the fucking door right now.
What are you going to do to fix this?
Tell the truth.
The fucking...
What does that even mean?
What does that even mean, tell the fucking truth?
You have an entire building
full of PR people
that are going to choose the right way forward.
That guy who's coming to kill us, that Beekeeper,
I'm telling him the truth about what you did, Derek.
Then I'm telling the entire nation.
And if it costs me everything,
well, so be it.
You fucking git!
Fuck!
You're just a man.
I know.
Thank you.
Jesus. Looks like a tornado came through here.
What's your plan here, huh?
You're going to tell this guy the fucking truth
and hope that he spares you and kills me instead?
No, Derek, I'll tell him the truth
because it's the truth.
It's gone far enough. You've proved your point.
Beekeepers live for the good of society.
I'm retired.
This is personal.
All the more reason to stop.
Go back. Live a quiet life.
Making honey for your neighbors.
That's all I wanted.
- My neighbor's dead.  - I know. I'm sorry.
But do you live in the real world
or just protect it?
What does it matter to you
how presidents come to be elected?
- Hm?  - It doesn't.
What does matter to you?
Right and wrong.
It's not fashionable.
I believe there's good in the universe.
Yeah, well, we agree. I mean, that's my view.
Until the Danforth family bought you.
- Ah.  - You can stop pretending.
We wouldn't need Beekeepers if it wasn't for men like you.
Wallace: Don't do that.
Sir, you might want to step back.
No.
- I don't want you to get hurt.  - I'm sorry. I can't do that.
Now, have a seat.
Nah, fuck the truth, man. The truth...
- Wait. You put that down.  - No, Derek.
Comes out of your fucking...
Jesus Christ!
That's fucking real right there.
- Clay, no!  - Drop your weapon. Drop it!
You decide who you work for.
For the law
or for justice.
Fuck this.
Bye, Mom.
- (swat 1) Go! Go!  - (swat 2) Move. Move.
- Move it out. Out of the way.  - Wiley: You're okay.
- I got you. I got you.  - No. No. I want my...
Clay!
(agent) Come with us right now!
- No! I want my... I want my...  - Back away. Back away.
No!
(agent 2) You need to come with me. Come on.
- No!  - Move out. Move out.
- Give me your hand. Come on!  - Jessica: No!
Goodbye, Adam Clay.
Keep eyes on! Let's go!