[SOUND]
I am no god of the
void, slicer of worlds.
Long ago, when light invaded my kingdom,
my symbiote children
betrayed me and imprisoned me here.
At last a codex is being created.
It is the key to my freedom.
It will unlock this prison.
I order you to search the corners
of the universe until you find this key.
Find me the codex.
And when I escape and
annihilate every living planet and
destroy my symbiote
offspring, I will reward you with your lives.
So you're saying in this
universe there's the superhero people.
Hi, so tell me again about your
purple alien friend who really loves stones.
I'll tell you what, man,
aliens, they do not love stones.
They don't start.
Do not love stones.
Do you know what they love?
They love eating brains
because that's what they do.
Señor, he made my
family disappear for five years.
Five years.
See, that is a long time.
All right.
We are drunk.
[SOUND]
We're home.
I'm so done with the multiverse shit
that I like our version of the barman better.
My head hurts.
I feel like I'm drunk, but
I'm also hungover at the same time.
You want a bloody marina?
I don't want to drink.
Why, gross milk.
You are destroying this man's bar.
I'm having a time of my life today.
I'd rather have a glass of water.
Be a man, Eddie.
We should have been a bartender.
Tequila!
I did it.
Señor?
What the hell were those things?
I was born with them.
Freaking bar, I'm done with this shit.
This is Kelly Roulet
reporting from San Francisco.
Police are still trying to locate
former reporter Eddie Brock for questioning after
the tragic death of
Detective Patrick Mulligan.
No.
Detective Mulligan
was found in Pail and that's a
series of bizarre
happenings at the city's cathedral.
They think that I killed him.
How long can he evade authorities?
Only time will tell.
If we are on the news
here, we are on the news everywhere.
We can't go back to San
Francisco and I'm not staying down
here hiding for the rest of
my life in Mexico, that's for sure.
Where will we go?
I don't know. I don't know.
That could work.
This church got me
kicked out of New York.
What a dick.
I still got a ton of shit on him too.
I've always wanted to
see the Statue of Liberty.
Maybe we could blackmail him.
Clear my name.
Let's go.
Road trip.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Take the change.
We keep our heads
down and we keep moving.
We are shooting him.
We are on the run.
Yes, we are in the shit.
Yes, but I will eat
every bad guy that gets in our way.
I need a title.
You did that?
Yes.
Someone's in trouble
and I need fuel for the road.
Yeah, okay.
That way.
Batman, Eddie, are we
the lethal protector or not?
Do you think?
It's a busy.
Jesus.
Cute.
I promised not to eat it.
They're fighting dogs.
I draw the line at fighting dogs, pal.
Just a few.
Oh, yo, what?
You're in the wrong place.
Oh, hello.
This is our territory.
Well, I assume by the
threatening look on your faces that I, uh...
I ought to be scared, right?
We should take the wrong path, Batman.
We can let you leave.
I have a headache.
On account of the
fact that I was drinking a lot.
I'm going to be honest.
I have a really dark
and unpredictable side to me.
We all have monsters inside us.
Not like this.
So dark that it is highly likely to
tear your head off and feed it to your asshole.
I'm here. You can feed it to me.
Yeah, I can feed it to him.
All right, look.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Come on.
I got a suggestion.
No, stop speaking.
I'm not going to stop
speaking. This is for you.
I'm doing this for
your benefit, all right?
I don't have to.
Okay? Just pay attention.
We're going to find
all of these dogs loving
forever homes, because
what you're doing is reprehensible.
And what does your
mother think of you, man?
My mother's dead, Colero.
You made it awkward.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Great.
Huh?
Part of the matter.
Thank you.
I'm giving you a chance.
Sweetie, I'm really, I'm giving
you a chance. You should probably take it.
See?
See.
Okay.
See when.
When?
Whoa.
Call the line.
Hola, bitches.
Who's a bad boy?
I'll get some sturdy footwear.
You going?
What?
Are you?
We are.
No.
Yeah, we.
We are.
Venom.
What?
We're totally going
to need to work on that.
Come on.
Mmm, that was delicious.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
You take me to all the finest places.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Where's my shoe?
Oh, hey, buddy.
There's my shoe.
These will fit.
Now we are on the run
for something we actually did do.
And I got stuck with
the superhero who can't fly.
One a bit. There you are.
Get me General Strickland.
What the...
Viral shedding.
These things want to live.
Hola.
Tell me about the man who was just here.
He was acting like
crazy talking to himself.
What was he saying?
He had these big, massive, wide arms.
They were bubbling like
this. Bring him. [MUSIC PLAYING]
You think they're another
brother and sister on one of those stars?
Looking at the same sky?
I'll be able to tell you one day.
My twin brother.
A future NASA scientist.
One day.
When thunder roars, head indoors.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
He's on life support.
Get him to emergency symbiosis now.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
It should be you.
They just came across a
news desk and it bears repeating.
For all you alien
enthusiasts out there, it's a sad day.
Washington has finally
announced the decommissioning of Area 51.
The controversial site is
famous for its alleged testing on aliens.
It's in other news today.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Right this way.
Slow down.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Strickland.
Strickland authorized.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
What's finally happening then?
Yes ma'am.
There'll be
nothing left but rock and dust.
And roaches.
Even the biggest of
banks couldn't kill them.
They've been around
280 million years and counting.
I did not know that Dr. Payne.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Good to go.
Have a good one Gus.
You too.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Thank you.
Good to go.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Morning Dr. Payne.
We'll keep them safe for you.
I still don't think
anyone wants my old beater gym.
Now would you like to evoke my H-couple?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Early morning wake up General Strickland.
Looks like all your dreams came true.
I know how that must bug you.
He arrived shortly before you did.
Did our new friend give them any trouble?
You see that's exactly the problem.
What?
Your assumption were meeting friends.
Morning.
The bonding was successful.
I heard.
You always have this look on your
face like something terrible is imminent.
Because in my line of work
something terrible is always imminent.
We contain them.
You study them.
That's how it works.
[MUSIC PLAYING] [INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Let's have a look.
His other symbiote left him for dead.
We saved him.
He would have died.
I'll try lowering those levels.
Morning Sadie.
Let me get back.
We got this down in Mexico.
Hi.
Welcome.
Any more on where the rest of them is?
We're getting to
update me as you have it.
I don't get this obsession.
I told you my mom made me this pen.
It's July.
I'll see you in there.
Everyone on this side is weird.
Leave her alone Rex.
God forbid anyone
should actually enjoy their work.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Area 51 will be fully
decommissioned by the end of the week.
It's just a shipwreck anyway
and they're tired of the tourists.
We don't exist down here.
100 feet subsurface,
undetectable to any human or non-human.
Everyone's phoning home from here.
My brother's greatest ambition was
to work up there at 51 doing what I do.
And I wish I could have
shown him what we built down here.
[PANTING]
You're okay.
Just...
Try to breathe.
Okay?
When my brother and I were kids they
told us that UFOs were just weather balloons.
Space trash.
Kubrick directed the moon
landing in a Hollywood studio.
Cool story.
Where are you going? This first.
Is there an increased risk of exposure?
It's not us I'm worried about.
You know we carry
all kinds of viruses and
bacteria that could be
harmful to a sensitive lifeform.
And we don't know
exactly what we're dealing with here.
As long as we're keeping the guests safe.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
This is the first time we've had a
host compatible with one of our symbiotes.
And now we'll be able to talk to one.
[MUSIC PLAYING] He's been
experiencing panic surges since we've bonded him.
Try jingle bells.
So soothing.
Well, why didn't I think of that?
Release him.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Payne. Teddy.
You're safe here.
I'm gonna help you.
Both of you.
The transfer was successful.
We had no choice.
We had to try and save you.
The monsters.
You're broken too.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
May I...
May I ask you some questions?
Is this symbiote communicating with you?
Do you hear it?
Sound distresses them.
Okay.
Why are they here?
What do they want?
Safe haven.
Safe haven?
We were running.
Is he talking about the other symbiotes?
I think so.
His creatures search the universe for us.
We will be fine.
And when we are, he will kill us all.
Who?
There will be nothing left.
Here? On Earth?
Why were they running?
Because there is a dark,
cold sea
around this universe.
What is it?
What?
You know what to do.
I've seen the future.
The darkness...
has to leave.
This is your captain speaking.
We are currently
cruising at a comfortable 31,000 feet.
If you look out there to your
left, just now you will see the Grand Canyon.
Those are we can find!
Oh my God!
Direct to New York!
My mouth is so dry!
And we clear your name!
It's so empressently cold!
All those tall girls doing it!
He doesn't whine like a little bitch!
What was that?
What is that?
I'm sorry, A.N.A.
But I've got to disappear.
What now?
We're in deep shit!
Why did you do that?
I will explain.
I'm gonna go ahead and say that
this is the shittest hangover of all time.
Look at it, Eddie.
Isn't it just astonishing?
Shut up.
I don't think I
might, living here forever.
We just came face to
face with a literal death machine.
Forever seems pretty optimistic.
With the
decommissioning of Area 51, will the
Pentagon finally admit
that they've been holding UAP?
That's unidentified
aerial phenomena to you.
Yeah, Dad, we know.
When I wouldn't get to
see who built one of those things.
That's why we cashed in our
savings and came on this road trip, babe.
So you could finally get to see.
That's bullshit.
Yeah, well what if I'm right?
Then I really hope we don't end up in
an alien space lab with probes up our asses.
We're dead.
Asses.
[Laughing]
Kicked up some gravel there.
In tight, family.
You good?
That was wild.
Did the dog vomit?
Yeah.
Okay.
We've got this.
Soft landing.
Bend your knees.
Engage your core.
Yes, yes, that's it.
Yes, that's it.
Whoa.
Well done.
That was terrifying.
This is not New York.
No, this is a wasteland.
I'm detecting passive aggression.
Are you?
Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry.
How about some active aggression?
You just threw me
off a 757 without even the
slightest
consideration from my chronic vertical.
It was an Airbus A320.
Was it?
I am sorry.
Hooray.
And what was that thing?
That thing that we
just juiced back there.
Well, that's going to be like this.
No, I can absolutely guarantee that.
I'm not gonna.
What are you doing?
Why are you doing that?
That's a pretty weird.
That's creepy.
That was a xenophage.
What?
A xenophage.
A symbiote cantella.
Of course.
Problem is, if she has found
her way here, others will soon follow.
Others?
The xenophage's
maker also created a symbiote.
So that's your sister.
Oh, the symbiote's turned on him.
Locked him up on Kinta.
Your planet.
No, not your planet.
Not your planet.
The prison we built for him to sleep.
Of course.
Fraternity.
What's his name then?
I didn't hear what he said.
No!
This is serious, Eddie.
This is not talk.
Quiet.
What is this, Isilom?
This zen thingy, the
symbiote hundred want with you anyway.
It doesn't?
It wants us.
We have something indeed.
We only have this shitty shit.
You got one vote.
Someone.
The codex.
What now?
I'll show you.
Damn it!
What are you doing?
Let's say you died.
I could bring you back to life.
Well, I like that.
But if I did, our separate life forces
would become one
single force called a codex.
What the hell is a codex?
It's a key.
A key that unlocks a cage.
The prison on Klyntar.
It would free our creator.
Well, thank God we haven't died.
Yeah, except that one time.
Oh no.
No.
So you're telling me
we're carrying this thing?
That's why this enophage is hunting us.
What do we do?
She can only see the codex when
a symbiote is in its full true form.
Right.
You mean you can't come out.
I can do this.
But if I fully transform, the
codex sends her a tracking signal.
She'll find us, rip it out of
our spine, and free Nal from Klyntar.
So how do we get rid of this codex?
As long as you and I
both live, the codex exists.
If one of us should
die, the codex will die.
That's not gonna work for me.
Or me.
That enophage was fast.
It will take long
for the feds to tie us to
those four headless
bodies we left in Mexico.
We gotta get outta here.
Yeah, we better go.
Four legs are better than one.
Be honest with me, buddy.
How fast do you think you can
get that thing to go without killing it?
Only one way to find out.
Shh, shh. Don't scare him.
Don't scare her. She was yours.
Nice horse, he.
Surprise, horse, he!
I love horse, he!
Ride me cowboy!
You are an asshole!
I swear to God,
when I get off this horse,
I'm gonna kick
your ass, you motherfucker!
Now, that's horse power!
Safe Haven?
No. They're not here for a safe haven.
How about a new home
to make the current tenants?
I think you've watched too
many alien invasion movies, Rex.
Have I?
They were running. That's what he said.
Don't kid yourself.
They were always migrating.
A meteor carrying symbiote life,
crashes on Earth, and they all survive.
Coincidence? Give me a break.
Alright.
Let's go get them.
You're so desperate to believe
that they're here for altruistic reasons.
Makes you dangerous.
[tense music]
We just intercepted an
emergency call from an airbus out
of Mexico, saying a man
jumped off the plane over Sequoia.
We'll take the osmore.
Eyes wide, Payne.
[screaming]
[gunfire]
[groaning]
I can't feel my balls.
Now...
That was horrible.
[screaming]
[thunder]
[gasping]
[muffled radio chatter]
Take him out.
Collect a symbiote.
[muffled radio chatter]
[grunting]
[gunfire]
[muffled radio chatter]
[gunfire] [gunfire]
[gunfire]
[muffled radio chatter] [thunder]
[grunting]
[gunfire]
[muffled radio chatter]
[gasping]
[squeaking]
[muffled radio chatter]
[muffled radio chatter] [knocking]
[grunting]
[muffled radio chatter]
[gunshot]
[gasping]
[panting]
[water splashing]
[grunting]
[gasping]
[water splashing]
[grunting]
No, the Codex!
Not let you die!
[gurgling]
[screaming]
[gurgling] [gurgling]
[gurgling]
Where did that come from?
Moss! Coffee!
[gurgling]
[grunting]
[water splashing]
[gurgling]
Time to go! Hell yeah!
[grunting]
[screaming]
[gurgling]
[water splashing]
[grunting]
[growling]
[gurgling]
What happened?
There's something
else out here. Something else?
He said this would
happen. I just lost three people.
Can you collect any samples?
Samples.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[wind blowing]
[birds chirping]
Those were not Feds.
Those were some special forces shit.
They were trying to
kill us. Yeah. Yeah, great.
Great. So now we have the cops.
The United States Army and
some creature from hell hunting us.
Oh, God, I just saw blood in a
spray out of the back of an alien's face.
They killed someone.
They didn't give you a choice.
You didn't give me a
choice. I couldn't get to you.
It's a year ago when you stole my life.
We've been together for a whole year.
A year too long. Just stay hidden
while we get to New York without getting killed.
[gurgling]
[thud]
We need you to come out.
The thing you
talked about, the creature...
It's here.
It killed some people.
[water splashing]
[hissing]
[gasps]
Will...
is so beautiful.
[hissing]
I sense...
I sense my old one.
And yet, the one Nolceaks is not here.
[hissing]
What does he seek?
The Black One.
The Black One?
Voxymbia?
He's the only one who carries a Codex.
The end...
is now.
[hissing]
You need your suit.
Still worried about
giving this thing a cold?
Venom carries the key to Nolce's freedom.
Never obtain it.
Or your race will be killed.
You...
and you...
and...
you...
everyone, everything.
How do we stop whatever's
up there from coming down here?
You can't.
He's older than the universe.
He means the key.
Then everything will end.
How do we stop him from getting it?
If the symbiote and the host are alive,
then the Codex is alive.
And if one of them dies?
The Codex dies?
The Codex dies.
Rex, you can't be serious.
Oh, I'm game.
Destroying the Codex is the
only way it remains unobtainable.
Right?
Hey, buddy, I'm talking to you.
Destroying it?
We have barely
even scratched the surface.
My people are dead.
Something is
coming that cannot be beaten.
I'm stopping all this shit right now.
Science is sacrifice.
Teddy.
Is serious. Listen to her.
[door opens]
Have you spoken to your family recently?
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
I smell wet dog and sauce emerges.
Hey, friendo. You okay there?
No, I'm not okay.
It's pretty wild out there.
I know. You hungry?
Yes.
Come over.
Thank you.
Well, this is my wife, Nova Moon.
Hi.
And these are my kids, Echo and Leaf.
A lifetime in therapy.
Don't.
Don't you dare.
Wow, how beautiful are your children?
And that's Blue.
Who is a dog?
And I'm Martin.
Hey, Martin.
Hey.
I'm Eddie.
Nice to meet you, Eddie.
You too. Pleasure.
Come sit, please.
Okay.
Come on, thank you.
Jesus Christ.
So, right.
Oh, so nothing died
on that plate namaste, man?
Thank you.
Help, Tash!
Oh, dear.
Eddie, where are you headed?
New York.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, all right.
Long way to New
York. We're naked shrimps, man.
Yeah.
We could ride you out to Vegas.
These people are weird. I'm telling you.
That would be so kind. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Of course. Life's one big adventure.
Who doesn't love making new friends?
Right?
This guy is so one of
those serial killer hitchhikers
from my favorite murder podcast.
Baby, not now.
That was social
services not taking us away yet.
She's joking.
I'm not.
Please, honey.
So we're riding the
extraterrestrial highway.
Yep.
Watch me. Who is it?
It's the road that leads to Area 51.
See if we can spot as an alien before
they shut the place down forever, you know?
It's my lifelong dream.
We can show him right now.
Not a believer?
Actually, Martin, how do I put this?
I am.
Oh.
That's the I am I big, big believer.
You're not that big.
Oh, and you can be enough.
And actually, I was in I.T.
Were you?
Yeah.
That's so cool.
Thanks.
I hope you don't
get disappointed, you know?
And I hope that if you do find
one, I hope you meet a really good alien.
Not a bad one.
Yeah.
I know a dark
force when I see one, Eddie.
It's kind of hot in here.
You get used to it.
A.C. is really bad
for your health, you know.
All right.
Family ready?
Yep.
Guest ready.
Let's rock this camper.
Ground control to Major Tom.
Oh, I love a sing-along.
Shoot me in the face.
Take your protein
pills and put your helmet on.
Oh, yeah.
This is my jam.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Commencing compound engines on.
Three.
Two.
Check it out.
One.
And make God's love be in the rafter.
Come on, Eddie, sing along.
I'm good.
Are you in the world?
No. Just think of this as the tour bus.
We're the band, and
you could be the groupie.
Come on.
Don't be square.
Don't get me started.
This is Major Tom's ground control.
I'm stepping through the door.
And I'm floating
in the most peculiar way.
Care up, and the
stars look very different today.
Why?
For he is my city in a tin can.
Can make a tin!
Far above the world.
Like a bath, already.
Planet Earth is blue,
and there's nothing I can do.
No.
This is ground control to Major Tom.
Sometimes I think we would
have been happier with a life like this.
And the players want to know, shall we?
Yeah.
Now the signs lead
to cash for a few days.
My love.
This is Major Tom to ground control.
I'm stepping through the door.
And I'm floating in a most peculiar way.
And the stars look very different today.
For he is my city in a tin can.
Far above the world.
(crunching)
You like chocolate?
Shh, they don't let us eat sugar.
They don't?
I have a friend who loves chocolate.
Thank you.
It's very kind of you.
I don't wanna see an onion.
You don't?
Scary.
Okay.
Well, you know, it's okay to be scared.
I'm scared.
Like, I go all the time.
Promise I won't see anyone?
Buddy.
Aliens are not real, okay?
Promise.
Okay.
You said the right thing.
You would make a good dad.
We've come a long way, you and me.
We have many more roads to travel, Buddy.
Wouldn't that be nice?
You say something?
No, just dream in, I guess.
That's the near Rika.
Near Rika?
Yeah.
There's a doorway in our minds
that usually remains hidden in secret
until the time of death.
Crazy things in this world, Eddie.
You can see them if you're open.
Oh, I seen them.
I'm glad we didn't eat this fine, family.
(upbeat music)
Welcome to the city of Second chances.
Whoa.
(upbeat music)
Thank you.
Here, buddy.
Stay blue, stay.
Thank you.
Okay, blue.
Vegas.
Listen, I just want you to have this.
Please.
Thank you.
Quality support, cushioning.
Plus, they come with
an anti-microbial footbed.
No, reject them.
Wasp the trucks.
Thank you.
Oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world
But I'll always remember you
Goodbye, Martin.
It's goodbye for now.
That's what I like to think, Eddie.
Okay, bye.
Hey, Martin.
That doorway, the near Rika?
Yeah, it's open.
Do I?
Just be safe.
Okay.
Thanks.
Oh, Jesus.
What?
Well, this is an all-time low.
You have chocolate.
Yum!
Oh, oh, oh.
I would like to see her
where we get to New York, Eddie.
You know, she was
built to welcome visitors
to America, buddy.
That's you.
You think so, Eddie?
Oh yeah, I know so.
When we get out of this
mess, we're gonna go see her.
We're gonna say, "Hi, Lady Liberty."
And see her Broadway show!
Yeah, sure.
Wow!
I know how much you hate musicals.
Yeah, it's gonna look great.
What's next, Thelma?
Well, Louise, I'm not sure $20
is gonna get us much
in the way of motor transport.
But I'm not ever
riding an alien horse again.
So I guess it looks
like we're stealing cars.
No, I've watched Rain Man
and in my infinite
wisdom as a celestial being,
working the system is easy.
You hit the slots,
then blackjack, then roulette,
bingo, bango, luxury
ride, Bluetooth sound system,
racing, and the top down.
Because that's how we roll.
Harris Casino has a strict dress code.
No, you know what?
It's a hotel.
These are my vacation clothes.
You're better ones.
He's not wrong.
Look at you.
No, don't push it, all right, buddy?
Want a hand?
Yes.
That did me, knock him out.
What are you doing?
He was being a dick.
Yeah, I was.
Oh, look.
We need a disguise.
What are we doing?
Hey, hey man.
Hi.
Oh, God.
Whoa.
Why do you keep rocking people out?
What is wrong with you?
What?
So sorry, buddy.
I am so, so sorry.
Hey there, you're my baby.
Now no one will recognize us.
Seriously.
You could get voted
people's sexiest man of the year.
If anyone cared who you are anymore.
I've won sexy man awards before.
Of course you have.
Hey, hey.
The guy that did that,
sorry, he's in the arched over there.
He shitfaced.
You're bad people.
Yeah, we are.
We're keeping his shoes, by the way.
We are so money and we know it.
Welcome to the Paris.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
Baby, here I am
I'm a man on the scene
I can give you what you want
But you got to go home with me
I forgot some good old lovin'
And I got some sun and gold
Oh, yes!
Let me multiply the 20.
Let me quadruple-fire it.
What are you doing?
No, this is all the money that we have.
Look for your lady tonight!
Snazzy jacket!
Let's eat up and steal it.
I know Lady Luck is on our side tonight!
No, I would say that Lady Luck
is definitely not on your side tonight.
But I would even go
so far to say that Lady Luck
hates you, buddy.
I can't stop now!
Of course you can't stop.
What is this feeling?
It's like-- This feeling?
Ha!
It's like all of my
problems have gone away!
Do this all the time.
Errol, I need more money.
But we don't have any more money, buddy.
God!
God bless!
You are a sore loser.
Yes, sir, it is!
Oh!
I think you broke my foot.
God, Lady Luck is a fickle slut!
Oh.
We should have played that machine!
Yes, yes, yes!
No, F-ing, wait!
Eddie, bro!
Mrs. Chen!
Oh, no, no, no!
Mr. Chen, it's Mrs. Chen!
Oh, Mrs. Chen!
Eddie, please!
Mrs. Chen, Mrs. Chen!
I'm gonna cry!
Me too.
Wow, what happened to you?
You look hot!
So do you.
Really hot.
I always look hot.
Yeah.
Is a big guy in there?
Do you like my dress?
I've been wearing so big,
they gave me a credit
line at the clothes store,
and then the penthouse suite.
Wow, you know I stole this suit
of a guy who pissed on me.
I knocked him out, I left him in a bush.
Well, that explained a stink.
You could use my room to clean up,
and then we--
Heartache.
Oh, that would be so good.
And room service.
(woman screams)
We got him.
Positive ID on Brock's
CCTV hit the Paris Hotel, Vegas.
Have we reconstituted the six?
Yes, sir.
Put him in.
The six are on route.
They'll bring him in.
But this time I'm requesting control
of the Imperium program.
You have my permission, General.
When thunder roars,
and it roars,
and it roars.
(ominous music)
Let's dance, baby.
Yeah, I love dances.
Please eat that thing will find us.
Don't be a party pooper.
No, do not encourage him.
You know what, Mr.
Chen, we are fugitives.
We are on the run,
so thank you for having us.
We gotta go.
You're no fun.
One last dance before you go.
We never do anything I want to do.
Just a little dance.
And you gave up.
Away my chickens.
Let's cut around, Mrs. Chen.
I give up.
Oh no, I cannot unsee that.
I cannot unsee that.
(upbeat music)
You can dance.
Having the time of your life.
When did you two practice this?
(sighs)
(upbeat music)
God damn it!
I told you this would happen.
(screams)
Don't panic, she can't see the kudex.
What the hell is that?
Wow, so ugly.
Stay where you can.
She can't see the
thing she's looking for.
(screams)
Oh!
You live anyhow!
I choose.
(suspenseful music)
Wow.
(laughs)
Area 51.
Yeah.
Huh?
We made it.
You finally got to see it, Den.
It's kind of cool.
Huh.
I guess.
Yeah.
Leaf.
Where you going, hon?
Well, let's see if we
can't find us something cooler.
Come on.
Come on, guys.
Okay, babe.
Life's long dream.
All right, go, go, go, go, go!
I smell alien.
(laughs) (suspenseful music)
He's deteriorating without his host.
Poor thing.
Put him below with the others.
I'm safer there.
(suspenseful music)
(grunts)
Down, down.
Come on, come on.
All right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I think we're gonna get
a better view from up there.
Follow me, guys, and come on.
This is so exciting.
I can't believe we're here.
Wow.
Whoa.
Oh, well.
What is this?
(suspenseful music)
It's all broken.
So sad.
Oh, buddy.
Hey, buddy.
Oh, no.
No.
Oh, no, how many
hours can you have in one day?
Eddie?
Hello?
They did this to me.
(suspenseful music)
Morgan?
What?
You're alive?
What are you doing here?
We're being hunted, Eddie.
You have what he needs.
Protect the Codex from dark hands.
A symbiote army waits here.
Free them.
Protected, Eddie.
Now must stay locked away.
Eddie, I'm Dr. Payne.
Where's my friend?
He's safe for now.
Great news.
We're all done here.
All of this is out of your hands.
This is my lab.
No, no, no, not yours.
You just work here.
Or you did.
You, Christmas, you're going home.
And what about them?
You heard what it said.
The Codex only
exists if they're both alive.
Yeah, we're good, we're good.
You killed one of my people.
I'm returning the favor personally.
Please escort Dr. Payne out here.
Christmas, time to go.
Hey!
(growling)
Big mistake.
(grunting)
(growling)
Fire!
Run!
(growling) (yelling) (gunshots)
(growling)
(gunshots)
Venom, run, go!
(yelling)
Release the symbiotes.
(gunshots)
(yelling)
(grunting)
(growling)
(yelling)
(gunshots) (yelling) (yelling)
Jim!
(growling)
Turn her down!
Get her!
(growling)
Let's go, boy.
Take her down!
(growling)
(yelling)
I'm gonna fall down!
Help!
(growling)
Come on!
Leave her!
Get the clonax outta here!
(growling)
That's our way out.
(gunshots)
You break us out of here!
(growling)
There's no aliens here, kids.
Best shoes ever!
Whoa!
What was that?
(gunshots)
We gotta go, move it!
(growling)
We are leaving!
Move!
Move, move!
It's all right, it's all right, kids.
Aliens!
Alien invasion!
Alien attack!
Motherfucker!
(growling)
You two, get out, Lord!
Hey, wait, sir, hold me!
You're high on the airborne!
Move, move, move!
In the harbor's gulf!
We got to get the
codex as far away as possible.
(growling)
It's Eddie?
It's Eddie.
Eddie!
Oh no, Eddie, Eddie!
Martin, I'm family!
Can't be here, Martin.
Dark forces, man!
(growling)
Ricky, can you help us?
I lied.
Aliens are real.
My best friend in the whole world is one.
He's gonna get you out of here, okay?
Don't be scared.
Hi.
Pleasure to meet you.
Huh?
It's for the chocolate.
You're welcome.
(growling)
No!
(screaming)
Hold on, Kari!
He was trying to protect you.
We are not the bad guys!
Ethel!
My baby, my baby.
Thank you, Eddie.
You're welcome.
You gotta be kidding me.
Get in!
Whoa, whoa!
Get out!
Stop!
Hey!
Come on.
Call, bring me that Codex.
What's that noise?
She found home.
(growling)
Oh, shit.
(screaming)
Get out!
Get out of here!
Take cover!
I got you.
(screaming)
She saved us.
I saw no one thing
that's gonna distract them.
Copy.
Get back to their van!
Come on!
Kari, Kari!
I'm gonna round them up.
Have the chopper follow me.
Go, go, go!
Go!
(growling)
He's leading them to a kill box.
When you get a lock, vaporize them!
(gunfire)
Shit!
(screaming)
We're back.
Okay, okay, hold it.
Come on, kids.
Go, come on!
Kari, honey.
Thank you.
Aliens suck!
(growling)
Light them up!
Copy that.
Torque eliminate.
(growling)
Thompson down!
It's coming down, go!
(growling)
(screaming)
Close!
I'll do it!
Let's finish this.
With pleasure.
The chopper blades.
(growling)
I got you.
Get him somewhere safe.
Oh boy.
(growling)
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Okay, okay.
(growling)
No.
Go on.
Okay, okay.
Still living your brother's dream.
(growling)
I'm coming.
Get over here!
Go, go!
(growling)
I'm proud of you, Eddie.
You did it all yourself.
Well, some of it.
(growling)
I really would
have liked to have seen her.
Who?
Lady Liberty.
Oh yeah.
Yeah, well, we're going.
We're gonna go just as
soon as we get out of here.
They're just going to keep coming.
We'll never leave this place, friend.
Oh God.
We were alive.
I thought we were
gonna be the lethal protector.
We are.
That's what this is.
Yeah. (dramatic music)
All right.
(growling)
Come again, us.
(growling) (growling)
(growling) (panting)
(growling)
Go.
Oh my God.
(growling)
What are you doing?
I'll never forget you.
Don't forget me, either, Eddie.
No.
Time to go.
Strickland.
Strickland authorized.
No.
Oh God.
Strickland.
Strickland authorized.
(growling)
Oh.
Huh?
It's just by for now.
(growling)
(growling) (growling) (growling)
No.
No, no.
(growling)
No.
No, Eddie.
(crying)
(growling)
Nureka.
Hey, buddy.
I just had a crazy dream.
Buddy.
He's not coming back.
He's coming back.
But I need him back.
He wasn't meant for this place.
You couldn't have kept him.
And he couldn't have kept you.
For your bravery, you
both have the heartfelt thanks
of a grateful nation.
Eddie, you're free
to start your life again.
Everything that happened in San Francisco
and in the last few days,
you'll be considered expunged.
Just so you're clear, of course,
you have a breath of
word of this to any living soul,
you will spend the rest of that life
in the coldest, darkest hole imaginable.
Good luck, Eddie.
(upbeat music)
I won't forget you, buddy.
Memories bring back
memories bring back y'all
Give me one last
dance before we hit the ground
(upbeat music)
Push me into
overdrive what a lovely way to go
If you're with me by
my side I'm in for the ride
(upbeat music)
There's no running no
escape all the venom never waits
Once you feel it
hits your veins it's too late
You're gone
(upbeat music)
There's no stopping we're slowing down
Give me one last
dance before we hit the ground
Before we hit the ground
Push me up against the
wall it's the final curtain call
About to be a ballroom bro oh come on
(upbeat music)
There's no stopping we're slowing down
There won't be a next time now
But I'll be fine if you're around
Give me one last
dance before we hit the ground
Before we hit the ground
(upbeat music)
There's no stopping we're slowing down
There won't be a next time now
But I'll be fine if you're around
Give me one last
dance before we hit the ground
(upbeat music)
Before we hit the ground
Before we hit the
ground Before we hit the ground
Before we hit the ground
(wind blowing)
Your champion has fallen.
The planets will be mine.
The king in black is awake.
I will kill your world.
Everyone will burn.
And you will watch.