["Django Theme Song"
by Luis Bacalov and Rocky Roberts playing]
♪ Django ♪
♪ Django
Have you always been alone? ♪
♪ Django ♪
♪ Django
Have you never loved again? ♪
♪ Love will live on
Oh, oh ♪
♪ Life must go on
♪ For you cannot
Spend your life regretting ♪
♪ Django ♪
♪ Django
You must face another day ♪
♪ Django ♪
♪ Django
Now your love has gone away ♪
♪ Once you loved her
Oh, oh ♪
♪ Now you've lost her
♪ But you've lost her forever
Django ♪
♪ When there are clouds
In the skies ♪
♪ And they are gray ♪
♪ You may be sad but remember
Love will pass away ♪
♪ Oh, Django ♪
♪ After the showers
The sun ♪
♪ Will be shining ♪
♪ Once you loved her
Oh, oh ♪
♪ Now you've lost her
♪ But you've lost her forever
Django ♪
♪ When there are clouds
In the skies ♪
♪ And they are gray ♪
♪ You may be sad but remember
Love will pass away ♪
♪ Oh, Django ♪
♪ After the showers
The sun ♪
♪ Will be shining ♪
♪ Django ♪
♪ Oh, Django ♪
♪ You must go on ♪
[chains clanking]
[slave grunting]
Whoa.
Who's that stumbling around in the dark?
State your business,
or prepare to get winged.
Calm yourselves, gentlemen.
I mean you no harm.
I'm simply a fellow weary traveler.
Whoa!
Good, cold evening, gentlemen.
I'm looking for a pair of slave traders
that go by the name of the Speck Brothers.
Might that be you?
-[Ace] Who wants to know?
-Well, I do.
I'm Dr. King Schultz.
This is my horse, Fritz.
-What kind of doctor?
-[Schultz] Dentist.
Now, are you the Speck Brothers,
and did you purchase those men
at the Greenville slave auction?
-So what?
-So, I wish to parley with you.
Speak English.
[chuckling] I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
It is a second language.
Now, amongst your inventory,
I've been led to believe,
is a specimen I'm keen to acquire.
Hello, you poor devils.
Is there one amongst you who was formerly
a resident of the Carrucan plantation?
[Django] I'm from the Carrucan plantation.
Who said that?
What's your name?
Django.
Then you are exactly
the one I'm looking for.
Do you know who the Brittle brothers are?
Who are they?
Big John.
Ellis.
Roger.
Sometime they call him Little Raj.
They was overseers
at the Carrucan plantation.
Not anymore.
Tell me, if you were to see any
of these three gentlemen again,
-would you recognize them?
-[Ace] Hey.
-Stop talking to him like that.
-Like what?
Like that.
My good man,
I'm simply trying to ascertain--
Speak English, goddamn it.
Everybody calm down. I'm simply a customer
trying to conduct a transaction.
I don't care. No sale. Now, off with you.
Don't be ridiculous.
Of course they're for sale.
[Ace] Move it.
My good man, did you simply get
carried away with your dramatic gesture,
or are you pointing your weapon at me
with lethal intention?
[cocks gun]
Last chance, fancy pants.
Oh, very well.
[Dicky screaming]
[Dicky groaning]
I'm sorry to put a bullet in your beast,
but I didn't want you to do anything rash
before you had a moment
to come to your senses.
You goddamn son of a bitch!
-You shot Roscoe!
-[Schultz] Well...
[Dicky] And you killed Ace!
I only shot your brother
once he threatened to shoot me.
And I do believe I have...
One, two, three, four...
Five witnesses who can
attest to that fact.
-Damn leg's busted.
-No doubt.
Now, if you could keep your caterwauling
down to a minimum,
I'd like to finish my line of inquiry
with young Django.
[Dicky screaming]
-[Dicky] God-fucking-damn it!
-As I was saying...
if you were to see
the Brittle brothers again,
you could recognize them?
Yeah.
Sold American! So, Mr. Speck?
Mr. Speck, how much
for young Django, here?
That iron is nasty business.
Could you hold this for a moment?
Thank you.
Django, get up on that horse.
Also, if I were you,
I'd take that winter coat
the dear, departed Speck left behind.
Nigger! Don't you touch my brother's coat.
[screams]
[Dicky] Goddamn it!
[Dicky groans]
One hundred, ten, twenty,
and five...
for young Django, here. And since
he won't be needing it anymore,
I'd like to purchase your brother's nag.
Also, Mr. Speck,
I'm afraid I will require a bill of sale.
Do you have one?
You go to hell, dentist!
I thought not.
No worries. I come prepared.
Thank you.
This will serve nicely as a bill of sale.
Whoa.
Now, as to you poor devils...
So, as I see it,
when it comes to the subject
of what to do next,
you gentlemen have two choices.
One. Once I'm gone,
you could lift that beast
off the remaining Speck,
then carry him to the nearest town.
Which would be at least 37 miles
back the way you came.
Or, two.
You could unshackle yourselves...
take that rifle,
put a bullet in his head,
bury the two of them deep,
and then make your way to a more
enlightened area of this country.
Choice is yours.
Oh, and on the off chance
there are any astronomy aficionados
amongst you,
the North Star is that one.
Ta-ta!
[clicks tongue]
[chains clanking]
Now, wait a minute, fellas.
Let's talk about this.
You gotta be reasonable
in a situation like this.
I'm not a bad guy. I'm just doing my job.
Blueberry, didn't I give you
my last apple?
Tell you what, boys.
Take me to the doc in El Paso, I'll get
you your freedom.
-[gun cocks]
-[Dicky] No. No, please.
All right, now.
I'd like you to take
two of these, tonight.
-[coughs]
-And then, in the morning...
There's a nigger on the horse!
What's everybody staring at?
They ain't never seen no nigger
on no horse, before.
[goats bleating]
Whoa.
Good morning, innkeeper.
Two beers for two weary travelers.
It's still a bit early.
We won't be open for another hour.
By then, we'll be serving breakfast.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What the hell you think you're doing, boy?
Get that nigger out of here.
[innkeeper] Help! Help!
[Schultz] Innkeeper!
Remember, get the sheriff,
not the marshal.
[innkeeper] Sheriff! Help!
Alas.
Now, we must act as our own bartender.
Sit down, my boy.
-What kind of dentist are you?
-[chuckles]
Despite that cart, I haven't
practiced dentistry in five years.
But these days,
I practice a new profession.
Bounty hunter.
Do you know what a bounty hunter is?
No.
Well...
The way the slave trade
deals in human lives for cash,
a bounty hunter deals in corpses.
[clicking tongue] Hat.
Prost.
The state places a bounty on a man's head.
I track that man, I find that man,
I kill that man.
After I've killed him, I transport
that man's corpse back to the authorities.
Sometimes that's easier said than done.
I show that corpse to the authorities,
proving yes, indeed,
I truly have killed him, at which point,
the authorities pay me the bounty.
So, like slavery,
it's a flesh-for-cash business.
What's a bounty?
It's like a reward.
You kill people
and they give you a reward?
Certain people, yeah.
-Bad people?
-Ah!
Badder they are, bigger the reward.
Which brings me to you.
And I must admit, I'm at a bit
of a quandary when it comes to you.
On one hand, I despise slavery.
On the other hand, I need your help.
If you're not in a position
to refuse, all the better.
So for the time being, I'm gonna make
this slavery malarkey work to my benefit.
Still, having said that...
I feel guilty.
So, I would like the two of us
to enter into an agreement.
I'm looking for the Brittle brothers.
However, at this endeavor,
I'm at a slight disadvantage,
insofar as I don't know
what they look like.
But you do. Don't you?
I know what they look like, all right.
Good.
So, here's my agreement.
You travel with me until we find them.
-Where we going?
-Ah,
I hear at least two of them
are overseeing up in Gatlinburg,
but I don't know where.
That means we visit every plantation
in Gatlinburg till we find them.
And when we find them...
you point them out, and I kill them.
You do that?
I agree to give you your freedom.
25 dollars per Brittle brother,
-that's 75 dollars.
-[chatter outside]
And, as if on cue, here comes the sheriff.
Okay, boys. Fun's over.
Come on out.
[indistinct chatter]]
All right, folks. Calm down.
Go about your business.
These jokers'll be gone, soon.
Now, why y'all wanna come
into my town and start trouble?
Scare all these nice people!
You ain't got nothing better to do
than to come into Bill Sharp's town
and show your ass?
-[gunshot]
-[sheriff screams]
[Sheriff groans]
[woman screams]
[man] What'd you just do to our sheriff?
-[gunshot]
-[woman gasps]
[crowd screaming]
Now, you can get the marshal.
[innkeeper] Marshal! Marshal!
-[Schultz] Should we wait inside?
-Can't we just leave?
After you.
Move that buckboard a long ways
across the street from the saloon.
I want six men, six rifles behind it.
I want two men, two rifles
up on this roof,
two men, two rifles on that roof.
All the barrels aimed at that front door.
Somebody get poor Bill out of the goddamn
street.
You, in the saloon!
We got 100 rifles aimed
at every way out of that building.
You got one chance
to get out of this alive.
You and your nigger come out, right now,
with your hands over your head
and I mean right now!
[Schultz] Is this the marshal
I have the pleasure of addressing?
Yes, it is.
This is U.S. Marshal Gill Tatum.
[Schultz] Na, wunderbar, marshal.
I have relieved myself of all weapons,
and, just as you have instructed,
I am ready to step outside
with my hands raised above my head.
I trust, as a representative
of the criminal justice system
of the United States of America,
I shan't be shot down in the street
by either you or your deputies
before I've had my day in court.
You mean, like you did our sheriff?
Shot him down like a dog in the street!
Yes, that's exactly what I mean.
Do I have your word, as a lawman,
not to shoot me down
like a dog in the street?
Well, much as we'd all enjoy
seeing something like that,
ain't nobody gonna cheat
the hangman in my town.
Fair enough, marshal. Here we come.
They're a little tense out there,
so don't make any quick movements
and let me do the talking.
-[door opening, closing]
-Come ahead.
-You unarmed?
-[Schultz] Yes, indeed we are.
Marshal Tatum, may I address you
and your deputies, and apparently
the entire town of Daughtrey,
as to the incident that just occurred?
Go on.
Thank you.
My name is Dr. King Schultz.
Like yourself, marshal,
I'm a servant of the court.
The man lying dead in the dirt,
who the good people of Daughtrey
saw fit to elect as their sheriff,
who went by the name of Bill Sharp,
is actually a wanted outlaw
by the name of Willard Peck
with a price on his head of 200 dollars.
Now, that's 200 dollars, dead or alive.
The hell you say?
I'm aware this is probably
disconcerting news,
but I'm willing to wager
this man was elected sheriff
at some time in the past two years?
-Yeah.
-[Schultz] I know this
because three years ago,
he was rustling cattle
from the B.C. Corrigan Cattle Company
of Lubbock, Texas.
Now, this is a warrant
made out by circuit court judge
Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin, Texas.
You're encouraged to wire him.
He'll back up who I am
and who your dear departed sheriff was.
In other words, marshal...
you owe me 200 dollars.
["Lo Chiamavano King (His Name Is King)"
by Luis Bacalov & Edda Dell'Orso playing]
I'll be damned.
♪ His name was King
He had a horse ♪
♪ Along the countryside
I saw him ride ♪
♪ He had a gun
I knew him well ♪
♪ Oh, I heard him singing
I knew he loved someone ♪
[Schultz] After this Brittle business
is behind us...
you'll be a free man.
With a horse,
75 dollars in your back pocket...
What's your plan after that?
Find my wife...
and buy her freedom.
Django!
I had no idea you were a married man.
Do most slaves believe in marriage?
Me and my wife do.
Old Man Carrucan didn't.
That's why we... ran off.
[Carrucan] Django...
Django, Django...
You got sand, Django.
The boy's got sand.
I got no use for a nigger with sand.
I want you to burn a runaway "R"
right here on his cheek.
And the girl, too.
[Django sighs]
And I want you to take them
to the Greenville auction and sell them.
Both of them.
Separately.
And this one...
You will sell him cheap.
[Schultz] In Greenville...
there should be some sort
of a records office.
You know, when she was sold...
you know where she came from...
and you know her name.
What is her name?
Broomhilda.
What?
Broomhilda?
Were her owners German?
Yeah, how you know?
She wasn't born
on the Carrucan plantation.
She was raised
by a German mistress. The Von Shafts.
She speak a little German, too.
-Your wife?
-Mm-hmm. When she was little,
her mistress taught her, so she'd have
someone to speak German with.
Well, let me get this straight.
Your slave wife speaks German
and her name is Broomhilda Von Shaft?
Yep.
They call me Hildi.
[rooster crowing]
When we gain access to these plantations,
we'll be putting on an act.
You'll be playing a character.
Huh?
No?
Now, during the act,
you can never break character.
Do you understand?
Yeah. Don't break character.
And your character is that of the valet.
What that is?
That's a fancy word for servant.
-Valet?
-Mm-hmm.
[Django chuckles]
And now, Django, you may choose
your character's costume.
Youse gonna let me pick out
my own clothes?
But of course.
["Lo Chiamavano King (His Name Is King)"
by Luis Bacalov & Edda Dell'Orso playing]
-♪ His name was King ♪
-♪ He had a horse ♪
-♪ He had a brother ♪
♪ Along the countryside
I saw him ride ♪
♪ He had a gun
Oh, I knew him well ♪
♪ And when he shot ♪
♪ Oh, that man, he never missed ♪
♪ Ride on, King, ride ♪
[Schultz] Whoa.
♪ You get your man ♪
It's against the law for niggers
to ride horses in this territory.
This is my valet. My valet does not walk.
I said, niggers on horses--
His name is Django. He's a free man.
He can ride what he pleases.
Not on my property.
Not around my niggers, he can't.
My good sir!
Perhaps we got off on the wrong boot.
Allow me to unring this bell.
My name is Dr. King Schultz,
this is my valet, Django,
and these are our horses, Tony and Fritz.
-[Fritz snorts]
-[women laughing]
Mr. Bennett, I've been led to believe
that you're a gentleman and a businessman.
And it is for these attributes
we've ridden from Texas to Tennessee
to parley with you, now.
I wish to purchase
one of your nigger gals.
You and your Jimmie
rode from Texas to Tennessee
to buy one of my nigger gals?
No appointment, no nothing?
Oh, I'm afraid so.
Well, what if I was to say
I don't like you
or your fancy-pants nigger,
and I wouldn't sell you a tinker's damn?
Now, what you got to say about that?
Mr. Bennett...
if you are the businessman
I've been led to believe you to be,
I have 5,000 things I might say
that could change your mind.
[chuckles]
Well, come on inside
and get yourself something cool to drink.
Huh! Mm-hmm.
[chuckles]
[indistinct chatter]
Maybe while we discuss business,
you could provide
one of your loveliest black creatures
to escort Django, here,
around your magnificent grounds.
[Big Daddy] Oh, well, absolutely. Betina?
-Yes, sir, Big Daddy?
-Uh... What's your Jimmie's name, again?
-Django.
-Django!
Betina, sugar, could you take Django there
and take him around the grounds, here,
and show him all the pretty stuff?
-As you please, Big Daddy.
-Oh, Mr. Bennett.
I must remind you, Django is a free man.
He cannot be treated like a slave.
Within the bounds of good taste,
he must be treated
as an extension of myself.
[Big Daddy] Understood, Schultz.
Betina, sugar?
-Yes'm?
-Django isn't a slave.
Django is a free man, you understand?
You can't treat him like any
of the other niggers around here,
because he ain't like any of the other
niggers around here. You got it?
You want I should treat him
like white folks?
No.
That's not what I said.
Then I don't know
what you want, Big Daddy.
[Big Daddy] Yes, I can see that. Uh...
What's the name of that
peckawood boy from town
that works with the glass?
His mama work over at the lumberyard.
-Oh, you mean Jerry.
-That's the boy's name. Jerry.
-You know Jerry, don't you, sugar?
-Yes'm, Big Daddy.
Well, that's it, then!
You just treat him like you would Jerry.
[plays classical violin]
That house we just left from
is the Big House.
Big Daddy call it that because it's big.
That there is the pantry.
That's where Big Daddy
hang all his dead meat.
Poor little squirrels.
What you do for your master?
Didn't you hear him tell you
I ain't no slave?
-So, you really free?
-Yes, I's free.
You mean you wanna dress like that?
-Betina, I need to ask something.
-What you want?
I'm looking for three white men.
Three brothers. Overseers.
-Their name is Brittle. You know them?
-Brittle?
Yes, Brittle.
John Brittle, Ellis Brittle...
Roger Brittle, sometime called Little Raj.
I don't know them.
They could be using a different name.
-They would've come this past year.
-You mean the Shaffers?
Maybe. Three brothers?
-Uh-huh.
-They here?
-Could you point one of them out to me?
Well, one's over in that field.
["Freedom" by Anthony Hamilton
& Elayna Boynton playing]
♪ Ooh ♪
[Django] Old Man Carrucan
ain't gonna appreciate this, now.
She work in the house, John.
You mess the skin up,
you gonna mess her up,
she ain't gonna be worth a damn thing.
Now, your Bible say...
♪ Felt like the weight of the
World was on my shoulders ♪
[Django] I told you, I made her do it.
-You ready?
-She didn't wanna run off with me.
If anybody should be getting whupped,
it should be me, John.
I've been here long enough.
You've known me a long time, now.
[dogs barking]
♪ Facing the fear that
The truth I discover ♪
You know, Master Carrucan
ain't gonna appreciate this.
She's a house slave.
-[whipping]
-[screams]
♪ I'm looking for freedom ♪
♪ Looking for freedom ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ And to find it
Cost me everything I have ♪
-[whipping]
-[screams]
♪ Well, I am looking for freedom ♪
-[whipping]
-[Django] I'm asking you, please.
Ain't this what you want? I'm keeping it
funny for you. Now, John, please.
-[whipping]
-[groans]
-♪ Oh, and to find it ♪
-Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God...
I's on my knees, John.
I like the way you beg, boy.
Is that who you was looking for?
Yep.
Where the other two at?
They by the stable,
punishing Little Jody for breaking eggs.
They whipping Little Jody?
Point me in that direction.
You go to that tree
and keep going thattaway.
Go get that white man I came here with.
-[Little Raj] Come on, now.
-[Jody] No, no, please!
[Little Raj] Come on, girlie. Come on.
-[Jody sobs]
-[Little Raj] Get you set up, now.
-And the Lord said, "The fear of ye..."
-[whipping]
"...and the dread of ye
shall be on every beast of the earth."
[whipping]
-[Little Raj] Hey, give me that arm!
-[Jody] Please, no!
[Little Raj] You better give me that arm.
You better give me that arm!
Okay, she ready!
[Jody whimpers]
And after this...
we'll see if you break eggs again.
John Brittle!
You remember me?
[girl gasps]
I like the way you die, boy.
Goddamn son of a bitch!
[grunts]
Keep it funny!
[screams]
[Little Raj groans]
Y'all wanna see something?
[cocks gun]
[Little Raj groans] No!
-[groans]
-[gunfire]
[cocks gun]
Who were they?
That's Big John, that's Little Raj.
Where's Ellis?
He's the one hightailing it
across that field right now.
-You sure that's him?
-Yeah.
-Positive?
-I don't know.
-If you're positive?
-I don't know what "positive" mean.
-It means you're sure.
-Yes.
-"Yes," what?
-Yes, I'm sure that's Ellis Brittle.
I'm positive he dead.
Django!
Everybody calm down.
We mean no-one else any harm.
Who are you two jokers?
I am Dr. King Schultz,
a legal representative
of the criminal justice system
of the United States of America.
The man to my left is Django Freeman.
He's my deputy.
In my pocket is a warrant
signed by circuit court judge
Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin, Texas
for the arrest and capture, dead or alive,
of John Brittle,
Roger Brittle and Ellis Brittle.
They were going by the name Shaffer.
[Schultz] You know them by the name
of Shaffer, but the butchers' real name
was Brittle.
These are wanted men.
The law wants them for murder.
Now, I reiterate.
The warrant states "dead or alive,"
so when Mr. Freeman and myself
executed these men on sight,
we were operating
within our legal boundaries.
I realize passions are high...
but I must warn you,
the penalty for taking deadly force
against an officer of the court
in the performance of his duty is...
you'll be hung by the neck
until you're dead.
Now, may I please remove the warrant
from my pocket so you may examine it?
Gimme.
Satisfied?
May I have that back, please?
Get off my land.
Posthaste.
Load up the bodies as quickly as you can,
and let's get out of here.
[Schultz whistles]
Yeah, that's them sons of bitches.
[men shouting and whooping]
[man 1] Come on, men!
[man 2] We're coming for you, nigger!
[Big Daddy] Now, unless they start
shooting first, nobody shoot them.
That's way too simple for these jokers.
We're gonna whup
that nigger-lover to death.
And I'm gonna personally strip and clip
that garboon myself.
Damn...
I can't see fucking shit
out of this thing!
[Randy] We ready or what?
[Big Daddy] Hold on,
I'm fucking with my eyeholes.
Oh. Oh, shit.
I just made it worse.
-[Harry] Who made this goddam shit?
-[O.B.] Willard's wife.
[Willard] Well, make your own
goddamn masks!
Look, nobody's saying they don't
appreciate what Jenny did.
[Redfish] If all I had to do
was cut a hole in a bag,
I could've cut it better than this.
[Randy] What about you, Robert?
Can you see?
[Robert] Not too good.
I mean, if I don't move my head,
I can see you pretty good, more or less,
but when I start riding, the bag's
moving all over, and I'm riding blind.
Shit.
I just made mine worse.
Anybody bring any extra bags?
[Redfish] No, nobody brought an extra bag!
I'm just asking.
[O.B.] Do we have to wear them
when we ride?
Well, shitfire!
If you don't wear them as you ride up,
that defeats the purpose!
[Redfish] Well, I can't see
in this fucking thing!
I can't breathe and I can't ride
in this fucking thing.
[Willard] Well, fuck all y'all.
I'm going home.
Now, I've watched my wife work all day,
getting 30 bags together for you
ungrateful sons of bitches,
and all I can hear is criticize,
criticize, criticize.
From now on, don't ask me
or mine for nothing.
Now, look. Let's not forget
why we're here.
We got a killer nigger
over that hill, there.
And we gotta make a lesson out of him.
Okay, I'm confused.
Are the bags on or off?
[Robert] I think we all think
the bag was a nice idea.
-[Randy] Yeah.
-[Robert] But, not pointing any fingers...
they could have been done better.
So, how about no bags this time...
but next time, we do the bags right,
and then we go full regalia.
-[man 1] I like that idea.
-[man 2] You get my vote, brother.
Wait a minute! I didn't say no bags.
But nobody can see.
-So?
-So, it'd be nice to see.
Goddamn it, this is a raid!
I can't see, you can't see.
So what? All that matters is,
can the fucking horse see?
That's a raid!
-[men shouting]
-[Harry] Sons of bitches!
I can't see shit!
[Big Daddy] There he is.
Get that nigger out from under that wagon.
And get that nigger-lover
out of the wagon!
-That nigger ain't down here, Big Daddy!
-What?
-They tricked us.
-Where are they?
Auf Wiedersehen!
-Oh! [laughs]
-Bullseye.
[men screaming]
[Django] Look at them run.
Yeah, cowards tend to do that.
[Big Daddy] Goddamn it!
Would you care to?
[Big Daddy] Can't see shit out of this!
-He's getting away.
-I got him.
[Schultz] Big Daddy's getting away.
I got him.
[bullet whistling]
[Big Daddy grunts]
Got him.
[horse neighing]
[chuckles]
The kid's a natural.
How you know Broomhilda's
first masters was German?
Broomhilda's a German name.
If they named her, it stands
to reason they'd be German.
Lots of gals where you're from
named Broomhilda?
Broomhilda is the name of a character
in the most popular
of all the German legends.
There's a story about Broomhilda?
Oh, yes, there is.
Do you know it?
Oh, every German knows that story.
Would you like me to tell you?
Well...
Broomhilda was a... princess.
She was a daughter of Wotan,
god of all gods.
Anyway, her father is really mad at her.
What she do?
I can't exactly remember.
She disobeys him in some way.
So, he puts her on top of the mountain.
Broomhilda's on a mountain?
It's a German legend, there's always going
to be a mountain in there somewhere.
And he puts a fire-breathing dragon there,
to guard the mountain.
And he surrounds her
in a circle of hellfire.
And there, Broomhilda shall remain...
unless a hero arises
brave enough to save her.
Does a fella arise?
Yes, Django. As a matter of fact, he does.
A fella named Siegfried.
Does Siegfried save her?
Quite spectacularly so.
He scales the mountain
because he's not afraid of it.
He slays the dragon
because he's not afraid of him.
And he walks through hellfire...
because Broomhilda's worth it.
I know how he feel.
I think I'm just starting to realize that.
Now, look... Django...
I don't doubt that, one day,
you'll save your lady love.
But I can't let you go to Greenville
in a good conscience.
A slave auction town in Mississippi
isn't a place for you to visit.
Free or not, it's just too dangerous.
But let me ask you a question.
How do you like
the bounty hunting business?
Kill white folks and they pay you for it?
What's not to like?
Now, I have to admit, we make a good team.
I thought you was mad at me
for killing Big John and Little Raj.
Yeah, on that occasion,
you were a tad overzealous,
but normally, that's a good thing.
How'd you like to partner up
for the winter?
What you mean, "partner up"?
You work with me through the winter
till the snow melts...
I give you a third of my bounties.
So, we make some money this winter,
and when the snow melts...
I'll take you to Greenville myself...
and we'll find where they sent your wife.
Why you care what happen to me?
Why you care if I find my wife?
Frankly...
I've never given anybody
their freedom before, and now that I have,
I feel vaguely responsible for you.
Plus, when a German meets
a real-life Siegfried,
that's kind of a big deal.
As a German, I'm obliged to help you
on your quest to rescue
your beloved Broomhilda.
["I Got a Name" by Jim Croce playing]
♪ Like the pine trees
Lining the winding road ♪
♪ I've got a name
I've got a name ♪
[indistinct chatter]
♪ Like the singin' bird
And the croakin' toad ♪
♪ I've got a name
I've got a name ♪
♪ And I carry it with me
Like my daddy did ♪
♪ But I'm livin' the dream
That he kept hid ♪
♪ Movin' me down the highway ♪
♪ Rollin' me down the highway ♪
♪ Movin' ahead
So life won't pass me by ♪
♪ Like the north wind
Whistlin' down the sky ♪
♪ I've got a song
I've got a song ♪
♪ Like the whip-poor-will
And the baby's cry ♪
♪ I've got a song
I've got a song ♪
♪ And I carry it with me
And I sing it loud ♪
♪ If it gets me nowhere
I'll go there proud ♪
♪ Movin' me down the highway
Rollin' me down the highway ♪
♪ Movin' ahead
So life won't pass me by ♪
[man] You got her.
[sighs]
Ooh! What happened to Mr. "I Wanna
Shoot White Folks for Money"?
His son's with him.
Well, good. He'll have
a loved one with him.
Maybe even share a last word.
That's better than most of them get.
Damn sight better than he deserves.
Put down the rifle.
Don't worry, I'm not mad at you.
Let's take out Smitty Bacall's handbill.
Now, read it aloud.
Consider that today's lesson.
"Wanted, dead or alive.
Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall G..."
-Gang.
-"...Gang...
for murder and stagecoach ro...
robbery.
-Seven, zero, zero, zero--"
-Seven thousand.
-Seven?
-Thousand.
"Seven thousand dollars
for Smitty Bacall,
One thousand, five hundred dollars
for each of his gang..."
-Mem...
-"...members.
Known members of the Smitty Bacall Gang
are as follas."
-Follows.
-"Follows.
Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash, and..."
Crazy Craig Koons.
That is who Smitty Bacall is.
If Smitty Bacall wanted
to start a farm at 22,
they would never have printed that.
But Smitty Bacall wanted
to rob stagecoaches,
and he didn't mind
killing people to do it.
Do you want to save your wife
by doing what I do?
This is what I do.
I kill people and sell
their corpses for cash.
This corpse is worth 7,000 dollars.
Now, quit your pussyfooting and shoot him.
[horse neighs]
[boy chuckles]
[boy] Pa?
Pa!
Here. You need to keep
this Smitty Bacall handbill.
-Why?
-It's good luck.
You always keep the handbill
of your first bounty.
That's accurate.
[Gus] Doctor, Django,
how the hell are you?
Who the hell have you got there?
[Schultz] The Wilson-Lowe Gang.
Who the hell is the Wilson-Lowe Gang?
Bad Chuck Wilson and meaner Bobby Lowe
and three of their acolytes.
Huh. Well, just leave them out here.
They ain't going nowhere.
Why don't you come in
out of the snowy snow
and get yourselves some coffee?
We had a birthday, yesterday.
Got some cake.
Pretty good.
[man 1] Move along! Can't hide!
[man 2] Keep moving. Get on up to that
auction block.
Don't let that mud
slow you down. Keep going.
[man 3] Come on.
[man 4] Keep going.
[Schultz] "Broomhilda Von Shaft. Age 27.
'R' on right cheek.
Calvin Candie."
He owns the fourth biggest cotton
plantation in Mississippi. Candyland.
Candyland?
-Oh, you've heard of it!
-Ain't no slave ever heard of Candyland.
Well, apparently,
that's where your wife is...
and that's the repellant gentleman
who owns her.
Let's just hope she works in the house,
not the field.
Oh, no. She ain't no field nigger.
She... She pretty.
And she talk good, too.
But when they tore her back up,
and then they...
burned that runaway "R" on her cheek...
they goddamned her.
[screams]
She ain't no field nigger, but she ain't
good enough for the house no more, either.
-They'll try to make her a comfort girl.
-What's a comfort...? Oh.
Not while I got freedom.
Not while I got my gun.
So, do we offer to buy her?
So...
say...
a man wants to buy a horse.
Needs to buy a horse.
He walks up to the farmer's farm,
knocks on the door and asks the farmer
to buy his horse. And you know
what the farmer says?
The farmer says, "No."
Well, I say, fuck that farmer.
And I'm stealing that horse.
Fair enough.
But now, you're a horse thief,
and they hang horse thieves.
Not to mention, the horse goes back
to its original owner,
because the horse is still his property.
We need her and we need a bill of sale.
If we ain't gonna try to buy her,
how we gonna get her?
May I offer an alternative plan of action?
Go ahead.
So...
The man walks up to the farmer's farm,
he knocks on the farmer's door...
and asks not to buy the horse,
but the farm.
-Mm-hmm.
-And makes an offer so ridiculous,
the farmer is forced to say, "Yes."
-We gonna offer to buy Candyland?
-No, it's far too big.
But apparently, this farmer
ain't all about the farm.
How much do you know
about Mandingo fighting?
What?
Can you convincingly masquerade as someone
who is an expert on Mandingo fighting?
Why?
[Schultz] Because my character is that
of a big money buyer from Dusseldorf
here in Greenville to buy my way
into the Mandingo fight game.
And your character is a Mandingo expert
I hired to help me do it.
[Django] They call that "One-Eyed Charly."
Bonjour!
Bonsoir, mon petite femme noire!
We're here to see Mr. Calvin Candie.
Entrer.
[Schultz] Thank you.
You want me to play a black slaver?
Ain't nothing lower than a black slaver.
A black slaver is lower
than the head house nigger.
And buddy, that's pretty fucking low.
Then play him that way.
Give me your black slaver.
[all]
♪ His heart was all a-flutter ♪
♪ Along came the 2:19 ♪
Toot, toot ♪
♪ Peanut butter fare thee well
Fare thee well, fare thee well ♪
Dr. Schultz!
-Good to see you again.
-Mr. Moguy!
Thank you for your assistance in creating
the opportunity for this appointment.
[Leo] Nonsense, it's my job.
So, this is the One-Eyed Charly
I've heard so much about!
Yes, this is Django Freeman.
Django, this is Mr. Candie's lawyer,
Leonide Moguy.
Just call me Leo.
Calvin's in the Julius Caesar room.
You all wanna follow me?
[Schultz] How long have you been
associated with Mr. Candie?
[Leo] Oh, Calvin's father and I
were about 11
when we went to boarding school together.
Calvin's father's father
put me through law school.
One could almost say I was raised
to be Calvin's lawyer.
One could almost say youse a nigger.
What did you say?
-I said--
-Nothing, he's just being cheeky.
Now, anything else about Mr. Candie
that I should know before I meet him?
-Yes, he is a bit of a Francophile.
-[laughs] What civilized people aren't?
And he prefers Monsieur Candie
to Mr. Candie.
[speaks in French]
He doesn't speak French.
Don't speak French to him,
it'll embarrass him.
[men grunting]
[Candie] Get back on top, now.
Turn around. There you go.
There you go.
Why do you want to get
in the Mandingo business?
You don't intend to allow your second
to make the proper introductions?
[Candie] Quit stalling, now.
Answer the question.
[men continue grunting]
The awful truth?
I'm bored. This seems
like a good bit of fun.
Well, come on over.
We got us a fight going on
that's a good bit of fun.
[Amerigo speaking in Italian]
Won't you accompany me to the bar?
You don't wear a hat in the house,
white man. Even I know that.
[men grunting]
[pool balls clacking]
-Dr. Schultz.
-What a rare pleasure.
-[Candie] Keep fighting, niggers!
-And, I might add, an honor.
Honor to meet you. Please, have a seat.
The pleasure's all mine.
Get free man Django, here,
whatever he wants.
And I'll have sweet tea and bourbon.
[both yelling]
[Candie] Use your weight, boy,
use your weight! There you go.
He's much bigger and stronger!
Come on, now!
Ah, he's not doing what I told him,
for God's sake!
Bravo! Bravo, Luigi!
[speaking in Italian]
[Candie] Come on, now, boy!
It's a fight to the death!
You either hit him or are you ain't?
[men grunting and roaring]
[speaking in Italian]
Big Fred, come on!
[Candie] Turn him around! Now, come...
Use your strength, boy!
Come on, now! Use your strength!
There you go.
There you go!
Look at that.
See, I told you to put
some more power in there.
Do what I told you, boy.
There you go.
No.
[Candie] Do what I told you!
Blind him black, boy!
Blind him black!
[Luigi screams]
Oh, no, Luigi.
[Candie] Yeah!
[whoops]
[sighs]
[panting]
[Luigi screaming]
Finish him.
[Luigi continues screaming]
Go on, boy, finish him.
-[hammer thuds]
-[Luigi is silent]
[Leo] That's why they call him Big Fred.
Worth every penny.
Well, arrivederci, Luigi!
Come on up, now, boy. Get yourself a rest.
You did a fine job. A real fine job.
Mercedes.
[music box playing distantly]
Tequila.
[indistinct chatter]
What's your name?
Django.
Can you spell it?
D-J-A-N-G-O.
The D is silent.
I know.
[Amerigo speaking in Italian]
[Candie] Mr. Moguy, I want you
to take care of my new boy, here.
You find him a room with a soft bed,
then bring him up a pony to lick his pole.
But you be ready to travel to Candyland
tomorrow morning, now, you hear?
-Yes, sir, Monsieur Candie.
-Before you go... Roscoe,
get Fred here a tall beer.
You enjoy that, boy. You've earned it.
Yes, sir.
What's your name, boy?
His name is Django Freeman.
[Candie chuckles]
Where'd you dig him up?
A fortuitous turn of events
brought Django and myself together.
I've heard tell about you.
I heard you been telling everybody
them Mandingos ain't no damn good,
ain't nothing nobody is selling
is worth buying. I'm curious.
What makes you such a Mandingo expert?
I'm curious what makes you so curious.
-What did you say, boy?
-Calm down, Butch.
No offense given.
None taken.
[Schultz] Monsieur Candie,
I'd appreciate if you could
direct your line of inquiry toward me.
One...
you do not have anything to drink.
Can I get you a tasty refreshment?
-Yes. I'll have a beer.
-Wonder-bar!
Roscoe, a beer for the man with the beard,
and I will have a Polynesian Pearl Diver.
Do not spare the rum.
Doc...
I am a seasoned slaver.
You are... Well, you are a neophyte.
I'm simply trying to ascertain if this
cowboy, here, is taking advantage of you.
With all due respect, Monsieur Candie...
I didn't seek you out for your advice.
I sought you out to purchase
a fighting nigger
at above top-dollar market price.
I was under the impression,
when you granted me an audience,
it would be to discuss business.
Well, we weren't talking business yet.
We were discussing my curiosity.
Thank you.
[Candie] Roscoe, Coco,
go outside and play.
Sheba, you stay right there.
I know you didn't mean me.
Prost!
German.
Now, according to Moguy,
if I do business with you,
I'm doing business with both y'all.
He does the eyeballing,
you the billfold? Is that it?
[chuckling] Well, you don't make it sound
too flattering, but more or less, yeah.
Hmm.
So...
Bright Boy, Moguy tells me
you looked over my African flesh
and you was none too impressed, huh?
Not for top dollar.
Then we got nothing more to talk about.
You see, you wanna buy
a beat-ass nigger from me,
those are the beat-ass niggers
I wanna sell, so...
He don't wanna buy the niggers
you wanna sell.
He wants the nigger you don't wanna sell.
Well, I don't sell the niggers
I don't wanna sell.
Well, you won't sell your best.
You won't even sell your second best.
But your third best? You don't want
to sell him either,
but if I made you an offer so ridiculous
you'd be forced to consider it...
[laughing] ...who knows what could happen?
And what do you consider ridiculous?
For a truly talented specimen?
The right nigger?
How much would you say, Django?
Twelve thousand dollars.
[Candie slurps]
Well, gentlemen, you had my curiosity,
but now, you have my attention.
[Candie] Willie? Willie.
Hold up. Hold up.
-Ah.
-Good morning, gentlemen.
Good Dr. Schultz.
Beautiful morning, isn't it?
You couldn't have picked a better one.
Please, won't you take a ride with us
here in the victoria?
[Schultz] Oh, thank you very much.
[Candie] You can tie
your horse up back there.
Django?
Where I part company from many
of my phrenologist colleagues
is I believe there is
a level above bright...
above talented, above loyal,
that a nigger can aspire to.
Say, one nigger
that just pops up in 10,000.
The exceptional nigger.
Bright day, huh, Bright Boy?
The sun is up.
It's shining on all of us.
Have a seat, doc.
Thank you. Quite an honor.
The honor is all ours. Thank you.
-[Schultz] Thank you.
-[Candie] But I do believe that,
given time,
exceptional niggers
like Bright Boy, here...
become, if not frequent...
more frequent.
Right, boy?
You are that one in 10,000.
The name of the game is keep up,
not catch up, nigger.
[men laughing]
-Whoa!
-[horse neighs]
-Touch your guns, you die.
-[Candie] Everybody calm down.
Now, I saw the whole thing. No harm done.
-Are you kidding me? This nigger just--
-I said, no harm done!
Now, take your hand off your pistol!
Butch, that means you, too.
Everybody stop antagonizing my guest.
Hoot, get back up on your horse.
[Hoot] He broke my collarbone.
For God's sake,
somebody please help Hoot, here,
back up on his goddamn horse.
-[Nick] Yes, sir, boss.
-Oh, you are one lucky nigger.
You better listen to your boss, white boy.
Oh, I'm gonna go walking
in the moonlight with you.
You wanna hold my hand?
[chuckles]
["100 Black Coffins" by Rick Ross playing]
[Candie] Willie, take us home.
[Jessie] Here we go. Start moving.
[Billy] Head them out.
♪ I need a hundred black
Coffins for a hundred bad men ♪
♪ A hundred black graves
So I can lay they ass in ♪
♪ I need a hundred black preachers
With a black sermon to tell ♪
♪ From a hundred black Bibles
While we send them all to hell ♪
♪ I need a hundred black coffins ♪
♪ Black coffins
Black coffins ♪
♪ I need a hundred black coffins ♪
♪ Black coffins, oh, Lord ♪
♪ Black coffins
I need a hundred ♪
You got a problem with your eyeball, boy?
-No, sir.
-You want a boot heel in it?
No, sir.
Then you keep
your goddamn eyeballs off me.
Flash that bad look at me again,
I'll give you a reason not to like me.
Now, move, nigger!
You niggers are gonna understand
something about me.
I'm worse than any
of these white men here.
You get the molasses out your ass,
you keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
He is a rambunctious sort,
ain't he? [chuckles]
Indeed!
May we stop for a moment so I may
put a word in my man's ear?
I'm expecting to fall in love
once I see the specimens at Candyland,
so before that moment,
it would be good if I could have
a confidential strategy meeting
with my confidant.
You mind telling me
what the hell you doing?
I confirmed that Broomhilda's
at Candyland.
-You're sure it's her?
-He didn't call her by name,
but she's a young lady,
whip marks on her back
and speaks German.
Now, while it's not wise to assume,
in this instance, I think
it's pretty safe. Point being...
don't get so carried away
with your retribution.
You lose sight of why we're here.
-You think I lost sight of that?
-Yes, I do. Stop antagonizing Candie.
You're going to blow this whole charade,
or, more than likely, get us both killed.
And I, for one, don't intend to die
in Chickasaw County, Mississippi, U.S.A.
I'm not antagonizing him.
I'm intriguing him.
You're yelling abuse at these poor slaves.
I recall the man...
who had me kill another man
in front of his son,
and he didn't bat a eye.
You remember that?
Yeah, of course I remember.
What you said was that this is my world.
And in my world, you gotta get dirty.
So, that's what I'm doing.
I'm getting dirty.
Well, you're paraphrasing a tad, but...
that was the general gist.
See you at Candyland.
[Django] All right, niggers. Back at it.
That means you too, Moonlight.
[dogs barking]
[Candie] I'll be.
D'Artagnan!
Now, boy, why do a fool thing
like run off?
I can't fight no more, Monsieur Candie.
[Candie] Yes, you can.
You might not be able to win,
but your ass can fight.
Mr. Stonesipher, would you please
shut these goddamn dogs up?
I cannot hear myself think!
Quieten down, Marsha! Marsha, hush up!
-[Marsha barks]
-[Stonesipher] Marsha! Hush up!
Hey! Get these goddamn dogs
away from this nigger!
[dogs whimpering]
Well, now, boy...
-get on out that tree.
-[D'Artagnan] Yes, sir.
[dogs barking]
How long was he loose?
A night. Day.
Half the other night.
How far he get off the property?
About 20 miles off prop.
Pretty far, considering that limp he got.
Mr. Moguy, who was D'Artagnan
supposed to fight on Friday?
One of this new lot.
Way he looks now, a blind Indian
wouldn't bet a bead on him.
[D'Artagnan] Please, Monsieur Candie,
I ain't got it in me no more.
Now, now, now. Now, no begging.
No playing on my soft heart.
-You in trouble now, son.
-Yes, sir.
You know, I done paid 500 dollars for you.
When I pay 500 dollars,
I expect to get five fights
out of a nigger
-before he roll over and play dead.
-Sir...
You got to understand,
I'm running a business here.
-You fought three fights.
-But I won every one!
Yes, you did. Yes, you did.
But that last one,
you muddled the line
between winning and losing.
Still, the fact remains.
I pay 500 dollars,
I want five goddamn fights.
So, what about my 500 dollars, huh?
What about my 500 dollars?
You gonna reimburse me?
You even know what "reimburse" means?
[all laughing]
[Schultz] I'll reimburse you.
You will?
Yep.
You'll pay 500 dollars...
for practically a one-eyed old Joe
ain't fit to push a broom?
No, he won't.
He just tired of you
toying with him, is all.
Matter of fact, so am I.
But we ain't paying a penny
for that piccaninny.
Ain't got no use for him.
Ain't that right, doc?
You heard him.
You're gonna have to excuse
Mr. Stonesipher's slack-jawed gaze.
He ain't never seen a nigger like you
ever in his life.
Ain't that right, Mr. Stonesipher?
That's right.
[Candie] For that matter...
nor have I.
Now,
seeing as you won't pay a penny
for this piccaninny, here...
you won't mind me handling this nigger
any way I see fit?
He's your nigger.
Mr. Stonesipher?
Let Marsha and her bitches
send D'Artagnan to nigger heaven.
[Stonesipher] Marsha!
Marsha, get him!
[dogs barking]
Get him, get him!
[all whooping]
[D'Artagnan screaming]
[screaming continues]
Your boss looks a little green
around the gills
for a blood sport like nigger-fighting.
No.
He just ain't used to seeing a man
ripped apart by dogs, is all.
Mm.
You are used to it?
I'm just a little more used
to Americans than he is.
-[Candie] Huh.
-Now,
[in French accent] Monsieur Candie...
[in normal voice] whenever you're ready.
We rode five hours
so you could show off your stock.
Let's get to it.
Because as of now, if he's an example...
I ain't impressed.
Follow me.
[clicks tongue]
[Jessie] Line them up
to the left here, now, boy.
Stand up straight, now!
Get up there.
Get up there, boy. Come on.
I said give me a line! Give me a line!
Get in line, there! Straighten up!
[Candie and Leo speaking indistinctly]
-[Candie] Hello! Stephen, my boy!
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hello, my ass.
Who this nigger up on that nag?
Oh, Stephen, you have
nails for breakfast?
What's the matter? Why you so ornery?
-You miss me, huh?
-[laughing] Oh, yes, sir.
I miss you like a hog miss slop.
-Like a baby miss mammy's titty.
-[both laugh]
I miss you like I misses
a rock in my shoe.
[laughs]
Now, I asked you,
who this nigger on that nag?
Hey, Snowball.
Wanna know my name
or the name of my horse, you ask me.
[Stephen] Just who the hell
you calling "Snowball," horse boy?
I'll snatch your black ass off that nag
down here in the mud so fast,
-make your head spin.
-Whoa, whoa! Stephen, Stephen, Stephen.
Let's keep it funny. Django here's a
Freeman.
-This nigger here?
-That nigger there.
Let me at least introduce
the two of you. Django?
This is another cheeky black bugger
like yourself, Stephen.
Stephen, this here's Django.
You two ought to hate each other.
Calvin, just who the hell is this nigger
you feels the need to entertain?
Django and his friend in gray here,
Dr. Schultz, are customers.
And they are our guests, Stephen.
And you, you old, decrepit bastard,
ought to show them hospitality.
-You understand that?
-[Stephen] Yes, sir. Him, I understand.
But I don't know why I got to take
lip off this nigger.
You don't have to know why.
Do you understand?
-Yes, sir. I understand.
-Well, good.
They're spending the night. Go up
in the guest bedrooms and get two ready.
He gonna stay in the Big House?
Stephen, he's a slaver. It's different.
-In the Big House?
-You got a problem with that?
No, I ain't got no problem with it.
If you ain't got no problem
burning the bed, the sheets
and everything else
when this black-ass motherfucker's gone!
That is my problem. They are mine to burn.
Now, your problem, right now,
is making a good impression.
I want you to start
solving that problem, right now,
and get them goddamn rooms ready!
Yes, sir, Monsieur Candie.
[Candie] Go on, now.
[Stephen] Can't believe you brought
a nigger to stay in the Big House.
-Your daddy rolling over in his grave.
-Man, the lip on him.
-[Stephen muttering indistinctly]
-Phew! He's getting worse and worse. Now!
[screaming] Where is my beautiful sister?
There she is!
[Candie whooping]
Dr. Schultz,
this attractive Southern belle
is my widowed sister.
Darling, you are a tonic for tired eyes.
May I present to you
Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly?
Chester, Rodney, Chicken Charly.
Y'all get over by that pen.
-[Tommy] Come on, Charly. Go on.
-[Bill] Let's go. Come on, now.
You know where it is. Like you on a rope.
[Tommy] Niggers don't walk
around here, niggers run.
[Schultz] Ah, Monsieur Candie?
[Candie] Mm?
About that matter, about the nigger girl
you were talking about?
Nigger gal?
Yeah, I believe you mentioned
she spoke German.
Ah, yes, Hildi! What about her?
Do you think, before the demonstration,
you could send her around to my room?
You little dickens, you! [laughs]
I don't see why not.
Stephen, when you get through
showing them to their rooms,
go fetch Hildi, get her cleaned up
and smelling real nice,
-and sent over to Dr. Schultz's room here.
-[laughs] Actually, Monsieur Candie, sir,
there's something I ain't
told you about, yet.
-What?
-Uh... Hildi in the hot box.
-[Candie] What's she doing there?
-[Stephen] What you think she doing there
in the hot box? She being punished.
-[Candie] What she do?
-[Stephen] She run off again.
Jesus Christ, Stephen!
How many people ran away while I was gone?
-Two.
-When did she go?
Last night.
They brung her back this morning.
How bad did Stonesipher's dogs
tear her up?
[Stephen] Lucky for her, they was out
chasing D'Artagnan's ass.
Bill and Cody went looking for her,
found her, brung her back.
-Now, she a little beat up.
-Mm.
But she done that to her own damn self,
running through them bushes.
[Candie] How long she been in the box?
[Stephen] How long do you think
she been in there? All damn day.
And the little bitch got
10 more days be in there.
-Still, take her out.
-Take her out? Why?
Because I said so, that's why.
Dr. Schultz is my guest.
Hildi is my nigger.
Southern hospitality dictates
I make her available to him.
-But Monsieur Candie, she run off.
-Jesus Christ, Stephen.
What is the point of having a nigger
that speaks German
if you can't wheel them out when you have
a German guest?
-I...
-Now, I realize it is inconvenient,
but still, you take her ass out.
Yes, sir.
[Candie] Lara Lee, will you
and Cora be responsible
for getting Hildi cleaned up
and presentable for Dr. Schultz, here?
-[Lara] Of course, darling.
-Now, gentlemen, I do apologize,
but I am weary from our travels
beyond words.
It is time for me to rest my tired eyes.
[clicking tongue]
Y'all done heard the man!
Get her ass up out of there!
Cora, come here.
Get over there, get her cleaned up,
bring her back over here to Dr....
-What'd you say your name is? Shoots?
-Schultz.
Schultz. Get her back
over here. Hurry up, girl.
Yes, sir.
[Broomhilda screaming]
[Hoot] Come on, girl. Stand up.
[Broomhilda] No!
[gasping]
[screams]
[Broomhilda screaming]
Is you coming with me, or is you gonna
sleep in that little box over yonder?
["Ancora Qui" by Elisa playing]
[Lara exhales]
Hello, ladies.
Dr. Schultz.
May I introduce to you Broomhilda?
Hildi, this is Dr. Schultz.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Broomhilda.
I've heard a lot of good things about you.
Well, it's not every nigger
speaks German, don't you know.
[both chuckle]
[Schultz] As I look
at you now, Broomhilda,
I can see all the passions you inspire
are completely justified.
The doctor here speaks German.
And I've been informed you do as well?
Go ahead, girl. Speak a little German.
[speaking in German]
[Lara laughs]
Astonishing.
[speaking in German]
-And I shall bring--
-[Schultz] Much obliged.
[speaking in German]
Ja.
Don't be afraid.
[speaking in German]
Hmm.
Pardon.
[speaking in German]
Danke.
[laughs]
Ich verspreche es.
Hey, Little Trouble Maker.
[gasps]
[sighs]
You silver-tongued devil, you.
-Hurry up, girl.
-These ready, Miss Cora.
No, no, no. They drinking, tonight.
Go downstairs, get the big jug
with the red stuff Monsieur Candie like.
Get your pretty ass out the way. You know
you like it.
That's because you knows
what I like. [laughs]
[Cora] Ooh! Come on
with these biscuits, girl.
Look, Monsieur Candie,
they were all fine specimens,
no doubt about it.
But the best three by far were Samson...
-What's that other one's name?
-Goldie.
Goldie,
and Eskimo Joe.
By the way, why is he called "Eskimo" Joe?
You never know how these
nigger nicknames get started.
His name was Joe, maybe one day
he said he was cold. Who knows?
[all laughing]
Well, regardless, Samson's your best.
We all know that.
You will never sell him,
and I can see why.
He's a champion.
Mm-mm-mm. All three are champions.
Samson's the champion.
Them other two pretty good.
-Calvin, what's this nigger you let--?
-It's all right, it's all right.
You have to understand, Monsieur Candie,
while admittedly a neophyte
in the nigger-fight game,
I do have a little bit of a background
in the European traveling circus.
Is that right?
[Schultz] Hence, I have big ideas when it
comes to presentation.
-Mm.
-[Schultz] I need something more
than just a big nigger.
Yeah, he needs to have panache.
-Need to have what? What?
-Panache. Uh...
-A sense of showmanship.
-Showmanship, yes.
I want to be able to bill him
as the Black Hercules.
[all laughing]
-The Black Hercules! Isn't that clever?
-More like Nigger-les.
[all laughing]
I said, and I quote...
"I would pay top dollar
for the right nigger."
Now, I'm not saying that Eskimo Joe
is the wrong nigger, per se.
But is he right as rain?
Oh, Dr. Schultz, I will have you know
there is no-one in the nigger-fight game
that appreciates the value of showmanship
more than Monsieur Calvin J. Candie.
Nobody.
But one must not forget
the most important thing
-in the nigger-fight game.
-Mm-hmm.
-And that is a nigger that can win fights.
Now, that should be your first,
second, third, fourth and fifth concern.
Now, after you have that,
and you know you have that,
then you can start to implement
a grand design.
In other words, first thing is first.
First thing's first.
[whispering in German]
-[chuckles]
-Ooh! I see you two getting on.
Famously!
Oh, Monsieur Candie, you cannot imagine
what it's like not to hear
your native tongue in four years.
Well, hell, I can't imagine
two weeks in Boston!
-[all laughing]
-[Stephen howls with laughter]
Two weeks in Boston!
[laughs] Monsieur Candie, you a mess.
[laughs] Two weeks in Boston!
[Schultz] I can't express the joy I felt
conversing in my mother tongue.
And Hildi is a charming
conversation companion.
[Candie] Well, be careful, now,
Dr. Schultz.
You might've caught yourself
a little dose of nigger-love.
-Nigger-love's a powerful emotion, boy.
-[Stephen] Mm!
It's like a pool of black tar.
Once it catches your ass, you caught.
Yes, sir, you stuck. [chuckles]
[Lara] I don't know, doctor.
You can lay on all the German
sweet talk you want, but...
it looks like this pony's
got big eyes for Django.
[Lara chuckles]
Well, naturally!
It is the soaring eagle that attracts
her attention, not the plucked chicken.
[all chuckling]
[Candie] Dr. Schultz, don't be
so down on yourself.
You are quite
the dapper European gentleman.
[Cora] You got to clean these dishes.
Put your elbow in these dishes, you hear?
You know that nigger, don't you?
-Who?
-"Who?"
Don't "who" me, bitch.
You know who I'm talking about.
At the table?
I don't know him.
You don't know him.
-No.
-"No," what?
No, sir.
[chuckles]
You wouldn't lie to me, now, would you?
[tuts] Okay.
Yeah. If you say so.
Eskimo Joe's a quality nigger,
no doubt about it.
But if it was my money...
I wouldn't pay no 12,000 dollars for him.
What would your price be?
Well, if I was inclined to be generous,
and I don't know why
I would be inclined to be generous...
nine thousand.
Maybe.
[Candie] Dr. Schultz.
Let me re-clarify how this whole
negotiation came about.
It wasn't me who came to you
to sell a nigger.
Sure wasn't.
-It was you who approached me to buy one.
-Sure was.
[Candie] That 9,000 dollars Bright Boy's
been bandying about
ain't too far off. If I wanted to sell
Eskimo Joe for that
-I could do so any day of the week.
-Any day.
But like you said in Greenville, doctor,
I don't wanna sell him.
It was only your ridiculous offer
of 12,000 dollars
-that made me even consider it.
-Mm-hm.
You know, Monsieur Candie,
you do possess the power of persuasion.
[chuckles]
[Schultz bangs table]
Why not? Monsieur Candie, you have a deal.
Eskimo Joe, 12,000 dollars.
Hooray, doctor. Hooray.
And a wise decision that is.
However, that is a tremendous
amount of money.
And the way you have your Mr. Moguy,
I have a lawyer.
Persnickety man named Tuttle.
And I would need my Mr. Tuttle
to draw up a legal contract
before I'd feel comfortable exchanging
that amount of money for flesh.
-Mm-hmm.
-Not to mention having Eskimo Joe examined
by a physician of my choosing.
-[Candie] Naturally.
-So, say I return in about...
-five days' time.
-Five days?
With my Mr. Tuttle.
And then my Mr. Tuttle and your Mr. Moguy
can hash out the finer details
between themselves.
I say splendid, doctor. Splendid.
Gentlemen...
may I propose a toast?
To Eskimo Joe.
Or shall we call him the Black Hercules?
-[all laughing]
-[Schultz] To the Black Hercules.
-[Stephen] The Black Hercules!
-The Black Hercules.
You was right, doctor.
That name do have pan-ass.
[chuckles]
Mm. Hildi? Top my drink off.
So, Hildi, how you like serving
at the big table in the Big House, huh?
When Monsieur Candie
talk to you, you answers.
-I like it a lot, Monsieur Candie.
-[Candie] Mm-hmm!
It's better than sizzling in that hot box
or dragging your ass
through a bramble bush.
Maybe not quite as much fun as getting
to pleasure all them Mandingos,
-huh, sugar bear?
-She like them niggers.
-Like Samson? Huh?
-[Broomhilda] No, sir.
You know, Monsieur Candie, the doctor here
might be interested in seeing
Hildi's peeled back, seeing as how
they don't have many niggers
where he come from.
Dr. Schultz, when you was alone
with Hildi, here,
did you just speak German,
or did you get to take her clothes off?
-No, we just talked, and--
-[Candie] So you haven't seen her back?
I haven't.
No, no, no. Stephen's right,
you might find this interesting.
Hildi, take off your dress.
Show Dr. Schultz your back, here. Go on.
[Lara] Uh... Calvin! I just got her
all dressed up and looking nice.
[Candie] But, Lara Lee,
Dr. Schultz is from Dusseldorf!
They don't got niggers there.
He is a man of medicine.
I'm sure it would fascinate him,
the nigger's endurance for pain.
These niggers are tough,
Dr. Schultz, no doubt about it.
Hildi's got something like
four lashes on her back.
Lara Lee just get one,
she'd lose her goddamn mind.
Look at that, doctor.
It's like a painting.
[shouting] Calvin!
[whispering] We are eating. Ain't no-one
wanna look at her whipped-up back.
Fine. Fine, fine, fine.
After dinner, then, Stephen. After dinner.
During the brandies, gentlemen. Hmm?
[Lara] Cora, come get this girl.
-She a mess.
-Yes, ma'am.
Oh. Why are you all undone?
I just got you done up. Come on in here.
Baby, you on Stephen bad side,
and you need to be on his blind side.
You say you ain't know him.
-[Broomhilda] Huh?
-I said...
you said you ain't know him.
[Broomhilda] I don't.
Yes, you do.
Mr. Stephen...
I don't.
Why is you lying to me?
I ain't.
Then why is you crying?
You scaring me.
Why is I'm scaring you?
Because you scary.
[Schultz] To speak German this afternoon
with Hildi was positively soul-enriching.
[Candie chuckles] Doctor, that warms
my heart to hear that.
You stay right here.
[Schultz] You indicated earlier
you'd be willing to part with Hildi.
Why, yes. Yessirree Bob, I did.
In that case,
allow me to propose another proposition.
I'm all ears.
Hurry up, goddamn it!
-Monsieur Candie--
-[Candie] Stephen.
[bangs table] You just
interrupted Dr. Schultz, here.
[Stephen] I'm sorry, Dr. Schultz.
My ears ain't worth a damn, these days.
Excuse him.
Monsieur Candie, could I get
a word with you in the kitchen?
You mean get up out of my chair?
If'n you could manage it.
-Why?
-It's about dessert.
What about dessert?
I'd rather discuss that in private.
[chuckling] We're having white cake!
What sort of melodrama
could be brewing, back there?
You right, Monsieur Candie, you right.
I'll handle it myself. [chuckles]
[whispering] Meet me in the library.
[speaking] I just can't understand
why you won't come talk to these niggers.
Shit get fucked up around here,
you blame me.
Fine, fine. Friend Stephen,
I... will be along momentarily.
Yes, sir.
[Candie] Well...
Gentlemen, as you can see, talented
as they are, no doubt, in the kitchen,
from time to time,
adult supervision is required.
[all chuckling]
If you'll excuse me a moment.
You may clear the dinner service.
[Cora] You heard him.
Go on, get. Hurry up, girl.
So, Dr. Schultz...
why don't you regale us
with a tale of the circus?
-The circus? [laughs]
-Yes.
What is the matter?
Them motherfuckers ain't here
to buy no Mandingos.
They wants that girl.
[chuckles]
Stephen, what the hell
are you talking about? Hmm?
They playing your ass for a fool,
is what I'm talking about.
They ain't here
for no muscle-bound Jimmie.
They here for that girl.
What... What girl? What, Hildi?
Yeah, Hildi. Her and Django?
Them niggers know each other.
-He just bought Eskimo Joe, I--
-Did he give you any money?
-No, not yet, but--
-Then he ain't bought diddly.
Not yet, no how.
But he's just about to buy...
who he come here to buy
when I interrupted him.
"Thank you, Stephen."
"You're welcome, Calvin."
Where you getting all this?
Why would they go through all that trouble
for a nigger with a chewed-up back
ain't worth 300 dollars?
They doing it 'cause that nigger Django's
in love with Hildi.
She probably his wife.
Now, why that German gives a fuck
who that uppity son of a bitch
is in love with, I'm sure I don't know.
If she's who they want...
why this whole snake oil pitch
about Mandingos, then?
You wouldn't pay no never mind
to no 300 dollar.
But that 12,000?
That made you real friendly,
now, didn't it?
Yes, it did.
His wife, huh?
If it had been a snake,
it would've bit me.
[chuckles]
Those lying...
goddamn time-wasting sons of bitches.
[claps] Sons of bitches!
[Lara] ...out of New Orleans,
so I have quite a bit of practice
with theater types. [chuckles]
Oh, there you are! I was beginning
to think that you and that old crow
-run off together.
-[all chuckling]
That'd be a hell of a note, wouldn't it?
Lara Lee, I was just looking
out the big window.
Billy Crash is out there
dealing with some shady slaver
trying to sell a passel of ponies.
Would you be a dear, go out there
and give them gals an eyeball?
-Hmm?
-Of course, brother.
-Thank you, darling.
-[giggles]
-Yeah. Business never sleeps.
-Mm-hmm.
Apropos, before your exit,
we were discussing
the possibility
of my purchasing Broomhilda.
Ah, yes. Yes, we were, doctor.
And we will again, in a moment.
Who's your little friend?
[clears throat]
This is Ben.
He's a old Joe that lived around here
for a long time.
And I do mean a long damn time.
Old Ben here took care of my daddy...
and my daddy's daddy.
Till he up and keeled over, one day...
Old Ben took care of me.
Growing up the son
of a huge plantation owner in Mississippi
puts a white man in contact
with a whole lot of black faces.
I spent my whole life here,
right here in Candyland...
surrounded by black faces.
Now, seeing them every day,
day in, day out, I...
I only had one question.
-Why don't they kill us?
-[laughs]
Now, right out there on that porch,
three times a week for 50 years,
Old Ben here would shave my daddy
with a straight razor.
Now, if I was Old Ben, I would've
cut my daddy's goddamn throat
and it wouldn't have taken me
no 50 years to do it, neither.
But he never did.
Why not?
You see, the science of phrenology...
is crucial to understanding
the separation of our two species.
In the skull of the African, here...
the area associated with submissiveness
is larger than any human or any other
subhuman species on planet Earth.
[sawing]
[Candie] If you examine...
this piece of skull, here...
[blowing]
[Candie] ...you will notice
three distinct dimples.
Here, here and here.
Now, if I was holding the skull
of an... Isaac Newton or Galileo,
these three dimples would be found
in the area of the skull
most associated with creativity.
But this is the skull of Old Ben.
And in the skull of Old Ben,
unburdened by genius,
these three dimples exist in the area
of the skull most associated with...
servility.
Now, Bright Boy.
I will admit you are pretty clever.
But if I took this hammer here...
and I bashed in your skull with it...
you would have the same three dimples...
in the same place...
-[wand chimes]
-[Candie] ...as Old Ben.
[roaring] Hey!
Now, lay your palms flat on that tabletop!
If you lift those palms
off that turtle shell tabletop,
Mr. Pooch is gonna let loose
with both barrels of that sawed-off.
There have been a lot of lies
said around this dinner table tonight,
but that, you can believe!
Mr. Moguy, would you be so kind
as to collect the pistols
hanging off these boys' hips, here?
-Thank you ever so much.
-[Leo] Doctor.
Where were we?
Jackass!
Ah, yes!
I do believe you were just getting ready
to make me a proposition
to buy Broomhilda.
Am I right?
Right.
Bring out Hildi!
[Stephen] Get over there yonder.
-Sit your ass in that goddamn chair!
-[screams]
[Stephen] Lay your hands flat
on that tabletop.
[Candie] Now, shut your mouth!
Dr. Schultz,
in Greenville, you yourself said
that for the right nigger,
you'd be willing to pay what some
may consider is a ridiculous amount.
To which me myself said,
"What is your definition of ridiculous?"
To which you said, "12,000 dollars."
Now, considering y'all have ridden
a whole lot of miles,
went through a whole lot of trouble
and done spread a whole lot of bull
to purchase this lovely lady right here,
it would appear
that Broomhilda is, in fact,
the right nigger.
And if y'all wanna leave
Candyland with Broomhilda...
the price is 12,000 dollars.
And I take it you prefer the "take it
or leave it" style of negotiation?
Yes, I do, doctor.
You see, under the laws
of Chickasaw County,
Broomhilda here is my property.
And I can choose to do
with my property whatever I so desire.
And if y'all think my price...
-for this nigger, here, is too steep...
-[yelps]
...what I'm gonna desire to do is...
take this goddamn hammer here
and beat her ass to death with it!
-Right in front of both y'all!
-Easy, big fella.
Then, we can examine the three dimples
inside Broomhilda's skull!
Now, what's it gonna be, doc? Huh?
-[Broomhilda sobs]
-What's it gonna be?
May I lift the hands off the tabletop
in order to remove my billfold?
Yes, you may.
[Broomhilda sobs]
That 12.
-Sold!
-[screams]
[Candie] To the man
with the exceptional beard
and his unexceptional nigger.
-Mr. Moguy.
-Yes, Calvin?
Will you make these gentlemen a receipt
for 12,000 dollars, please?
Twelve thousand dollars.
It was a pleasure
doing business with y'all.
Now, gentlemen...
if you care to join me in the parlor...
we will be serving white cake.
["Für Elise" by Ludwig van Beethoven
playing on harp]
[D'Artagnan screaming]
Well done, Calvin. [chuckles]
Excuse me.
Excuse me, ma'am?
Could you please stop playing Beethoven?
Take your hands off the harp.
[Stephen] Doctor.
-Doctor, you can't go in there.
-Stephen, Stephen--
-He ain't got no business going in there.
-Let it be.
He's just a little upset,
that's all. I'll handle this.
White cake?
[Schultz] I don't go in
for sweets. Thank you.
Hmm.
[Candie chuckles]
You brooding about me
getting the best of you, huh?
[Schultz] Actually, I was thinking of that
poor devil you fed to the dogs today.
D'Artagnan.
And I was wondering what Dumas
would make of all this.
Come again?
Alexandre Dumas.
He wrote The Three Musketeers.
[Candie] Yes, of course, doctor.
I figured you must be an admirer.
You named your slave
after his novel's lead character.
Now, if Alexandre Dumas
had been there today,
I wonder what he would've made of it.
You doubt he'd approve, huh?
Yes. His approval would be a dubious
proposition at best.
[chuckles]
Soft-hearted Frenchie.
Alexandre Dumas is black.
-Are these Broomhilda's papers?
-[Candie] Yes, they are.
-May I?
-[Candie] Of course.
Thank you.
That is her bill of sale,
her ownership history,
and of course, her freedom papers, doctor.
Would you have ink and pen for me?
-Right over there on that little table.
-[Schultz] Thank you.
Thank you.
Broomhilda Von Shaft.
Consider yourself a free woman.
Mr. Candie.
Normally, I would say auf Wiedersehen.
But since what auf Wiedersehen
actually means is "till I see you again,"
and since I never wish
to see you again, to you, sir...
I say goodbye.
Let's go.
Come on.
[Candie] One more moment, doctor.
What?
It's a custom here, in the South...
once a business deal is concluded,
that the two parties...
shake hands.
-It implies good faith.
-I'm not from the South.
But you are...
in my house, doctor.
So I'm afraid I must insist.
Insist?
On what? That I shake your hand?
Oh, then I'm afraid I must insist
in the opposite direction.
-You know what I think you are?
-What you think I am?
No, I don't.
I think you are a bad loser.
And I think you're an abysmal winner.
[Candie] Nevertheless...
here in Chickasaw County,
a deal ain't done
until the two parties have shook hands.
Even after all that paper signing,
don't mean shit...
you don't shake my hand.
If I don't shake your hand,
you're gonna throw away 12,000 dollars?
I don't think so.
Mr. Pooch?
If she tries to leave here before this
nigger-loving German shakes my hand...
you cut her ass down.
[cocks gun]
You really want me to shake your hand?
I insist.
If you insist!
[screaming] No! Calvin!
Calvin!
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
[sobbing]
Nigger's gone crazy! Help!
-[screams]
-Help, he's killing everyone!
[screams]
[groaning]
[Leo screams]
-[man 1] Holy--!
-[Maynard] Shit!
-[man 2] Son of a--!
-[Maynard] Bitch!
-[gunfire]
-[men yelling]
-[man 3] Damn it!
-[Maynard] Fucking... Get the...
[Jessie groaning]
[Maynard] Damn it,
son of a bitch! What...?
What the... Fucking... Goddamn it!
-What the fuck is going on?
-[screams]
You shot me! You stupid son of a...
[Maynard] Sorry, Jessie!
Who the fuck gave a nigger a goddamn gun?
[whimpering]
[screaming]
[Maynard] Aim low!
Nigger gonna kill!
[screams] God! Oh, my God!
Ow! Motherfucker!
[woman screaming]
♪ Am I wrong 'cause I wanna
Get it on till I die ♪
[Maynard] Shit!
♪ Get it on till I die
Get it on till I die ♪
Y'all remember me ♪
♪ I like the way you die ♪
♪ Am I wrong 'cause I wanna
Get it on till I die ♪
♪ Get it on till I die
♪ Y'all remember me
I like the way you die ♪
♪ I only wish to breed I explode
Into a million seeds ♪
♪ Y'all remember me
Legendary, live eternally ♪
♪ Bury me in pieces, 'cause
They fear reincarnation ♪
♪ Niggas screaming peace
'cause they fear when my squad face 'em ♪
♪ Take them to places
Stake they face then erase them ♪
♪ Brake 'em
Murder motherfuckers at a rate ♪
♪ Quicken the pace
Blast me, but never ask me live a lie ♪
♪ Am I wrong 'cause I wanna
Get it on till I die? ♪
♪ Now, even if you die
You still see my prophecy ♪
♪ My destiny to overcome... ♪
[2pac] Expect me, nigga,
like you expect Jesus to come back.
Expect me, nigga. I'm comin'.
Shit.
[Stephen] Hold your fire!
Hold your fire!
Stop shooting, goddamn it!
[gunfire ceases]
Django!
What?
[grunts]
We got your woman.
Billy Crash, here, got his pistol
upside her head.
-[Broomhilda gasps]
-[Stephen] You don't stop all that
carrying on, he gonna blow
her goddamn brains out.
Now, that ain't no threat, horse boy.
That there is a promise.
Or you can give up, throw your gun out.
We won't kill Hildi.
Horseshit!
Honest Injun, Django. I swear 'fore God.
You give up?
Ain't no harm gonna come to her.
And I'm supposed
to believe your black ass?
[Stephen] I don't give a good goddamn
what you believe or don't believe!
I believe if you don't give up
in the next ten seconds,
we gonna blow this bitch's
brains out. Believe that!
[sobbing] Don't do it. You give me up.
-[Stephen] Six!
-Just let me go.
-[Stephen] Seven!
-They got too much.
-[Broomhilda] Django...
-[Stephen] Eight!
-I love you.
-Nine!
-[Django] Hold it!
-No!
I give up.
I can't hear you, nigger.
I said, I give up.
["Freedom" by Richie Havens playing]
♪ Freedom, freedom
Freedom ♪
[sobbing] No.
No.
♪ Freedom, freedom
Freedom ♪
♪ Sometimes I feel ♪
♪ Like a motherless child ♪
♪ A long ♪
[man coughing]
♪ Way ♪
♪ From my home ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
[door opening]
[footsteps approaching]
Cock-a-doodle-doo, nigger.
So, y'all bounty hunters, huh?
I knew there was something fishy
about y'all.
We found your wanted posters.
And a book of figures in your saddlebags.
I got to say...
I ain't never heard
of no black bounty hunter before.
Black boy paid to kill white men?
How'd you like that line of work?
Probably pretty good while it lasted, huh?
[Django grunting]
Time to say good night
to them nuts, blackie. On three.
-One...
-[Django screams]
I got you.
-Two...
-[Django screams]
Calm down, now. Here it comes.
-[Stephen] Captain?
Miss Lara want to see you.
Something to do
with the Old Man's funeral.
[clears throat] Oh, and she changed
her mind about snipping Django.
She gonna give him to the LeQuint Dickey
people.
[Django whimpers]
Well, she didn't waste
a minute telling me.
How disappointing.
[knife sizzles]
-[laughs]
-[horse neighing]
[Stephen] You leaving.
This, here, what you take with you.
Your black ass has been all them
motherfuckers at the Big House
could talk about for the last few hours.
Seem like white folk ain't never had
a bright idea in they life
was coming up with all kinds of ways
to kill your ass.
Now, mind you, most of them ideas had
to do with fucking with your fun parts.
Now, that may seem like a good idea,
but truth is...
when you snip a nigger's nuts,
most of them bleed out in,
oh, about, hmm, seven minutes.
Most of them.
[chuckles]
Oh. More than most.
Then I says...
"Shitfire!
The niggers we sells to LeQuint Dickey
got it worse than that."
And they still saying,
"Let's whip him to death,"
or, "Throw him to the Mandingos,"
"Feed him to Stonesipher's dogs."
And I said, "What's so special about that?
We do that shit
all the time. Hell's bells,
the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey
got it worse than that."
Lo and behold,
out of nowhere, Miss Lara
come up with the bright idea...
of giving your ass
to the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company.
And as a slave
of the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company...
henceforth, till the day you die...
all day, every day...
you will be swinging a sledgehammer...
turning big rocks into little rocks.
Now, when you get there,
they gonna take away your name...
give you a number and a sledgehammer...
and say, "Get to work."
And one word of sass,
they cuts out your tongue.
And they good at it, too.
You won't bleed out.
Oh, they does that real good.
They gonna work you,
all day, every day,
till your back give out.
Then they're gonna hit you
in the head with a hammer,
throw your ass down the nigger-hole.
And that will be the story of you, Django.
["Ain't No Grave (Black Opium Remix)"
by Johnny Cash playing]
♪ There ain't no grave
Can hold my body down ♪
[Floyd] And what's the golden rule,
Frankie, eh?
You don't root abos.
Hey, white boy.
I said, hey, white boy.
Shut up, black. You ain't got
nothing to say I wanna hear.
How'd you like to make 11,000 dollars?
Do what, now?
I said, how'd you like
to make 11,000 dollars?
11,500, actually.
What the fuck you talking about?
Back there at that plantation, Candyland,
there was an 11,500-dollar fortune.
Just sitting there.
And y'all rode right past it.
You be damned, blackie.
We're not bandits.
I ain't saying that.
Nice thing about this fortune
is it ain't illegal.
You can't steal it.
You got to earn it, white boy.
You got something to say, mate,
you say it.
The 11,500-dollar fortune
waiting for you back at Candyland
is in the form
of a "wanted, dead or alive" bounty
on Smitty Bacall and the Bacall Gang.
Who the fuck is Smitty Bacall?
Smitty Bacall is the leader
of this murderous gang
of stagecoach robbers,
the Bacall Gang.
There's a 7,000-dollar
"wanted, dead or alive" bounty on him,
1,500 dollars for each
of his three accomplices,
Dandy Michaels,
Gerald Nash and Crazy Craig Koons.
All four of them gentlemen,
they back there at Candyland
laughing their ass off. You know why?
Because they just got away with murder.
But it ain't got to be that way.
You and your mates?
Y'all can ride back there
and y'all can get that money.
What'd these jokers do, again?
These sons of bitches,
they killed innocent people.
Stagecoach robbery. Innocent white people.
I got the handbill right here
in my pocket, if you let me get it.
Get it out.
[Roy] "Wanted, dead or alive.
Smitty Bacall
-and the Smitty Bacall Gang."
-[Frank] But you're a slave.
-[Django] I ain't no goddam slave!
-[Roy] "Murder and stagecoach robbery."
Do I sound like a fucking slave?
-[Roy] "7,000 dollars for Smitty Bacall."
-[Frank] That's a shitload.
I'm a bounty hunter.
Yesterday, as a free man,
I rode into Candyland on a horse
with my German, white partner,
Dr. King Schultz.
We tracked the Bacall Gang
all the way from Texas
to Chickasaw County.
We finally found their ass
laying low in Candyland.
We went in there to get them,
things went sour...
my partner got killed,
Calvin Candie got shot,
then everybody there decided to blame me,
so here I am.
But y'all know I ain't on that manifest.
And all y'all know I ain't
supposed to be on this trip.
But them four men is still back there,
they're still wanted,
and that 11,500 is up for grabs,
and the last thing
they'd expect is y'all
riding back in there and getting it.
[Roy] Well, what's the deal?
You tell us who they are
and we turn you loose?
No, no, no. I ain't gonna
tell you who they are.
But you give me a pistol,
one of them horses,
and 500 dollars of that 11,500?
And I'll point them out to you.
[Roy] This is a real handbill.
Just because it's a real handbill, doesn't
mean that other bunch of malarkey is.
Now, why would a slave
have a "wanted, dead or alive" handbill
in his pocket?
Did that black ride into Candyland
yesterday?
-All right, I'm gonna ask you again.
-[cocks gun]
I want you to remember,
I don't like liars.
Is he a Candyland slave,
or did he ride in with a white man
on a horse, yesterday?
Yeah.
They walked us
from the Greenville auction
and he rode in on a horse
with a white man.
Now, this white man...
Was the black his slave?
He wasn't no slave.
You fucking sure about that?
Damn sure.
Uh-huh.
What happened over in Candyland?
Bunch of shooting. Master got shot.
-Who shot him?
-The German.
Why'd he do that?
Nigger and the German was acting like
they were slavers, but they wasn't.
-[Roy] Well, what were they?
-Bounty hunters.
Fuck me, Roy. I mean,
this could be big, mate!
Well, smoke, you got a deal.
I got one more condition.
[Roy] What's that?
When we get there, when time come...
-you let me help you kill them.
-Hey? [laughs]
You're a funny bugger! [laughs]
-Cut him loose.
-[Floyd] Yeah, yeah.
You got yourself a deal, blackie.
[in Australian accent]
Got yourself a deal, mate.
Hey? [laughs]
You're all right
for a black fella. Oh, yeah.
[men chuckling]
There we go. There you go, mate.
Yeah.
[Roy] We're gonna give you
that packhorse over there.
-What the saddlebags got in them?
-[Floyd] Dynamite.
I ain't riding no horse
with no goddamn dynamite on its back.
I can understand that.
Frankie, why don't you take
them sticks off that horse
and stick them in the nigger-cage?
A little dynamite for you black fellas
to play with! [laughs]
Here, Floyd, you got that rifle
up on the wagon, don't you?
Yeah, right.
Why don't you give him
your gun and gun belt?
Righto.
Now, don't drop
the fucking thing, all right?
I just had the sights fixed and they're
perfect.
Oh, that's good to know.
[horses neighing]
["Who Did That to You?"
by John Legend playing]
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Now I'm not afraid
To do the Lord's work ♪
♪ You said vengeance is his
But I'mma do it first ♪
♪ I'm gon' handle my business
In the name of the law ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Now if he made you cry
Oh, I gotta know ♪
♪ If he's not ready to die
He best prepare for it ♪
♪ My judgment's divine ♪
♪ I'll tell you who you can call ♪
♪ You can call ♪
♪ You better call the police
Call the coroner ♪
♪ Call up your priest
Have him warn ya ♪
♪ Won't be no peace
When I find that fool ♪
♪ Who did that to you
Yeah ♪
My baby ♪
♪ Who did that to you ♪
Throw me up that dynamite.
♪ Now I don't take pleasure
In a man's pain ♪
♪ But my wrath will come down
Like the cold rain ♪
♪ And there won't be no shelter
No place you can go ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ It's time put your hands up
Time for surrender ♪
♪ I'm a vigilante
My love's defender ♪
♪ You're a wanted man
Here everybody knows ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ You better call the police
Call the coroner ♪
♪ Call up your priest
Have him warn ya ♪
♪ Won't be no peace... ♪
[locks door]
["Too Old to Die Young"
by Brother Dege playing]
[dogs barking distantly]
♪ Round and round
Round we go ♪
♪ Where it stops?
Nobody knows it ♪
-[Stonesipher] Jake.
-Yeah?
Get out there and see what's wrong
with them goddamn dogs.
Get them.
♪ Side to side, baby ♪
[Django] D'Artagnan, motherfuckers!
♪ You got your reasons
And I got my wants ♪
♪ Still got that feeling, but
I'm too old to die young now ♪
♪ Too old to die young now ♪
♪ Above or below the ground ♪
♪ Just too old
To die young now ♪
♪ Still the good Lord might lay me down ♪
[horse neighing]
[Django] Auf Wiedersehen.
[horse approaching]
[horse neighing]
[Django] It's me, baby.
[Stephen] ♪ In the sweet by-and-by ♪
♪ We will meet ♪
♪ On that beautiful shore ♪
[Stephen humming]
♪ By-and-by
By-and-by ♪
♪ By-and-by we will meet ♪
♪ We will meet by-and-by ♪
Cora, would you prepare us some coffee?
Sheba, you help her.
Come on.
[Stephen] ♪ In the sweet-- ♪
[Django] ♪ By-and-by, oh ♪
Y'all gonna be together with Calvin
in the by-and-by.
Just a bit sooner
than y'all was expecting.
[Lora screams]
[screams]
Billy Crash. Now, where were we?
Oh, that's right.
Last time I seen you,
you had your hands on my...
[screams]
-Sweet Jesus.
-[Billy continues screaming]
Django! You black son of a bitch!
The D is silent, hillbilly.
[Lara sobbing] Oh, no!
Now, all you black folks,
I suggest you get away
from all these white folks.
Not you, Stephen.
You right where you belong.
Uh... Cora, before you go,
will you tell Miss Lara goodbye?
Do what now?
I said, tell Miss Lara goodbye.
-Bye, Miss Lara.
-[Lara shrieks]
Y'all two run along, now.
[door closing]
Stephen! How you like my new duds?
You know, before now, I didn't know
that burgundy was my color.
I count six shots, nigger.
I count two guns, nigger.
You said, in 76 years on this plantation,
you seen all manner of shit
done to niggers.
But I notice, you didn't mention
kneecapping.
Oh, God! Motherfucker! Damn it!
-Seventy-six years, Stephen.
-[Stephen] Shit!
How many niggers you think you see
come and go, huh? 7,000? 8,000?
9,000?
9,999?
Every single word that came out
of Calvin Candie's mouth
was nothing but horseshit.
But he was right about one thing.
I am that one nigger in 10,000.
[Stephen screams]
You son of a bitch!
Oh, you motherfucker!
Oh, sweet Jesus, let me kill this nigger!
You ain't gonna
get away with this, Django.
They gonna catch your black ass.
You gonna be
on the wanted posters now, nigger.
The bounty hunters
gonna be looking for you!
You can run, nigger,
but they gonna find your ass!
And when they do, oh, Lord,
what they gonna do to your ass!
They ain't gonna just kill you, nigger.
You done fucked up!
This Candyland, nigger.
You can't destroy Candyland!
We been here! There's always gonna be a
Candyland.
["Trinity: Titoli" by Annibale
e I Cantori Moderni playing]
[Stephen] Can't no nigger gunfighter
kill all the white folks in the world!
They gonna find your black ass!
[Stephen laughing]
Django!
You uppity son of a--
♪ He's the guy
Who's the talk of the town ♪
♪ With the restless gun ♪
♪ Don't shoot broad out
To fool him around ♪
♪ Keeps the varmints on the run, boy ♪
♪ Keeps the varmints on the run ♪
♪ You may think he's a sleepy, tired guy ♪
♪ Always takes his time ♪
Hey, Little Trouble Maker.
Hey, Big Trouble Maker.
♪ When you've seen him use a gun, boy ♪
♪ When you've seen him use a gun ♪
♪ He's the top of the West ♪
♪ Always cool, he's the best ♪
♪ He keeps alive with his Colt .45 ♪
[Schultz] You know what they
are going to call you?
"The fastest gun in the South."
♪ You won't bother to fool him around ♪
♪ When you've seen him use a gun, boy ♪
Let's get out of here.
♪ When you've seen him use a gun ♪
♪ He's the top of the West ♪
♪ Always cool, he's the best ♪
♪ He keeps alive with his Colt .45 ♪
♪ Who's the guy who's riding into town ♪
♪ In the prairie sun? ♪
♪ You won't bother to fool him around ♪
♪ When you've seen him use a gun, boy ♪
♪ When you've seen him use his gun ♪
["Ode to Django (The 'D' Is Silent)"
by RZA playing]
♪ In the eyes of the sparrow
Every father would love ♪
♪ To overthrow a tyrant
This is simple science ♪
♪ Jack overthrows the giant ♪
♪ Neither snow, rain mountain, or ice
Can block my path of vengeance ♪
♪ There's no repentin',
I'm giving you the death sentence ♪
♪ Blood stains on the cotton field
In the cotton mill ♪
♪ Cold steel heat your body up
May you rot in hell ♪
♪ Thirty-six lashes on my back
Left gashes ♪
♪ For every crack of the whip
I felt mental flashes ♪
♪ Interrupt my baby-making
Have my ladies taken ♪
♪ To a place far up north
And more forsaken ♪
♪ Lord, help this fool
He's a dead man ♪
♪ 'Bout to put another hole
In his Klan headband ♪
♪ The good Dr. Schultz
Check the dental records ♪
♪ The slug'll make
His whole mug disconnected ♪
♪ I learned to shoot the dead man
With a tango ♪
[audio from 1966 film Django plays]
[man 1] Yeah, his name is Django.
[Maria] I love you, Django.
[man 2] Django, I think
you should make a last request.
[Maria] I love you, Django.
[man 2] I'll be glad to oblige you
any way I can.
[man 2] Start praying if you like
I don't mind.
It's a smart thing to do when you know
that death is coming for you.
How come you haven't got
your burial suit with you?
-We'll have to leave you to the vultures.
-[Maria] I love you, Django.
[man 1] Where life has little value
compared to death.
[Maria] I love you, Django.
[woman] Maria, it's terrible.
He enjoys killing.
[Maria] I love you, Django.
I love you, Django.
Who was that nigger?