Mum!
Mummy!
I had the dream again.
"And he climbed down
that chimney,
straight into the
huge black pot.
And that was the end of
the big bad wolf."
Did they really kill the
wolf, Mum’?
I'm sure they did.
I'll kill the monster
when it comes.
I'll smash its head in.
It's time to go to sleep now,
sweetie.
It's very late.
Can we read it again?
"Along time ago--
just yesterday, in fact--
there were three little pigs
and one nasty, big wolf."
What have you done?
It's not broken.
It just slipped.
I don't want you firing
things off in the house anymore.
Wait, wait, wait!
Watch this.
When the monster comes,
I'm gonna do this.
Please don't!
Nothing in my hands.
Stand still please.
Look at me, Mum.
- Come on, Samuel.
- Look at me.
Stand still please.
Nothing in my hands.
I don't want you making
weapons anymore.
It doesn't work if you
don't look at me!
This monster thing has
got to stop, all right?
Mm!
Don't do that
Ready?
Come on.
Quick.
You're late already.
What have you got in there?
See you later, alligator!
Here's one for you, Norma.
It's got milk in if.
What?
One with your milk in it.
I don't want milk.
No worries.
I'll make you another one.
Ah, just where a woman
should be: In the kitchen.
"Get to work, woman!"
- Do you want a cuppa?
- Nah.
I'm heading for the
dementia ward.
Ah.
It’s a few years before you end
up there, isn't it?
Right?
Amelia, your son's school
is on the phone.
Oh, my God.
Did he hurt anyone?
A dart could have gone into a
child's eye or even worse.
I'm gonna have a serious
talk with him.
Mrs. Vanek,
we've had the talks.
We've had the sessions
with the counsellor.
We're going to have to
employ cu monitor for him.
Monitor?
He'll be separated from
the other children.
The monitor will supervise him
one-on-one.
Samuel won't cope with this.
He already feels so different.
I'll have a talk with him.
I'll have a serious--
Mrs. Vanek, the boy has
significant behavioural problems.
You know, Samuel doesn't
need a full-time monitor.
What he needs is some
understanding.
I have 24 other first-graders
in that class!
Do you want me to put them all
at risk because of your son?
I think I'll just find
another school.
Mrs. Vonek, you can’t just
take the boy out of school.
You look after your business,
and I'll go find a school that
sees my son as Cl human being
and not just as another problem
to be gotten rid of.
That's very unfair.
We're only trying
to help the boy.
Please stop calling him
"the boy."
His name is Samuel.
We can see Ruby and
Auntie Claire at the park today.
You can play on
that swing you like
for as long as you like,
okay?
Mrs. Bowen hates me.
No, she doesn't.
You just need a break.
That's all.
Don't tell Auntie Claire
what happened.
I'll tell her later.
Mum, come and look at this.
I can do it again.
Sam, don't bother the lady.
Oh, no, no,
that's all right.
We have to go home and
see Daddy though, haven't we?
- My dad's in the cemetery.
- Oh, that's--
He got killed driving Mum to
the hospital to have me.
Samuel!
- I'm sorry, he just--
- No, that's all right.
I shouldn't have...
Well, your Mum's very lucky to
have you then, isn't she?
We have to go.
- Say "See you later," Katie.
- Bye.
The artist was so drunk
he vomited,
right in front of his
own installation.
Lost all these sales.
You're not listening.
Oh, I am.
I am.
So, you... You lost all these
sales and then what happened?
Ruby.
Don't play there, it's wet.
Mum! Mum!
I'm gonna smash its head!
Be careful.
Mum, Mum!
I'm gonna smash it!
What would you like me
to do for Wednesday?
I can get their birthday cakes.
That's easy.
I was hoping Ruby would
change her mind.
She doesn't want a joint party
with Sam this year.
Oh.
Mum, Mum!
She wants to have
a princess party.
Mum! Mum!
That's okay.
We don't have to come.
You can still come.
Mum!
She just doesn't want to
share the day with Sam anymore.
I understand.
- Mum!
- I understand.
Mum, I can go really high!
Watch!
Maybe you want to
celebrate his birthday
properly this year
anyway, on the day.
Yeah, we'll see.
You know, Amelia, I just want
you to be happy, and then this
birthday thing rolls around,
and I end up feeling awful.
I don't want you to
feel awful, Claire.
We'll be fine.
We'll be absolutely fine.
Mum!
Look at me!
Mummy!
Who do we have here?
Hello, Mrs. Roach.
You look fired, little one.
You been in the wars today?
A few wars.
He's had a big day,
that's all.
He's just exhausted.
Poor little sweetheart.
BUQSY!
Hello, darling.
Hello.
You look tired too, love.
You Okay?
Nothing five years of sleep
wouldn't fix.
I'll put your rubbish out
for you, Gracie.
No, no, no.
You just got in, pet.
I'll do it now.
Then it's done.
You can choose one tonight.
Where'd you get this?
On the shelf.
''If it's in a word or
it's in a look,
you can't get rid of
the Babadook.
If you're ca really clever one,
and you know what it is to see,
then you can make friends
with a special one,
ca friend of you and me."
"His name is Mister Babadook.
And this is his book.
A rumbling sound then
three sharp knocks.
Ba-ba-ba dook!
Dook! Dook!
That's when
you'll know he's around.
You'll see him if you look.
"Ba-ba-ba dook! Dook! Dook!"
We might read another one
tonight, eh?
But you said I could choose.
"This is what
he wears on top.
He's funny, don't you think?
See him in your room
at night..."
Mum, does it hurt the boy?
Mum?
Does it live under the bed?!
Mummy.
Mummy!
"How sweetly they sung,
telling of their happiness and
Iovingness way at the bottom of
the ocean and enfreaﬁng the
sirens not to be afraid."
It's that time of the night
again, time--
If that's what
the doctor ordered, I--
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's...
what the doctor ordered.
Mum!
It's in my room!
- What is?
- The Babadook!
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
This is not going to happen.
The closet doors were closed,
and now they're wide open.
It's just a book.
It can't hurt you.
You've had a big day.
You're just exhausted.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you, Mum.
Nothing bad's gonna happen,
Sam.
I'm gonna protect you.
Mum, it's 9:00.
He's not running CI fever
anymore.
No, no, no, my sister's
going to take him.
Put it back.
Put it back,
or it goes in the bin.
Aw!
Sorry.
What was that?
Oh, no, no,
I couldn't get to the phone.
He was vomiting.
Yeah, yeah, no worries.
I'll see you soon.
Samuel.
No monster talk at
Auntie Claire's, okay?
Samuel?
No Babadook, no nothing.
All right?
88.
Number 88.
Two fat ladies?
Good, Elaine.
Another few days, and someone
could call out "bingo."
Number 11.
Who has number 11?
Less?
11?
Right.
Let's see what else we've got.
5 billion.
Anyone got 5 billion?
Beverly's not very impressed
with your bingo skills.
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah.
No, I'm fine.
How are you?
How's G wing?
Fine, yeah.
Just a bunch of old people.
You don't have to be fine,
you know.
Just a bit stressed
at the moment.
Why don": you go home?
Old cranky bitch,
she goes after lunch.
I can cover for you.
You'd do that?
Yeah.
I'll give you my pay.
Aw, don't...
Don't be ridiculous.
You've got a sick boy.
Life's too short.
You're so sweet, Robbie.
- You should go.
- Yeah.
Say hi to Sam for me.
I will.
Where have you been?!
You weren't at work.
- I rung you a million times.
- What happened?
He scored the crap
out of Ruby, that's all.
He insisted on talking to this
bloody Babadook thing.
All day, just talking
to the air.
- It even freaked me out
- I'm so sorry.
You need to get him to
see someone, Amelia.
It's not normal for a kid to
carry on with this rubbish.
It's not rubbish!
It's real!
Don't you talk to your
Auntie Claire like that!
Where did you get
those firecrackers?
You got them for me
on the internet.
Well, that's the
end of the internet.
If the Babadook was real,
we'd see it right now,
wouldn't we?
It wants to scare you first.
Then you'll see if.
Well, I'm not scared.
You will be when it creeps
into your room at night.
That's enough.
You will be when it
eats your insides!
I've decided you're not
having your birthday
with Ruby this week.
No cake, no games.
That's the end of it.
Samuel!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Mum and Dad!
Life is not always as it seems.
It can be a wondrous thing!
But if can also be
very treacherous.
Don't worry, Dad.
I'll save Mum.
I'm gonna trap the Babadook
like this!
When he's trapped,
I'm gonna kill it!
Samuel?
I was just putting
something back.
All your father's things
are down there.
He's my father!
You don't own him!
Just thought I'd see
how you're going.
Can I come in?
Hi, matey.
This is for you.
My mum always got me a
model plane when I was sick.
I'm not sick.
Oh. I...
I thought...
No, he's not, actually.
The truth is, he's so
disobedient he can't
go to school anymore.
You said that's not true!
How many six-year-old boys
do you know, Robbie,
who still believe in monsters?
I hate you!
She won't let me
have a birthday party,
and she won't let me
have a dad!
Ow.
Don"r eat it.
The Babadook did it, Mum.
Go and watch a DVD, and
I'll make something else.
The Babadook did it!
Just go and watch a DVD,
Samuel.
Ladies and gentlemen,
girls and boys,
welcome to The Great Martin's
DVD School of Magic.
Life is not always as it seems.
It can be ca wondrous thing.
But it can also be very
treacherous.
On this DVD, you will learn
magic tricks to surprise,
to delight and
perhaps even shock
your family and friends.
Do you think this is funny?
Oh, no.
No. No.
Give it to me!
Do you want to die?!
Don't let it in!
Mum, do we have to go to
Ruby's party?
I've already got this doll, Mum.
Now she's got 0 twin.
They can go shopping together.
Come on.
Off you go.
He's just really tired.
Go and play right now.
Claire tells me
you're Cl writer.
Oh. no, not really.
Not anymore.
What kind of writing
did you do?
I wrote some articles for
some magazines
and did some
kids‘ stuff.
You just need to get
back into it, hat’s all.
It must be difficult.
I do volunteer work with some
disadvantaged women,
and a few of them have
lost their husbands,
and they find it very hard.
How's Richard's merger going?
Ah. Good.
I mean, his workload's
just ballooned.
I've got the kids 24/7,
it feels like.
- Tell me about if.
- I don't even have time to go
to the gym anymore.
It's ridiculous!
That's a real tragedy.
Not having time to go to the gym
anymore, how do you cope?
You must have
so much to talk about
with those poor
disadvantaged women.
This is my tree house.
You're not allowed in here.
I'm not hurting anybody.
Thank you.
Bye.
Thanks
How would your mum
know if it's real or not?
She never comes to our house.
Mum told Dad
she didn't want
to go to your house
‘cause it's too depressing.
The Babadook would eat
your mum for breakfast.
- It’d rip her arms off!
- Shut up!
They feel sorry for me, Claire.
There's a big difference.
God, Amelia, as soon as anyone
mentions Oskar, you can‘? cope.
- That's not true.
- It'll be seven years.
Isn't it time you moved on?
I have moved on.
I don't mention him.
I don't talk about him.
What strain is that on you,
Claire?
You're not even good enough
to have Cl dad.
Everyone else has one,
and you don't.
I do have CI dad!
I listen to your life,
day in, day out,
and you never stop
to ask me anything about mine.
I do.
I want to know how you are!
You don’t come around
to our house anymore.
Because I can‘? stand being
around your son.
I can't believe
you just said that.
You can't stand being
around him yourself.
Your dad died so he didn't
have to be with you.
That's not true!
And your mum
doesn't want you.
No one wants you.
What did you do?!
She said I didn't have a dad!
She kept saying if!
Is she all right?
Stay here and
look after the children!
Do you want another one
to get hurt?
Mummy!
She wouldn't believe me!
Mummy! MummY!
Why can‘? you
just be normal?!
There is no Babadook!
Get out!
- Get out!
- Samuel.
- Mummy!
- Stop this now.
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Please help me!
There's something
wrong with my son!
I think it may have been a
febrile convulsion.
That's when the brain overheats.
It always looks worse
than it is.
I've never seen
anything like this.
We'll have to wait until
the tests come back.
All his other results
are normal.
He's obviously suffering
a high level of anxiety,
very committed
to the monster theory.
That's an understatement.
All children see monsters.
Not like this.
And it's getting worse.
He's becoming aggressive.
He could see a psychiatrist.
I can refer you.
Takes a few weeks to get in.
That’d be great.
But can you just give me
something for now,
just to make him sleep?
And just until...
Just until we can
get an appointment.
Please.
I haven": slept in weeks, and...
and neither has Samuel.
And when we go home tonight,
this whole nightmare will start
up again, and I'm really...
I'm really not coping.
I can give you a
short course of sedatives,
just until the tests come back.
Most mothers aren't too keen on
them unless it's really bad.
It's really bad.
These can make
children feel...
foggy, perhaps some
temporary nausea.
They'll certainly help him
sleep, though.
That's for one week.
Thank you.
Why don": people like me?
WhY do you say that?
Ruby said people don't like
me because I'm weird.
Sometimes people say things
that aren't true.
You just need to
take your medicine,
have a big sleep,
and not worry.
I don't want you to die.
I'm not gonna die
for a long time yet.
Did you think that about my
dad before he died?
Just take your pill
so you can go to sleep.
I've got the day off tomorrow.
Maybe we can do something, hmm?
Will these make
the Babadook go away?
I think so, but you
have to promise me
not to mention it
again.
I promise to protect you if
you promise to protect me.
Then I won't mention it.
I promise to protect you.
Come on.
Can you stay here with me?
Yes.
I love you, Mum.
Me too.
Her nose is broken
in two places.
She's gonna need surgery.
I'll pay for everything.
You can't even pay
your own bills.
Look, I really have to go.
Claire, I think someone is
stalking me and Samuel.
What?
A book turned up
at our place.
I threw it away,
but somebody
glued it back together
and put it on our doorstep.
Amelia.
I just can‘? help you right now.
I don't expect you to help.
I just wanted--
If you're that worried,
you should go to the police.
I have to go.
Claire.
Hello?
Ba-ba dook!
Dook! Dook!
Hi.
I want to report someone
stalking me and my child.
Can you tell us what
happened?
Somebody sent me...
ca children's book.
And...?
And it contained violent and
graphic images of my child and
me being murdered.
Can we have a look
at the book, please?
I burnt if.
You burnt it.
Yes.
Well, unfortunately there's
nothing we can do about it.
He's been making phone calls
to me, as well.
What's he been saying?
Nothing.
Just making these... noises.
How do you know
it's the same person?
Because of what he
wrote in the book!
The book you burnt.
Yes.
Okay.
Don't worry about it.
Did you get your things done?
Mrs. Roach has Parkinson's.
That's why she shakes like this.
Samuel, you don": have to say
everything that goes
through your head.
Oh, it’s all right, love.
He wanted to know,
so we talked about it.
He sees things as they are,
that one.
Oskar was the same.
He always spoke his mind.
Do you have to keep on
bringing him up?
Hey, Bugsy.
Hey.
Don't come in here!
I don't want to buy anything.
Are you Amelia Vanek?
Yes.
I'm Warren Newton, and this
is Prue Flannery from the
Department of
Community Services.
My son's only been away
for two days.
He's not actually registered
at Babbage Bay anymore.
If I could just come in
and meet Samuel
and get you to look at
these papers, that'd be great.
I'm just in the middle of
cleaning up the house
at the moment.
I'm sorry.
There's, um, stuff everywhere.
Hello, Samuel.
I'm Prue,
and this is Warren.
How are you?
I'm a bit tired from the
drugs Mum gave me.
Not drugs.
Tranquillizers.
From the doctor.
Oh, he had a fit yesterday.
I'm really tired actually.
That's no good.
May I have a
glass of water please?
Yes, of course.
I'll... get you one.
It's a real mess.
I just found this
cockroach infestation.
I normally have
the house sprayed.
I did actually already
have if sprayed,
but there's this hole in
the wall behind the fridge,
and that's why I...
I didn’t mean
cu hole in the wall.
Uh, there was a
hole in the wallpaper.
That's where they were
laying their eggs, I think.
We've caught you
at a bad time.
I'll leave you with this.
We're required to
come back in a week
to talk through
your options.
Here's my card.
Mum.
I think I'm gonna vomit.
What was that noise I heard?
I didn't hear any noise.
Yeah, howling, doors
slamming.
Why, I declare, Bonnie
thinks this house is haunted.
Mum.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Are you sick?
It's only 6:00.
Don't you want to stay up
with your Mum for a while?
No.
If you go to bed now the
pills won't work properly.
You have to stay up for a while,
sweetheart.
Where's its mother, Skip?
Koalas don"r leave
their babies about.
Hey, you're still there.
Yep, soon as I've fuelled up.
Tell Jerry I'll keep in touch
on the radio,
and I'll be back before breakfast
the day after tomorrow.
"And the prince and the
princess lived happily together
in a beautiful palace for the
rest of their days."
Ba-ba dook! Dook! Dook!
Where are we going?
We're going downstairs.
- Why?
- Because we are.
Iris, Iris, Iris.
No.
Glass and mirror attachment.
Clean and polish
shower doors or mirrors
for a streak-free shine.
As part of this
steaming special,
we'll even include the
garment and uphoIst--
I don't want to give it
to anyone at work.
All right, give
all my shifts away.
That's just what I need.
I can‘t help it if I'm sick.
What do you expect me to do?
You do that!
Mum.
I took the pills,
but I feel sick again.
I need to eat something.
I couldn't find any food
in the fridge.
You said to have them
with food.
I'm really hungry, Mum.
Why do you have to keep
talk-talk-talking?
Don't you ever stop?
- I was just—
- I need to sleep!
I'm sorry, Mummy.
I was just really hungry.
If you're that hungry, why
don't you go and eat shit?!
I'm so sorry.
I don't know why I said that
That was terrible.
I've had absolutely no sleep.
I didn't know what I was saying.
I'll cook you something, eh?
What would you like?
I'm not hungry anymore.
We really need to
get out of this house.
We've been cooped up
here too long.
That's the problem.
Do you want to go to WaIly's?
You can have anything you want,
all right?
Even ice cream for breakfast
if you like.
Give it back now.
- It's mine!
- Give it back.
Stop it. Sit down.
Sit down now.
- Now.
Give my drink back.
Go sit down, please.
Where are we going?
I just want to drive
for a little while.
Mummy!
Ba-ba dook! Dook! Dook!
You run straight into me!
I just bought this bloody car!
What were you thinking?
Oh, driving on the
wrong side of the road,
with a kid in the
back!
You could've killed someone!
Hey!
Hey, what are you doing?
Crazy bitch!
Hi, sweetheart.
Mum?
I can call Auntie Claire.
I can call and
she can come over.
Mum?
Auntie Claire doesn't want to
talk to us anymore.
Mum?
Mum, look at me.
It's nice and warm in here.
I don't want you to go away.
I'm not going anywhere.
Mum?
Mum.
I don't think we should
stay here tonight.
I can call Mrs. Roach.
I don't want you
to call anyone.
I just need to sleep.
- Mum.
- Leave it!
There's something in the house.
There's someone in the house!
Mrs. Roach.
Can we come
and stay the night?
Gracie, I'm so sorry.
Has someone broken
into the house?
- Sam said that—
- No, no, we're fine.
Samuel's just being very
disobedient again.
Oh.
I was so worried.
I told him
not to call anyone.
He asked if you could
stay the night.
No, no.
We're fine.
I just had a headache.
That's all.
I really have to go,
though, now, Gracie.
I'm so sorry for
troubling you.
Yes.
Talk soon?
No worries.
Talk soon.
I told you not to call anyone,
and you deliberately
disobeyed me.
Do you want to
frighten Mrs. Roach,
an old lady who
can hardly walk?
Do you want to make her sick?
Get that bloody thing off!
Is this the only way
I can trust you
not to embarrass me
in front of our neighbours?
Is this what I have to do?
I'm sorry, Mummy.
It's just that the Babadook made
you crash the car and then--
- What did you say?
- I said the BCIbCldOOk--
The Babadook isn't real,
Samuel.
It's just something you've made
up in your stupid little head.
I just didn't want you
to let it in!
I'll make sure nothing gets
in tonight, all right, Samuel?
Nothing is coming
in here tonight.
Nothing!
I feel sick.
If you don't take the pill,
you'll feel worse.
Mum, I don't think I need--
I am the parent,
and you are the child,
so take the pill.
Good boy.
Mum!
Hey, Bugsy.
Hey, sweetie.
Come here, sweetie.
Hey.
Here we go.
There's more
where that came from.
Decide, or we all die.
What’s the secret—
...Ietter of Max's,
didn't you?
No, not for c: minute.
Don't lie.
You called me Cl Jezebel.
- Why?
- The north--
Natural corset.
With fresh meat—
Only five in--
You don't want to go in there
all by yourself, do you?
Police say the woman used a
kitchen knife to stab her son.
His body was found
in their basement.
The woman later attacked
officers with the knife.
They drew their guns
and shot her to death.
Little is known about the
tragedy but neighbours say
boy was celebrating his
birthday today.
He had just turned seven.
Samuel.
Wake up, Mummy.
But you're the one who's
asleep, sweetheart.
Don't go down there.
It's not safe.
I thought you were dead.
We can be together.
You just need to
bring me the boy.
You mean Samuel?
You can bring me the boy.
Stop calling him "the boy."
I think it's going to rain.
No.
No. No.
It isn't real, it isn't real,
it isn't real.
Aah! Ohh!
Oh, no.
No, no.
No! No!
Bugsy!
Samuel!
Samuel.
Bugsy's hurt,
and we need to get help.
You don't want him to die,
do you?
Samuel.
Are you listening to me?
Let me in, you little shit!
Let me in!
You little pig!
Six years old and
you're still wetting yourself!
You don't know how many times
I wished it was you,
not him, that died!
I just want you to be happy.
''I just want you
to be happy."
Sometimes...
I just want to smash your head
against a brick wall until
your fucking brains pop out!
You're not my mother.
What did you say?
I said, you're not my mother!
I am your mother!
Run, run, run
as fast as you can!
Get awCIY!
Didn't I tell you not to play
with weapons?!
I'm sorry, love.
I know it's late.
I just wanted to make sure
you were okay.
I'm okay.
I know...
this time of year is
terribly hard for you.
And I know you don't want me to
go on about it, so I won"r.
I just wanted you to know that
I'd do anything for you and Sam.
I love you both.
Samuel.
I'm sorry.
I understand you're scared.
I haven't been good
since your dad died.
I haven’t been good at all.
I'm sick, Sam.
I need help.
I just spoke with Mrs. Roach.
We're gonna stay there tonight.
Do you want that?
I want to make it up to you,
Sam.
I want you to meet your dad.
It's beautiful there.
You'll be happy.
- Aah!
- Unh!
Sorry, Mummy!
Aah!
Unh!
Mum!
I'm not leaving you!
Mum?
We said we'd protect
each other!
I know you don't love me.
The Babadook won't let you.
But I love you, Mum.
And I always will.
You let it in!
You have to get if out!
I don't want you to go away!
No, Mum, no!
NO! Mummy!
Mummy!
What is if?
You can't get rid
of the Babadook.
Unh!
Ohm
What do you want?
What do you want?!
No.
Keep breathing.
Put your seat back, sweetheart.
10 more minutes,
and we're there.
No.
I think it's gonna rain.
Stop!
You are nothing.
You're nothing!
This is my house!
You are trespassing in my house!
If you touch my son again,
I'll fucking kill you!
Mummy, don't!
Don’t!
Watch out for your Mum's leg,
little one.
He's fine.
I've had the stitches out.
What time's the party?
Oh, any time
after 3:00 is fine.
I'll see you
in a few hours then.
Bye.
Bye, Sam.
That school's a good choice.
I've been doing a lot of
reading about it,
so I think Sam will be
happy there.
He's been out of school
over two weeks now.
It's time to get back.
We needed some time
to sort Cl few things out.
- Are you having a party?
- It's Sam's birthday today.
My first birthday
I've ever celebrated.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
My first party on the day.
That's unusual.
My husband died
the day that Sam was born.
He got killed driving Mum to
the hospital to have me.
Sam's just like his dad was.
Always speaks his mind.
Well, parties are lots of fun,
especially when they're yours.
My cousin's not coming
because I broke her nose
in two places.
I'll take that for you.
Good shot!
Look, there's another one!
Where's your bowl?
Wow, you've got a lot today!
Am I ever going to see it?
One day,
when you're bigger.
You go outside.
And you don't come in
until I tell you.
It's all right!
l’r's all right.
It's all right.
Shh!
Shh-shh!
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
Shh-shh-shh.
How was if?
It's pretty quiet today.
Come here.
It's getting much better,
Mum.
Wait!
I have a new trick.
Life is not always as it seems.
Nothing in my hands,
nothing in my hands.
That's great.
I haven't finished.
Abracadabra!
How did you do that?!
Come here, you.
Come here.
Happy birthday, sweetheart.