(WHISTLING)
CHILD: (MUFFLED) Mum!
(CREAKING)
(GROANING)
CHILD: Mum!
(SCREECH OF METAL,
GLASS SHATTERING)
Mummy!
Mum!
(CLEARER) Mum!
I had the dream again.
(READS) "And he climbed down
that chimney,
"straight into
the huge black pot.
"And that was the end of
the big, bad wolf."
Did they really kill the wolf,
Mum?
I'm sure they did.
I'll kill the monster
when it comes.
I'll smash its head in.
It's time to go to sleep now,
sweetie.
It's very late.
Can we read it again?
"A long time ago -
just yesterday, in fact -
"there were three little pigs
and one nasty big wolf."
(GRINDS TEETH, MURMURS)
(ALARM BEEPS)
(THUD!)
MOTHER: What have you done?
It's not broken.
It just slipped.
I don't want you firing
things off in the house anymore.
Wait, wait, wait. Watch this. When the
monster comes, I'm gonna do this.
Please don't!
BOY: Nothing in my hands.
- Nothing in my hands.
- Stand still, please.
Look at me, Mum!
Come on, Samuel.
- Look at me.
- Stand still, please.
Nothing in my hands.
I don't want you
making weapons anymore.
It doesn't work
if you don't look at me.
This monster thing
has got to stop, alright?
Mmm.
Don't do that!
Ready?
Come on.
Quick. You're late already.
(BAG RATTLES)
What have you got in there?
See you later, alligator.
Here's one for you, Norma.
It's got milk in it.
What?
One with your milk in it.
I don't want milk.
No worries.
I'll make you another one.
Ah, just where a woman
should be. In the kitchen.
Hmm. Get to work, woman.
(LAUGHS)
Do you want a cuppa?
Nah. I'm heading for
the dementia ward.
Aw.
It's a few years before
you end up there, isn't it?
(LAUGHS)
Right?
Amelia?
Your son's school
is on the phone.
Oh, my God.
Did he hurt anyone?
A dart could have gone into
a child's eye or even worse.
I'm going to have a serious talk
with him.
Mrs Fanning,
we've had the talks.
We've had the sessions
with the counsellor.
We're going to have to employ
a monitor for him.
Monitor?
He'll be separated
from the other children.
The monitor will supervise him
one-on-one.
Samuel won't cope with this.
He already feels so different.
I'll have a talk with him.
I'll have a serious talk...
Mrs Fanning,
the boy has significant
behavioural problems.
You know, Samuel doesn't need
a full-time monitor.
What he needs
is some understanding.
I have 24 other
first graders in that class.
Do you want me to put them
all at risk because of your son?
I think I'll just find
another school.
Mrs Fanning, you can't just
take the boy out of school.
You look after your business
and I'll go and find a school
that sees my son
as a human being
and not just as another problem
to be gotten rid of.
That is very unfair. We're only
trying to help the boy.
Please stop calling him
'the boy'.
His name is Samuel.
We can see Ruby and
Aunty Claire at the park today.
You can play
on that swing you like
for as long as you like, OK?
Mrs Bruen hates me.
No, she doesn't.
Just need a break, that's all.
Don't tell Aunty Claire
what happened.
I'll tell her later.
(BEEP! BEEP!)
- Mum, come and look at this!
- I can do it again.
Sam, don't bother the lady.
No, no, no. That's alright.
We have to go home and
see Daddy, though, haven't we?
My dad's in the cemetery.
Oh. That's...
He got killed driving Mum
to the hospital to have me.
Samuel.
I'm sorry. He just...
No, that's alright.
I shouldn't have...
Well, your mum is very lucky
to have you, then, isn't she?
We have to go.
- Say, "See you later," Katie.
- Bye.
WOMAN: The artist was so drunk,
he vomited.
Right in front of
his own installation.
Lost all these sales.
You're not listening.
I am. I am.
So you lost all these sales
and then what happened?
Ruby! Don't play there.
It's wet.
Mum! Mum!
I'm gonna smash its head!
- Be careful.
- Mum, Mum! I'm gonna smash it.
(SIGHS)
What would you like me
to do for Wednesday?
I can get their birthday cakes.
That's easy.
I was hoping Ruby
would change her mind.
She doesn't want a joint party
with Sam this year.
- Oh.
- Mum! Mum!
She wants to have
a princess party.
Mum! Mum!
That's OK.
We don't have to come.
You can still come.
SAMUEL: Mum!
She just doesn't want to share
the day with Sam anymore.
- I understand. I understand.
- Mum!
Mum, I can go really high!
Watch.
Maybe you want to celebrate
his birthday properly
this year, anyway.
- On the day.
- Yeah, we'll see.
(GROANS)
You know, Amelia,
I just want you to be happy
and then this birthday thing
rolls around
and I end up feeling awful.
I don't want you to feel awful,
Claire.
We'll be fine.
We'll be absolutely fine.
Mum! Look at me!
(CRIES)
Mama!
- Who do we have here?
- Hello, Mrs Roach.
You look tired, little one.
Have you been in the wars today?
A few wars.
He's had a big day, that's all.
He's just exhausted.
Poor little sweetheart.
Bugsy.
Come here, little girl. Hello.
You look tired too, love.
You OK?
Nothing five years of sleep
wouldn't fix.
(LAUGHS)
I'll put your rubbish out
for you, Grace.
No, no, no.
You've just got in, pet.
I'll do it now. Then it's done.
(SCRATCHING)
You can choose one tonight.
Where did you get this?
On the shelf.
(READS) "If it's in a word
or it's in a look,
"you can't get rid of
the Babadook.
"If you're a really clever one
and you know what it is to see,
"then you can make friends
with a special one -
"a friend of you and me."
(LAUGHS)
"His name is Mister Babadook
and this is his book.
"A rumbling sound,
then three sharp knocks -
"ba BA-ba Dook! Dook! Dook!
"That's when you'll know
he's around.
"You'll see him if you look.
"Ba BA-ba Dook! Dook! Dook!"
We might read another one
tonight, hey?
But you said I could choose.
"This is what he wears on top.
"He's funny, don't you think?
"See him
in your room at night..."
Mum? Does it hurt the boy?
Mum?
Does it live under the bed? Mum?
Mummy?
Mummy?!
(CRIES)
"How sweetly they sung,
"telling of the happiness
and loveliness
"that lay at the bottom of
the ocean
and entreating the sirens
not to be afraid."
(SAM GROANS)
(LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYS)
WOMAN: It's that time of
night again.
Time...
WOMAN: If that's what
the doctor ordered, I...
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's what the doctor ordered.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYS)
- MAN: Do you...
- (SWITCHES OFF TV)
(BUZZING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(MOANS)
Mum!
- It's in my room!
- What is?
- The Babadook!
- Oh, no.
No, no, no.
This is not going to happen.
The closet doors were closed
and now they're wide open.
It's just a book.
It can't hurt you.
You've had a big day.
You're just exhausted.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you, Mum.
Nothing bad's going to happen,
Sam.
I'm gonna protect you.
(CLOCK TICKS)
(DISTANT THUMPING)
(FOOTSTEPS, CREAKING)
(TRAIN RATTLES ON TRACKS)
SAMUEL: Mum, it's 9:00.
He's not running a fever
anymore.
No, no, no. My sister's gonna
take him. Put it back!
Put it back
or it goes in the bin.
(GROANS)
Sorry. What was that?
Oh, no. I couldn't get to
the phone. He was vomiting.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No worries. I'll see you soon.
Samuel, no monster talk
at Aunty Claire's, OK?
Samuel - no Babadook.
No nothing. Alright?
(GENTLE MUSIC)
88. Number 88.
Two fat ladies.
Good, Elaine!
Another few days and someone
could call out, "Bingo!"
Number 11.
Who has number 11?
Legs 11.
Hey? See what else we've got.
5 billion.
Anyone got 5 billion?
Beverley's not very impressed
with your bingo skills.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah, yeah.
No, I'm fine. How are you?
How's D wing?
Fine. Yeah.
Just a bunch of old people.
You don't have to be fine,
you know.
Just a bit stressed
at the moment.
Why don't you go home?
Old cranky bitch -
she goes after lunch.
I can cover for you.
- You'd do that?
- Yeah.
I'll give you my pay.
Oh, no. Don't be ridiculous.
You've got a sick boy.
Life's too short.
You're so sweet, Robbie.
(SIGHS)
- You should go.
- Yeah.
- Say hi to Sam for me.
- I will.
(YELLS) Where have you been?
You weren't at work.
Rung you a million times.
What happened?
Just scared the crap
out of Ruby. That's all.
He insisted on talking to this
bloody Babadook thing all day.
Just talking to the air -
even freaked me out.
I'm so sorry.
You need to get him
to see someone, Amelia.
It's not normal for a kid
to carry on with this rubbish.
It's not rubbish. It's real!
Don't you talk to
your Aunty Claire like that.
Where did you get
those firecrackers?
You got them for me
on the internet.
Well,
that's the end of the internet.
If the Babadook was real, we'd
see it right now, wouldn't we?
It wants to scare you first
then you'll see it.
Well, I'm not scared.
You will be when it creeps
into your room at night.
That's enough.
You will be
when it eats your insides.
I've decided
you're not having your birthday
with Ruby this week.
No cake, no games.
That's the end of it.
Samuel.
(TV PLAYS IN DISTANCE)
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mum and Dad,
life is not always as it seems.
It can be a wondrous thing.
But it can also be
very treacherous.
(YELPS)
Don't worry, Dad. I'll save Mum.
I'm gonna trap
the Babadook like this.
And when it's trapped,
I'm gonna kill it.
AMELIA: Samuel.
I was just
putting something back.
All your father's things
are down there.
He's my father.
You don't own him!
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Just thought I'd see
how you're going.
Can I come in?
Hey, matey. This is for you.
My mum always got me a model
plane when I was sick. (LAUGHS)
I'm not sick.
Oh. I-I thought...
No, he's not, actually.
The truth is he's so disobedient
he can't go to school anymore.
You said that's not true.
How many 6-year-old boys
do you know, Robbie,
who still believe in monsters?
I hate you!
She won't let me have
a birthday party
and she won't let me have a dad!
(GASPS)
Ohh.
Don't eat it.
The Babadook did it, Mum.
Go and watch a DVD
and I'll make something else.
The Babadook did it!
Just go and watch a DVD, Samuel.
MAN: (ON TV)
Ladies and gentlemen,
girls and boys,
welcome to the great Martin's
DVD 'School of Magic'.
Life is not always as it seems.
It can be a wondrous thing.
But it can also be
very treacherous.
In this DVD,
you will learn magic tricks
to surprise, to delight
and perhaps even shock
your family and friends.
Do you think this is funny?
Oh, no. No. No!
(GRUNTS) Give it to me!
(SCREECHES)
Do you wanna die?
(DRIPPING)
(PANTS)
(PANTS HEAVILY)
(THUMP!)
(GASPS)
(SINISTER MUSIC)
(PANTS)
Don't let it in!
Don't let it in! Don't
let it in! Don't let it in!
Don't let it in!
(FOOTSTEPS)
SAMUEL: Mum, do we have to
go to Ruby's party?
I've already got this doll, Mum.
Now she's got a twin.
They can go shopping together.
- Off you go.
- (SAM GROANS)
He's just really tired.
(CRIES OUT)
Go and play right now.
Claire tells me you're a writer.
Oh, no, not really. Not anymore.
What kind of writing did you do?
I wrote some articles for some
magazines, did some kids' stuff.
You just need to get
back into it. That's all.
It must be difficult.
I do volunteer work
with some disadvantaged women
and a few of them
have lost their husbands
and they find it very hard.
How's Richard's merger going?
WOMAN: Oh, good. I mean,
his workload's just ballooned.
I've got the kids 24/7,
it feels like.
CLAIRE: Tell me about it!
I don't even have time to go to the gym
anymore. It's ridiculous!
That's a real tragedy.
Not having time to go to the gym
anymore. How do you cope?
You must have so much
to talk about
with those poor
disadvantaged women.
(CHILDREN GIGGLE)
This is my tree house.
You're not allowed in here.
I'm not hurting anybody.
Bye.
- Thanks.
How would your mum know
if it's real or not?
She never comes to our house.
Mum told Dad she didn't want
to go to your house
'cause it's too depressing.
The Babadook would eat your mum
for breakfast.
- It'd rip her arms off.
- Shut up!
They feel sorry for me, Claire.
There's a big difference.
God, Amelia, as soon as anyone
mentions Oskar, you can't cope.
- That's not true.
- It'll be seven years.
Isn't it time you moved on?
I have moved on.
I don't mention him.
I don't talk about him.
What strain is that on you,
Claire?
RUBY: You're not even
good enough to have a dad.
Everyone else has one
and you don't.
I do have a dad!
I listen to your life
day in, day out,
and you never stop to ask me
anything about mine.
I do!
I want to know how you are.
You don't come round
to our house anymore.
Because I can't stand
being around your son.
I can't believe
you just said that.
You can't stand being around him
yourself.
RUBY: Your dad died so he didn't
have to be with you.
That's not true!
And your mum doesn't want you.
- No-one wants you.
- (GRUNTS)
(THUD!)
(CRIES)
What did you do?!
She said I didn't have a dad.
She kept saying it.
Is she alright?
Stay here
and look after the children
or do you want another one
to get hurt?
SAMUEL: (SCREAMS) Mummy!
She wouldn't believe me!
Mummy! Mummy!
(SHRIEKS) Mummy!
- Mummy! Mummy!
- Why can't you just be normal?!
(SCREAMS)
There is no Babadook!
Get out!
- Get out!
- Samuel?
- Mummy!
- Stop this now!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
(SCREAMS)
Please help me!
There's something wrong
with my son.
I think it may have been
a febrile convulsion.
That's when the brain overheats.
It always looks worse
than it is.
I've never seen
anything like this.
We'll have to wait
until the tests come back.
All his other results
are normal.
He's obviously suffering
a high level of anxiety.
Very committed to
the monster theory.
That's an understatement.
All children see monsters.
Not like this.
And it's getting worse.
He's becoming aggressive.
He could see a psychiatrist.
I can refer you.
Takes a few weeks to get in.
That'd be great.
But can you just give me
something for now,
just to make him sleep?
Um, just until...
...just until
we get an appointment.
Please?
I haven't slept in weeks
and neither has Samuel
and when we go home tonight,
this whole nightmare
will start up again
and I am really...
...I'm really not coping.
I can give you
a short course of sedatives.
Just until the tests come back.
Most mothers aren't too keen
on them unless it's really bad.
It's really bad.
These can make children
feel foggy.
Perhaps some temporary nausea.
They'll certainly
help him sleep, though.
- That's for one week.
- Thank you.
SAMUEL: Why don't people
like me?
AMELIA: Why do you say that?
Ruby said people don't like me
'cause I'm weird.
Sometimes people say things
that aren't true.
You just need to take
your medicine, have a big sleep
and not worry.
I don't want you to die.
I'm not gonna die
for a long time yet.
Did you think that about my dad
before he died?
Just take your pill
so you can go to sleep.
I've got the day off tomorrow.
Maybe we could do something,
hmm?
Will these make
the Babadook go away?
I think so
but you have to promise me
not to mention it again.
I promise to protect you
if you promise to protect me.
Then I won't mention it.
I promise to protect you.
Come on.
Can you stay here with me?
Yes.
I love you, Mum.
Me too.
(EERIE MUSIC)
(DRIPPING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
(LOUD KNOCKING AT DOOR)
(TINKLING)
(SNAP!)
(GASPS)
CLAIRE: (ON PHONE) Her nose
is broken in two places.
She may need surgery.
AMELIA: I'll pay for everything.
CLAIRE: You can't even pay
your own bills.
Look, I really have to go.
AMELIA: Claire, I think someone
is stalking me and Samuel.
CLAIRE: What?
AMELIA: A book turned up
at our place.
I threw it away but somebody
glued it back together
and put it on our doorstep.
CLAIRE: Amelia,
I just can't help you right now.
I don't expect you to help.
I just wanted...
CLAIRE: If you're that worried,
you should go to the police.
I have to go. (HANGS UP)
(PHONE RINGS)
Claire!
Hello?
(RASPY VOICE) Mmm, Babadook...
...dook... dook.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hi.
I want to report someone
stalking me and my child.
Can you tell us what happened?
Somebody sent me
a children's book.
(LAUGHS)
And?
And it contained violent
and graphic images
of my child and me
being murdered.
Can we have a look at the book,
please?
I burnt it.
You burnt it?
Yes.
Well, unfortunately, there's
nothing we can do about it.
He's been making phone calls
to me as well.
What's he been saying?
Nothing,
just making these... noises.
How do you know
it's the same person?
Because of what
he wrote in the book.
The book you burnt?
Yes.
(SINISTER MUSIC)
OK.
Don't worry about it.
Did you get your things done?
Mrs Roach has Parkinson's.
That's why she shakes like this.
Samuel, you don't have to
say everything
that goes through your head.
Oh, it's alright, love.
He wanted to know
so we talked about it.
He sees things as they are,
that one.
Oskar was the same.
He always spoke his mind.
Do you have to
keep on bringing him up?
(BARKS)
Hey, Bugsy.
- (BUGSY GROWLS, BARKS)
- Hey.
- (BUGSY CONTINUES BARKING)
- Hey!
(SIGHS)
Eugh! (GASPS)
Don't come in here.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
I don't want to buy anything.
Are you Amelia Vanick?
Yes.
I'm Warren Newton
and this is Prue Flannery
from the Department of
Community Services.
My son's only been
away for two days.
He's not actually registered
at Babbage Bay anymore.
If I could just come in
and meet Samuel
and get you to look at
these papers, that'd be great.
I'm just in the middle
of cleaning up the house
at the moment.
I'm sorry.
There's stuff everywhere.
Hello, Samuel.
I'm Prue and this is Warren.
How are you?
I'm a bit tired from the drugs
Mum gave me.
Not drugs. Tranquillisers...
from the doctor.
He had a fit yesterday.
I'm really tired, actually.
PRUE: That's no good.
May I have a glass of water,
please?
Yes. Of course. I'll get you one.
It's a real mess.
I just found
this cockroach infestation.
I normally have
the house sprayed.
I did actually already
have it sprayed
but there's this hole
in the wall behind the fridge
and that's why I...
I didn't mean
a hole in the wall.
There was a hole
in the wallpaper.
That's where they were
laying their eggs, I think.
WARREN: We've caught you
at a bad time.
I'll leave you with this.
We're required
to come back in a week
to talk through your options.
Here's my card.
SAMUEL: Mum,
I think I'm gonna vomit.
(TV PLAYS IN DISTANCE)
WOMAN: (ON TV) What was
that noise I heard?
WOMAN 2: (ON TV)
I didn't hear any noise.
WOMAN: Wind howling,
doors slamming.
I declare, I think this house
is haunted.
(GASPS)
Mum, I'm gonna go to bed.
WOMAN 2: Are you sick?
WOMAN: Oh, no, Granny.
It's only 6:00.
Don't you want to stay up
with your mum for a while?
No.
If you go to bed now,
the pills won't work properly.
You have to stay up for a while,
sweetheart.
(SIGHS)
(TV PLAYS)
BOY: (ON TV) Where's its mother,
Skip?
Koalas don't leave
their babies about.
Are you off now, Dad?
MAN: (ON TV) Yep.
Soon as I fuel up.
Tell Jerry I'll keep in touch
on the radio
and I'll be back before breakfast
the day after tomorrow.
AMELIA: (READS) "And the Prince
and the Princess
"lived happily together
in a beautiful palace
"for the rest of their days."
(WIND HOWLS)
(CLATTERING)
(BUGSY BARKS)
(GASPS, SIGHS)
(CLATTERING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(GASPS)
(CLATTERING)
(RASPY VOICE) Babadook...
...dook... dook.
(PANTS)
(CLICK!)
(GROWLING, SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
SAMUEL: What are we doing?
AMELIA: We're going downstairs.
- Why?
- Because we are.
(GROWLING)
MAN: (ON TV) Iris, Iris, Iris.
WOMAN: (ON TV) No.
(MUSIC BOX TINKLES)
(MUSIC BOX WINDS DOWN)
(BUGSY BARKS)
WOMAN: (ON TV)
Glass and mirror attachment.
Clean and polish
shower doors or mirrors
for a streak-free shine.
As part of
your steaming special,
we'll even include
the garment and upholst...
Oh, I don't want to give it
to anyone at work.
(LAUGHS) Alright.
Give all my shifts away.
That's just what I need.
I can't help it if I'm sick.
What do you expect me to do?
You do that!
Mum, I took the pills
but I feel sick again.
I need to eat something.
I couldn't find any food
in the fridge.
You said to have them with food.
I'm really hungry, Mum.
Why do you have to keep talk,
talk, talking?
Don't you ever stop?
- I was just...
- I need to sleep!
I'm sorry, Mummy.
I was just really hungry.
If you're that hungry,
why don't you go and eat shit?
I'm so sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
It was terrible.
I've had absolutely no sleep.
I didn't know what I was saying.
I'll cook you something. Hey?
What would you like?
I'm not hungry anymore.
We really need to get
out of this house.
We've been cooped up here
too long. That's the problem.
Do you want to go to Wally's?
You can have anything you want.
Alright?
Even ice-cream for breakfast
if you like.
- (ARGUING)
- Give it back!
- Stop it! Sit down. Sit down.
- No!
- Now!
- Give my drink back!
Sit down, please.
Where are we going?
I just want to drive
for a little while.
(GASPS)
- (SCREECHING)
- Aarggh!
Mummy! Mummy!
(BOTH SCREAM)
(RASPY VOICE) Babadook.
(GROWLING, TYRES SQUEAL)
You ran straight into me!
I just bought this bloody car.
What were you thinking?
Oh, driving on the wrong side of
the road with a kid in the back.
You could've killed someone!
- (REVS ENGINE)
- Hey!
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey! Crazy bitch!
Hi, sweetheart.
Mum?
I can call Aunty Claire.
I can call
and she can come over.
Mum?
Aunty Claire doesn't want
to talk to us anymore.
Mum. Mum, look at me.
It's nice and warm in here.
I don't want you to go away.
I'm not going anywhere.
Mum?
Mum, I don't think
we should stay here tonight.
I can call Mrs Roach.
I don't want you to call anyone.
I just need to sleep.
- Mum...
- (YELLS) Leave it!
(WHISPERING)
VOICE: There's something
in the house.
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
VOICE: (YELLS)
There's someone in the house!
(GASPS)
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
(SILENCE)
(WHISPERING RESUMES)
(CREAKING)
SAMUEL: (WHISPERS) Mrs Roach...
...can we come and stay
the night?
Gracie, I'm so sorry.
GRACIE: (ON PHONE) Has someone
broken into the house?
- Sam said that...
- No, no, no. We're fine.
Samuel's just being
very disobedient again.
GRACIE: Oh, I was so worried.
I told him not to call anyone.
GRACIE: He asked
if you could stay the night.
No, no, no. We're fine. I just
have a headache. That's all.
I really have to go, though,
now, Gracie.
I'm so sorry for troubling you.
GRACIE: Yes. Talk soon.
No worries. Talk soon.
I told you not to call anyone
and you deliberately
disobeyed me.
Do you want to frighten
Mrs Roach?
An old lady who can hardly walk?
Do you want to make her sick?
(YELLS)
Get that bloody thing off!
Is this the only way I can trust
you not to embarrass me
in front of our neighbours?
Is this what I have to do?
I'm sorry, Mummy.
It's just that the Babadook made
you crash the car and then...
What'd you say?
I said the Babadook...
The Babadook isn't real, Samuel.
He's just something you've made up
in your stupid little head.
I just didn't want you
to let it in!
I'll make sure nothing
gets in tonight.
Alright, Samuel?
Nothing is coming in here
tonight.
(SCREAMS) Nothing!
SAMUEL: I feel sick.
If you don't take the pill,
you'll feel worse.
Mum, I don't think I need...
I am the parent and you are
the child so take the pill.
Good boy.
(MACABRE MUSIC PLAYS)
(GROWLS)
Ohh! (GASPS, PANTS)
(YELLS) Mum!
(SCRATCHING)
Hey, Bugsy. Hey, sweetie.
Come here, sweetie. Hey?
Hey.
Hey!
(BARKS, YELPS)
(GROWLS, BARKS)
(TV PLAYS)
Here we go.
There's more
where that came from.
Oh! (GASPS)
Aarggh!
VOICEOVER: What's the secret?
(MACABRE MUSIC PLAYS)
WOMAN:
...letter of Max's, didn't you?
MAN: No, not for a minute.
WOMAN: Don't lie.
You called me a Jezebel. Why?
- MAN 2: The north, east.
- VOICEOVER: Natural corset.
WOMAN 2: With fresh meat.
- WOMAN 3: Only five...
- (WHIRRING)
MAN 3: You don't wanna go
in there all by yourself, do you?
REPORTER: Police say the woman
used a kitchen knife
to stab her son.
His body was found
in their basement.
The woman later attacked
officers with a knife.
They drew their guns
and shot her to death.
Little is known about the tragedy
but neighbours say the boy was
celebrating his birthday today.
He had just turned seven.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Samuel?
Wake up, Mummy.
But you're the one who's asleep,
sweetheart.
Don't go down there.
It's not safe.
Ohh... I thought you were dead.
I thought you were dead.
We're gonna be together.
You just need to bring me
the boy.
You mean Samuel?
(DEEP VOICE)
You can bring me the boy.
Stop calling him 'the boy'.
I think it's going to rain.
No.
(GASPS, PANTS)
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS, CRIES)
(PANTS)
(GROANS)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS, CRIES)
(GROWLING)
It isn't real. It isn't real.
It isn't real.
(ROARING)
(WOMAN ON TV SCREAMS)
Oh, no. (WHIMPERS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(PANTS)
No! No!
- (BARKS)
- Bugsy!
(BARKS)
(GROWLS, BARKS)
(BUGSY CONTINUES BARKING)
(BUGSY STOPS BARKING)
(TURNS TV OFF)
(BUGSY YELPS, SHRIEKS)
(BUGSY GROWLS, WHINES)
(AMELIA GRUNTS LOUDLY)
(BUGSY'S NECK SNAPS)
(MOANS IN PAIN)
(SHOUTS)
(TOOTH COMES LOOSE)
(TOOTH CLATTERS ON FLOOR)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
Samuel!
(BANGS TWICE)
(SOFTLY) Samuel.
Bugsy's hurt
and we need to get help.
You don't want him to die,
do you?
Samuel.
Are you listening to me?
Let me in, you little shit!
Let me in!
(VOICE DEEPENS) Let me in!
Let me in! (GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKS)
You little pig!
Six years old and you're still
wetting yourself.
You don't know how many times
I wished it was you, not him,
that died.
I just want you to be happy.
(MOCKING) "I just
want you to be happy."
Sometimes...
...I just wanna smash
your head against a brick wall
until your fucking brains
pop out.
You're not my mother.
What did you say?
(SHOUTS) I said
you're not my mother!
I am your mother!
(LOUD BANG)
Run, run, run,
as fast as you can!
(DOOR SLAMS)
Get away!
Didn't I tell you
not to play with weapons?
(FIRES)
- Argh!
(DOOR SLAMS)
(FAINT KNOCKS AT DOOR)
I'm sorry, love. I know it's late.
I just wanted to make sure
you were OK.
I'm OK.
I know... this time of year's
terribly hard for you.
And I know you don't want me
to go on about it, so I won't.
But I just wanted you to know
that I'd do anything
for you and Sam.
I love you both.
Samuel.
I'm sorry.
I understand you're scared.
I haven't been good
since your dad died.
I haven't been good at all.
I'm sick, Sam. I need help.
I just spoke with Mrs Roach.
We're going to
stay there tonight.
Do you want that?
I want to make it up to you,
Sam.
I want you to meet your dad.
It's beautiful there.
You'll be happy.
(SCREAMS)
Sorry, Mummy!
(RAPID BREATHING)
(GRUNTS)
- (SHOUTS)
- Mum!
Mum!
I'm not leaving you.
Mum? Mum?
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS)
You said
we'd protect each other.
I know you don't love me.
The Babadook won't let you.
But I love you, Mum.
And I always will.
(CRIES)
You let it in.
You have to get it out!
I don't want you to go away.
No! No! No!
Mummy!
Mummy! Mummy!
(CRIES) Mummy!
Mummy!
(DRAWS BREATH)
What is it?
You can't get rid of
the Babadook.
(SAMUEL SCREAMS)
Ooh!
What do you want?
No.
Keep breathing.
Put your seat back, sweetheart.
10 more minutes and we're there.
No.
(HORN BLARES FAINTLY)
I think it's gonna rain.
Stop!
(TYRES SCREECH)
(MOANS)
(LOW GROWL)
You are nothing.
(SNARLING, HISSING)
You're nothing!
(HISSING)
This is my house!
(ROARING)
You are trespassing in my house!
(SCREECHING)
(GROWLING)
If you touch my son again
I'll fucking kill you!
(SCREECHING, ROARING)
(SAMUEL SCREAMS)
No!
(GROWLING FADES)
(LOW MOAN)
Mummy, don't!
Don't!
(MOANS)
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM)
Aaaargh!
Watch out for your mum's leg,
little one.
He's fine.
I've had the stitches out.
What time's the party?
Any time after three is fine.
I'll see you in a few hours, then.
Bye.
Bye, Sam.
PRUE: That school's
a good choice.
AMELIA: I've been doing
a lot of reading about it
so I think
Sam will be happy there.
He's been out of school
over two weeks now.
It's time to get back.
We needed some time
to sort a few things out.
Mmm.
Are you having a party?
It's Sam's birthday today.
My first birthday
I've ever celebrated.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
My first party on the day.
That's unusual.
My husband died the day
that Sam was born.
He got killed driving Mum
to the hospital to have me.
Sam's just like his dad was.
Always speaks his mind.
Well, parties are lots of fun,
especially when they're yours.
My cousin's not coming because
I broke her nose in two places.
(TEACUP RATTLES GENTLY)
I'll take that for you.
Good shot.
Look, there's another one!
Where's your bowl?
Wow. You've got a lot today.
Am I ever gonna see it?
One day, when you're bigger.
You go outside, and you don't
come in until I tell you.
(GROWLING)
Argh!
It's alright.
(GASPS) It's alright.
Shhh...
How was it?
It was pretty quiet today.
Come here.
It's getting much better, Mum.
Wait!
I have a new trick.
Life is not always as it seems.
Nothing in my hands.
- That's great!
- I haven't finished.
Abracadabra!
How did you do that?
(LAUGHS)
Come here, you.
Come here.
Happy birthday, sweetheart.