Mum!
Mummy!
I had the dream again.
"And he climbed down that chimney,
"straight into the huge black pot.
"And that was the end
of the big, bad wolf."
Did they really kill the wolf, Mum?
I'm sure they did.
I'll kill the monster when it comes.
I'll smash its head in.
It's time to go to
sleep now, sweetie.
It's very late.
Can we read it again?
"A long time ago...
just yesterday, in fact...
"there were three little pigs
and one nasty big wolf."
- What have you done?
- It's not broken. It just slipped.
I don't want you firing things
off in the house anymore.
Wait, wait, wait. Watch this. When the
monster comes, I'm gonna do this.
Please don't!
Nothing in my hands.
- Nothing in my hands.
- Stand still, please.
Look at me, Mum!
Come on, Samuel.
- Look at me.
- Stand still, please.
Nothing in my hands.
- I don't want you making weapons anymore.
- It doesn't work if you don't look at me.
This monster thing has
got to stop, alright?
Don't do that!
Ready?
Come on.
Quick. You're late already.
What have you got in there?
See you later, alligator.
Here's one for you, Norma.
It's got milk in it.
What?
One with your milk in it.
I don't want milk.
No worries.
I'll make you another one.
Just where a woman
should be. In the kitchen.
Get to work, woman.
Do you want a cuppa?
Nah. I'm heading for
the dementia ward.
It's a few years before
you end up there, isn't it?
Right?
Amelia? Your son's
school is on the phone.
Oh, my God. Did he hurt anyone?
A dart could have gone into
a child's eye or even worse.
I'm going to have a
serious talk with him.
Mrs Fanning, we've had the talks.
We've had the sessions
with the counsellor.
We're going to have to
employ a monitor for him.
Monitor?
He'll be separated from
the other children.
The monitor will supervise
him one-on-one.
Samuel won't cope with this.
He already feels so different.
I'll have a talk with him.
I'll have a serious talk...
Mrs Fanning,
the boy has significant
behavioural problems.
You know, Samuel doesn't
need a full-time monitor.
What he needs is some understanding.
I have 24 other first
graders in that class.
Do you want me to put them
all at risk because of your son?
I think I'll just
find another school.
Mrs Fanning, you can't just
take the boy out of school.
You look after your business
and I'll go and find a school
that sees my son as a human being
and not just as another
problem to be gotten rid of.
That is very unfair.
We're only trying to help the boy.
Please stop calling him 'the boy'.
His name is Samuel.
We can see Ruby and Aunty
Claire at the park today.
You can play on that swing you
like for as long as you like, OK?
Mrs Bruen hates me.
No, she doesn't.
Just need a break, that's all.
Don't tell Aunty
Claire what happened.
I'll tell her later.
- Mum, come and look at this!
- I can do it again.
Sam, don't bother the lady.
No, no, no. That's alright.
We have to go home and see Daddy,
though, haven't we?
My dad's in the cemetery.
Oh. That's...
He got killed driving Mum
to the hospital to have me.
Samuel.
I'm sorry. He just...
No, that's alright.
I shouldn't have...
Well, your mum is very lucky
to have you, then, isn't she?
We have to go.
- Say, "See you later," Katie.
- Bye.
The artist was so drunk, he vomited.
Right in front of his
own installation.
Lost all these sales.
You're not listening.
I am. I am.
So you lost all these sales
and then what happened?
Ruby! Don't play there. It's wet.
Mum! Mum!
I'm gonna smash its head!
- Be careful.
- Mum, Mum! I'm gonna smash it.
What would you like me
to do for Wednesday?
I can get their birthday cakes.
That's easy.
I was hoping Ruby would
change her mind.
She doesn't want a joint
party with Sam this year.
- Oh.
- Mum! Mum!
She wants to have a princess party.
Mum! Mum!
That's OK.
We don't have to come.
You can still come.
Mum!
She just doesn't want to share
the day with Sam anymore.
- I understand. I understand.
- Mum!
Mum, I can go really high! Watch.
Maybe you want to celebrate his
birthday properly this year, anyway.
- On the day.
- Yeah, we'll see.
You know, Amelia,
I just want you to be happy
and then this birthday
thing rolls around
- and I end up feeling awful.
- I don't want you to feel awful, Claire.
We'll be fine.
We'll be absolutely fine.
Mum! Look at me!
Mama!
- Who do we have here?
- Hello, Mrs Roach.
You look tired, little one.
Have you been in the wars today?
A few wars.
He's had a big day, that's all.
He's just exhausted.
Poor little sweetheart.
Bugsy.
Come here, little girl. Hello.
You look tired too, love.
You OK?
Nothing five years
of sleep wouldn't fix.
I'll put your rubbish
out for you, Grace.
No, no, no. You've just got in, pet.
I'll do it now. Then it's done.
You can choose one tonight.
Where did you get this?
On the shelf.
"If it's in a word or it's in a look,
"you can't get rid of the Babadook.
"If you're a really clever one
and you know what it is to see,
"then you can make friends
with a special one...
"a friend of you and me."
"His name is Mister Babadook
and this is his book.
"A rumbling sound,
then three sharp knocks...
"ba BA-ba Dook! Dook! Dook!
"That's when you'll know he's around.
"You'll see him if you look.
"Ba BA-ba Dook! Dook! Dook!"
We might read another
one tonight, hey?
But you said I could choose.
"This is what he wears on top.
"He's funny, don't you think?
"See him in your room at night..."
Mum? Does it hurt the boy?
Mum?
Does it live under the bed? Mum?
Mummy?
Mummy?!
"How sweetly they sung, telling
of the happiness and loveliness
"that lay at the bottom of the ocean
and entreating the sirens
not to be afraid."
It's that time of
night again. Time...
If that's what the
doctor ordered, I...
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's what the doctor ordered.
Do you...
Mum!
- It's in my room!
- What is?
- The Babadook!
- Oh, no.
No, no, no. This is
not going to happen.
The closet doors were closed
and now they're wide open.
It's just a book.
It can't hurt you.
You've had a big day.
You're just exhausted.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you, Mum.
Nothing bad's going to happen, Sam.
I'm gonna protect you.
Mum, it's 9:00.
He's not running a fever anymore.
No, no, no. My sister's
gonna take him. Put it back!
Put it back or it goes in the bin.
Sorry. What was that?
Oh, no. I couldn't get to
the phone. He was vomiting.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No worries. I'll see you soon.
Samuel, no monster talk
at Aunty Claire's, OK?
Samuel... no Babadook.
No nothing. Alright?
88. Number 88.
Two fat ladies.
Good, Elaine!
Another few days and someone
could call out, "Bingo!"
Number 11.
Who has number 11?
Legs 11.
Hey? See what else we've got.
5 billion.
Anyone got 5 billion?
Beverley's not very impressed
with your bingo skills.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah, yeah.
No, I'm fine. How are you?
How's D wing?
Fine. Yeah. Just a
bunch of old people.
You don't have to be fine, you know.
Just a bit stressed at the moment.
Why don't you go home?
Old cranky bitch...
she goes after lunch.
I can cover for you.
- You'd do that?
- Yeah.
I'll give you my pay.
Oh, no. Don't be ridiculous.
You've got a sick boy.
Life's too short.
You're so sweet, Robbie.
- You should go.
- Yeah.
- Say hi to Sam for me.
- I will.
Where have you been?
You weren't at work.
Rung you a million times.
What happened?
Just scared the crap
out of Ruby. That's all.
He insisted on talking to this
bloody Babadook thing all day.
Just talking to the air...
even freaked me out.
I'm so sorry.
You need to get him to
see someone, Amelia.
It's not normal for a kid to
carry on with this rubbish.
It's not rubbish. It's real!
Don't you talk to your
Aunty Claire like that.
Where did you get those firecrackers?
You got them for me on the internet.
Well, that's the end of the internet.
If the Babadook was real,
we'd see it right now, wouldn't we?
It wants to scare you
first then you'll see it.
Well, I'm not scared.
You will be when it creeps
into your room at night.
That's enough.
You will be when it
eats your insides.
I've decided you're not having
your birthday with Ruby this week.
No cake, no games.
That's the end of it.
Samuel.
Ladies and gentlemen, Mum and Dad,
life is not always as it seems.
It can be a wondrous thing.
But it can also be very treacherous.
Don't worry, Dad. I'll save Mum.
I'm gonna trap the
Babadook like this.
And when it's trapped,
I'm gonna kill it.
Samuel.
I was just putting something back.
- All your father's things are down there.
- He's my father.
You don't own him!
Just thought I'd see
how you're going.
Can I come in?
Hey, matey. This is for you.
My mum always got me a model
plane when I was sick.
I'm not sick.
Oh. I-I thought...
No, he's not, actually.
The truth is he's so disobedient
he can't go to school anymore.
You said that's not true.
How many 6-year-old boys
do you know, Robbie,
- who still believe in monsters?
- I hate you!
She won't let me have a birthday party
and she won't let me have a dad!
Don't eat it.
The Babadook did it, Mum.
Go and watch a DVD and
I'll make something else.
- The Babadook did it!
- Just go and watch a DVD, Samuel.
Ladies and gentlemen, girls and boys,
welcome to the great Martin's
DVD 'School of Magic'.
Life is not always as it seems.
It can be a wondrous thing.
But it can also be very treacherous.
In this DVD,
you will learn magic tricks
to surprise, to delight
and perhaps even shock
your family and friends.
Do you think this is funny?
Oh, no. No. No!
Give it to me!
Do you wanna die?
Don't let it in! Don't let it in!
Don't let it in!
Mum, do we have to
go to Ruby's party?
I've already got this doll, Mum.
Now she's got a twin.
They can go shopping together.
Off you go.
He's just really tired.
Go and play right now.
Claire tells me you're a writer.
Oh, no, not really. Not anymore.
What kind of writing did you do?
I wrote some articles for some
magazines, did some kids' stuff.
You just need to get
back into it. That's all.
It must be difficult.
I do volunteer work with
some disadvantaged women
and a few of them have
lost their husbands
and they find it very hard.
How's Richard's merger going?
Oh, good. I mean,
his workload's just ballooned.
I've got the kids 24/7,
it feels like.
Tell me about it!
I don't even have time to go to
the gym anymore. It's ridiculous!
That's a real tragedy.
Not having time to go to the
gym anymore. How do you cope?
You must have so much to talk about
with those poor disadvantaged women.
This is my tree house.
You're not allowed in here.
I'm not hurting anybody.
Bye.
- Thanks.
How would your mum
know if it's real or not?
She never comes to our house.
Mum told Dad she didn't
want to go to your house
'cause it's too depressing.
The Babadook would eat
your mum for breakfast.
- It'd rip her arms off.
- Shut up!
They feel sorry for me, Claire.
There's a big difference.
God, Amelia, as soon as anyone
mentions Oskar, you can't cope.
- That's not true.
- It'll be seven years.
Isn't it time you moved on?
I have moved on.
I don't mention him.
I don't talk about him.
What strain is that on you, Claire?
You're not even good
enough to have a dad.
Everyone else has one and you don't.
I do have a dad!
I listen to your life
day in, day out,
and you never stop to ask
me anything about mine.
I do! I want to know how you are.
You don't come round
to our house anymore.
Because I can't stand
being around your son.
I can't believe you just said that.
You can't stand being
around him yourself.
Your dad died so he didn't
have to be with you.
- That's not true!
- And your mum doesn't want you.
No-one wants you.
What did you do?!
She said I didn't have a dad.
She kept saying it.
Is she alright?
Stay here and look after the children
or do you want another one to get hurt?
Mummy! She wouldn't believe me!
Mummy! Mummy!
Mummy!
- Mummy! Mummy!
- Why can't you just be normal?!
There is no Babadook!
Get out!
- Get out!
- Samuel?
- Mummy!
- Stop this now!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Please help me!
There's something wrong with my son.
I think it may have been
a febrile convulsión.
That's when the brain overheats.
- It always looks worse than it is.
- I've never seen anything like this.
We'll have to wait until
the tests come back.
All his other results are normal.
He's obviously suffering
a high level of anxiety.
Very committed to the monster theory.
That's an understatement.
All children see monsters.
Not like this.
And it's getting worse.
He's becoming aggressive.
He could see a psychiatrist.
I can refer you.
Takes a few weeks to get in.
That'd be great.
But can you just give
me something for now,
just to make him sleep?
Just until...
just until we get an appointment.
Please?
I haven't slept in weeks
and neither has Samuel
and when we go home tonight, this
whole nightmare will start up again
and I am really...
I'm really not coping.
I can give you a short
course of sedatives.
Just until the tests come back.
Most mothers aren't too keen
on them unless it's really bad.
It's really bad.
These can make children feel foggy.
Perhaps some temporary nausea.
They'll certainly help
him sleep, though.
- That's for one week.
- Thank you.
Why don't people like me?
Why do you say that?
Ruby said people don't
like me 'cause I'm weird.
Sometimes people say
things that aren't true.
You just need to take your medicine,
have a big sleep and not worry.
I don't want you to die.
I'm not gonna die
for a long time yet.
Did you think that about
my dad before he died?
Just take your pill so
you can go to sleep.
I've got the day off tomorrow.
Maybe we could do something?
Will these make the Babadook go away?
I think so but you have to promise
me not to mention it again.
I promise to protect you if
you promise to protect me.
Then I won't mention it.
I promise to protect you.
Come on.
Can you stay here with me?
Yes.
I love you, Mum.
Me too.
Her nose is broken in two places.
- She may need surgery.
- I'll pay for everything.
You can't even pay your own bills.
Look, I really have to go.
Claire, I think someone is
stalking me and Samuel.
What?
A book turned up at our place.
I threw it away but somebody
glued it back together
and put it on our doorstep.
Amelia, I just can't
help you right now.
I don't expect you to help.
I just wanted...
If you're that worried,
you should go to the police.
I have to go.
Claire!
Hello?
Babadook...
dook... dook.
Hi.
I want to report someone
stalking me and my child.
Can you tell us what happened?
Somebody sent me a children's book.
And?
And it contained violent
and graphic images
of my child and me being murdered.
Can we have a look
at the book, please?
I burnt it.
You burnt it?
Yes.
Well, unfortunately,
there's nothing we can do about it.
He's been making phone
calls to me as well.
What's he been saying?
Nothing, just making these... noises.
How do you know it's the same person?
Because of what he wrote in the book.
The book you burnt?
Yes.
OK.
Don't worry about it.
Did you get your things done?
Mrs Roach has Parkinson's.
That's why she shakes like this.
Samuel, you don't have to say
everything that goes through your head.
Oh, it's alright, love.
He wanted to know so
we talked about it.
He sees things as they are, that one.
Oskar was the same.
He always spoke his mind.
Do you have to keep
on bringing him up?
Hey, Bugsy.
Hey.
Hey!
Don't come in here.
I don't want to buy anything.
Are you Amelia Vanick?
Yes.
I'm Warren Newton and
this is Prue Flannery
from the Department
of Community Services.
My son's only been away for two days.
He's not actually registered
at Babbage Bay anymore.
If I could just come
in and meet Samuel
and get you to look at
these papers, that'd be great.
I'm just in the middle of cleaning
up the house at the moment.
I'm sorry. There's stuff everywhere.
Hello, Samuel.
I'm Prue and this is Warren.
How are you?
I'm a bit tired from
the drugs Mum gave me.
Not drugs. Tranquillisers...
from the doctor.
He had a fit yesterday.
I'm really tired, actually.
That's no good.
May I have a glass of water, please?
Yes. Of course. I'll get you one.
It's a real mess.
I just found this
cockroach infestation.
I normally have the house sprayed.
I did actually already
have it sprayed
but there's this hole in
the wall behind the fridge
and that's why I...
I didn't mean a hole in the wall.
There was a hole in the wallpaper.
That's where they were
laying their eggs, I think.
We've caught you at a bad time.
I'll leave you with this.
We're required to come back in a
week to talk through your options.
Here's my card.
Mum, I think I'm gonna vomit.
- What was that noise I heard?
- I didn't hear any noise.
Wind howling, doors slamming.
I declare, I think this house is haunted.
Mum, I'm gonna go to bed.
Are you sick?
Oh, no, Granny.
It's only 6:00.
Don't you want to stay up
with your mum for a while?
No.
If you go to bed now,
the pills won't work properly.
You have to stay up
for a while, sweetheart.
Where's its mother, Skip?
Koalas don't leave their babies about.
- Are you off now, Dad?
- Yep. Soon as I fuel up.
Tell Jerry I'll keep
in touch on the radio
and I'll be back before breakfast
the day after tomorrow.
"And the Prince and the Princess
"lived happily together
in a beautiful palace
"for the rest of their days."
Babadook...
dook... dook.
What are we doing?
We're going downstairs.
- Why?
- Because we are.
Iris, Iris, Iris.
No.
Glass and mirror attachment.
Clean and polish shower doors or
mirrors for a streak-free shine.
As part of your steaming special, we'll
even include the garment and upholst...
Oh, I don't want to give
it to anyone at work.
Alright. Give all my shifts away.
That's just what I need.
I can't help it if I'm sick.
What do you expect me to do?
You do that!
Mum, I took the pills
but I feel sick again.
I need to eat something.
I couldn't find any
food in the fridge.
You said to have them with food.
I'm really hungry, Mum.
Why do you have to
keep talk, talk, talking?
Don't you ever stop?
- I was just...
- I need to sleep!
I'm sorry, Mummy.
I was just really hungry.
If you're that hungry,
why don't you go and eat shit?
I'm so sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
It was terrible.
I've had absolutely no sleep.
I didn't know what I was saying.
I'll cook you something. Hey?
What would you like?
I'm not hungry anymore.
We really need to get
out of this house.
We've been cooped up here
too long. That's the problem.
Do you want to go to Wally's?
You can have anything
you want. Alright?
Even ice-cream for
breakfast if you like.
Give it back! Give it back!
- Stop it! Sit down. Sit down.
- No!
- Now!
- Give my drink back!
Sit down, please.
Where are we going?
I just want to drive
for a little while.
Mummy! Mummy!
Babadook.
You ran straight into me!
I just bought this bloody car.
What were you thinking?
Oh, driving on the wrong side
of the road with a kid in the back.
You could've killed someone!
Hey! Hey, what are you doing?
Hey! Crazy bitch!
Hi, sweetheart.
Mum?
I can call Aunty Claire.
I can call and she can come over.
Mum?
Aunty Claire doesn't want
to talk to us anymore.
Mum. Mum, look at me.
It's nice and warm in here.
I don't want you to go away.
I'm not going anywhere.
Mum?
Mum, I don't think we
should stay here tonight.
I can call Mrs Roach.
I don't want you to call anyone.
I just need to sleep.
- Mum...
- Leave it!
There's something in the house.
There's someone in the house!
Mrs Roach can we come
and stay the night?
Gracie, I'm so sorry.
Has someone broken into the house?
- Sam said that...
- No, no, no. We're fine.
Samuel's just being
very disobedient again.
Oh, I was so worried.
I told him not to call anyone.
He asked if you could stay the night.
No, no, no. We're fine. I just
have a headache. That's all.
I really have to go,
though, now, Gracie.
I'm so sorry for troubling you.
Yes. Talk soon.
No worries. Talk soon.
I told you not to call anyone and
you deliberately disobeyed me.
Do you want to frighten Mrs Roach?
An old lady who can hardly walk?
Do you want to make her sick?
Get that bloody thing off!
Is this the only way I can
trust you not to embarrass me
in front of our neighbours?
Is this what I have to do?
I'm sorry, Mummy.
It's just that the Babadook made
you crash the car and then...
What'd you say?
I said the Babadook...
The Babadook isn't real, Samuel.
He's just something you've made
up in your stupid little head.
I just didn't want you to let it in!
I'll make sure nothing
gets in tonight.
Alright, Samuel?
Nothing is coming in here tonight.
Nothing!
I feel sick.
If you don't take the pill,
you'll feel worse.
Mum, I don't think I need...
I am the parent and you are
the child so take the pill.
Good boy.
Mum!
Hey, Bugsy. Hey, sweetie.
Come here, sweetie. Hey?
Hey.
Hey!
Here we go.
There's more where that came from.
What's the secret?
- ...letter of Max's, didn't you?
- No, not for a minute.
Don't lie. You called
me a jezebel. Why?
- The north, east.
- Natural corset.
With fresh meat.
Only five...
You don't wanna go in there
all by yourself, do you?
Police say the woman used a
kitchen knife to stab her son.
His body was found in their basement.
The woman later attacked
officers with a knife.
They drew their guns
and shot her to death.
Little is known about the tragedy
but neighbours say the boy was
celebrating his birthday today.
He had just turned seven.
Samuel?
Wake up, Mummy.
But you're the one
who's asleep, sweetheart.
Don't go down there.
It's not safe.
I thought you were dead.
We're gonna be together.
You just need to bring me the boy.
You mean Samuel?
You can bring me the boy.
Stop calling him 'the boy'.
I think it's going to rain.
No.
It isn't real. It isn't real.
It isn't real.
Oh, no.
No! No!
Bugsy!
Samuel!
Samuel.
Bugsy's hurt and we need to get help.
You don't want him to die, do you?
Samuel.
Are you listening to me?
Let me in, you little shit!
Let me in!
You little pig!
Six years old and you're
still wetting yourself.
You don't know how many times
I wished it was you,
not him, that died.
I just want you to be happy.
"I just want you to be happy."
Sometimes...
I just wanna smash your
head against a brick wall
until your fucking brains pop out.
You're not my mother.
- What did you say?
- I said you're not my mother!
I am your mother!
Run, run, run, as fast as you can!
Get away!
Didn't I tell you not
to play with weapons?
I'm sorry, love. I know it's late.
I just wanted to make
sure you were OK.
I'm OK.
I know... this time of year's
terribly hard for you.
And I know you don't want me
to go on about it, so I won't.
But I just wanted you to know that
I'd do anything for you and Sam.
I love you both.
Samuel.
I'm sorry.
I understand you're scared.
I haven't been good
since your dad died.
I haven't been good at all.
I'm sick, Sam. I need help.
I just spoke with Mrs Roach.
We're going to stay there tonight.
Do you want that?
I want to make it up to you, Sam.
I want you to meet your dad.
It's beautiful there.
You'll be happy.
Sorry, Mummy!
Mum!
I'm not leaving you.
Mum? Mum?
You said we'd protect each other.
I know you don't love me.
The Babadook won't let you.
But I love you, Mum.
And I always will.
You let it in.
You have to get it out!
I don't want you to go away.
No! No! No!
Mummy!
Mummy! Mummy!
What is it?
You can't get rid of the Babadook.
What do you want?
No.
Keep breathing.
Put your seat back, sweetheart.
10 more minutes and we're there.
No.
I think it's gonna rain.
Stop!
You are nothing.
You're nothing!
This is my house!
You are trespassing in my house!
If you touch my son again
I'll fucking kill you!
No!
Mummy, don't!
Don't!
Watch out for your
mum's leg, little one.
He's fine. I've had the stitches out.
What time's the party?
Any time after three is fine.
I'll see you in a few hours, then.
Bye.
Bye, Sam.
That school's a good choice.
I've been doing a lot of reading about
it so I think Sam will be happy there.
He's been out of school over two
weeks now. It's time to get back.
We needed some time to
sort a few things out.
Are you having a party?
It's Sam's birthday today.
My first birthday
I've ever celebrated.
That's not true.
Yes, it is. My first
party on the day.
That's unusual.
My husband died the
day that Sam was born.
He got killed driving Mum
to the hospital to have me.
Sam's just like his dad was.
Always speaks his mind.
Well, parties are lots of fun,
especially when they're yours.
My cousin's not coming because
I broke her nose in two places.
I'll take that for you.
Good shot.
Look, there's another one!
Where's your bowl?
Wow. You've got a lot today.
Am I ever gonna see it?
One day, when you're bigger.
You go outside, and you
don't come in until I tell you.
It's alright. It's alright.
It's alright.
How was it?
It was pretty quiet today.
Come here.
It's getting much better, Mum.
Wait!
I have a new trick.
Life is not always as it seems.
Nothing in my hands.
- That's great!
- I haven't finished.
Abracadabra!
How did you do that?
Come here, you. Come here.
Happy birthday, sweetheart.