Subs transcripted by journaldhirondelle
Mum!
Mommy!
I had that dream again
And he climbed down that chimney
Straight into the huge black pot
That was the end of the big bad wolf
Did they really killed the wolf mum?
I am sure they did
I' ll kill the monster when it comes
I'll smash its head in
It's time to go to sleep now sweetie, it's very late
Can we read it again?
A long time ago, just yesterday in fact
There were three little pigs
And one nasty big wolf
It's not broken it just slipped
Non l'ho rotto è scivolato
Don't you were firing things over the house anymore?
Wait, wait, wait, watch this! When the monster comes
I'm gonna do this!
Please don't!
Nothing in my hands, nothing in my hands
Stand still please
Look at me, mum!
C'mon Samuel
Look at me!
Stand still please
Nothing in my hands nothing in my hands
I don't wanna you making weapons anymore
It wont work if you don't look at me
This monster thing has got to stop
All right?
Don't do that!
Ready?
C'mon
Who get late already?
What have you got in there?
See you later alligator!
Here is one for you Norma has got milk in it
What?
One with your milk in it
I don't want milk
No worries I'll make you another one
Ah just where all the women should be, in the kitchen
Get to work woman!
Do you want a cup of?
Nah, I'm headed to the dementia ward
Just a few years before you end up there isn't it?
Right?
Amelia, your son's school is on the phone
Oh my God
Did he hurt anyone?
A dart could have gone into a child's eye or even worse
I'm gonna have a serious talk with him
Mrs Fanning we had the talks
We had decisions with the counselor
We're going to have to employ
a monitor for him
A monitor?
He'll be separated from the other children
The monitor will supervise him one on one
Sammy wont cope with this he already feels so different
I'll have a talk with him
I'll have a serious talk
Mrs Fanning the boy has significant behavioral problems
You know, Sammy doesn't need a full time monitor
what he needs is some understanding
I have 24 other first graders in that class
Do you want me to put them all on risk because of your son?
I think I'll just find another school
,Mrs Fanning you can't just take the boy out of school
You'll look after your business and I'll go find a school
that sees my son as a human being
and not just as another problem to be gotten rid of
That's very unfair we're only trying to help the boy
Please
Stop calling him "the boy"
He's name's Samuel
We can see Ruby and auntie Claire at the park today
You can play in that swing you
like for as long as you like ok?
Mrs Browning hates me
No, she doesn't
You just need a brake that's all
Don't tell auntie Claire what happened
I'll tell her later
Mum come and look at this!
I can do it again
Samuel
Don't bother the lady
No no no that's all right!
We have to go home see daddy there haven't we?
My dad's in the cemetery
Oh, that's...
He got killed driving mum to the hospital to have me
Samuel!
I'm sorry he just...
No, that's all right I shouldn't have...
Well your mum is very lucky to have you then isn't she?
We have to go
Say see you later Kathy -Bye
Yeah and he was so drunk he vomited
right in front of his own installation
Lost all the sales!
You're not listening
Oh, I am I am
So you've lost all these sales and then what happened?
Ruby! Don't play there it's wet!
Mum! Mum!
I'm gonna smash its head!
Be careful!
Mum! Mum! I'm gonna smash it!
What would you like me to do for Wednesday?
I can get the birthday cakes, that's easy
I was hoping Ruby would change her mind
She doesn't want to join party with Sam this year
Mum!
MUM!
She wants to have a princess party
Mum!
That's ok
We don't have to come
He can still come
Mum!
She just doesn't want to share the day with Sam anymore
I understand
Mum!
Mum! I can go really high! Watch!
Maybe you wanna celebrate his
birthday properly this year anyway
On the day
Yeah we'll see
You know Amelia I just want you to be happy
and then this birthday thing rose
around and I end up feeling awful
I don't want you to feel awful Claire
We'll be fine
We're absolutely fine
Mum! Look at me!
Mum!
Who do we have here?
Hello Mrs Roach
You look tired little one!
You've been in the worse today?
The worse
He just had a big day, that's all
He's just exhausted
Poor little sweetheart!
Betsy
You little girl!
Hello
You look tired too love
You ok?
Nothing five years of sleep wouldn't fix
I'll put your rubbish out for you Grace
No no no you just got in pet
I'll do it now then it's done
You can choose one tonight
Where did you get this?
On the shelf!
If it's in a word or it's in a look
You can't get rid of the babadook
If you are a really clever one and
you know what it means to see
Then you can make friends with a
special one a friend of you and me
He's name is Mr Babadook
And this is his book
A rumbling sound then
three sharp knocks
Ba baba dook dook dook
That's when you'll know he's around
You'll see him if you look
Ba baba dook dook dook
We might read another one tonight eh?
But you said I could choose!
This is what he wears on top
He's funny don't you think?
Seeing him in your room at night
Mum does it hurt the boy?
Mum?
Does it live under the bed?!
Mum!
Mommy!
Mummy!
How sweet did they sound
Telling of the happiness and loveliness
secretly at the bottom of the ocean
and in treating the seals not to be afraid
right time the night again turn
If that's what the doctor ordered I...
Yeah yeah that's what the doctor ordered
It's in my room!
What is?
The babadook!
Oh no
No no no this is not going to happen
The closet's door were closed and now they're wide open!
It's just a book
It can't hurt you!
You've had a big day
You're just exhausted
I don't want anything bad to happen to you mum
Nothing bad it's gonna happen Sam
I'm gonna protect you
Mum it's nine o'clock!
He's not running a fever anymore
No no no my sister is gonna take him. Put it back!
Put it back or it goes in the bin
Sorry what was that?
Oh no I couldn't get to the phone he was vomiting
Yeah no worries I'll see you soon
Samuel no monster talking at auntie Claire's ok?
Samuel!
No babadook, no nothing
All right?
88! Number 88!
Too fair ladies!
Cool Alaine another few days and
someone cuckoo will say loud bingo!
Number 11! Who has number 11!
Next 11! All right...
Five billion!
Anyone got 50000000000?
Pewey's not very impressed with your Bingo skills
Are you all right?
Yeah yeah no I'm fine
How are you? How's Stevie?
Fine yeah, just a bunch of "milkavour"
You don't have to be fine you know?
Just a bit stressed at the moment
Why don't you go home?
Oh, cranky bitch? She goes after lunch I can cover for you
You'd do that?
Yeah
I'll give you my pay
Oh, no that would be ridiculous
You've got a sick boy is a part to assure
You're so sweet Robbie Ethan
You should go now
Say hi to Sam from me
Yeah I will
Where have you been?!
You weren't at work rung you million times!
,Just scared the crap out of Ruby that's all
He insist her on talking to this bloody babadook thing
all day. Just talking to the air and freaked me out!
I'm so sorry
You need to get him to see someone Amelia it's not
normal for a kid to carry on with this rubbish
It's not rubbish it's real!
Don't you talk to auntie Claire like that
Where did you get those firecrackers?
You've gotten for me on the Internet!
Well that's the end of the Internet!
If the babadook was real we'd see it right now, wouldn't we?
He wants to scare you first
Then you'll see it
Well I'm not scared
You will be when it creeps into your room at night
That's enough!
You will be when he eats your insides!
I decided you're not having your
birthday with Ruby this week
No cake no games that's the end of it
Samuel!
Ladies and gentleman
Mum and Dad
Life is not always as it seems
It can be a wondrous thing
But it can also be very treacherous
Don't worry Dad, I'll save Mum!
I'm gonna trap the babadook like this!
And when is trapped I'm gonna kill it!
Samuel?
I was just putting something back!
All your father's things are down there!
He's my father you don't own him!
Just thought to see how are you going
Can I come in?
Hi matey! This is for you!
My mom always got me a model flight when I was sick
I'm not sick!
Oh
I... I... I thought...
No he's not actually. The truth is he's so
disobedient he can't go to school anymore
You said it's not true!
The only 6 years old junior boy Robbie
which still believes in monsters
I hate you!
She wont let me have a birthday party and
And she wont let me have a dad!
Don't eat it
The babadook did it mum!
Go and watch a DVD and I'll make something else
Babadook did it!
Just go and watch a DVD Samuel
Ladies and gentlemen!
Girls and boys!
Welcome!
To the great Martin's DVD school of magic!
Life is not always as it seems
It can be a wondrous thing
But it can also be very treacherous
In this DVD you will learn magic tricks to surprise
To delight!
And perhaps even shock!
Your family and friends!
Do you think this is funny?
Oh no, no, no!
Give it to me!
Do you wanna die?!
Don't let it in!
Mum do we have to go to Ruby's party?
I've already got this doll mum!
No you've just got a twin!
They can go shopping together
Be good
He's just really tired
Go and play, right now!
Claire told me you are a writer
No, not really. Not anymore
What kind of writing did you do?
I wrote some articles for some
magazines and get some kid's stuff
It takes time to get into it, that's all!
It must be difficult
I do volunteer work with some disadvantage women and
well a few of them have lost their
husbands and they find it very hard
How's Richard's marriage going?
Oh good, I mean his wife has just ballooned
I've got the kids 24/7 and feels like...
Don't tell me about it
I don't even have time to go to
the gym anymore it's ridiculous
That's a real tragedy!
Not having time to go to the gym anymore. How do you cope?!
You must have so much to talk about
with those poor disadvantaged women
This is my tree house your not allowed in here
I'm not hurting anybody!
Bye
Thanks
How your mum know if it's real or not
She never comes to our house!
Mum told dad she didn't want to go to
your house because is too depressing!
The babadook would eat your mum for breakfast
And then rip her arms off!
Shut up!
They feel sorry for me Claire there's a big difference
God Amelia as soon anyone mentions Oscar you can't cope!
That's not true
It will be 7 years!
Isn't it time you moved on?
I have moved on!
When do I mention him?
When I talk about him?
What strain is that on you Claire?
You're not even good enough to have a dad!
Everyone else has one you don't!
I do have a dad!
I listen to your life day in day out
And you never stopped asking anything about mine
I do!
I want to know how you are!
You're not coming around the house anymore!
Because I can't stand being around your son!
I can't believe you just say that
You can't stand being around him yourself!
Your dad died so he didn't have to be with you
That's not true!
Your mum doesn't want you
No one wants you
What did you do!
She said I didn't have a dad! She kept saying it!
Is she all right?
Stay here and look after the children
or do you want another one to get hurt?
Mummy! She won't believe me!
Mommy!
Why can't you just be normal?!
There is no babadook!
Get out!
Samuel?
Mommy!
Stop please now!
- Get out!
Get out! Get out!
Please help me!
There's something wrong with my son!
Nothing more than a febrile convulsion
It's when the brain hardly heats
It always looks worst than it is
But I've never seen anything like this!
We have to wait until the tests come back
all these other results are normal
He's obviously suffering a high level of anxiety
Very committed to the monster theory
Yet an understatement
All children see monsters
Not like this!
And it's getting worse
He's becoming aggressive
He could see a psychiatrist
I can refer you
Takes a few weeks to get in
That'd be great
But can you...
Just give me something for now, just...
To make him sleep?
And just until...
Just until we get an appointment....
Please!
I haven't slept in weeks and...
Neither has Samuel…
And when we go home tonight this whole nightmare
will start up again and I am really...
I'm really not coping
I can...
I can give you a short course of sedatives
Just until the tests come back
Less the mothers
are too keen on them unless it's really bad
It's really bad
These can make children feel
Foggy
Perhaps in temporary nausea
but certainly help him sleep back
That's for one week
Thank you
Why don't people like me
Why do you say that?
Ruby said people don't like me because I'm weird
Sometime people say things that aren't true
You just need to take your medicine
Have a big sleep and not worrying
I don't want you to die
I'm not gonna die for a long time yet
Did you think that about my dad before he died?
Just take your pill so you can go to sleep
I've got the day off tomorrow, maybe we can do something uh?
Will these make the babadook go away?
I think so but you have to promise
me not to mention it again
I promise to protect you if you promise to protect me
Then I wont mention it
I promise
To protect you
C'mon
Can you stay here with me?
Yes
I love you mum
Me too
The nose is broken in two places and then the surgery
I'll pay for everything
You can't even pay your own bills!
Look I really have to go
Claire... I think somebody is stalking me and Samuel
What?!
A book ended at our place
I threw it away but somebody glued it
back together and put it on our door step
Amelia
I just can't help you right now
I don't expect you to help I just wanted
If it's that urgent you should go to the police
I have to go
Claire!
Hello?
BA-BAA
DOOK
DOOK!
Hi
I want to report someone stalking me and my child
Can you tell us what happened?
Somebody sent me
A children's book
And?
And it contained violent and graphic
images of my child and me being murdered
Can we have a look at the book please?
I burnt it
You burnt it
Yes
Well unfortunately there's nothing we can do about it
He's been making phone calls to me as well
What's he being saying?
Nothing he was just making this...
Noises...
How do you know is the same person?
Because of what he wrote in the book!
The book you burnt
Yes
Ok
Don't worry about it
Did you get your things hon?
Mrs Roach has Parkinson's
That's why she shakes like this!
Samuel you don't have to say
everything that goes to your head
It's all right love!
He wanted to know
So we talked about it
Sammy sees things as that they are that one
Oscar was the same
He always spoke his mind
Do you have to keep on bringing him up?
Hey Bugsy!
Hey!
Don't come in here!
I don't wanna buy anything
Are you Amelia Vannick?
Yes
I'm Warren and this is
Prue Flanery from the department of community services
My son's only been away for two days!
He's not actually registered at Babidge bay anymore
If I could just come in and meet Samuel and get
you look at these papers that it'd be great
I'm just in the middle of cleaning
up the house at the moment
I'm sorry there's stuff everywhere
Hello Samuel!
I'm Prue
And this is Warren
How are you?
I'm a bit tired from the drugs mother gave me
Not drugs, tranquilizers
From the doctor!
You know he had a fever yesterday
I am really tired actually
That's no good!
May I have a glass of water please?
Yes of course I'll get you one
It's a real mess I...
I just found this cockroach infestation
Normally I have the house sprayed and I
did actually already have it sprayed but
There's this hole in the wall behind
the fridge and that's why I...
I didn't mean...
Hole in the wall
There was a hole in the wall paper that's
where they were laying the insects I think
We've caught you with a bad time
I'll leave you with this
We are required to come back in a week
To talk through your options
Here's my card
Mum
I think I'm gonna vomit
What was that noise I've heard
I didn't hear any noise
The howling dogs
Then what? I declare but I think this house is haunted
Mum?
I'm gonna go to bed
Are you sick?
Oh no granny!
I'll just do one...
It's only six o'clock
Don't you wanna stay up with your mum for a while?
No
If you go to bed now the pills wont work properly
You have to stay up for a while sweetheart
This is not escaped
Koalas don't leave their babies around
Are you off now there?
Yep as soon as I fuel up
Tell Jerry I'll keep in touch on the radio
And I'll be back before breakfast the day after tomorrow
And the prince and the princess live
happily together in a beautiful palace
for the rest of their days
BA BA
DOOK
What are we doing?
We are going downstairs
Why?
Because we are!
I loose I loose I loose
No
I don't want give it to anyone at work
All right give all my shifts away that's just what I need
I can't help out if I'm sick what do you expect me to do
You do that!
Mum!
I took the pills but I feel sick again
I need to eat something
I couldn't find any food in the fridge
You said to have them with food
I'm really hungry mum
Why do you have to keep
alk talk taking. Don't you ever stop!
I was trying...- I need to sleep!
I'm sorry mum I was just really hungry
If you are that hungry why don't you go an eat shit!
I'm so sorry
I don't know why I said that
It was terrible
I've had absolutely no sleep
I don't know what I was saying
I'll cook you something ok?
What would you like?
I'm not hungry anymore
We really need to get out of this house we've
been cooped up here too long that's the problem
Do you wanna go to Wally's?
You can have anything you want. All right?
Even the ice cream for breakfast if you like
Give it back
Give it back! Stop it! Sit down!
Sit down!
Now!
- Give my drink back!
No -Sit down!
Where are we going?
I just wanna drive for a little while
The tree! Mommy!
BA BA
DOOK
You run straight into me
I just bought this bloody car what were you thinking!
Oh driving on the wrong side of the road with a
kid in the back you could have killed someone!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Hey crazy bitch!
Hi sweetheart!
Mum
I can call auntie Claire
I can call and she can come over
Mum?
Auntie Claire doesn't want to talk to us anymore
Mum look at me!
It's nice and worm in here
I don't want you to go away
I'm not going anywhere
Mum?
I don't think we should stay here tonight
I can call Mrs Roach
I don't want you to call anyone
I just need to sleep
Mum?
Leave it!
...something is in the house...
There is someone in the house!
The babadook is making her sleep
Mrs Roach
Can we come and stay tonight?
Gracie, I'm so sorry!
Someone broken into the house?
Sam said that...
No no we're fine Samuel is just being very disobedient again
I told him not to call anyone!
He asked if he could stay the night...
No no we are fine I just had an headache that's all
I really have to go tough now Gracie
I'm so sorry for troubling you
Yes talk soon
No worries talk soon
I told you to do not call anyone
and you deliberately disobeyed me
Do you wanna frighten Mrs Roach?
An old lady who can hardly walk. Do you wanna make her sick?
Get that bloody thing off!
Is this the only way
I can trust you not to embarrass
me in front of our neighbors?!
Is this what I have to do?
I'm sorry mommy
it's just that the babadook maybe crashed
the car engine -What did you say?
I said the babadook...
The babadook is not real Samuel
It's just something you made up
In your stupid little head
I just didn't want you to let it in!
I'll make sure nothing gets in tonight
All right Samuel?
Nothing is coming in here tonight!
NOTHING!
I feel sick
If you don't take the pill
You'll feel worse
Mum I don't think I need
I am the parent and you are the child so take the pill!
Good boy
Mum!
Hey Bugsy
Hey sweetie
Come here sweetie
Here we call
There's more where that came from
Be mind or we all die!
What's the secret
You sent her a message didn't you?
No not for a minute
Don't lie you call me and that it was why
You don't wanna go in there by yourself do you?
Police say the woman used a kitchen knife to stab her son
His body was found in the basement
The woman later attacked officers with a knife
They drew their guns and shot her to death
Little is known about the tragedy
but neighbors say the boy was celebrating his birthday today
He had just turned 7
Samuel?
Wake up mommy!
But you're the one whose asleep sweetheart
Don't go down there!
It's not safe!
I thought you were dead!
We can be together
You just need to bring me the boy
You mean Samuel?
You can bring me the boy
Stop calling him the boy
I think it's going to rain
No
It isn't real it isn't real it isn't real
Bugsy!
I beg you!
Samuel!
Samuel
Bugsy is hurt we need to get help
You don't want him to die do you?
Samuel
Are you listening to me?
Let me in you little shit!
Let me in!
You little pig!
Six years old and you're still wetting yourself
You don't know how many times
I wished that was you
not him that died
I just want you to be happy
Sometimes
I just wanna smash your head against the prick wall
Until your fucking brain pops out
You're not my mother
What did you say?
I said your not my mother!
I am your mother!!!
Run run run as fast as you can!
Get away!
Didn't I tell you not to play with weapons?!
I'm sorry love
I know it's late
I just wanted to make sure you were ok
I'm ok
I know
This time of the year is terribly hard for you
And I know you don't want me to go on about it so I wont
I just want you to know that I
would do anything for you and Sam
I love you both
Samuel
I'm sorry
I understand you're scared
I haven't been good since your dad died
I haven't been good at all
I'm sick Sam
I need help
I just spoke with Mrs Roach
We're gonna stay there tonight
Do you want that?
I wanna make it up to you Sam
I want you to meet your dad
It's beautiful there
You'd be happy
Sorry mommy!
Mum!
I'm not leaving you
Mum?
We said we protect each other
And now you don't love me
The babadook wont let you
But I love you mum
And I always will
You let it in!
You have to get it out!
I don't want you to go away
No! Mommy!
Mommy!
What is it that?
You can't get rid of the babadook
What do you want?
What do you want!
No
Keep breathing
Put your sit back sweetheart ten
more moments and we are there
I think it's gonna rain
Stop!
You're nothing!
This is my house!
You're trespassing in my house!
If you touch my son again
I'll fucking kill you!!!
Mommy don't!
Don't!
Watch out for your mum's leg little one!
He's fine I got the stitches out!
What time is the party?
Anytime after 3 it's fine
I'll see you in a few hours then
Bye!
Bye Sam!
That school is a good choice!
I've been doing a lot of reading about it
and I think Sam will be happy there
He's been out of school over two weeks now
It's time to get back
We needed sometime to sort a few things out
And you are having a party!
It's Sam's birthday today
My first birthday I've ever celebrated
- That's not true!
- Yes it is!
My first party on the day!
That's unusual
My husband died the day that Sam was born
He got killed driving mum to the hospital to have me!
Sam's just like his dad was
Always speaks his mind
Parties are a lot of fun! Especially when they are yours!
My cousin's not coming because I
broke her nose in two places!
I'll take that for you
Good shot!
Look there's another one!
Get your bowl
Wow you've got a lot today!
And may I begin to see it?
One day when you're bigger
You go outside
And you don't come in until I tell you
It's all right
How was it?
Just a bit quiet today
Come here
It's getting much better mum
Wait!
I have a new trick
Life is not always as it seems
Nothing in my hands nothing in my hands
Oh that's great!
I haven't finished
Abracadabra!
How did you do that!
Come here you! Come here
Happy birthday sweetheart