(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAX: Come on, time to go.
We haven't got all day.
- Get that monkey on the train.
- (WHISTLE BLOWING)
The Medici Brothers' circus
is taking off!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(KIDS SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Breathing normal...
- heart rate normal.
- (SQUEAKING)
You're cleared to perform.
Milly!
Another train!
(SQUEAKING)
Niños, wait!
We are coming, too!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(BELL DINGING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- TRAIN CONDUCTOR: Joplin!
- (WHISTLE BLOWS)
Joplin, Missouri!
- Hey, sweetheart!
- Daddy! (LAUGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Oh, I meant to tell ya.
You know,
in the letter I sent?
I'm so sorry
that I wasn't here.
Well, come here now.
Still me.
And you...
you're just as pretty
as your momma.
MILLY: We missed you, Dad.
I missed you, too.
Ivan and Catherine,
thank you both...
for looking out for them.
Captain Farrier, of course.
Oh, it's Holt, come on now.
It's just Holt.
Don't you worry.
Everything's gonna be
just like it was before.
JOE: Come on! Come on!
HOLT: Home sweet home.
PUCK: Hey! Holt!
HOLT: Hey, Puck.
- Hey, Thomas.
- JOE: Milly, come on!
Hi, Holt.
Oh! Hey, Miss Atlantis.
Pramesh!
The very best journey,
dear friend.
The road that leads home.
Welcome home. (LAUGHING)
(SNAKE HISSING)
(GRUNTING) No hugs!
Pramesh, I missed you, too.
What's going on? The camp's
half the size it used to be.
Hard times, my friend.
For everyone.
- (CLATTERING)
- (MAN EXCLAIMING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (MONKEY CHITTERING)
MAX: Attention, everybody!
Why is Rule Number One
called Rule Number One?
Because
"keep the cages locked"
is the most important
rule of all!
When I catch
that fugitive scalawag
who interrupted my dream...
Rongo!
Where is Rongo?
(GASPS)
Who's heading camp management?
I'm the strongman.
Yes, but we're all wearing
multiple hats!
You're in charge of budgets,
and accounting, and inventory.
Which means
animal whereabouts!
Now, go find that monkey!
I'll have a look around.
(CHITTERING)
(GASPS)
MAX: All right, everybody.
Back to work.
Holt!
This winter, the influenza
hit us like a hurricane.
Natalya, Vincenzo...
the Vanderjees, and then...
your wife.
Poor Annie.
How she fought.
She was the best of us.
I know it.
So, uh, you know, for her,
let's have
our best season yet!
Now where's my horses?
Ah...
Funny story about that.
Funny how?
BOTH: He sold them.
But our act is the soul
of this show!
And first, we lost you,
and then Annie, to ride 'em!
If only Milly would have
learned the trade.
I don't wanna be a show-off
in your circus.
- "Show-off"?
- You see?
I wanna make
scientific discoveries.
I wanna be noticed
for my mind.
Okay.
Then learn clairvoyance.
Telepathy! Something!
I can do a handstand
for almost ten seconds.
- MAX: Oh.
- (JOE GRUNTS)
"Child does handstand."
We'll be broke by July.
Hang on now. Without horses,
what the hell's my act?
The crowds come to see me!
Max, please.
I need to work.
Good news.
One job, I have.
Okay, then.
Give me a showstopper.
You know that old rascal
Itchy McPhee?
He finally ran off
with the bearded lady.
I've been filling in with
roustabouts ever since.
I need somebody good
to tend the elephants.
No, you're not serious.
I am on occasion.
This is a big job
and you know it.
No, it's a big shovel
for a big pile of...
KIDS: Dad.
So you sold my horses
and kept your elephants.
Your scrawny, mangy,
cut-rate elephants.
They're important.
Especially this season.
Why's that?
I know it goes
against my nature...
but for once,
I made an investment.
(GRUNTING)
Bellissima! There she is!
Our brand-new Asian female.
I bought her off
a Brugelbecker in Biloxi.
I had to get him
way down on the price.
But I swear to you, Holt,
I saw something special
in her eyes.
HOLT: This is your investment?
An old, sick elephant.
Oh, no. She's not sick.
Any day now...
she's having a baby.
(ELEPHANT BREATHING
LABORIOUSLY)
Dad, watch! Dad!
I'm getting better!
Hang on now, this is our tent?
What happened to our things?
We had nice furniture,
we had rooms.
Max, what didn't you sell?
You son of a gun.
JOE: Dad, look!
Toys?
They're not toys.
They're for
my science experiments.
Well, we're a circus, darlin',
a circus.
We need to be practical
if we want to survive.
You couldn't
just take up one act?
Tumblin' or tightrope?
Maybe I don't need
the world staring at me.
Maybe I'm just not
you and Mom.
Well, who makes the rules
in this family?
Mom did.
HOLT: Yeah, well,
I make them now.
So just, uh...
Go to your room!
This is my room.
This is all our rooms.
HOLT: See this?
You know what this is?
It's your inheritance.
JOE: Dad!
Don't worry,
he's not going anywhere.
He's stuck here.
Like you and me.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GRUNTING)
JOE: Come on, come on,
you're missing it!
Look, I can do it!
I'm doing it, Milly!
A new season!
(SINGING CASEY JUNIOR)
(VOCALIZING)
(GRUNTS)
Let me in,
you little hairball!
(MONKEY CHITTERING)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
- (SCREECHES)
- Hey!
Would somebody please
let me in my own train?
(BIRD CAWS)
(SNORING)
- JOE: Dad, wake up! Let's go!
- (GASPS)
The elephants need us!
Good God, son,
you're gonna make me
miss the war.
- (ROOSTER CROWS)
- (GRUNTS) Gimme that.
Go on, lead the way.
- Move it!
- (ELEPHANT TRUMPETS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Let's skedaddle, Mrs. Jumbo!
Don't make me
have to incentivize.
Get her out of there, boys.
(MEN GRUNTING)
Easy, Rufus.
That's a lady in there.
Well, well, our own Tom Mix
ridin' in to the rescue.
But he just ain't
on the marquee no more.
Time to see
what he's been missing.
Do you ever get that feeling?
Like there's something
you're missing?
Imagine my surprise,
you didn't enlist.
- Weak ticker. Doc's advice.
- Uh-huh.
- Dad? Something's wrong.
- (MEN GRUNTING)
She doesn't wanna leave.
Come on!
Let's get her outta there!
- JOE: What are you doing?
- Come on!
HOLT: Leave her alone!
- Stop hurting her, please!
- Leave her alone!
(RUFUS GRUNTS)
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
JOE: Dad, look.
What now?
RUFUS: Move her!
Whoa, we got a baby in here.
(TYPEWRITER DINGS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN DISTANCE)
WOMAN: She had a baby!
- Baby!
- Huh?
Notify the press!
"The Medici Brothers...
"proudly present
America's newest,
"precious bundle of joy!"
(LAUGHS)
HOLT: Look at that.
It's okay now.
Don't be scared.
Don't be scared now,
your momma's right outside.
- (GRUNTS)
- (BABY ELEPHANT TRUMPETING)
(ALL GASP)
(TRUMPETS)
(TRUMPETING)
Baby! We got a baby!
We got a baby!
What is that?
Baby Jumbo.
I already got fake freaks
in the freak show!
I don't need a real one
in the center ring!
Rongo!
We've been swindled!
RUFUS: (SCOFFS)
Gone and bought yourself
a baby monster.
Think he can hear me?
- Boo! (LAUGHS)
- (BABY ELEPHANT SHRIEKS)
(TRUMPETING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
Rongo!
Telegram to Brugelbecker.
"We have been bilked
with damaged goods.
"This is an aberration,
travestation...
"and I demand my money back."
But whatever you do,
do not call the papers.
We are not advertising
this baby.
(CHUCKLES)
Tell me you didn't do it.
You did it?
Never do anything I tell ya
without checking
with me first!
(SIGHS)
Why me? Why me?
A face
only a mother could love.
MISS ATLANTIS: Sir?
Many of us find you handsome.
I was talking
about the elephant!
Look, she's drawing him
a bath.
(SQUEALING)
Need a vet to come
to look at him, Max.
No, no witnesses!
We are going to be in Joplin
for two weeks.
We promised them
a beautiful baby!
You have until tomorrow night
to fix that!
- HOLT: Me?
- Yes, you!
This is my problem?
Yes.
You tend the elephants.
Make those ears disappear!
Don't look at me.
JOE: Look at him, those
giant ears weigh him down.
Hi, Baby Jumbo.
- Welcome to the circus.
- (SQUEAKING)
We're all family here.
No matter how small.
Aren't elephants
afraid of mice?
Says who?
That's why we experiment.
Someone needs to
keep him company.
When he's not with his momma.
(SQUEAKING)
(SNIFFING)
Look. Give him one.
If he can lift his ears
out of the way.
No. You have to blow your ears
Like this. (BLOWING)
(SNIFFING)
Good luck with that.
Maybe you can teach him
to juggle, too.
Baby Jumbo, look at me.
Do what I do.
Blow. (BLOWS)
(HUFFING)
(BLOWS)
No, not the feather.
Your ears. Blow!
He thinks it's a game.
- Oh, Max, come here.
- What?
Watch this.
I ride out, I do some jumps,
then all of a sudden...
(LAUGHS) stampede!
(WHISTLES) Send 'em!
(DOGS BARKING)
Get out of the way, Max!
I'm, uh, still working out
the timing.
Let me have a turn.
(SNIFFING)
(GRUNTS)
- (SNEEZES)
- (GASPS)
(TRUMPETING)
Meanwhile, for when you
- lead out the elephants...
- HOLT: Uh-huh.
I had the costume departments
make you up
a little something.
HOLT: Okay.
What in gosh...
You really broke the bank
with this, Max.
A lot of kids
come to the show.
You don't want me to
scare anyone, I get it.
Dad, Dad!
It's Baby Jumbo. Come see.
He jumped in the air.
With his ears.
Guys, I said leave him be.
But he was this far
off the ground!
Yeah, I bet he was.
He'll be tripping all over
with ears like that.
Dad, really.
We tried an experiment.
Just leave the poor guy alone.
First rule of science,
you have to have interest.
Otherwise,
you don't deserve to know.
MAX: It's been a rough year
for both of them.
Annie knew how to talk to 'em.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CIRCUS MUSIC PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, step right up.
Hurry, hurry.
Come see the circus today.
- (LIVELY CHATTER)
- (BELL RINGS)
PUCK: "To be or not to be...
"that is the question.
"Whether 'tis
nobler in the mind
"to suffer the slings and
arrows of outrageous..."
(FLUTE PLAYING)
BOY: That ain't no snake.
Heck, I could do it.
As you wish.
- (BOYS SCREAM)
- Get out of here!
Rongo, let's go!
(AUDIENCE GASPS AND APPLAUDS)
MAN: Hey, get away
from the baby elephant!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(APPLAUSE CONTINUES)
(TRUMPET AND DRUMS PLAYING)
Welcome, Joplin, Missouri!
Ladies and gentlemen...
I am
your Master of Ceremonies,
Maximilian Medici.
(APPLAUSE)
And now, I give to you...
the Medici Brothers' circus.
(CIRCUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- Okay.
- (TRUMPETS)
Okay, okay,
no one's gonna hurt him.
Okay, little guy,
let's put on a show.
- (MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
Hey, ain't that Holt Farrier,
the Stallion Star?
Hey! Ain't you Holt Farrier?
HOLT: Nah, he died in the war.
So sad.
AUDIENCE: Aw!
- AUDIENCE: Aw!
- (SQUEALS)
What's he doing?
MILLY: He's reaching
for the feathers.
(WOMAN YELPS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Coat, coat, coat, coat!
(GASPING)
(SNEEZES)
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Ooh...
What'd you do to that thing?
That ain't a real elephant.
Those ears are fake!
Look! Look at the sign!
"Dumbo!" (LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Uh-oh.
- (TRUMPETS)
- Whoa, calm down, now.
(TRUMPETING)
He's a fake!
Yeah, he's a fake!
Shut up!
- (TRUMPETING)
- You're scaring the elephants!
Take it easy now. Calm down.
AUDIENCE: (CHANTING) Dumbo,
Dumbo, fake, fake, fake!
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
HOLT: All right, sit down.
AUDIENCE: Dumbo, Dumbo,
fake, fake, fake!
I said sit down!
It's okay, little fella.
Fake!
Rongo! Music!
- Happiness, joy!
- (PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(CHANTING CONTINUES
IN DISTANCE)
Hear 'em making
fun of your ugly baby?
Who's gonna help him now?
Holt, get those ears
off the stage!
(WHIMPERS)
(TRUMPETING)
HOLT: Whoa!
(TRUMPETS)
Okay, all right.
Okay, nobody's gonna
hurt your baby.
Just calm down.
Okay. Attagirl.
We're here to protect him.
Same as you.
Attagirl.
Nice and easy.
(WHIMPERING)
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
Shh. Okay, nobody's gonna
hurt your baby.
(RUFUS YELLS)
- Rufus, no!
- (TRUMPETS)
HOLT: Rufus, stop!
RUFUS: Mad elephant!
Get back!
(ROARING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Max, get the kids out of here!
Everybody, out!
Get to safety.
Careful, careful.
(ROARING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Kids?
CATHERINE:
Go, go, go!
MAN: Quick, quick, quick.
Go, go, go.
Come on. This way, come on.
How do you like your job now,
cowboy? (LAUGHS)
Uh-oh.
Milly, Joe!
Come on!
Let's go!
(RUFUS SCREAMS)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(TRUMPETS)
MAX: And I wanna
just emphasize,
we did everything right.
What it is, the tent
just absolutely fell down.
It just collapsed.
And we had no way of knowing
what was gonna happen.
(SINGING BABY MINE)
(SNIFFING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(WHIMPERING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(CHAIN CLANKS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Brugelbecker,
I have a man dead,
do you understand?
This is what they're reading
from the Great Lakes
to the Gulf!
You have
a moral responsibility
to buy
your killer elephant back.
What about the baby?
(SCOFFS) Well, at least
he got a few laughs.
I'll put him in the clown act,
see if I can
salvage something.
I'll buy her back half price.
You will buy her back
full price.
Quarter price.
Half price it is!
- (TRUMPETS)
- (MAN EXCLAIMING)
Up!
(DUMBO WHINES)
What's happening?
Where are they taking her?
Away. Back to your tent now.
JOE: But she's his mom!
MILLY: Dad, please. Stop them.
Please!
Do something.
Mom would have done something.
Momma's not here.
(WHIMPERING)
Okay, little fella.
Okay. Come on.
(DUMBO TRUMPETING)
HOLT: I know, I do.
Beautiful creature,
we'll take care of your son.
(DUMBO TRUMPETING)
(TRUMPETS)
(TRUMPETS SOFTLY)
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTS)
- (DUMBO WHIMPERS)
- (TRUMPETS)
(WHINING)
(FAINT RATTLING)
HOLT: Darlin', it's late.
Go on now.
I know. I can't sleep, either.
My momma told me
there'd be times
when my life seemed
locked behind a door.
So, she gave me this key,
that her momma gave her.
And said
whenever I have that feeling,
imagine that door...
and just turn the key.
So, I keep trying.
(DOOR OPENS)
Not supposed to
be in here alone.
I'm not. You're here.
What's that?
JOE: I just thought
he might be hungry.
He's sad.
You don't eat when you're sad.
The mermaid does.
Come on.
Have one, Dumbo.
We're calling him Dumbo now?
If we call him Jumbo Junior...
it might make him
miss his mom.
Here you go... Dumbo.
Come on,
and flap those ears again.
To show us
we didn't imagine it.
Your momma, she didn't
mean to hurt anyone.
She was just protecting you.
And we think
your ears are great.
Maybe he wants to be alone.
Like Dad.
Nobody wants to be alone.
Well...
if you change your mind...
Night-night, Dumbo.
(SNIFFING)
(SQUEAKS)
(SNEEZES)
(EARS FLAPPING)
MILLY: Wow!
It's not the peanuts
that made him do it.
It's the feathers!
(JOE GASPS)
Dumbo!
(SQUEALS)
Dumbo, you gotta do this
in the show.
What do you mean?
'Cause if the circus
sells more tickets
and Medici makes more money...
then we can get him
to use some
to buy Mrs. Jumbo back.
Yeah!
We can get her back, Dumbo.
You can.
Just show them all
what you can do.
Come on. We gotta tell Dad.
No. He'll just tell us
to be practical.
Shows got canceled
for a week, right?
We can research
and study and test.
You're a miracle elephant,
Dumbo.
And we're gonna
bring your momma home.
- (CIRCUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- Fire!
(CHITTERING)
(BELL RINGING)
(CLOWN YELPS)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
- (HORN SQUEAKING)
- (LAUGHING)
So low.
An all-time low.
Who said he didn't want
to be recognized?
(SIGHS)
Okay, Big D, this is it.
Just like in rehearsal.
Except for lights, music,
fire and crowds.
- You can do it.
- Come on, Dumbo.
You can do it, Dumbo!
Show 'em all
like you showed us!
(FANFARE PLAYS)
- Come! Come! Come!
- HOLT: Attaboy, come on.
Keep comin'. Come on.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Go on now, Dumbo!
Come on.
Whoa.
(GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
CLOWN: Hey! Hey!
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
They love it! They love it!
(LAUGHING)
All right, Dumbo.
You put out the fire.
He won't fly. He's scared.
I know.
Now, he's up too high.
(MONKEY CHITTERING)
(WHISTLES)
Go on, Dumbo!
(ALL CHEERING)
Attaboy.
MAX: Yeah! Rule Number One.
"Always have a big finish!"
- (CHITTERING)
- AUDIENCE: Aw!
(SCREECHING)
Okay, guys.
Bring him down.
SPIROS: Yeah!
(ALL GASP)
- (TRUMPETS)
- Holt!
- HOLT: Look, Max!
- What? What?
- He's trapped up there.
- Put the fire out!
(TRUMPETS)
JOE: Dumbo! Fly!
He won't fly
without a feather!
Put the fire out!
Put it out!
- Joe!
- Stop!
(PEOPLE GASP)
Holt, I thought she didn't
want to be in an act.
- HOLT: Milly!
- (DUMBO TRUMPETS)
(CHITTERS)
(TRUMPETING)
Here, Dumbo!
- (SNIFFING)
- Come on.
Show 'em.
Come on, Dumbo.
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
(MILLY SCREAMS)
- (CREAKING)
- (DUMBO WHIMPERS)
- (TRUMPETING)
- Fly, Dumbo.
Fly!
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Whoa!
Yeah!
(CHITTERING)
(LAUGHS)
(YELLS)
(BOYS LAUGHING)
(BOYS EXCLAIMING)
(TRUMPETS)
You knew he could do this?
You should talk
to your kids more.
VANDEVERE: Sotheby...
cancel my dinner
with the president.
We've got business
with an elephant.
- (PEOPLE GROAN)
- Friends,
the next available shows
are in Arkansas!
(ALL CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
(SINGING) Happy clowns!
(HUMMING)
- Ah, Rongo the Strong!
- RONGO: Boss.
MAX: Hello, Jo!
The Medici Brothers' circus.
Where true love
and mystery abound!
Now where's my star?
- (TRUMPETS)
- Ah, Dumbo!
How's your bath?
Too warm? Too cold?
Ladies, make sure his wrinkles
don't get wrinkles.
In our country,
legend tells us
the gods can
take animal forms.
Champagne for Dumbo!
No booze near the baby!
(TRUMPETING IN DISTANCE)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
(HORN HONKING)
Sorry, Dumbo.
It's not your momma.
Take Dumbo back inside.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Ladies and gentlemen,
please make way
for the emperor
of enchantment.
For the architect of dreams.
For the Columbus
of Coney Island.
Mr. V.A. Vandevere!
(PEOPLE GASP)
(APPLAUSE)
And traveling with him,
his bright shining star.
Colette Marchant,
the Queen of the Heavens!
MAN: Miss Marchant!
Miss Marchant!
(APPLAUSE)
Ah.
Signore Medici!
He knows who I am.
We were just
passing through Missouri...
and we heard you were
putting on a little show.
Mr. Vandevere. It's an honor.
No, sir. The honor is mine.
MAX: I would like
to offer you a drink.
But I'm all out of bourbon.
- (GRUNTING)
- (RATTLING)
And cognac and scotch.
- (CHITTERING)
- (MAX YELPS)
- Not now!
- (MUFFLED CHITTERING)
(FAINT RATTLING)
Is that a monkey in your desk?
Just for emergencies.
Look, Mr. Vandevere...
I probably should tell you...
the elephant is not for sale.
Dumbo will only fly
for the Medici circus.
That's assuming he is real.
See for yourself.
And all due respect,
I don't got all day.
- Pleasure to meet you...
- Excuse me.
Hello there.
So this, uh,
creature of yours...
is supposed to fly?
Trade secrets.
(CHUCKLES)
Ugh.
(SNIFFING)
VANDEVERE: Uh, Max,
if you don't mind my asking...
where did you
come upon the animal?
He hails from the far east.
How far?
Far.
He doesn't look
like "magic" to me.
Well, what the heck can you
tell by appearances, right?
And you train
flying elephants, too?
Yeah, it's a little hobby
on the side.
It's the kids taught Dumbo.
Ah, yes.
Yeah?
And how on earth
did you do that?
With the scientific method.
(EXCLAIMS)
One picture, one picture!
Max.
You possess something
that's very rare in life.
And the tragedy of it is,
is you don't even know
that you have it.
Do you know what it is
that you have, Max?
No.
It's mystique.
VANDEVERE:
Max, I know your type.
Charlatan, con man,
opportunist...
New York is that way,
in case you need directions.
And I know it comes
from a deep desire
to build something
authentic and true.
I know your game.
It's not a game.
Some men cheat the rules,
others change them.
It's up your sleeve.
It's in your pocket.
The secret to show business
is always keep a rabbit
in your hat.
Or a monkey in your desk,
I guess.
MAX: Ownership shares?
Max, look around you.
Your entire way of life
is dying.
The future
of the entertainment business
is to bring
the audience to you.
And I've built
that destination.
What I'm lacking...
is a protégé.
I know
there's no Medici Brothers.
You probably always
wanted one.
You're offering me
a partnership?
Yes.
And a home.
For you and the entire troupe.
A home?
For all of us?
Yes. Join me.
Join me and my family.
Let me take us all
into the future.
Let me take us all...
to Dreamland!
(BAND PLAYING)
I wish Momma
could've seen this.
Well, somehow,
I think she knows we're here.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Way to work your magic, Max.
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
We hear you, Dumbo!
Why won't you
let him see outside?
Remember, young lady...
mystique.
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING)
Now this is why
I joined the circus.
Dad.
Wonders of Science!
All right, sugar plum.
Remember, we got
a job to do here.
My daughter, she fancies
herself the next Marie Curie.
Don't ever let anybody
tell you what you can't do.
Hang on,
I wasn't saying she can't.
What is it exactly that
we do here, ma chérie?
We make
the impossible possible.
SOTHEBY: And that's where
you'll perform.
The Colosseum!
Dumbo will stay
in the training tent behind.
JOE: Dumbo!
(TRUMPETS)
Why aren't we going with him?
Because that is your new home.
JOE: Wow!
Look at this place!
A library...
"And the children
shall lead them."
We're grateful for the
opportunity, Mr. Vandevere.
Oh, your family's mine.
- (HORSE NEIGHS)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
You know, I've been brushing
up on your story, Mr. Farrier.
Kentucky's top trick rider.
Well, there's no reason
you can't be again...
only here,
you'd be Captain Farrier...
war hero.
(FANFARE PLAYS)
One-armed wonder.
National treasure.
HOLT: Wow!
(STAMMERS)
Well, I still can ride.
VANDEVERE: Oh, I know you can.
And you're going to.
Right after you get
that little elephant
off the ground for me.
You mean
once his act's working?
You're back in the saddle.
We're still working
on the schedule
for the rest of your troupe...
but on Friday...
we premiere our little Dumbo.
I get goose bumps.
Why are you looking at me?
Well, because the only thing
more amazing
than a flying elephant...
is the goddess who can fly it.
Have you lost your mind?
(SCOFFS)
Let's not forget from
whence we came, darling.
So, we fly Friday!
Uh, Dumbo's never flown
with anyone.
That's why it's become
abundantly clear
why we need you.
MILLY AND JOE: Dumbo!
(TRUMPETS)
- Hey, buddy.
- We missed you. You all right?
Hey. Captain Farrier
is in charge.
No one sees the animal
without his approval.
Holt.
Just call me Holt.
I thought you were
a military man.
Nice boots you bagged there.
What are they, shark skin?
(CHUCKLES) No.
So you better keep
your elephant friend
on my good side.
Hiya, Dumbo.
Dumbo, you mind?
Can I get my arm?
And these are the hands
I'll be putting my life in?
Welcome.
For the record,
this was not my idea.
Dumbo works alone.
So do I.
Bonjour, Milly, Joe...
And you...
(HUFFS)
Hmm, charming.
Well, maybe he doesn't
recognize you
without your makeup.
So I gotta teach you to fly?
I know how to fly,
ever since I was a child.
They taught Dumbo to fly, no?
So I don't need
your expertise.
HOLT: All right.
Well, just so you know,
I've been to France.
It wasn't a good experience.
COLETTE: Show me your secret!
How on earth
does your elephant fly?
Well, first,
he needs a feather.
He won't fly
without a feather.
Well then, neither will I.
(SNIFFING)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(SHRIEKS)
(TRUMPETS)
Whoa, slow down, princess.
Safety first.
Guys, nets.
Come on, hurry.
All right, guys, good.
- See, Dumbo?
- (DUMBO TRUMPETS)
I fly!
See if you can catch me!
Here, Dumbo!
(SNIFFING)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(DUMBO TRUMPETING)
(SNIFFING)
Oh, we got some work to do.
- (MACHINERY WHIRRING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Friends and colleagues...
let's give a warm
Dreamland welcome
to our new executive
vice president...
Mr. Max Medici.
Anything he needs,
anything at all...
make it happen
as you always do.
This is Miss Verna.
She will handle your schedule,
correspondence,
and all your calls.
When you're needed
in meetings,
she'll let you know.
Are there meetings today?
I'll let you know!
(TYPEWRITER DINGS)
MAX: Uh, Mr. Vandevere,
one question.
Exactly what do I do?
(MUMBLES)
HOLT: So where'd
Vandevere find you?
I was a street performer
in Paris.
He discovered me.
And here I am.
A millionaire's girlfriend.
That's a tough break.
It's all for show.
So you and he,
you're not, uh...
I'm one of many gems he wears
to reflect the light
back onto him.
Huh.
Good boy, Dumbo.
- MILLY: Good job.
- Yeah! They're gonna love him.
I think you are the lucky one.
JOE: Well done, Dumbo.
MILLY: Good boy.
(SINGSONGY)
Who's been dreaming
like I've been dreaming?
So, how's everything?
- Good?
- Oh, we're making progress.
But he ain't quite ready yet.
What's the problem?
Doesn't the animal trust you?
- It's not that simple.
- Ma chérie...
we've already sold
all the tickets.
Maybe our little
scientist here
can show us
that it's going to work.
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
MILLY: Prepare for takeoff.
- Right wing?
- Check!
Left wing?
Check!
Take her up, Dumbo.
Let's go.
JOE: Come on, buddy. Come on.
MILLY: Come on, Dumbo.
That's it. Come on.
(TRUMPETING)
- MILLY: Let's try it again.
- (TRUMPETS)
You got this.
Here you go.
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
You beautiful
one-armed cowboy.
You've made me a child again.
(FANFARE PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER:
Welcome to the Colosseum...
where the impossible
is possible.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
TRIUMPHANT MUSIC)
Buonasera. Max Medici.
I discovered the elephant,
my elephant.
And basically I said no.
I walked out
and that was the end of that.
MAX: The flying
elephant's mine.
VANDEVERE: Yeah.
You're the guy!
You're the guy that's
made out of magic dust!
VANDEVERE: Max.
J. Griffin Remington.
Atlas Forge Bank.
He's the money man.
The J?
Whoa! It's a pleasure
to meet you.
How are you?
You know, they say the moon
is made out of magic dust.
That's why
they're going to send
a man up there
one of these days.
And my bank is
going to be the bank
that finances the expedition.
What do you think of that?
Uh-huh.
VANDEVERE:
Needless to say, Max...
we all have high hopes
for tonight.
Oh, yeah. High hopes.
High hopes.
Well, you know,
hopes, and dreams,
that's one thing.
That's words.
But what we're talking
about here is facts!
Plans!
Plans! That takes
a lot of money.
Which he hasn't got!
So, we are hoping
that your pachyderm
comes through with the goods.
Now let's get this show
on the road!
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
MAN: We are looking good!
HOLT: Don't worry, Big D.
There's just more room to fly
out there, that's all.
Round and round,
just like we practiced.
JOE: And then Dad can talk
to Vandevere about the deal!
HOLT: About the what?
We made a deal with Dumbo.
We promised we'd buy
his mom back
with all the money
he makes for the circus.
That's why he flies.
- Joe, not now!
- Are we ready?
Yeah.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
HOLT: Okay, let's go.
Okay, Dumbo, let's do this.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUEALS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Pink elephants?
So?
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(APPLAUSE STOPS)
(FEEDBACK WHINES ON MIC)
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls of all ages!
This is the moment
we've all been waiting for!
V.A. Vandevere,
in association
with Max Medici...
proudly presents,
making his Dreamland debut...
You've seen a horse-fly.
You've seen a dragonfly.
You've even seen a housefly.
But you haven't
seen anything...
until you see an elephant fly.
Let's get ready for Dumbo!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
TRIUMPHANT MUSIC)
Coming through.
Come on.
He can do it.
I know he can.
And here to welcome him...
our own Queen of the Heavens!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
ETHEREAL MUSIC)
(WHISPERS) Dumbo.
Five times around the ring.
That's all we have to do.
Nice and easy,
like we practiced.
- Dad?
- HOLT: Mmm-hmm.
Why aren't they
putting up the nets?
Hey, guys?
Guys, what's going on?
Your men are supposed
to be out there!
Change of plan. From the top.
(GASPS)
I can't see the nets.
- They're invisible.
- REMINGTON: Hmm.
What's wrong with you?
They need nets!
Colette!
Wait, don't take off!
COLETTE: Dumbo...
Oh, boy!
...Prince of the Elephants.
I command you to fly with me.
(TRUMPETS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- (YELPS)
- (TRUMPETS)
(ALL GASP)
(TRUMPETING)
- (FABRIC RIPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(TRUMPETING)
Colette!
- (SCREAMS)
- (TRUMPETS)
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- (TRUMPETING)
Lower the platform!
(TRUMPETING)
- (DUMBO TRUMPETS IN DISTANCE)
- (HOWLING)
(ROARS)
(TRUMPETING)
(TRUMPETING IN DISTANCE)
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- Fly, little one!
(ALL CHEERING)
Magic dust!
(MEN SHOUT)
(ALL MURMURING)
Where's my show?
(TRUMPETING IN DISTANCE)
The elephant's headed
to Nightmare Island.
- (DUMBO TRUMPETS)
- (WOMAN YELPS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(ROARS)
WOMAN: Come on, sweetie.
Let's go.
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
(TRUMPETING)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
(CHAIN CLANKING)
Dumbo, it's okay.
- We're here.
- (ELEPHANT HUFFS)
VANDEVERE: Good evening.
MAN: It's Mr. Vandevere.
- Hello, hi.
- Hey, that's V.A. Vandevere!
VANDEVERE:
Everyone having fun?
Good.
- Having a good time?
- MAN 2: Yes, sir.
- (GROWLS AND TRUMPETS)
- VANDEVERE: Fantastic.
Get him outta here.
- Yes.
- WOMAN: Over here!
- GUARD: Folks, please.
- Hello.
GUARD: Folks, I need you
to leave the exhibit.
- (DUMBO SQUEALING)
- Come on.
Guys, guys, go easy,
he's just a baby.
Soldier,
I give the orders here.
- (DUMBO SQUEALING)
- (TRUMPETING)
It's his bedtime.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
ANNOUNCER: (ON SPEAKER)
This attraction is now closed.
(TRUMPETING CONTINUES)
Dad?
Uh-huh.
It's Mrs. Jumbo.
BOY 1: Come on,
I want to see Dumbo!
BOY 2: I want to see Dumbo!
- MAN: I want my money back!
- (ALL GRUMBLING)
I don't understand.
The elephant flies.
You saw it.
I saw a vanishing act.
I'm not investing one cent
until I can see this works.
You can't control your animal.
You give me a little time,
I can fix this.
Whatever! Till then,
the bank is closed.
What happened up there?
You lost control
of the animal.
COLETTE: You're the animal.
Where was my net?
Nets are for rehearsal.
This is the show.
(DOOR OPENS)
Training?
You call that training?
Now, hold on, Mr. Vandevere,
we know why he flew away.
He recognized
that other elephant's call.
The one on Nightmare Island.
It's his momma!
HOLT: It's true. It's her.
She was sold from our circus
two months ago.
MILLY: Every child
knows its mother.
And they say
elephants never forget.
They can be together now.
Why are there children
in my office?
Mr. Vandevere, please,
all Dumbo wants is his momma.
Just reunite them,
and he'll do
whatever you want.
No, he'll do
whatever she wants.
You think I'd have bought her
if I thought she was
related to him? Hmm?
(SCOFFS)
Doesn't help me at all.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
You wanna know
the most important thing
about growing up?
You've got to learn
to go it alone.
Get rid of the mother.
You know where to take her.
And treat yourself
to some new boots.
But, sir,
you can't just kill her.
Why not?
HOLT: Mr. Vandevere.
Wait!
Don't separate 'em, please.
Don't do that to my kids.
You know, Holt,
when my father left us,
it was a blessing really.
Because I had to learn
how to fend for myself.
Maybe that's what
your children need.
Don't tell me
what my children need.
Best take a step back,
Elephant Man.
Darling...
Dumbo and his mom
need a little alone time.
So, Mommy's going to
take a little trip...
so that Dumbo
won't be distracted.
Milly! Milly!
Colette?
I have rehearsal.
Max.
ANNOUNCER: (ON SPEAKER)
Nightmare Island.
Milly?
Home of the most dangerous
beasts in the world.
GUARD: Sir, park's closing.
HOLT: Milly!
Milly!
Did you find her?
No.
(HOLT SIGHS)
Well, her momma always knew
what to say. No matter what.
She always knew.
Your children don't need you
to be perfect.
They just need you
to believe in them.
That simple, huh?
All right, well,
I'm gonna keep looking.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
That's my daughter all right.
The only girl I know
who runs away to go to school.
It's our fault.
Bet Dumbo wishes
he never met us.
HOLT: Ah, you showed him
he could fly.
You think
he'd ever trade that?
He would to have his mom back.
(HOLT SIGHS)
I miss Momma.
Yeah, so do I.
There's something
I want to show you.
MAN: (ON SPEAKERS)
With advances in both
engineering and medicine...
the human and the mechanical
will soon be combined...
to assist ordinary families,
workers and veterans.
All kinds
of technological marvels
await us in the 20th century.
HOLT: You're gonna do
great things.
I know it.
Whoa, whoa. What's this?
Oh, give me a break.
I gotta teach you
how to read English, too?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Oh, Max, hello!
Good, you brought
the paperwork.
Max...
I was reviewing your troupe...
and to be honest with you...
they're really pale imitations
from the acts we already have.
So I was thinking,
I don't know,
a month's severance?
Seems fair.
Capisce?
I thought you promised to...
Max, the contract says
that I'd hire them.
It never stipulated
for how long.
So, get your little band of
low-rent freaks out of here.
But they're my troupe.
They're countin' on me.
Okay, let's have a heart.
Why don't you tell them?
(MUFFLED CHATTER AND LAUGHTER)
'Bout time, boss.
So, when do we start?
HOLT: What's going on, guys?
Vandevere's fired them all.
They're to leave by tomorrow.
(DUMBO BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHIMPERS)
PRAMESH:
Goodbye, little friend.
Goodbye.
We wanted to see him
one last time.
One last time to see him fly.
I don't think
he wants to anymore.
Oh, no. But he must.
He cannot lose
Mrs. Jumbo again!
SOTHEBY: Uh, I'm afraid
it's rather worse than that.
Mr. Sotheby?
I've come
to clear my conscience.
I resigned my position as soon
as I heard him give the order.
What order?
Mrs. Jumbo will be gone
by tomorrow night.
And she's not
meant to survive.
(DUMBO WHIMPERING)
This "Dreamland"
doesn't deserve him.
No circus does.
Well, who's gonna be
willing to help me?
Set Dumbo and his momma free.
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
ANNOUNCER: (ON SPEAKER)
Welcome to the Colosseum,
where the impossible
is possible.
Okay. Second time's the charm.
Let's see if Dream Daddy's
worked out the kinks.
TRUCK DRIVER: (ON PHONE)
Here to pick up the elephant
- from Nightmare Island?
-Confirmed.
Unlock the back gates.
- Dumbo in position!
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Soon as he flies,
you run back to his tent
and I'll find you there.
All right, Big D.
(SQUEALING)
HOLT: It's all up to you now.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Come on, Holt!
(OBJECT THUDS)
- To hell with it.
- (CLATTERS)
MAN: Ready for positions.
We could have used
a little rehearsal.
Rehearsal?
Think we got a rehearsal
at the Battle of the Argonne?
You sure you can do this?
I fly elephants all the time.
Are you sure you can do this?
With one hand
tied behind my back.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
GUARD: Wait. What's that?
Ma'am?
Sorry, ma'am,
attraction's closed.
My dream... to be a mermaid...
and now they've taken it away.
And yet I hear
the water singing.
I hear them beckoning me home.
Lady, just be careful, okay?
MISS ATLANTIS: Return me
to the vast abyss!
Let's go.
- My destiny, the sea!
- Okay.
(GUARD YELPS)
(GRUNTS)
(BARS CREAKING)
(GAS HISSING)
(BARKING)
We've lost power!
Even the cages?
- GUARD 1: But the animals...
- (GROWLING)
Find the breakers.
Get the lights back on!
And make sure
those cages are locked.
(WOLF HOWLING)
(ANIMAL SCREECHES)
(ANIMAL GROWLING)
- (GASPS)
- (HISSING)
BARITONE BATES: (ON SPEAKERS)
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls.
Making his second
Dreamland debut.
Let's get ready for Dumbo!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
TRIUMPHANT MUSIC)
(ANIMAL GROWLING)
(HOWLING)
(ROARS)
(DISTANT SCREECHING)
(DISTANT GROWLING)
- (HOWLING)
- (SCREECHING)
(GROWLING)
(ANIMAL ROARS)
(KEYS JANGLING)
Hey!
(HOWLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
It's a trick!
Get back to the...
(TRUMPETS)
(GUARDS GRUNT)
And once again, our very own
Queen of the Heavens!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
ETHEREAL MUSIC)
You.
Where is
your circus of freaks?
What's going on?
The elephant's mother is gone!
His troupe's behind it!
Alert the tower
and secure the gates.
Don't let them get out.
But why would they
only take the one?
Keep your eye on Farrier
and those kids.
You! Come with us.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
There they are!
SKELLIG: Hey!
(MUFFLED THUMPING)
(GRUNTING)
GUARD 1: Hey, you!
What are you doing up there?
GUARD 2:
That's private property.
Come on! Get down here!
Now!
Hey, I'm Max Medici,
Vandevere's partner.
He's just a maintenance man
fixing a light!
Get back to your posts!
Yes, sir, Mr. Medici.
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERING)
Let's try this again.
You and me.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, the kids?
Where are the kids?
Hey, have you seen the kids?
COLETTE: Dumbo,
Prince of the Elephants!
I command you to fly with me.
(WHISPERING)
Dumbo, please fly.
Do it for your momma.
(TRUMPETING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(BOTH GASP)
- (DUMBO TRUMPETS)
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
Where's your father?
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
- Dumbo!
(TRUMPETS)
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Hey! Get those kids!
Dumbo!
(GRUNTING)
Come on.
- There!
- (TRUMPETS)
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
Bonsoir.
Just passing through!
Hey! You can't do that!
- (TRUMPETING)
- Get the elephant!
ENGINEER 2:
You get the elephant!
(ALARM BUZZES)
(SHIFTING GEARS)
(GRUNTS)
Don't worry.
Dad'll be here soon.
SKELLIG: Where's the elephant?
(BOTH GASP)
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
Why are you
just standing there?
Get to the tower!
Electricity's failing!
There's no elevators!
When I last checked,
they invented stairs.
ANNOUNCER: (ON SPEAKERS)
We seem to be experiencing
some technical difficulties.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
What happened to my power?
- (TRUMPETS)
- What power, mon chéri?
You ungrateful...
You were nothing
before I made you my... Uh...
I believe the word is "queen."
I need lights!
(ALARM BLARING)
Mr. Vandevere, wait!
We have to reset the mains,
or you could cause a surge!
Right now it's impossible!
Nothing's impossible! (GRUNTS)
Mr. Vandevere!
Mr. Vandevere, stop!
(GRUNTING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Milly! Joe!
(NEIGHING)
Come on. Go!
Come on!
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
- (ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
- Get everyone out!
Evacuate the park!
Milly! Joe!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
SKELLIG: Hey!
Where is the elephant?
- JOE: Let her go!
- (SKELLIG GROANS)
- (JOE GRUNTS)
- (HORSE NEIGHS)
(SCREAMING)
- (HOLT URGES HORSE)
- (CONTINUES SCREAMING)
MILLY: Come on!
Milly! Joe!
JOE: Dad!
- You all right? All right?
- MILLY: We're fine.
Okay, come on.
All right, cover your faces.
Give me your hand!
Come on!
Back!
Stay close.
(MRS. JUMBO TRUMPETS)
Come on, everybody.
Let's get to the seaport!
Now!
- Where are the Farriers?
- They must still be inside.
(TRUMPETS)
Dad!
MILLY: It's okay, Joe.
(HOLT GRUNTS)
Come here. Come here.
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
Dumbo!
(TRUMPETING)
JOE: Dumbo!
Come on!
- Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Jump!
Come on. Come on.
(TRUMPETS)
- All right, let's go.
- Stay close, come on.
Okay. Go! Go! Go!
Come on!
JOE: Dumbo!
HOLT: Come on!
JOE: Dumbo! What's wrong?
HOLT: Guys! Milly! Joe!
Come on!
JOE: Dumbo, let's go!
HOLT: Go!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Dumbo!
Get him!
He's seen us.
Dumbo, you gotta go.
They're comin' for you.
You gotta go, Dumbo.
He lost the feather.
Feather doesn't do nothin'.
Dumbo, you don't need
the feather to fly.
JOE: Dad, they're coming!
- (BELL DINGING)
- Stand back! Stand back!
GUARD: Out of my way!
Dumbo, remember this?
From my momma?
I can unlock any door.
And you can, too.
But I don't need
this key to do it.
And you don't need
the feather.
Come on.
(WHINES SOFTLY)
JOE: Dad!
Gotta go. Come on!
JOE: What are you doing?
HOLT: There ain't room
for the three of us.
You get him to the seaport
and I'll see you there.
Go on, Big D.
GUARD: Grab 'em!
Hey!
(SQUEALS)
- (ALL CLAMORING)
- Hey!
That's my elephant!
They're safe.
Come on, let's go!
Hey! Get back here!
(HORN HONKING)
You freak!
What have you done?
HOLT: What they pay me for,
mister.
Put on a hell of a show.
(URGES HORSE)
Hey! Him!
Right there, arrest that man.
He stole my elephant.
Hey, we had a contract,
Medici!
I'm no expert, but I think
you got bigger problems here.
- (EXPLOSION)
- (ALL GASP)
(METAL CREAKING)
Wow. This is a disaster.
Come on,
I'll buy you a hot dog.
MAX: Sounds good, J.G.
- (PEOPLE GASP)
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
Last call for cargo!
All aboard!
- (JUMBO HUFFS)
- (MAN SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
(TRUMPETING)
(TRUMPETS)
MILLY: Colette!
(SQUEALS)
Where's your father?
Don't worry.
He'll be here.
(HORSE GALLOPING)
Dad!
I knew you could ride.
(CHUCKLES)
(KIDS CHUCKLE)
- Pramesh, we have to go.
- Please, hurry.
Hurry! Come on! Hurry!
Come.
Let's go home.
Hey! (CHUCKLES)
(MILLY SIGHS DEEPLY)
Well, get out of here,
you little troublemaker.
Go on.
(MILLY SNIFFLING)
(JOE SNIFFLES)
(DUMBO TRUMPETS)
Ladies and gentlemen...
introducing our world-famous
flying elephant.
(PEOPLE GASP)
(APPLAUSE)
Welcome to
the Medici Family circus!
Where we believe
no wild animals
- shall be held in captivity.
- (SQUEAKING)
(MONKEY CHITTERING)
(PEOPLE GASP)
(STRAINING)
MAX: See Rongo...
the world's strongest
and most versatile man.
Meet the bewitching
Miss Atlantis...
now performing
underwater Shakespeare,
with the world's
only living merman, Puck!
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
And visit
our newest attraction,
Milly Farrier's
World of Wonders...
to discover
all the real-life amazements
that are shaping
tomorrow today!
(MACHINERY CLICKING)
Marvel at the skills
of the legendary Holt...
our cowboy of the future!
(APPLAUSE)
(NEIGHING)
(PEOPLE GASP)
And the Pearl of Paris,
Colette.
Queen of the Heavens!
(APPLAUSE)
- (ALL CHEERING)
- (HAND WHIRRING)
Friends, young and old,
you have a home at our circus.
Where anything is possible
and miracles happen.
Believe me, they do.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(TRUMPETING)
(ALL TRUMPETING)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
(TRUMPETS)
(SQUEALING)
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)