Picket One, copy.
Do you got eyes on the hostages?
Still negative.
20 bucks says they don't show.
You two morons really making bets
on whether a drug cartel
has executed these hostages?
Abso-fucking-lutely.
I believe that was implied. Yeah.
Just checking. I am in for 20.
I got two hostages.
No crosswind.
I am not waiting.
10-50 out.
Bluebill Two, are you out there?
Over.
Goddamn it!
Dupree, Jesus!
Where is Haines?
Don't know.
Comm's not fucking working.
Give me the pack.
It's evidence.
Aingt nobody gonna believe this one.
The fuck is that, Cap?
It's above our pay grade.
Haines!
Come in. Over.
Haines, goddamn it, come in.
Over!
Sir?
The fuck is that, Cap?
Comm's not fucking working.
Haines?
Light it up!
Gentlemen, remember.
They are large, they are fast,
and fucking you up,
is their idea of tourism!
Go!
Eyes up! Move!
I want the passenger.
I want the pod.
If it's not from here...
You want it.
I want it.
Hola.
I need help.
And I have money.
I need you to mail this,
for me.
You send it to this address.
Mail what's in the pack,
not the backpack.
Ahora. Go!
Ok.
Yo. Do it, man.
No, you do it.
Ok.
Do it.
Oh, shit.
Looky, looky, loo.
Hey EJ, you hungry?
I am hungry for an ass-burger.
Sounds delicious.
A nice, big, juicy ass-burger.
Oh, yeah.
What the hell are you doing?
He is a goner.
Alright.
Hi, there.
Does, Quinn McKenna live here?
His post office box payments
are past due.
Department of Defense.
He works for the government,
does he?
MOS-1-1-B-3-V-W-3.
Military designation.
He kills people...
so you can be a mailman.
Dr. Brackett?
I understand you enjoy...
stargazing?
My men will take care of your dog.
Will you come with me, please?
What am I looking at?
It's exactly what you think it is. Yeah.
They ave been here before.
'87. '97.
Lately, the visits are increasing
in frequency.
Rory, I am home!
Hey, I got you something.
Hey.
Did you do one of these after school?
I did all of them.
Ok.
Well,
I got you two options.
We have...
pirate...
or...
Frankenstein.
Frankenstein, you know, green skin?
Threw a girl to see if she would float?
No. Ok. Well, let's go with pirate.
Yeah?
This is dumb.
The guys will...
They will still be able to see.
See what?
That it's me.
You were once quoted as saying,
I dropped from my mother's womb,
I hit the floor,
and I started crawling through hostile
territory toward my grave.
About right, yeah.
That's badass.
It's pretty morbid.
It's pretty dark.
What's with the..
Polygraph?
I thought this was a psych eval.
We need to know if you pose a threat.
I am a sniper.
Isn't posing a threat kind
of the fucking point?
You spend most of your time
now in country...
estranged from your wife and son?
Look, I get it.
Something went down in Mexico
and nobody wants any witnesses.
Excuse me?
You are not here to find out if I am crazy.
You wanna make sure the label sticks.
So, you feel you are being railroaded?
I can see the tracks on the floor!
I don't see tracks on the floor,
for the record.
You feel like you are a stranger
on your own planet,
don't you, Captain?
Like an alien, you mean?
That's what you wanted.
Do I get a cookie now?
He saw something.
Yeah.
You shove me again,
I am gonna break your neck.
Did I say that out loud?
Look... McKenna.
Last one.
Thanks for your kindness.
Thank you.
Yeah?
You alright over there?
No, don't worry about him.
He is just got Tourettes.
He can't control it.
Fuck you Coyle.
You get used to it, bro.
Welcome to Group Two.
Yeah? What's that?
Like a unit?
No, group. Group Two.
Group therapy, room two.
McKenna.
Nebraska Williams.
That's your real name?
Gaylord.
That's a good call, then.
Yeah, I thought so.
Where did you serve?
Operation Enduring Freedom, '03.
Went for the Taliban,
stayed for the opium.
That's Coyle.
Friendly fire incident.
Got turned around,
fired at one of his own vehicles.
Now, he tells jokes.
That's Lynch.
Got a medal for blowing up
half a mountain in Mosul.
Entropy.
That's my game.
Things like to fall apart,
and I...
make it happen.
Just... Just like that.
Hey.
Hey. Don't.
Don't.
That's Nettles.
Ok, I am Nettles.
Did three tours flying Hueys.
He loves his Bible.
Hey, Netty?
Is it end times yet?
Yeah, laugh all you want.
But when you are standing at
attention before your Maker.
I always stand at attention
before I make her.
God makes shitty people.
Yeah.
I mean, why do you think
people make war?
Why, Baxley?
Why do we make war?
Come on, Baxley!
Because fuck-cock-cock!
Because we fuck cock-cock?
Yes, we fuck cocks.
That's it, because we fuck cocks,
that's why.
We get upset.
How did you snag a ticket
on this shit mobile?
Put a bullet in a CO.
Any particular reason?
He was an asshole.
Keep your head down.
Here, throw this on.
Is it just your imagination?
Or is this haunted room
actually stretching?
Every fucking time?
Your attention, please.
The GRC meeting has been moved
to section 3, room A.
There you are!
Welcome.
I am Sean Keyes.
I heard you basically wrote the book
on evolutionary biology.
I am. I am sorry, can I just...
Is that?
Oh, my God!
Holy shit.
That's alien technology.
This is what you brought me here to see?
Well, yeah.
Can I...
Can I see this?
Can I get into this?
Doc.
Let's go.
Everything good?
Yes, sir.
What is it?
Dr. Brackett.
Would you like to meet a Predator?
Come on.
Please observe decontamination protocol.
So, how did they rope you into this?
I wrote a letter to the president
when I was six.
Told him how much I loved animals and,
that if NASA ever found a space animal,
they should call me.
Couple years ago,
I was put on a short list for a...
paper I wrote on hybrid strains.
Computer cross-referenced
the letter and...
here I am.
Dr. Brackett.
Thanks for coming.
I am sure you have questions.
Just two, actually.
Ok.
Why do you call it the Predator?
It's a nickname.
You know, the data suggests
that it tracks its prey.
Exploits weakness.
Seems to...
well enjoy it.
Like a game.
That's not a predator,
that's a sports hunter.
Sorry?
A predator kills its prey to survive.
I mean...
what you are describing...
is more like a bass fisherman.
Well, we took a vote.
Predator is cooler, right?
Fuck yeah.
Found his escape pod in Mexico.
Still looking for the ship he came in.
He is heavily sedated.
You are one beautiful motherfucker.
I am gonna guess your second
question is, why are you here?
Our test results yielded
something a little...
odd.
Is this a joke?
We ran the genome sequence ten times.
This specimen has...
Human DNA?
Yeah.
Look, we know about spontaneous speciation.
Mostly plants and insects, but...
But some mammals,
sheep, goats...
Yeah.
The red wolf is known to be a hybrid
between the coyote and the Grey wolf...
Or possibly some form of
recombinant technology...
Guys, guys, guys.
I get it, I get it.
You wanna know
if someone fucked an alien?
Yeah.
Ok, it's got some kind of
atmospheric mask,
bio helmet and...
What are these?
Like, some kind of wrist gauntlets?
Exactly.
So, where is the helmet
and the other gauntlet?
We have looked, believe me.
Who is this?
He made first contact with the Predator.
Great.
I would like to talk to him.
Well, he is...
he is being evaluated, so...
Ok. Well, before you lobotomize him,
I would like to ask him a few questions.
We have a request to reroute.
Read you five-by-five. Destination?
Starkweather Dam.
Proceed at once.
You will be met by military personnel.
Over.
Hey, Baxley!
Question for you.
Alright, here we go.
How do you circumcise
a homeless man?
Here it comes.
Kick your mom in the chin.
Fuck your mother.
Shut the fuck up!
Alright.
You shut the fuck up.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
You all going too fucking much.
I just wanna know
who this motherfucker is.
Why are you here?
Come on man this...
is the loony bus.
Look at this motherfucker.
Loonies! Yeah.
Loonies.
I had a run-in with a space alien.
Shit!
No, let him...
Ok, that guy wins.
That's the best story I have ever heard.
Classic story...
That's the winner right there.
Fucking hell.
Would you shut the fuck up?
They want to put a lid on it,
so here I am.
Stuck in Group Two.
The sequel to Group One,
only stupider.
Give this man a fucking cigar.
Shut the fuck up.
Would you shut the fuck up?
It's a conspiracy.
The goddamn space aliens?
What are yo doing down there, Rory?
Just...
playing games.
Well, dinner is getting cold.
Major?
Weird-ass bogey, sir.
One second it's on the grid,
the next it's ghosting.
Damn it.
We need something in the air.
Get me NORAD.
I feel like I am missing
something in the research.
There is something I am just not seeing.
Look, if this is the blood.
Ok, I think...
can you just tell me what that is?
Because I was trying to get into this
earlier, but somebody stopped me.
He gave me the hairy eyeball.
That guy actually.
Hold that thought.
NORAD is reporting a 202 anomaly,
possibly heading our direction.
Is it coming here?
God, I hope not.
Holy shit!
How far away are we talking about?
Unknown.
But it's definitely heading your way.
Level two alert.
Shit!
Hey, what's happening?
Proximity alert.
Bogey is inbound.
Range 200 miles.
Lock it down.
He is awake!
He is awake! He is awake!
Hey!
Hey, hold him down!
Keep him down!
Hold him down!
Oh, shit!
Doc, on me, now!
Move! Move!
Church, Thomas, J.
Move!
Please observe decontamination protocol.
Chamber secure.
Remove outer garments.
Church, Thomas, J.
Please observe decontamination protocol.
All personnel, Code Orange.
Code Orange.
This is not a drill.
Sit tight.
There is been a breach.
Do you have an estimate?
Not right now.
I will give you cover fire.
Get him out!
Movement, twelve o'clock!
Hey. Hey.
Don't let him get away.
Not my space animal.
What the fuck?
Alien.
Your green boy?
Yep.
Goddamn space aliens.
What? What?
Did you not just fucking see that, man?
Am I going fucking mad?
Hey.
Shut up.
Take it easy, man.
I didn't fucking see it.
Nettles, be quiet.
Where the fuck is it?
I wanna see it.
That's the thing that killed my men.
Yeah, they will do that.
We got to get off this thing.
We got to move.
Brother, it's a bus.
It moves.
Hey, Baxley!
If your mom's vagina were a video game,
it would be rated E for Everyone.
Hey!
Knock it off.
What's the difference between
five big black guys and a joke?
Baxley's mom can't take a joke.
What, motherfucker!
Come on, bitch!
Everyone on the floor, face down!
Face down! Now!
Come on!
Keys!
Gun!
Hey! Nettles! Nettles!
Wait, hey! Hey!
You got him, alright?
You got him, brother.
Hey Nebraska, you mind making a detour?
What, for your green boy?
I am a sniper, just get me close, baby.
You wanna kill him?
Oh, yeah!
Why didn't you just say so, man?
You are gonna kill a fucking alien?
Hold on.
Fuck!
Yo, what the fuck is that?
Easy, easy. Hey! Hey!
Hey.
Take cover!
Behind the fucking bus!
Hey! Come on. Come on, I got you.
I got you, lady.
Ok.
Let's go! Hey.
Come on, come on.
Come on. Goddamn it.
Sorry.
Move!
Damn.
Get to the choppers!
Stargazer, I got eyes on the woman.
Instructions?
Eliminate her.
Hey.
Retrieve any contraband.
Roger that Stargazer.
That's it, that's it, girl.
Hey Nebraska!
Got it.
Everything ok back there?
You fucking guys.
We found the one place to hide out
where we don't look crazy.
It's been a long time since
I had a gun in my hand.
What's it feel like?
Like a gun.
Hey, you think she is safe
in there with them?
The girl?
They are soldiers, man.
Sleeping ladies? No, bro.
Sit down.
Here.
It's the end of times?
Worst thing about the end times...
they never fucking are.
So...
did he live?
Say again?
The CO? The asshole you shot,
did he live?
Yeah.
He did.
Yeah, and where is he at now?
You are shitting me.
I missed.
Why did you do that?
Miss?
No, shoot yourself.
Doctors asked me the same thing.
Walked to the hospital
with a bullet in my skull.
Good times.
Hey.
Should I be worried?
Probably.
There we go.
Did you get that?
That's too close to her hand.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
But then she's gonna drop that there.
Guys!
What the hell are you doing?
What is all that shit?
We are trying to make her
feel comfortable.
Come on.
She is gonna wake up and see a
bunch of motherfuckers. Come on.
What are you doing?
Nettles! Nettles!
Move!
Get out of there!
Morning, sunshine.
I really wish people
would stop calling me that.
Chill, hey!
I told you she would grab it. Ten bucks!
Pay up.
Fuck it, fuck it.
Where is my phone?
You are not gonna need that.
That's not cool.
It's ok.
I said it's ok.
Give me the gun.
No. No.
She pulled.
Shit, I told you she
would pull the trigger!
I should have bet you that time!
I like her. I like her.
I like her.
I like her. I like her a lot.
Give me that, ding-dong.
Shit! Attagirl.
What? You are a scientist?
What they got you working on?
You are not gonna last a day out there!
What you think, you are special?
Back at the dam, they were gonna
put a bullet in your head.
They were gonna shoot her?
Yes.
I am sorry.
Get out of the way.
See you around.
Eat your pussy.
Wait, what?
How you doing?
No, you just said, Eat your pussy.
Hey...
How you doing?
No, you said, Eat my pussy.
What the fuck is wrong with him?
I said you are pushy.
He said you are pushy.
No, you said, Eat your pussy.
No. I said, Sheesh! You are pushy!
No, you said, Eat my pussy.
No, that's what he said, I heard it.
He said... pushy.
What the fuck?
Which is also fucking rude.
He doesn't mean your pussy
in particular.
You are insane, right?
Are you fucking insane?
Probably.
Well, what's it gonna be?
Maybe.
He is fucking crazy.
Fuck you, Baxley.
I feel fine.
They were gonna shoot me?
Why?
Maybe because of...
this?
Well, I guess I am in.
Stay the fuck away from me.
What the fuck is this?
What is this?
What is that? Like a unicorn?
A unicorn.
It's a unicorn.
I made a unicorn.
I, hey, its...
I am sorry, it's a piece of shit.
So...
what's the upside to me
staying here with you guys?
Maybe staying alive?
We are soldiers.
We are the good guys, ok?
Well, that's debatable.
I read your file. The...
The guys in Mexico it killed?
They yours?
They are gonna need a patsy for that.
You are looking at him.
Yeah, I figured.
Ex-sniper with PTSD?
That's actually kind of perfect.
How about you telling us,
what you were doing in a secret base.
Surrounded by trained soldiers.
Mercs.
I am a biologist,
and they have me on
call in case there is...
contact.
What did I tell you?
End days. End days.
Nettles, if you don't stop
with this Bible shit,
I am gonna set you on fire.
Guys, if we wanna keep breathing,
we need to find this thing.
Expose it.
It's called the Predator.
It hunts people for sport.
Technically, that's not a predator.
That's like...
Thank you.
It's a hunter.
I said the same thing.
I said the same thing, a sportsman.
A hunter or a fisherman.
Well, look at you...
I was there when it escaped.
It's looking for something.
Equipment. Weapons.
I took its gear.
What?
You took something from the thing?
So, I would have evidence.
I think I know where it's going.
What?
Hi, honey, you are home.
I am looking for a package.
A package?
Rory!
Hey!
This is not your house anymore!
Rory!
Hey, buddy.
Where are you?
He is not here.
What do you mean, he is not here?
Shit!
What? So we ordered some video games.
No! No! No! No! No!
The whole fucking reason
I sent it to a P.O. box,
was so I didn't put you in danger.
Goddamn it, we need to find him.
Wait Quinn, you are scaring me now.
I specifically said no first-person
shooter. No combat games.
Did you ever think that maybe he plays
them to connect with his father?
Oh, my God.
We are doing this again.
Hey! Can you stop taking all my...
Who are these people in my house?
Emily, loonies.
Loonies, Emily.
Good evening.
The brushstrokes on this are really
dynamic. It's a wonderful piece.
Ok, you need to put that down.
What exactly is she doing
with her right hand?
They are my unit.
They are soldiers.
Marines. There is his unit.
Hi. You seem like a really nice...
No, don't touch me. No.
Hang on. Back up.
Your unit?
What happened to Haines and Dupree?
They are dead.
And the thing that killed them
is out there looking for Rory.
What are you talking about?
There is something out there.
It tore my friends apart.
What is it?
Is is like...
it's like a creature.
Seriously, it's not a person.
Like from the Bible.
Revelations.
From the Bible?
That's the most ridiculous
thing I have ever heard.
It's a space alien.
Know who Whoopi Goldberg is?
It's like an alien Whoopi Goldberg.
Oh shit!
Shit.
I want a grid search.
Three teams.
Hey!
No.
No, no, I am coming with you.
No nix that.
Is there a problem?
Thing is, we are kind of moving targets.
Yeah, in case you have not
noticed, we are fugitives.
Yeah. Plus, like where are we
gonna get our meds and stuff?
I get it. Fine, stay here and watch TV.
You know what?
If you try to split?
Or draw the Feds?
Or if you jeopardize my son
by your half-assed yardbird bullshit
I will come back here, and I will happily
kill every single fucking one of you.
Come on brothers. Let's go.
Seriously?
It's not our fight.
Is your husband the man I think he is?
Excuse me?
Tell me about your husband, please?
He is a security counter-sniper.
Army Rangers.
He supervised,
23 close precision engagements
across five continents,
and he has 13 confirmed kills.
And he is one of only 14
captains in the armed forces,
to ever receive a Distinguished
Service Medal and the Silver Star.
So, he might be a lousy husband
but he is a good soldier.
Well, sounds like he can
probably take care of himself.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
That's what I thought.
Fucking pussies.
Where you going Nettles?
I didn't like your speech.
It didn't really inspire me.
But...
he called me a pussy
and nobody calls me a pussy, so...
Ok.
Fuck off, pussy.
Come on Bax, let's go.
Let's get some.
Before these army fuckers
screw up the whole thing.
Come on, what are you doing?
Let's move. Hey!
You too, lucky charms.
Coyle, you wanker.
I would like to watch TV
with you sometime.
Ok.
I liked your speech.
I liked the couch.
What's happening? What?
Well, we are finding my son, that's what.
Alright, when all this is over...
Fuck me in the face with an aardvark.
I just want to be famous.
Ostensibly,
if Forrest Gump
just read the side of the box,
it would tell him exactly
what he would get.
You are using ostensibly incorrectly.
Is this for me?
This is like the reverse of a clown car.
Alright Nebraska, let's find some wheels,
nothing flashy.
Copy.
Alright.
Find my son.
Casey, you are with me.
Let's go.
Hey, ass-burger.
What are you supposed to be?
Leave me alone.
Or what? You will wash our
hands five hundred times?
Trick or treat?
What's the matter, dude?
Here is a treat, you little shit.
I got a male juvenile.
10 to 12 years old.
Metal cast on his arm.
Yo McKenna,
do you hear that?
Ran right in front of my car.
Moving east on Woodruff.
Repeat, moving east on Woodruff.
Nebraska, you got wheels?
Yeah, I got wheels.
Something flashy.
Listen, the kid's spooked, he is rabbiting.
Where is he headed?
Where is some place he knows?
There he is.
Dad!
How you doing, buddy?
I am good.
Move! Move!
Hey, Doc, come get my kid.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Shit!
McKenna!
Take cover!
Williams!
Get the fuck out of there!
What are you doing?
Get out of there!
Shit! Oh shit!
Ok.
Doc, the dreads.
What's that all about?
I don't know.
Maybe like, like sensor receptors.
Kind of like cat whiskers.
What the...
I am getting a sample.
It's a fucking space dog.
You ok?
What, is your mom cutting your hair now?
You kidding me?
This is a once in a lifetime moment.
Shut up. Please shut up.
All I wanted was a little sample.
Please shut up.
All I wanted was
a goddamn fucking sample.
Come here.
Sample.
There you go.
Thank you. You are welcome.
Fucking space dog, man. It's a fucking...
My man, you need to...
I can't. I can't. I can't.
Get it together.
I can't do this.
Oh, my God!
Fucking hell!
Fuck!
Go now!
Please!
Rory!
Shoot him!
Hey! No! No! No! No! No!
No! No! No! No! No!
Oh, fuck, fuck. No, no, no! No!
Cock! Cock! Fuck! Dick!
Suck! Suck my cock!
Fuck! Goddamn it!
Go! Go! Go!
I got him! I got him!
Go, go, go!
On Williams! On Williams!
Hurry!
Take cover!
Move! Move!
Go! Go!
Come on!
FYI, back at Stargazer,
I was naked and unarmed,
it walked right past me.
Can you tell your kid to tone
down the psychosis, please?
Let's do this. Let's do this.
Wait and do what?
You know, we could keep running,
or we give him back what he wants.
What, this is it?
Oh, my God. Shit.
Shit.
No, no, no! Move! Move! Move!
Hey, come on.
You good?
Fucked!
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Netty, get the vehicle.
The rest of you on me.
Copy.
Move back.
No! No! No!
No!
Incoming!
What the fuck?
Come here!
Roll out! Roll out, let's go!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Move!
Move out, move out!
Move! Move out!
Let's go!
Let's move!
Come on. Let's go!
Go, go, go! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move!
Move! Move!
Come on, get in! Come on!
Good! Good! Good!
Go! Last man!
Go! Go! Go!
What's the big one?
What's the big one, Doc?
Is that like the male?
He didn't even give a shit about us.
Just wanted to kill that thing.
Quinn, you saw that, right?
Guys! Did you see that? He...
He grew an exoskeleton
under his fucking skin.
What, are they hunting each other now?
We are still sorting through it right now.
Hey, it's me.
Tell me he is ok.
He is fine.
I am going to bring him back.
It's ok, don't say anything, just be safe.
Hey!
No! Don't do that!
What?
Hello?
Damn it.
You guys fucked with the wrong family.
How tall?
Witnesses say 11 feet.
That's pretty fucking tall.
Ok.
Fucked that nigga up.
Sir?
Nothing.
I would be careful with that, sir.
You know what I think?
I think this one went rogue.
A runner.
And the big one?
He is a tracker.
Sent to take that one out.
Some kind of interstellar cops and robbers.
Now he is going after that missing ship.
And whatever is on board.
I want that fucking ship.
We are in the ballpark.
Captain McKenna's son.
Mother confirms.
He has the operating system.
Get the fuck out of here.
Thought it was a video game.
So, we find the kid, we find the ship.
What the fuck we still standing here for?
You don't want to know what that one is?
I know what it is.
Our big boy is a hunter.
He brought his dogs with him.
No, it had to be like a government
experiment or some shit like...
Like a robot or whatever.
Nettles, are you fucking retarded, man?
Use another word, would you?
Yeah, man.
Show a little sensitivity.
His son is retarded.
Here you go.
He does this from time to time.
Just give him a minute.
Hey, Lynch.
What's the deal with these two?
Coyle lit up one of his own vehicles?
Back in '09, yeah.
It was bad business. Six dead.
What, no survivors?
Yeah, there was one.
It's fucking romantic.
Are you kidding me, they are friends?
Picture it.
Military inquiries,
sitting outside courtroom,
waiting to go in,
side by side,
day after fucking day.
After fucking day.
Unbelievable.
It's the loonies.
Alright, kid.
I have talked to your mother.
She is doing fine.
Mom says you are a killer.
Well, I am a soldier.
What's the difference?
Well, when you like it,
that's when you are a killer.
Are you good?
Sorry I never grew up.
You know,
the way you wanted.
Tell you a secret.
Truth is kid,
I never grew up the way I wanted.
Are we gonna get killed?
Nope.
Come on.
I am single.
I don't know if you knew that.
No, I could tell that you are single.
We got so much
stuff in common, you know like...
You like music, I like music.
You like music, right?
Shit.
What?
This is more than spinal fluid.
What does that mean?
If I am right,
they are trying to upgrade themselves.
McKenna, I got something.
I think I know what they are up
to on Predator World these days.
You see this?
They found this in the Predator's plexus.
So, remember how I told you how
they take people's spines, right?
Yeah, for trophies.
Yes! Yes!
From the strongest, smartest,
most dangerous species
on every planet they visit.
Collecting survival traits
from the most high-end specimens.
I think they are attempting hybridization.
You are just pulling this out of your ass.
Did you not see the new Predator?
It's evolving.
Or being upgraded.
That little boy,
managed to figure out alien technology.
You know, a lot of experts say that,
being on the spectrum
isn't really a disorder.
It's actually the next step
in the evolutionary chain.
Hey, yo!
What the fuck are you...
Get the fuck away from me yo!
Casey!
Casey, get inside.
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Calm down!
Calm down! Calm down!
Casey! Look.
I think this thing is been following us,
Alright?
Move, Netty!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Space dog!
Move, Netty!
What the fuck.
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! You had your fucking chance.
Look, I am just saying,
what the fuck is it gonna do?
You know, maybe we can
use it or something?
Ok, what are we doing?
What are we doing with it?
We are gonna study it.
That's what we are gonna do with it.
What's to learn? Except Williams
sucks at shooting shit in the head.
Williams, you lobotomized him.
Ok, new rule.
No one shoots my fucking dog.
There it is.
It's official.
You were right, we can use this.
Shit.
Netty, what is that?
Everybody, tighten up.
Little man, come here.
That's an EC-130.
That's not civilian.
Shit.
Hey, hey, hey!
You are not starting
a firefight with my kid here.
There you go.
Do you wanna help?
Go get a helicopter and some pyro.
Alright! On me!
Now go!
Casey! I will be right back!
No, you won't.
Hold on. Hey. See this?
Come on. Let's go!
Let's go! Come on!
Fetch!
Where is it?
Where is what?
The device.
It goes,
right in here.
Ok, so, the first Predator,
Thing One.
Why did he come here? To Earth?
The Thing One,
as you called him,
arrived in a hijacked spacecraft.
We think there is something on it.
Something he didn't want
his enemies to have.
Wait, enemies?
Other Predators.
Like that big one.
So, he brought some what?
Gift for the human race?
I will help you find it.
We can analyze it...
Shut the fuck up!
Why are they here?
You remember a few years back
when Hostess went bust?
There was a run on Twinkies?
Snapped up from coast to coast.
Get them while they still last.
Remember?
How long before climate change
renders this planet unlivable?
Two generations?
One?
That's why their visits are increasing?
They are trying to snap up
all of our best DNA before we are gone.
Adapt themselves with it
and then move in.
We are an endangered species,
and they know it.
They thrive in a hothouse environment.
Maybe they want to move into ours.
And that dead Predator
was bringing us a way to stop them.
You have hidden this thing
before, in the mail.
So, where is it this time?
Your mother's ass.
Wait, did I say that out loud?
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
No, no, no.
That is not for you.
That is my son's files and you are
violating his privacy reading that.
Madam!
You both need to leave right now.
Madam, I don't wanna restrain you.
Really?
Well, why don't you try?
You have not found the spacecraft?
Why are we trying
to crack the entry code?
Because when we do find it,
would not it be great
if we could get into the fucking thing?
What's that?
A map.
A map to what?
Give us a clue of where this place is,
maybe we can try to get into it.
But if you don't give us
anything, we can't get in!
Hey Rory,
I am Will.
How you doing?
I understand you know
where the spaceship is.
Golf tomorrow?
Why not?
You two never read my file, did you?
What makes you say that?
Because you two morons
are making plans for tomorrow.
The worst part is,
you are making me lie to my son.
What lie did you tell him?
That I won't enjoy this.
Hey please, don't.
Look, I don't know what they told you...
Can you just wait for a second?
Just wait!
No, no, no, no, no!
No.
Jeez!
Oh, my God.
Nebraska!
Yeah?
You just kill somebody?
Well, he aingt well.
Untie my friend.
They got Rory. We got to move.
Shit, they rough you up?
Did worse on myself, back in the day.
What do you want to do with this guy?
Sorry, buddy,
that was a dumb question.
Yeah, that was a dumb question.
Casey!
Can I interest you in getting
the fuck out of here?
Getting the fuck out of here
is my middle name.
And I thought Gaylord was bad.
What? What's wrong?
Alright.
Hey!
Just let me unpack this.
You are saying my son is headed
towards a spaceship
and so is a 10-foot alien.
11, actually.
Used to be a contractor.
This thing is a hybrid?
What does that mean?
Meaning it's the Chinese menu of DNA.
Comprised of the deadliest
species in the entire...
In the entire universe, yeah?
Galaxy.
What?
Galaxy. 250 billion stars.
Why go universe? Just saying.
Jesus Tap-Dancing Christ!
That's what you asked for?
Yeah, that will do.
Saddle up!
It's the best we could do, man.
Go ahead. Go!
That's it?
Another one.
The other one!
Come on.
Let's go get my kid.
Figured something out.
I think we are gonna die.
We are gonna go hunt and fight
the what, the army?
We are not gonna fight the army.
And some fucking people from space!
You wanna talk survival?
Fine!
You yesterday, you were on a prison bus,
barking to yourself,
now you got a gun in your hand.
Who is a survivor now?
We put bullets in our head
and walk to the fucking hospital.
We are soldiers!
Nettles, what's our 20?
I can follow your boy's chopper.
I locked into its frequency.
Fence is hot!
What do you say, buddy?
You think you can get us in there?
Because I am not sure that you can.
Nice reverse psychology.
I can do that too.
Don't go fuck yourself.
That's good. Come on.
Good. Almost up and running.
Five minutes.
Right on.
It's a translator unit, Rory.
Been trying to figure out
what these bird-chirping motherfuckers
been saying since '87.
Gave the Harvard School
of Linguist is a billion-dollar grant.
Voila.
Watch your step, come on.
Goddamn kid, I don't know
where you get it from.
Put the translator into the mainframe.
Download everything.
What the hell is inside there?
It's property of Project Stargazer.
That's what the fuck it is.
Code three. Code three.
We have motion
at the south fence line.
Send a fire team to check it out.
That's my dad.
He is gonna come save me now.
Is he?
Is that what he is gonna do?
I will tell you what, buddy...
if it is your daddy,
and I truly hope that it is...
he is got to be just about the dumbest
motherfucker I have ever met.
I mean, a ranger sniper
tripping wire sensors?
He is got to be...
creating a diversion.
It's a fucking diversion.
Oh, shit!
Howdy.
What, are you gonna kill us
with a fucking tranq gun?
You took my boy, so yeah.
Told you.
Take this, son.
You out of your mind?
We literally have you surrounded.
That's why you are coming with me.
I just want the boy.
Nobody is got to die.
Dad?
From here forward.
Don't look at the dead guy.
That was pretty good.
You alright? Did I get you?
No, I am good.
Welcome back.
Fuck you. I never left.
You open your mouth,
I am gonna blow your brains
right through it.
Come on, just get behind me.
All units. They got Traeger.
They got Traeger.
Let's go. Let's go.
Just tell the to put the guns down.
Tell them!
If Captain McKenna doesn't lower his
weapon in the next 10 seconds
shoot the kid's knees out.
That work for you?
Oh, that's a really bad idea.
My guys got this place covered
on every angle.
That's a funny story.
See, I don't give a shit.
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Come on, you just give
the fucking word, man.
Five.
Oh, shit!
Come on, son!
Take them down!
Get down, sir.
Let's go, son. Go!
Come on. Come on.
Ok, take this.
You wanna vanish,
you really vanish son, you understand?
Alright, we are going home.
I promise you.
It's here.
No! No! No!
Come on,
go around the end there!
Stay on him!
Move, move, move!
You got him?
Yeah!
Stay back.
Get down! Get down!
Cease fire!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Alright.
Hey, McKenna.
Be reasonable. There is six
of you, seven of us.
Fuck!
Who taught you math?
You aingt the only
fucking sniper, white boy.
You can walk away from this, Captain.
I just want the ship.
Dad, he is lying.
Yeah.
McKenna!
I don't like this.
What's he doing in there?
It's using the translator.
Hello. I have enjoyed
watching you kill each other.
I came here to destroy this vessel.
You cannot have it.
What you can do is run.
I detect one among you
who is a true warrior.
The one called McKenna.
He will be your leader.
He will be my prize.
I offer time advantage.
Go.
What the fuck is time advantage?
Like a head start?
I am gonna wake up on a bus.
Hey!
I am coming out!
We are in.
Baxley!
Shit!
Watch where the fuck you are
throwing, dickhead.
Will do.
Ok, so we split up.
12 different directions.
McKenna's the one he wants.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
We stay together,
or it will take us one by one.
He is right. It's their MO.
Grow a dick, will you?
Nothing is starting!
Son of a bitch. He must have
hacked the vehicles.
If we can get to the helicopter,
go two klicks north.
Got you.
Hey?
When this is over, you and me,
we are gonna dance.
I got my shoes all picked out.
Alright.
Fuck.
No, no, no! Don't.
Here, boy. Fetch.
Here, boy.
Here you go.
That was a valuable weapon.
Let's go.
He will be coming for us.
Give me the goody bag.
Hey. On Halloween,
this blew up a whole house.
How do you shoot it?
You don't.
It just fires by itself
when it's being attacked.
Seriously? Oh, shit.
I heard something.
Hey, man.
That's Predator technology.
That... It's gonna come back.
You got, a catcher on the wrist.
That's gonna come back.
No!
Quiet. Quiet.
Let me see. Let me see.
My fucking hand.
Shit.
Gotta be quiet.
Moving!
No, no, no!
This way. This way. This way.
There is a clearing up ahead.
Lynch left some pyro up there.
To cover our retreat.
Let's find it and trap the motherfucker.
You guys go set it up.
We will lure him in.
Who?
You and me.
Yeah? Alright.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Come on.
Can I talk to you for a second?
What's this we shit?
What are you gonna live
forever Coyle, just calm down.
Calm down?
Me, calm down?
Yeah, Ok, thanks, twitchy.
Move, move, move!
Up here. Up, up, up.
Shit!
Ok, fuck this.
Hey! Asshole!
What the fuck was that?
It's a chance for you to survive.
Go! I got this.
That's the stupidest fucking
thing I have ever heard.
Come and get us, asshole!
Contact!
Alien!
He is coming!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Light him up!
Coyle!
Bax, no!
Traeger!
Baxley!
Die!
Shit.
Fuck.
Move, move!
Nettles!
Let's go!
McKenna.
Rory.
I love you.
Hey! I am the one you want.
Right here! Come on! You ugly...
Dad!
No!
No! No! No!
McKenna.
No! No!
I hate you, you stupid fucking...
He said he wanted me.
He said he wanted me!
No. He said he wanted McKenna.
The next step in the evolutionary chain.
Not you. Your son.
Yo, he is taking off.
No!
Come on, man.
Come on.
Let's take it down!
Come on!
Hang on!
Fuck! Nebraska!
I got you!
Dad, there is a force field
coming online. Look out!
Guys! Something is coming!
Go!
Netty!
Fuck!
Hey, hey, hey.
No, no, no! Bro!
Bro.
No.
Fuck!
Shit!
Rory!
Toss it!
What are you?
Shut the fuck up.
My unit.
Nettles.
Coyle.
I see you saw Lynch's card.
Baxley had this the whole time.
Nebraska's bad habit.
Son...
these are the ones
that no one is gonna remember.
Just us.
What do you say we put them to rest?
Captain McKenna.
Hiroshi Yamada.
Sir.
First things first.
I want to say thank you
for having such a great kid.
He loves it here.
Yeah, he is something else.
What do we got, Doctor?
Well, I assume that you know by now,
but the first Predator,
it didn't come here to hunt us.
He brought something.
Exactly.
Now, you want to hear the good news?
The cargo survived.
With some sort of fail-safe.
Before the upgrade Predator
blew up the ship,
a pod escaped.
Jettisoned.
Saved itself.
It seems that...
our boy
was not taking any chances.
He wanted us,
to have this.
What is it again you do here, exactly?
He is the world's number one
authority on cybernetics.
Hey, kiddo.
Pretty cool?
Pretty cool.
You got your own desk.
I will make sure to tell Mom.
So,
this is his gift to humankind?
Get back! Get back!
Look out!
Everyone, stand back!
Stand back!
Clear the area!
Dad, the pod sent me a message.
Rory, what's in that pod?
Don't know!
Oh shit!
It's got a name!
Name? What name?
I guess you would call it,
the Predator Killer.
Get him out of here!
Come with me. Let's go.
Get back.
Clear the area.
Eyes on it.
Whatever it is, it appears to be dormant.
I assume it needs to be...
Eyes on.
Keep your weapons trained.
Get it off!
Get it off me!
What the hell is that?
That's my new suit, bubba.
I hope they got it in a 42 long.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections June 2022