- I'm starting a new life.
Up here where it's quiet and
clean among the redwoods.
And almost no one knows me.
Poor Jerry.
I had a nervous breakdown
after he left me.
They say I'm cured now.
But I still have intrusive
thoughts.
My therapist told me that
I'm not unusual at all.
People are abused all over the
world
every day
much worse than me
and they do fine.
- Your tail light's out, Miss.
- Oh, thank you for letting me
know.
Are you gonna write me a ticket?
- I'll let you go this time,
but make sure you get it fixed.
- Thank you, Officer.
- You drive safely.
- When Jerry left me,
I devoured everything
I could about how to get your
man back.
According to the experts,
men are very fragile.
They can get crushed down if
you assert yourself in any way.
You have to be very tricky.
- Elaine?
Hi, I'm Trish.
- Hi, Trish, it's nice to meet
you.
- Oh, you're so pretty.
Oh, um, I didn't mean anything.
I'm married and everything.
- No, I didn't think anything.
- Well, let me help you with
your bags.
Is this all you've got?
- For now.
My art supplies are
being shipped over later.
- So you're an artist?
- Yes, I am.
- I'm an interior decorator.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
That's how I met Barbara.
I decorated this apartment.
It was lucky I still had the
keys.
Barbara didn't exactly
know when she'd be back.
How do you know Barbara?
- We used to dance
together in San Francisco.
- Oh, really?
Well, I hope you like the
apartment.
It's a bit garish but
Barbara wanted it that way.
She had me take all of the
colors from the Thoth Tarot deck
and she and her students did
a bunch of occult paintings
for me to hang.
She's into all that Wicca stuff.
Well, this is it.
- Oh, Trish, I love it.
It's just beautiful.
- Really?
Oh, I'm so glad.
I thought I may have overdone
it.
- Oh no, it's exactly my taste.
- You must be exhausted.
I'm sure you want to lie down.
- Actually, I was thinking
about getting a bite to eat.
Do you know of a place around
here?
- There's the Victorian Tea
Room.
We could go together, if
you don't mind the company.
- Oh, how fantastic.
Where can I freshen up?
- The bedroom is through there.
- I'll only be a moment.
- What a lovely room.
- Yes, isn't it?
I love Victoriana.
- Being here is like being
a princess in a fairy tale.
- Do you have fairy
princess fantasies, Elaine?
- Of course.
We may be grown women, but
underneath
we're just little girls
dreaming about being carried off
by a prince on a white horse.
- Yes, I suppose so.
It's ridiculous, isn't it?
- I don't think I've found
my Prince Charming yet,
but I think I found the formula.
You know, I've been
studying parapsychology
and I understand men so
much better than I used to.
If only I would have known
before what I know now.
Then Jerry would have never left
me.
- Who's Jerry?
- My ex-husband.
The day he left me was
the day that I died.
But then I was reborn as a
witch.
Barbara and Gahan brought me
back to life.
They taught me everything I
know about magic and about men.
Men are like children.
They're very easy to please
as long as we give them what
they want.
♫ I dreamed of a fairy
lady in a strange land
♫ She captured the hearts
of all the boys and men
♫ She wore a gown
♫ Of pink and purple roses
♫ It was so tra la la and so la
di da ♫
- Where were we?
Oh, men, you said we need
to give them what they want.
Well, what do men want?
- Just a pretty woman to
love and to take care of them
and to make them feel like a man
and to give them total freedom
in whatever they wanna do or be.
- But what about what we want?
How are we going to be equals
with men
if we keep catering to all of
their needs?
- I think that if you want
love, you have to give love.
Giving men sex is a way of
unlocking their love potential.
- You sound as if you'd been
brainwashed by the patriarchy.
Your whole self-worth is
wrapped up in pleasing a man.
I'll admit, I used sex to get
this,
but I'm not proud of it.
A whole world doesn't
revolve around a man's needs.
If I gave Richard sex
every time he wanted it,
I'd be a wreck.
- Poor Richard.
He loves you and he wants
you and you torture him.
You have to give a man his
fantasy.
- His fantasy?
- Yes, his fantasy.
But what I'm really interested
in
is love.
You might say I'm addicted to
love.
I wonder if all women feel that
way?
- Well, it depends on
what you mean by love.
A husband isn't a prince,
Elaine,
and life isn't a fairy tale.
We have to face that fact.
- Why?
Maybe life could be a fairy tale
if you pleased your husband
more.
- I don't
need to please Richard.
Richard loves me for myself.
- Of course.
Perhaps you did find your Prince
Charming.
- Perhaps I did.
- Guess who.
- Richard, what are you doing
here?
This tea room is for ladies
only.
- Oh, I went to visit you at
work
and Julie said you were here.
I thought we could have lunch
together.
- Well, that's very sweet,
but I've already had my lunch.
Oh, uh, Richard, this is Elaine.
Elaine, this is my husband,
Richard.
- I've heard so much about you,
- Nothing too horrible, I hope.
- On the contrary.
- Goddess, please,
send me a beautiful, sweet man
to love me as I love him.
To love me, love me,
love me,
love me.
Hi, are you Wendy?
- Yes, what can I do for you?
- I'm Elaine.
We spoke on the phone.
I make natural soaps
and candles and things.
- Elaine, right.
Thanks for coming by.
Mind if I have a look?
- Please do.
- These are nice.
Really nice.
I think these will do well in
the store.
- Then you'll take them?
- Let's start with these
and see how they do.
If these sell in the next
week or two, I'll order more.
Sound good?
- Yes, fantastic.
Thank you, Wendy.
- Sure, Elaine.
Bright blessings.
- People always
ask me why I'm a witch.
I tell them it's because I
want to have magical powers.
But it's not like it sounds.
All it is is using your
will to get what you want.
- Hi.
- It's a beautiful day.
- Yes, it is.
I love to be out in
nature on days like this.
- Oh, you like nature?
- Very much.
You seem like a nature type too.
I'll bet you like to
spend time in the woods.
- That's right.
How'd you know?
- I can just tell.
Nature is where your heart is.
City and people can get
to be too much for you.
- Whuh, that is a lot to get
from someone in a few seconds.
- I'm talented that way.
- Well, you're right about the
city.
In fact, I have a house out in
the woods
about an hour from here.
I like to go there whenever
I can to, you know,
just think and read.
- Do you take your wife up
there?
- No.
I'm not married.
- Well, you might at
least take a girl up there
once in a while.
- I do.
I do, once in a while.
- You wanna take a girl up there
now?
What do you mean?
- Well, I'm new in town
and I haven't seen much
of the nature around here.
I'll make you a nice dinner.
- Yes, okay, sure.
Uh, my car is right over there.
- Okay.
Let's go.
You know what I'd like to do
right now?
I'd like to make love
right here in the car
just like we were kids.
- Wait, wait.
You want some?
- What is it?
- Something I made.
Oh, wo, ho, ho, ho,
that is, that is strong.
- Finish it.
- No, Wayne, Wayne, stop.
Not here.
Let's go inside.
This is beautiful.
I'll start the dinner.
- Wow.
This looks delicious.
- To nature.
- This is really nice, isn't it?
I like to come up here a lot
at the end of the semester to
unwind.
- Are you a teacher?
- Yeah, I teach at the
university.
- Oh, what do you teach?
- English and French literature
with a focus on the 18th
century.
- So, you must be quite a
libertine.
- A libertine?
Why would you say that?
- Oh, you know.
All of the dangerous
liaisons, Fanny Hill stuff.
Not to mention Casanova.
- Well, there
were a lot of books written
in the 18th century.
- Well, is it true?
Are you a libertine?
- Yes I am.
I love women.
Does that bother you?
- On the contrary.
I feel strange, dizzy.
What was in that drink you gave
me?
- Organic berries, vodka,
hallucinogenic herbs.
- Hallucinogenic herbs?
Oh, baby.
You are really wild.
- Would you mind if I made
myself more comfortable?
- Not at all.
- What the hell?
Your coat.
It's so bright.
- I always line my clothing.
- You have two selves.
Dark and quiet that you show the
world.
Who do you give that to?
The rainbow?
- I give the rainbow to you.
Right now.
Oh God.
Oh, Elaine.
Look at you.
- You can make love to me now.
- Aw, okay.
- What is it, Wayne?
What is it, baby?
- Oh, Elaine, I feel so strange.
- It's all right, you're with
me, shhh.
- Elaine.
No woman has ever given
herself like that to me before.
- Life has been tough, huh?
- Yeah, in a way.
You're not like any other woman
I've met.
No games, no agendas.
You just seem to take life as it
is.
- Is there any other way to take
life?
- Well, the women I've been
with,
they all want you to make
a bunch of promises to 'em
as soon as you sleep with 'em.
But, how can you commit to someone
that you don't even know?
It's crazy.
- I know, baby.
I know.
- I never thought I wanted
to be tied down to anybody.
But it's just 'cause no
one was ever quite right.
All the women that I'm
attracted to physically
they're never bright enough.
And all the bright ones are
homely and don't arouse me.
- That seems like quite a
problem.
- It is.
I feel my whole life as a loner,
thinkin' I didn't need anybody.
But now I'm not so sure.
Oh, Elaine,
I have never felt real
love like this before.
- You're just having a
lot of emotions right now.
Elaine, I'm scared.
I'm not used to feeling
things so strongly.
I can't take it, I can't take
it.
Elaine, I'm sick.
I'm sick.
- Hey, it's all right.
I've got you.
I love you.
And I'll always be here for you.
Try to get some sleep.
- Elaine.
Elaine, where are you?
- What a pussy.
What a baby.
I thought I'd found a real man,
but he's just like a little
girl.
- Elaine!
- No one was ever there for me
when I was crying my heart out.
No one ever comforted me.
No one.
- Good morning, Wayne.
- Hi, Elaine.
- Here, drink this.
- I had such horrible dreams
last night.
- What did you dream about,
baby.
- I dreamt that I was calling
your name
and you didn't answer.
I kept calling and calling,
but I couldn't find you.
Oh, Elaine, you love me, don't
you?
- Of course, I love you.
- Oh God, oh God, Elaine.
- Are you hungry?
- I don't know what I am.
- Well, try to get some sleep.
- Elaine.
Don't leave me.
- I'm not going anywhere, baby.
I'll be right here.
Wayne, wake up.
It's late.
Wayne.
Wayne, baby, wake up.
Wake up.
Wayne.
- Tampons aren't gross.
Women bleed and that's a
beautiful thing.
Do you know that most men have
never even seen a used tampon?
Part of me can be with Wayne
now.
Always.
I don't really mind death.
I've buried people before.
People I really cared about.
In the end we're all just
compost anyway.
Everything regenerates.
I'd like to come back as a cat.
I've been so depressed since my
cat died.
His name was Greymalkin,
but he was black and white.
He was my best friend.
- I give the rainbow to you.
Right now.
Just a minute.
Oh hi Trish.
Come on in.
- Hey, Elaine.
You look gorgeous.
I love what you've done with
your hair.
- Thank you.
What's up, honey?
- Well, I haven't been able to
reach you,
so I thought I'd come over
to see if everything was all
right.
- I'm fine.
Really.
Can I offer you something?
I just made some tea and cake.
- Just tea, thank you.
- Cream and sugar?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
So, what have you been so busy
with?
A man, I hope.
- Yes, it was a man.
But, it didn't work out.
- I'm Sorry.
- Yes, it's a shame
and I really liked him.
I thought that he was the one.
- Well, maybe next time.
- Are you sure you won't have
some cake?
- Oh, no, thank you.
I just came over to check up
on you and to say good bye.
- Good bye?
Why, where are you going?
- Oh, just to Dallas for
a furniture convention.
- Is Richard going with you?
- No, it's just a business trip.
Richard will have to fend
for himself for awhile.
- Sam, give me two whiskeys on
the rocks.
- Sure thing, Jane.
Did you see the papers today?
- No, why?
- They found a body in the Eel
River.
- A murder?
- Maybe.
They found a symbol carved in
his chest.
Here.
- It's a pentagram.
- It's them witches again.
- That's what I was thinking
too, Lyle.
- So yeah, Barbara, that's
everything.
After Jerry died, the cops
wouldn't stop harassing me.
They couldn't prove anything.
They actually thought that I
killed him.
Can you believe it?
Anyways, San Francisco got
to be a really bad trip
after you left.
That's when I remembered you
had that extra apartment.
- Well, it was perfect timing.
I'm just sorry I wasn't here to
greet you.
That's all right.
Trish has been lovely.
And I've been getting
a lot of artwork done.
But I had this experience last
weekend
that really shook me up.
- Why, what happened?
- Well, I met this great-looking
guy.
And I used love magic on him.
Then he got really weird on me.
All these emotions started
flowing out of him.
Then he got really
sick.
- Well, guys can't handle
their emotions too well.
That's why they don't
like heavy conversations.
It was probably just too much
for him.
All the love and the great
sex that you were giving him.
- I guess that's what it was.
But, I don't know.
- Honey, you have to be more
careful.
Maybe you shouldn't be
messing with love spells
in the first place, you know.
- Merry Meet, Elaine.
- Bright blessings Gahan.
- I heard you discussing love
spells.
You do have to be careful,
Elaine.
Love spells never work the
way you think they will.
But on a lighter note, it's
wonderful to see you, Elaine.
What's it been now, a year?
We must celebrate this
reunion of dear friends.
Thank you, Goddess, everywhere,
for the blessings that we share.
- Blessed be, Hurrahya!
- Go home, witches.
Go home.
- Just ignore them.
They're always giving us
trouble.
- I didn't know this town
was hostile to witches.
- Well, it's certainly not San
Francisco.
But it's not bad for a small
town.
Not all of them embrace our
methods
of practicing witchcraft.
But, I don't see why we
ought to be so uptight now.
Back in the day, we all made
love freely
and put up Baphomet posters
and no one was dogmatic
about whether they were a witch
or a Satanist or a Thelemite
or a Druid or a Wiccan or
whatever.
And it was fun.
But our classes and circles
have been very popular.
- What have you been teaching?
- Let's see, I've got a
new class on sigil magic
and Barbara's got a new
class on organite alchemy.
Otherwise, we're still
teaching the staples,
energy grounding,
Earth-based spirituality,
pagan arts and crafts,
candle work, the spellcraft
master class, ancient mysticism,
herbs and spices, and
sex magic, of course.
- Oh, are you still teaching
that?
- Yes, in fact, we've invited
some girls here tonight
for a seminar about the
power of sexual dancing.
Dancing is such a powerful
thing for women and girls.
- Are you still dancing?
- Yeah, some of us dance
here on Amateur Night.
You should come.
- Hi, Barbara.
Hi, Gahan.
Sorry we're late.
- Hello lovely ladies, please
have a seat.
Elaine, this is Star and her
sister Moon.
They're our students for
tonight.
Girls, this is our dear friend
Elaine.
- Hi.
- I was just pointing out that
dancing
is a powerful thing for women
and girls.
We asked you to meet us here
tonight
so you could learn about that.
Do you see how powerful that
girl is?
These men would do anything for
her.
Wouldn't you like to have
that power yourselves?
Then let us begin.
All witches need to figure
out where their power lies.
And we feel that a woman's
greatest power
lies in her sexuality.
We don't view this power as
Satanic or anti-feminist,
but as a celebration of
woman as a natural creature.
An earthly body, a spiritual
essence, and a womb.
- The whole history of
witchcraft is interwoven
with the fear of female
sexuality.
They burned us at the
stake because they feared
the erotic feelings we elicited
in them.
Later, they used marriage
to hold us in bondage
and made us into servants,
whores, and fantasy dolls
never asking us what we wanted.
- They teach us that a
normative human being
is a hyper-rationalist, stoic
male
and that women's emotions
and intuitions are illnesses
that need to be cured.
And we believe that men
and women are different
and that true equality
lies in that difference.
- We strive for male/female
polarity and to regain
our primal power as goddesses.
We need to teach men how to love
us
using ways they can understand.
So goddesses, use perfume,
wear high heels and makeup,
learn to dress your
hair in attractive ways,
display flesh artfully,
and know what to conceal.
Be a mother and a lover.
Stand your ground, but always
let the man feel like a man.
- Use sex magic to destroy his
fear of you
and to open his heart to
the floodgates of love.
Only then will he begin to
see you as a human being
with all of your inner beauty.
Then, when his heart is open to
love,
you may do with him what you
will.
- I love you, Elaine.
You know that, don't you?
I love you very much.
But you need to be more careful.
Dinner was late three times this
week.
And that house is a total
pigsty.
Do you know that I found an old
hot dog
under the bed this morning?
And why don't you ever brush
your hair?
You need to take better care
of yourself and of the house.
I'm embarrassed to have people
over.
I've been really patient up
until now,
but you need to step up your
game.
- I have a
crazy bitch for a daughter.
What?
You're not crazy?
Well, if you're not
crazy then you're stupid.
Which is it?
Are you crazy or are you stupid?
And you could lose a few pounds.
You're looking a little fatty.
- Oh my God, Elaine,
you've lost so much weight.
You have such a hot body now.
Do you like it when I touch you
like this?
Or like this?
I wanna make you come.
- Don't be frightened, Elaine.
I would never hurt you.
I'm not the big, bad wolf.
You need to have perfect
love and perfect trust.
- Hast thou the courage to make
the essay?
- I have two words, perfect
love and perfect trust.
- Assist me to erect the ancient
altar
at which in days past all
worshiped.
For in the old times, a woman
was the altar.
And the sacred place was
the point within the center
of the circle, the origin of all
things.
Therefore, should we adore it.
- Good morning, Sergeant Griff.
Congratulations on your
promotion.
- Thanks, Connie.
Is there any coffee.
- Yeah, I just made some.
I made it just the way you like
it.
- Is there anything you don't do
well?
- Why don't you try me
sometime and find out?
- How's the coffee, Steve?
- Uh, too strong.
- Well, I like it strong.
Man's gotta stay awake
on the job after all.
- Why, have you been keeping
late nights?
- Maybe so.
- But, now that you've been
promoted,
maybe you ought to start
thinking about settling down.
- Me, you kidding?
- Sergeant Meadows, a
lady's here to see you.
- I'm Shelly Curtis.
I phoned about Wayne Peters,
the teacher who disappeared.
- Yes, of course.
Have a seat, Miss Curtis.
You say you think Mr. Peters
might have been kidnapped?
- Yes, no one's seen him for two
weeks.
I went by his house and
the mail's piled up.
We had lunch the day he
disappeared.
I saw him drive away with a
strange woman near the plaza.
- Do you have any idea where
he might have gone with her?
- Wayne used to spend weekends
up in a cabin he had in the
woods.
He used to take dates there.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Hey Griff, look.
- Good lord.
- What the hell is this?
- I don't know.
We're going to have to dig,
Steve.
- I know.
I think you should go
back to the house, Shelly.
this cake is absolutely
fantastic.
And what a great dinner.
- Thank you.
I enjoy cooking.
Hope you don't mind my calling
you.
Sometimes it's so hard to be
alone.
- Not at all.
I get a little lonely, too,
when Trish is out of town.
- How long have you
and Trish been married?
- 10 years this September.
- 10 years!
It's really amazing.
No one has ever loved me the
way you love Trish, no one.
- What about your husband?
- My husband never loved me.
He couldn't wait to get away
from me.
- I'm sorry.
Sometimes I think Trish would
like to get away from me, too.
- Poor baby.
Poor, poor baby.
So, tell me, what turns you on?
- What turns me on?
Wow, no one's ever asked me that
before.
Let me think.
You know what really turns me
on?
Flying.
- Flying?
- Yeah, flying a plane.
You don't know what kinda high
it is.
You're soarin' up there above
everything.
You're in control.
- Oh, how fantastic.
- It really is.
It's the only time I feel
really clear about things.
Sometimes I look at my life
and I wonder how I got here.
I feel like my life is slipping
away
and there's so many things I
haven't done.
- Like what?
- I've never had any sordid love
affairs
or gotten into any mischief.
I used to watch those
old Steve McQueen movies,
you know, the ones where
they'd rob a bank or something,
and I'd fantasize that I was one
of those
crazy kinda gangsters with a
sexy, messed up girl on my arm.
Or those Westerns, when
they'd shoot up a town
and then go visit the local
prostitutes.
It's sounds stupid, I know.
- No, it doesn't.
It's very sweet.
- Really?
Trish doesn't think so.
She just rolls her eyes
when I talk like this.
- That's because she
doesn't understand you.
I understand you perfectly.
- You do?
- Of course.
You wanna have a sordid love
affair.
You wanna get into some
mischief.
Who are you?
What are you doing to me?
- I'm the love witch.
I'm your ultimate fantasy.
- That's right.
That's right.
- Steve, I'm going out
to see that witch doctor.
- Who?
- Professor King.
He specializes in black
magic and witchcraft.
He might be able to help me
identify some of the items we
found.
- It's great.
Did you get the lab report?
- Yeah, yeah, it looks like
heart failure.
But the toxicology report
showed traces of Jimson weed
also known as Devil's weed, a
highly toxic hallucinogenic.
- It's unbelievable.
You want me to come with you?
- No, this will only take a few
minutes.
Can you order me a turkey
and avocado on whole wheat?
- Mustard, mayo?
- Yeah and cole slaw.
Thanks.
- Done.
- Ah, Sergeant Meadows, sorry
to have kept you waiting.
- Glad to meet you, Professor.
Professor, this is the
bottle we found in a grave
of Wayne Peters, the one
you read about in the paper.
- Interesting, yes.
Just as I thought.
The contents indicate
that it's a witch bottle.
- A witch bottle?
- Yes, witches used to make them
for protection against curses.
They'd take something personal
like bodily fluids or hair
along with herbs and something
sharp
like pins or broken glass
to scare away evil spirits.
Witch bottles have often been
found buried in the hearths
of very old houses.
- Would it be safe to assume
that the person who made this
was a witch?
- It's very likely.
Witchcraft, long dormant
in civilized places,
has taken root again in cities.
There have several rituals per
year.
One of them, Samhain,
corresponds of our Halloween.
Other rituals celebrate
Summer Solstice, Litha,
or the Winter Solstice,
which they call Imbolg.
Here the members of a coven
kiss the devil's behind
in a mockery of Christian
rituals.
Here, a satanic cult sacrifices
a child.
- Does this stuff really go on
today?
- Yes, indeed.
Those who practice human
sacrifice are the black witches
who perform blood rituals
to gain demonic powers
and to bind their members
together in secrecy.
Law has been trying to root
out these cults for decades
but they've been unsuccessful.
Then there are the
white witches or Wiccans
who commune in nature
in the healing spirit
and who have a strict law
that forbids harming others.
Every city and rural
village today has pockets
of both black and white witches
who practice the ancient rites.
- I invoke and call upon
thee, Mighty Mother of us all.
I invoke thee to descend upon
the body of this thy servant
and priestess.
- Of the Mother Darksome and
Divine
here I charge you in this sign.
- Listen to the words of the
Great Mother.
She, who of old, who
was also called Artemis,
Aphrodite, Cerridwen, Diana,
Isis,
and by many other names.
- Whenever ye have need of
anything,
then ye shall assemble in some
secret place and adore me,
who am Queen of all witches.
There shall ye assemble,
ye who are fain to learn
all sorcery.
Behold all acts of love and
pleasure are my rituals.
Behold I have been with
thee from the beginning
and I am that which is
attained at the end of desire.
Bagabi lacha bachabe.
Lamac cahi achababe.
Hurrahya! Hurrahya!
- Arise.
Eko, Eko, Azarak
Eko, Eko, Zomelak
Eko, Eko, Cernunnos
Eko, Eko, Aradia!
- You're looking a little
tense tonight, love.
What's the matter?
- Oh nothing, just my usual
roller coaster love life.
- Well, have a drink and relax.
Nothing's that dire, at least
not for you.
It's an entirely different
story for your victims.
- What victims?
- There's no need to play
Miss Innocent with me, dearie.
- Please, don't touch me.
- Bright blessings, Barbara.
- Merry meet, Elaine.
How's it going?
- I'm back in the dating pool
again.
- What happened?
I thought you were crazy about
that new guy you were seeing,
the married man.
- No, I broke it off.
He just became really obsessive,
morose,
and his aura became really
murky.
He didn't even wanna make love
anymore.
He became just like a woman,
crying at every little thing.
There was no polarity.
But, I should have known.
He's a Pisces.
- Richard?
- I thought I told you
never to interrupt me
when I'm working.
What do you want?
- I just wanted to let you
know that I'm going to bed
and I'm taking a pill.
Are you coming to bed?
- No.
I have some more work to do.
- All right, see you tomorrow,
then.
- Sergeant Griff Meadows
of the Police Department.
I'd like to ask you a few
questions.
- Okay.
- Does this look familiar to
you?
- It's a witch bottle.
- Do you have any idea
who could have made it?
- No, no I don't.
- Ever seen any of these in here
before?
- Yeah, we have some witch
bottles.
I'll show you one.
Here's one.
- How common are these bottles?
- I've never seen 'em in here
before until
a girl started supplying 'em to
us.
- Who is this girl?
- Her name is Elaine, Elaine
Parks.
- Who is it?
- Sergeant Meadows, Police
Department.
Sorry to bother you, ma'am,
but I'm investigating a case
and I just wanted to
ask you a few questions.
- About what?
- Well, it's a potential
homicide case.
Just a routine check.
I thought you might be able to
help us.
- Of course.
Please come in, Sergeant.
So you say there was a homicide.
How horrible.
Who was killed?
- A man named Wayne Peters.
Did you know Wayne Peters?
- No.
- Here's a picture of him.
Ever seen him before?
- No.
I guess I can't help you,
Sergeant.
Good bye.
- Ms. Parks, wait.
Have you ever seen
anything like this before?
- It's a Magic Bottle.
I made it myself.
- Have you ever seen one
containing urine?
- Urine?
No.
- We found this bottle containing
urine and a used tampon
on the grave of Wayne Peters.
- Will you excuse me
for a moment, Sergeant?
- Ms. Parks, are you a witch?
- Yes, I am.
Is there a law against that?
- I guess not, not unless
you do something wrong.
- Do you think that being
a witch makes me evil,
capable of murder even?
- No, I wasn't trying to
imply...
- Sergeant Meadows, do
you know what it's like
to really suffer?
You have to fight and fight
until you're too exhausted to go
on.
Witchcraft is my religion,
Sergeant.
And this religion, which is
older than your Christianity,
saved my life.
- Ms. Parks, I'm sorry
if I've offended you.
I didn't realize.
- That's all right, Sergeant
Meadows.
- You can call me Griff.
- Griff?
I know I've seen you before.
I just don't know where.
- I have that same feeling.
- I know.
You're the man in the cards.
You're my fate.
- What do you mean, I'm your
fate?
- I did a Celtic Cross reading.
For my future card I got Knight
of Wands.
Always felt that if that card
showed up in a future reading,
I would soon meet the man
that I'm going to marry.
But, the man that I marry
has to love animals.
Do you like animals, Griff?
- Why yes, I love animals.
In fact, a friend of
mine has a couple horses
I'm very fond of.
You know, tomorrow is my day off
and it's supposed to be quite
nice out.
Maybe I'll get away from
the city and do some riding.
Do you like to ride, Elaine?
- Oh Patchouli, you're such a
sweetheart.
- How's my girl?
- Am I your girl?
- For today you are.
You're my girl and there's
nobody around
to tell me otherwise.
- Except me.
- And what's that supposed to
mean?
- Nothing.
Kiss me.
- What's that sound?
- I don't know.
Let's go see.
- Now is the time of the Summer
Solstice.
The strength of the Oak King is
waning.
And the Holly King stands
ready to challenge him
for the hand of the Green
Maiden.
- Let the battle begin.
- Your season is over old man.
- Oh never.
- I will have her.
- Never have her.
- Never.
- Holly King, I name you the
victor.
The Green Maiden is yours.
- M'lady.
Come on.
- Elaine.
- You know these people?
- Well yes, in a way.
- All hail, fair Lord and Lady.
Welcome to our little gathering.
- All hail.
- We are the good people
of the Renaissance
and Medieval players and we
are celebrating the Midsummer.
Won't you join us?
- To be sure, fair consorts.
- They are charming, are they
not?
- Yes, quite charming.
- I see two people in love.
This calls for a wedding.
- A wedding?
- Yes, a mock wedding, if you
will.
To honor the gods of love.
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Love will make you feel
like a Queen or a King
♫ Unicorns, rainbows, lucky
charms
♫ Await you in your true love's
arms
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Mystical, physical, alchemical
♫ We're pretending to be in love
today
♫ But pretending is also real
♫ There's a lady in a castle
♫ She's sad and so forlorn
♫ When her troubadour
returns and kisses her
♫ She's all smiles and laughter
♫ Lady, you're so beautiful
♫ Come lie with me and be my
love
♫ I'd slay any dragon, endure
any danger
♫ Just to have you near me
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Lucky lovers mate in the
spring
♫ We sip from goblets full of
joy
♫ But when love dies all
life it does destroy ♫
- Okay.
- Now, ye are wed.
- I'm so happy for you,
Elaine, he's adorable.
- I'm not in love.
It's not that I don't have
sentiment,
it's just that love is soft.
You need guts in this business.
I've seen guys get shot to
death because they fell in love
and got soft inside.
I want an heir some day
and then I would need to have a
wife,
but love is something else.
A man can get destroyed
by things like that.
It's like he's not even a man
anymore.
I never wanna get like that.
- When you really love him,
it's like fireworks and
nothing else matters.
You love all the little quirks
about him.
The way he slurps his cereal.
The way his mouth is a little
crooked.
Those details about him
become your whole life.
Something inside you
opens up like a flower
and you realize that you
have more love to give
than you ever thought was
possible.
'Cause the more you know him,
the more you love him.
- The more
you get to know a woman,
the less you can feel about her.
At first, she's this
incredible object of mystery
who fulfills all you're wildest
fantasies.
Then she starts to reveal little
flaws
and after a while, just
gets pretty hard to care.
Feminine ideal only
exists in a man's mind.
No woman could ever fulfill it.
And sometimes, when she
tries to love you more,
give you more, you feel
like you're suffocating,
drowning in estrogen.
The most awful feeling.
- Dinner tonight, Griff?
- Um, can't tonight, Connie.
Some other time.
- Hey Griff, I got more
information
on that Elaine Parks girl.
- You leave it on my desk.
- Don't you wanna hear it?
- Steve, Captain wants
us to lay off the case.
- Are you serious?
- He says we have a policy
of leaving the witches alone.
He says they've lived
in this town a long time
and he doesn't like to mess with
them.
- Even if they murder?
- He says he's satisfied
that Wayne's death
was a heart attack.
I think so too.
- Has everyone gone crazy around
here?
Let me at least tell you what I
found.
Now, Elaine used to run
an organic beauty store
in Berkeley with her husband,
Jerry.
Two years later they were
divorced
and Elaine moved to San
Francisco
to start dancing at a burlesque
club
where she got involved with a
witch coven.
The coven broke up
after police questioning
when some of it's members
died mysteriously.
Soon after, Elaine's ex-husband
died of a drug overdose
shortly before he was planning
to remarry.
The police questioned Elaine
but they couldn't find enough to
hold her.
- Well, if the San Francisco
Police couldn't find anything,
what happened there is
none of our business.
- Are you serious?
- I'd say this woman is
a dangerous character
and you better watch her.
- You mean because she's a
witch?
That doesn't mean anything.
- No, her husband died of a
drug he'd never taken before.
And did you ever find where
Wayne Peters
got the Devil's weed?
- I questioned Ms. Curtis about
that.
There was Devil's weed
growing near his cabin.
Apparently, he experimented
often with drugs.
- Come on Griff, can't
you connect the dots?
We have a possible murder here
and Elaine is our only suspect.
- I told you, we're laying off
her.
- Because of orders or because
you're in love with her?
- Who says I'm in love with her?
Get the hell off my back.
- You're out of line,
Griff, way out of line.
- Richard.
Richard!
- Thank you for meeting me,
Elaine.
It's not good for me to be alone
too much.
I know you're busy.
- Of course.
I wanted to come.
- I can't help but blaming
myself for what happened.
- You can't blame yourself.
You were a good wife to Richard.
- I tried to be.
I tried so hard to please him,
but I should have tried harder.
He wanted a certain type of
woman, someone I could never be.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe you should give a man his
fantasy.
I thought that was so
awful when you said that.
Maybe I was being naive,
but I really thought he loved me
for me.
But now, now I wish...
- You have to stop torturing
yourself.
You have to let go.
Remember how he changed
after my Dallas trip?
I think that's when he
started having that affair.
Whoever she was she drove him
crazy.
I hated him so much for that.
I wanted to kill them both.
If I ever found out who she
was, I would rip her to pieces.
But now I see I should have
helped him.
I didn't know that he was
going to take his own life.
- Hey,
hey.
- Enough about me.
What's going on with you?
- Trish, I'm in love.
- Who is he?
- He's a detective and he's
everything
a woman could ever want.
He's strong and handsome, smart
and kind.
I just know that he's the one.
He even gave me this ring.
I call it my magic ring.
It's not an engagement ring
but I just know that he's
gonna pop the question soon.
- When we first came here
I showed you my engagement ring,
remember?
I can barely stand to look at it
anymore.
It's too painful.
I'm sure he's going to ask you
soon.
You're going to make a beautiful
bride.
The first day we met,
you were envious of me because I
had a man
and you were all alone.
Now it's the reverse.
Life is funny, isn't it?
- Trish, I'm sorry, I've gotta
go.
Would you like to walk out with
me?
- No, I'd like to stay and
finish my tea.
- All right.
Take care, love.
- Hi Elaine, it's me.
Yeah, you left your ring here.
You're probably driving but
I'll drop it by on my way home.
See you in a minute.
- You bitch.
You killed my husband.
Bitch, skank, whore.
You'll burn for this.
- Crash, crash, crash.
Die, die, die.
Eko, Eko, Azarak!
Eko, Eko, Zomelak!
Eko, Eko, Aradia!
Eko, Eko, Azarak!
Eko, Eko, Zomelak!
- Oh Habondia, bind these two
with a heady lovers' brew.
Even should they strive to flee
they'll cling for all eternity.
- Scotch.
- Bottle o' beer, Sam.
Who are those new girls?
They can't dance at all.
And they're weird.
- I don't know, but the
customers really like 'em.
- They're friends of the
witches.
I seen them come in together
before.
- Yeah, the witches.
They're everywhere.
- One gin and tonic, Sam.
- Gin and tonic coming up.
- Did you read about the teacher
buried in the back yard of his
cabin?
They said it was done by the
witches.
- Oh yeah, I read about that.
They found all kinds of
witchcraft things on the grave.
- Yeah, I heard about that, too.
Creepy.
- Sit down, Elaine.
Elaine, the DNA came back from
the lab.
It connects you with Wayne
Peters.
Patricia Manning came by the
station.
With some things of yours.
Including this.
She said you drove her husband
to suicide.
- So, I was a bad girl.
Are you going to punish me?
- What sort of person are you,
Elaine?
What sort of sick mind
would do such things?
- Why are you so negative?
I didn't kill anyone.
Wayne died of heart failure
after a beautiful night of
lovemaking.
And Richard died because
he loved me too much.
These men weren't used to
the deep feelings of love
that they were experiencing with
me.
- Are you saying these men died
of love?
That's insane.
What about the spells and the
drugs?
Are you saying witchcraft
had nothing to do with it?
- Witchcraft is just a way
of concentrating energy.
It can only work with
what's already there.
I just use sex magic to create
love magic.
I didn't know how strong
the spells would be.
Sometimes it's almost scary
how strong the love gets.
- Love?
What do you know about love?
What you call love is a
borderline personality disorder
or worse.
- Don't diagnose me.
Maybe you're a narcissist who
can't love.
You think that I'm sick
because you've never loved like
I have.
Well, I would do anything for
love.
- That's right, you'll
never get enough love.
Even when a man loves
you so much it kills him,
it's not enough for you.
You're like a bottomless hole.
You doll yourself up and
do the Stepford Wife thing
thinking every man is
going to fall at your feet.
But your creepy little sexy
act doesn't work with me.
I don't love you.
- How can you stand there and
boast
about being immune to love?
Why does the genuine love of
a woman scare you so much?
You think that your way
is a superior way to live?
I know a lot of women who
feel the way that I do.
Only men make us work
so hard for your love.
If you would just love us for
ourselves,
but you won't.
My ex-husband was just like you.
He used to punish me by
withholding his love from me.
All my life I've been
tossed in the garbage
except when men wanted to use my
body.
So, I decided to find my own
power.
And I found that power through
witchcraft.
That means that I take
what I need from men
and not the other way around.
- I'm sorry, Elaine.
It won't work this time.
I'm afraid I'm going
to have to arrest you.
- What for?
Marrying a lover according to my
religion?
Seducing a married man?
I know 400 years ago you could
be burned
for a thing like that, but not
today.
- No, not burned,
but you'll be booked for
burying Wayne Peters illegally
and we'll find out more.
- Oh, that's the witch
who killed the teacher.
- Thou shalt not suffer a witch
to live.
- Burn the witch.
- Burn the witch, burn
the witch, burn the witch,
- Burn!
- Burn her.
- Burn.
Burn.
- Poor baby.
Poor, poor baby.
Don't worry, everything will be
okay
because I love you so much.
- I love you, Elaine.
I've never loved anyone but you.
I want to marry you.
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Love will make you feel
like a Queen or a King
♫ Unicorns, rainbows, lucky
charms
♫ Await you in your true love's
arms
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Mystical, physical, alchemical
♫ We're pretending to be in love
today
♫ But pretending is also real
♫ There's a lady in a castle
♫ She's sad and so forlorn
♫ When her troubadour
returns and kisses her
♫ She's all smiles and laughter
♫ Lady, you're so beautiful
♫ Come lie with me and be my
love
♫ I'd slay any dragon, endure
any danger
♫ Just to have you near me
♫ Love is a magical thing
♫ Lucky lovers mate in the
spring
♫ We sip from goblets full of
joy
♫ But when love dies all
life it does destroy ♫