[AMC]
[MUSIC]
Okay, let's see what we got here.
Seen it, seen it.
Hmm, what's this about?
That's the dog.
[SOUND]
Here we go.
At the dawn of time, there was our
gracious and powerful creator.
Primus, to protect our universe, he
sacrificed his life force.
Transforming himself
into our planet, Cybertron.
From within Cybertron's core, Primus
birthed the first
transformers known as the Primes.
The most powerful transformers appointed
to lead and protect future generations.
To assist them, Primus created an entity
of great power, the Matrix of Leadership.
Matrix, there it is, okay,
good, come on, keep going.
With the Matrix in the Primes'
possession, Cybertron's
natural power source, Energon,
flowed in abundance,
sustaining life of profit.
[MUSIC]
Attention, unauthorized
movement detected in archival vault.
Sector J, U, A.
K-12, 2K-1, reaching
archives in 10 seconds.
For generations, there was peace and
prosperity until the
Matrix of Leadership was lost,
causing Energon to no longer flow.
Why is every legend about
the Matrix end right there?
One of these has to say what happened.
Halt, criminal, prepare to be detained.
Uh...
Uh-oh.
Freeze!
Get down!
Well, hello guys, yeah,
I'm so glad you're here.
Which way's the exit?
I must have taken a wrong turn.
Is that defective mining
pot or are you on picks?
Orion Pax.
Who cares?
We told you to never come back here.
Why are we all yelling?
I'm gonna smash you.
Hold on, whoa, hold on.
No need for violence.
How about this?
I run away, you chase
me, we play that game, huh?
Come on, you're
bigger, faster, it'll be fun.
He doesn't have a cog.
Let's give him a head start.
Why not?
It's not like he can transform.
Oh yeah?
Well, watch this.
Get him!
I... I... I...
I'm something to fly.
Uh...
Oh, ha!
Prepare to be detained.
Oh! [Grunting]
You don't gotta finish that.
Come on, come on!
[Grunting]
So long, sir.
Ooh, energon.
Evening, everyone.
Pardon me.
Oh, Ryan.
Hey, fellas, thanks for the head start.
You want to give me another one?
You're dead!
I'll take that as a no.
Hey, watch where you're going, though.
What did you say, no cog?
Sorry, sir. I didn't mean you.
I was referring to the
bot who was behind you.
Where? Where'd he go?
The filthy red and
blue bot has a big mouth.
Squeaky joints gives off a
corroded metallic flinch.
Where is he?
He went that way.
When I get my hands on him.
All right, all clear.
Okay, 8D16, I may be a
little dusty, but corroded?
That is too far.
Let me guess.
Chased out of the archives?
Yeah, I had to jump out
of a window this time.
Almost died. That's wild.
And digging through
ancient data is worth dying for.
Yes, it is.
I need a new best friend.
If there are clues in
our recorded history
that can help locate
the Matrix of Leadership,
they're in the archives. Trust me.
Sentinel Prime.
The Sentinel Prime is up
on the surface right now,
risking his life for us
in search of the Matrix.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
I'm trying to help him.
Yeah. Okay.
The sooner energon flows again,
the sooner we won't have to mine for it.
Don't you want to choose your own path,
do whatever you want?
We're miners. We mine. That's all.
Oh, there's got to be
something more I can do.
I can feel it.
Oh, yeah?
Like the time that you had a feeling
you could transform without a cog?
You said you were never
going to mention that again.
Took me three days to pry you open.
Your feelings get you in trouble.
Yeah, yeah.
Just trust in Sentinel Prime.
I do trust in him.
Hey, if we did have cogs...
I'd transform into a shovel and beat you.
I don't like how fast you answered that.
But listen, if you did beat me,
I couldn't give you this awesome
Megatronus Prime thing I have here.
Let's go. I'll give it to someone else.
What Megatronus Prime thing?
Ah, it's nothing.
It's just a, you
know, the mint condition,
Megatronus Prime decal, first edition.
What?
I mean, if you don't want
it, I can just throw it away.
Throw it away. That's
not funny. Let me see.
What? Don't grab.
You're going to crease it.
You know, Sentinel says Megatronus was
the strongest Prime to ever live.
I know, buddy.
Looks good on you.
Ah, it's really cool.
Thanks.
Always got your back.
No matter what.
Approaching sub-level
station, stand clear of doors,
mining teams prepared for aid.
[MUSIC]
Metal to the pedal
drill bits, this is it.
How much energon have you
mined under my leadership?
So much, are you the one.
And how perfect is my mining record?
So perfect are you the one.
We are a mere 30 units of energon away
from my promotion to supervisor.
Are you happy for me?
So happy for the leader one.
Elita, I am the captain.
You are looking
especially shiny this morning.
New polish?
Oh, Ryan Pax, I'm sorry that I somehow
gave you the
impression that we're friends.
Apology accepted.
Light up that wall.
Let's go. Ten seconds.
Happy to take the lead today, captain.
I feel like I have enough power in me to
drill down and touch Primus myself.
You don't have the touch or the power.
Ready positions, Ross Boggins. Let's go.
She's in a good mood today.
You ready?
Always ready. Let's punch in.
Here we go. This one won't be over long.
Raise it up.
Here we go.
Lower channel is open.
Don't go on that.
Hold tight.
Throw it out.
I shot the base.
I shot the stable.
Got it, though. Got it, bro.
Evacuate!
When everyone out, evacuate immediately.
The tunnel is closing.
I repeat, the tunnel is closing.
You ripped me deep.
One, two, six. Keep going.
One down.
The gas is stuck. Alita,
we've got a trap in mind here.
I'm falling back to assist.
Negative. Do not
bring protocol. Evacuate.
We're gonna need more left. It's closing.
Just grab your package. Go.
Good idea.
What? No! I didn't mean it.
Pull the flimp.
Hacks, what's happening?
Nothing much. Just normal
protocol following stuff.
It's all good.
Oh, that's not good.
Orion Pax, could you
please exit the tunnel of death?
Alita, it's about to get messy out there.
Go! Go!
Run! Run!
Where did I make it?
Come on. Go, go, go!
What the hell, Pax? I
told you to evacuate.
I did, eventually.
If I get fired because of you...
Oh, please. They're not gonna fire you.
Alita-1, you're fired.
What? Why? I followed
protocol to the letter.
That is true. I was the
one who broke the rules.
No one asked you, Darkwing. Please. I
have worked too hard for this.
You are no cog bots with limited options.
Report the waste management immediately.
Waste management?
Alita. Next time, why don't you stop and think
before you ruin someone's life?
I'm sorry.
Hey, Darkwing.
Don't do it.
I may not have a cog, but
my finger can transform.
Guess which one. I'll
give you a limited option.
Excuse me, sir. Allow me.
I apologize on his behalf for the dis-
That really hurt.
What'd you expect? He's metal.
You know you were out of line.
Talking back to a superior like that.
Darkwing was out of line. He deserves it.
How are you tired of being
treated like we're nothing?
He had every right to
hit me. I interfered.
Hey, and I appreciate you having my back.
I'm glad you were there with me to get
punched in the face.
That was fun.
Anytime, buddy.
Attention all sectors. Stand by for a
live transmission from Sentinel Prime.
He's back? He's back already?
Maybe you found the Matrix.
Is it on? Okay, thank you.
Hello, my friends. Hello, Iacon City.
Hello to our saviors, the industrious
miners who toil selflessly to maintain
our energon reserves.
I celebrate you.
Humility and presence. That's leadership.
Ah, nobody does it better.
Once again, I have narrowly returned with
my fleet after another treacherous
expedition across the desolate, dangerous
surface of our planet.
I departed with hopes of finding the
Matrix of Leadership, the key to bringing
balance to Cybertron.
I regret to inform you that we've
returned empty-handed.
This is a setback, but not a failure.
Rest assured, I will find the Matrix of
Leadership so that
energon can flow again.
But that's in the future.
Right now, I think we
all deserve a little fun.
Tomorrow there will be no work. All
shifts off because
tomorrow is the Iacon 5000.
Woo!
My favorite event. A high
octane race all across Iacon City.
Let's all see which competitor can prove
they are truly more than meets the eye.
Dee?
Hey, Dee.
Oh, good. You're up.
Come on. I have an idea.
Whatever this is, it better be good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, listen.
Alright, what if, what if, what if,
tomorrow we ran in the Iacon 5000?
Huh? What if I kill you for waking me up?
No, no, no. Hear me out.
We don't even have to win.
No, that's good because we wouldn't.
But, but if we beat just one Transformer,
it proves we're just as good as they are.
Not only would we go down in history,
the, the mining bots
that did the impossible,
but we would show everyone that we're,
we're capable of so much more.
Or we get publicly humiliated and then
busted back to tier one.
Yeah, but at least we would have done
something, you know?
Hex. Come on, Dee-win.
Hex. We're mining bots who can't
transform. We can't fly. We can't roll.
We can't race. Come on, let's go.
Ah, fine. Yeah, maybe you're right.
Maybe.
The Iacon 5000 is finally here.
I have a surprise for you.
Come on. Where are you going?
The stadium's that way.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Follow me.
Great. We're gonna be late now.
I wanted good seats.
We came all this way to miss the opening
ceremony. This is one.
Trust me, I know what I'm doing.
Pull up.
Get caught in one of those, it'll launch
you halfway across the city.
Okay, where are you taking me?
Don't be a glitch, this will
be totally worth it. Trust me.
Hey, you don't be a glitch.
I know this is like fun for
you, like you took it around,
but if you let me miss
any part of the Iacon 5000,
I swear I will smelt your face.
Welcome to the Iacon 5000.
There they are. Put your hands together
as today's competitors
are taking the field.
Look, there's Thunderbird and Behemoth.
This is unbelievable. I
feel like I'm in the race.
You did this for me?
No, I did this for us.
And now, the moment
you've all been waiting for.
The Iacon of Iacon.
The savior of Cybertron.
Which is on Spirit, but we love it.
Our leader, the one
and only, Sentinel Prime.
I love you, Sentinel.
Hey, guys.
It feels so good to be
here with you all today.
My friends, my Cybertronian family.
It has been precisely 50 cycles since the
Quitesans attacked our home.
50 cycles since we lost
the Matrix of Leadership,
and our Energon supply dried up.
50 cycles since the battle
that killed the other Primes,
my brothers and sisters in arms.
Today, we honor the Primes
who gave their lives for ours.
We show them that the strength of
Cybertron will never be diminished.
Racers, on your marks.
I can't believe we get to watch from the
starting line for the best season out.
Why'd you bring jet bags?
It's time to show them we
are more than meets the eye.
Oh, no.
And they're off!
Are you crazy?
It sure feels like it.
The Iacon 5000 has begun.
I'm sorry. Are those miners in the race?
Miners! Those are miners! Look at us!
I can't believe we're not sitting here.
There are miners trying
to run in the background.
This is insane!
There's miners in the race!
Miners! They can't even transform!
The Ryan Pax is P-16!
This is a burst in Iacon 5000 history.
How are they going to survive?
If we survive this, I'm gonna kill you!
I accept those turns.
It's tailwind pulling into the lead down
the main stretch,
followed by straight and skywire.
Take this out!
I own the one!
More like a thousand!
I can't believe we're not in left field!
No!
I'm not in the race!
Fire!
Darkwind delivers a devastating blow!
We're not fast enough!
Improvise!
Hey! Get off!
Get off! Big Ben!
Get off!
So sorry, big friend.
Fire at this right!
And now!
Move!
And the miners have fallen way behind.
We can now focus on the
real contenders in this race.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I don't believe it!
The miners tinned down Darkwing!
Oh, miners!
Great effort, Darkwing!
Now work them!
It actually worked!
Is this the dumbest
thing we've ever done?
Oh yeah, it's up there!
[SCREAMING]
Move!
Wait!
Go, go, go!
Four-bought pile up in the magnetic top,
and the two-liners are
now in first position!
This is unbelievable!
Dean! No!
Go!
Leave me!
No!
We do this together!
One miner is now carrying the other mere
steps from the finish line!
The most amazing sensational dramatic
heart-waving excited,
thrilling finish in a distinct up-
And we have a winner!
Chromia comes from kinda big surprise!
Talk about an Iacon 5000 for Jesus!
Well, second place is still pretty good!
Do not worry, you will
be fixed up in no time.
Uh... did I win?
You participated.
Yay!
So... how long do you
think we'll be here?
I'm not talking to you.
You know what?
I can't believe you made me do that.
We are so screwed!
Thought you weren't talking to me.
Hey, look, I know it's all a
big joke to you, but not me.
I was paying my dues.
I was going places, and now
they're gonna bust me down.
I don't even know how many to use.
I'm sorry, Dee.
But come on, didn't you feel it?
Even for just a second,
didn't you feel liberated?
Didn't you feel like
you were something else?
Like you could be more
than what they say you are?
Yeah, I felt it.
I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it. I felt it.
I did.
But it doesn't matter.
We're going to get punished and demoted.
Ugh, Sentinel Prime saw the whole thing.
This is so embarrassing.
It's clear.
Orion Pax.
D16.
What you two did today was one of the
craziest things I've ever seen.
Sir, this is all my
idea, and we're so sorry.
I loved it!
You did?
How could anyone not love it?
You gave my best racers a
real run for their money.
So we're not getting demoted?
Demoted?
[Laughing]
The fact of the matter is, we're halfway
into the first shift
since the race ended.
And that mining crew has
already reached 150% quota.
You inspired them to work harder.
With Sentinel Prime, sir, we joined the
race to show everyone our potential.
That weak bots can do
more than just mine energy.
Outstanding.
I love a bot that can think for himself.
Perhaps you two could tour the mines,
speak to your brethren, and
help them see their potential.
Wow.
Great.
That sounds incredible.
I would love to be--
Sir, it's time.
Ah, yes.
I'm sorry, friends.
We're preparing our
next travel to the surface.
But in the meantime,
I've got a treat for you.
Hang tight.
Arachnid, have someone escort these
heroes to my personal service facilities?
Best care in Iacon.
Until next time, Legends.
Sentinel Prime.
Ha ha ha.
The Sentinel Prime.
You're still mad at me?
I am less mad at you.
I'm telling you, Dee, I got a feeling
that everything's going to change.
And we're going to go--
Argh!
You miners!
Darkwing.
No!
Wait, wait, you don't understand!
We were supposed to go to Sentinel
Prime's service pod!
You two folks aren't going
to see anyone ever again!
I'll make sure of that!
You're picking up a fake-ass Sentinel!
Ugh.
Hate that guy.
You, products of the Sentinel!
It's like our chest of the Sentinel.
There's no one to tell you
who can call it "Gumwood".
You're real!
You're-- you're-- you're others!
You're not me!
You're here!
And you're not me!
Uh, yeah?
Awesome!
I am so sorry.
That must have been weird for you.
I just haven't had a lot of company since
they put me down here in sublevel 50.
50?
But there are only 40 sublevels.
That's what I thought!
Turns out they're 10 more
and they are not pleasant.
Probably why nobody ever
really talks about them.
How long have you been down here?
How long have I been here?
Haha!
Let's see.
Somewhere between a
long time and forever.
I mean, I had other jobs,
but I kept getting reassigned,
because I'm so good at what I do.
Oh!
I'm B-127, by the way.
But you can call me "B".
I'm actually working on some nicknames.
The one I'm floating
right now is "Badassatron",
which is actually
pronounced "Badassatron".
But if you have any critiques--
Great, great.
How do we get out of here?
Great question.
You don't.
We don't?
No.
We have limited access to
the waste management area,
but the new shift manager
there does not like distractions.
No, they prefer we stay
here on the task at hand.
Which is?
Oh!
The scrap comes in from the chute there
onto the conveyor belt.
Our job is to look for anything that
might be worth salvaging
before it hits the
furnace and gets smelted.
So you watch Garbage Barn?
Yes!
It is so great that you're here now.
I can't wait to learn
everything about you
and then tell you everything about me.
I have a lot of hopes and dreams that I
am just dying to share
with one or two new best friends.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, where are my manners?
Come on.
I'll introduce you to
the rest of the crew.
Hey, guys!
We've got company!
This is EP-508.
This is A-atron.
And this fella here is Steve.
Steve?
Yeah, he's for him.
Question.
Do they talk back to you?
Um, they're not real.
What?
You think I'm that crazy?
No, no, it's just you've been down here.
I was talking to Steve.
What?
Classic Steve.
What is that?
This guy.
Who's he coming from?
Oh!
Steve!
No!
I am so sorry.
Steve!
No!
Put this on ambush.
Pulling the high guard
for immediate support.
Immediate support!
That's Alpha Trion.
One of the primes?
Repeat.
Zeta Prime has fallen.
It's an SOS message.
Protect the matrix.
Sending location coordinates.
Holy primus.
Are those a coordinates to
a location on the surface?
This could be where the
primes died in the Quintesson War.
Which means this is where we could find
the Matrix of Leadership.
What are you talking about?
It's an old beacon inside
a statue made of garbage.
Or it's a clue of how we can find the
Matrix of Leadership.
No, no way.
Absolutely not.
AD, come on.
This could be our chance to
show everyone that we're not--
You already tried to
show everyone in the race.
You tricked me into running, which got us
stuck down here in this
waste hole with this, uh...
Really cool guy.
Oh, thank you.
I'm just saying.
There's a reason no
one goes to the surface.
It's dangerous.
I'm waiting right here
until Zeta Prime finds us.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
Well, we'll just stay here forever.
And cool with you, B?
Forever? This is great.
I have you coworkers and roommates.
There's plenty of room
now that Steve is dead.
I usually sleep on the conveyor belt, but
you can totally have it.
I'll sleep in the corner next to A-atron.
Plenty of room for you guys to stretch
out to, because you're taller than I am.
You know what I mean?
AD, what do you think sending those letters to?
What do you think Shennil's reaction
would be if you personally handed him the
matrix of leadership that you found?
Okay, stop.
I know what you're trying to
do, and it's definitely working.
I'm in.
Haha, yeah, buddy.
How do we get to the surface?
Pfft. You kidding me?
The surface? Easy.
I know a way, but it won't be easy.
Why is there so much trash?
It's a warning next time, please.
My mouth was open.
49 sub-levels to go.
Waste disposal trains are the only
vehicles that go all
the way to the surface.
Yeah, but they don't allow passengers.
Their trains are autonomous.
Yeah, that's the won't-be-easy part.
It's perfect. We'll be
safe inside the train.
That's the last one.
Let's drop.
Hold up. One more.]
I'll lock it down.
Heh. Thanks for being an
idiot, whoever you are.
Turning you in will definitely get me
promoted back up a rink or two.
Got him!
No, wait, wait, wait. I--
Alina, stop!
Orion?
Hold on, let me--
Security! Sound the alarm!
What's wrong?
He's headed through the engine!
Don't worry, I got this.
Hold on, let me
explain. We're on a mission.
No, am I. To ruin your life.
Alina, wait. We found a
message. You know her.
This bot is crazy! Who is she?
Dead end, Alina. There's
no way, um, um, she's gone.
Ugh.
Oh! Why? Why am I doing this, why am I
doing this, why am I doing this, why am I doing this?
Why? Why do I--
Faster!
Rock!
Run!
Ah, the surface.
It's... beautiful.
I am... speechless.
Alina, listen to me. We know where the
Matrix of Leadership is.
Oh, sure. And I'm really a Prime. I just
prefer loading crates of toxic--
Whoa. Where did you get this?
From my friend Steve. Orion killed him.
I did not kill Steve.
He was never alive.
What?
Look, Sentinel told us he was going to
the surface, and then
we found this message.
We figured that we could hand deliver it
to him or scout the locations ourselves.
Whichever comes first.
This was too important to wait. It will
change all of our lives.
No, no, no, no. I'm not going to get
demoted again because of you. I'm turning
this rig around and I'm notifying--
Hey, hey, guys, guys. What is that?
Is it getting bigger?
Or closer?
[TIRES SQUEALING]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, you're closing. Don't close. Stop
closing. It's closed.
Come on!
Oh, now I know why no
one comes to the surface.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
Alita. Alita.
You okay?
[GRUNTING]
Please stop punching me in the face.
Aye, Connor. The
train. Where's the train?
Relax, okay. Here it comes.
There it goes. Okay, I was wrong about
that. It was going the other way.
[SCREAMING]
Okay, so, uh, this is us, and if we
follow the path to--
Now, you listen to me, Mr. Zero Seconds,
since my last accident.
I'll go on your little quest, because I
don't have a choice.
But I carry the map, I navigate, and if
this leads to nothing,
then I'm dragging you and those two idiot
go-bots back to Iacon City
with the first supervisor depot we see,
at which point you will explain
everything that's happened using words
that reflect me in a very positive light.
Got it!
Yeah, okay. Deal. All right.
Let's go.
She's joining us? Fantastic.
Hi there. Alita, right?
Am I saying that right?
Wanted to formally
introduce myself. I'm B-127.
You need me in the
face earlier, back there.
You can call me B. Or Badassatron to
nickname some of the guys
I don't know. I didn't
give it to myself or anything.
Actually, it's pronounced "Badassatron."
In case you were wondering.
Badassatron.
You like that, right?
I'm gonna need you to talk less.
Sure. No, yeah, no problem. What am I
talking less about? My nickname?
That's fine with me.
Hey, you're thinking about what you'll
say when you hand the
Matrix to Sentinel, aren't you?
I can't help it.
D, we're really doing this. So glad I'm
out here with you. This was a great idea.
I'm just having a good time. How much
further is the Matrix on this map?
We can educate against it.
This is the coolest thing that's ever
happened to anyone
anywhere. I'm telling you.
One, not two, not three, but four. Four
best friends who were
walking through the door.
There's no doors. We're outside.
Hey, look. There's more of it over here.
What is it?
It's not metal. It's like some kind of
weird nature. It's weird.
So are they.
What was that?
I think this is not right. We should go.
Yeah. Good idea.
Run!
What are we running from?
What is that?
Oh no. It's a grid design ship.
Really?
What do we do? What do we do?
Shh! Quiet.
No!
Scanning for lifeforms. Move, move!
Go, go, go!
Come on! They're not going to make it.
What were they searching for?
Someone to hug be. How should I know?
I'm not waiting around to find out.
This way. We're close.
Quinisans haven't
been here for 50 cycles.
It doesn't make sense.
There's nothing out here.
A cave with teeth.
Nothing scary about that.
Nice. Coming out of the ceiling. Amazing.
Everyone, do we have to go inside?
Okay. Yep. We're going in.
Why shouldn't we? Just walking into the
scariest place I've ever
seen in my entire life.
Ridiculous.
I don't believe it. The Primes.]
We're here.
Megatron is Prime.]
Zeta Prime.
The Matrix.
It's gone.
Let's keep looking.
Hey, guys.
It's Alpha Trion.]
He's powered down.
But he's sparked. He's still lit.
It's Alpha Trion.
You're safe.
I have eaten snuggly.
That's his reward.
Whoa, whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
You're safe now. The war is over.
I failed you, old friend.
You deserved so much
better than this. End.
Though you didn't fail.
We heard your message.
We've come to find the Matrix.
Your transformation,
Cogs. What happened to you?
Who are you?
We're Cogless miners. From Iacon.
Miners? Why?
Well, we've had to drill for energon ever
since it stopped flowing.
Impossible.
That's why we came. To fix things.
If we find the Matrix of Leadership and
get it to Sentinel Prime, he can--
Sentinel is no Prime.
What?
He's broken. Fantastic.
What are you talking
about? Why would you say that?
Sentinel Prime is our protector. He's
been saving us from the
Quintessons ever since--
You have not been saved.
You've been living a lie.
I saw the truth with my own eyes.
Come.
I will show you.
For thousands of cycles, the war with the
Quintessons had been a brutal conflict.
Until Sentinel, the principal aide to the
Primes, intercepted
an enemy transmission.
There was going to be a secret gathering
of Quintesson commanders.
Their elimination could end the war.
It was a mission so important, we Primes
took it on ourselves.
We agreed to meet Sentinel for his
sensitive intel in secret.
Here, in this cave.
But we were not alone.
Quintessons!
We're here!
We're trapped!
Quintessons!
We're fine!
For
Spider-Con!
We were outnumbered but stood as one.
Our victory was near.
Until we were betrayed.
Sentinel!
Why?
We're all the power of Cybertron.
Sentinel! Why? We're all the power of Cybertron.
But Sentinel never understood the true
power of what he desired.
The Matrix of Leadership can only be
wielded by one that
Primus himself deems worthy.
And Sentinel most certainly was not.
No!
Wait, hold on, you're saying that the
Matrix of Leadership just vanished?
No.
No, no, no, no, that is impossible!
I don't believe it!
Why would Sentinel do that?
To make a bargain.
A bargain?
With who?
With the new rulers of Cybertron.
Quintessons.
There are so many.
He's here.
Sentinel Prime is here.
They always are.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I loathe those crates.
Those are filled with contaminated metal.
I don't understand.
What do the Quiddisoth
want with toxic waste?
Our energy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Swader!
No.
I know what I promised you, but our
minds, they're running out.
There's barely enough energy out for us.
I swear I will catch you the rest.
Triple time, every mining shift.
No miner gets a break
until I get my Energon.
All of it. Let's go.
Now you have seen the truth.
Every day, every single day
of my life has been a lie.
Oh my god, I knew it.
Deep down, I always
felt something was off.
He deceived everyone.
Sentinel bought himself power and then
put us to work, paying off his debt.
I can't believe it.
Well, obviously, I can believe it. I just
saw it, but I still--
I can't believe it.
Sentinel lied to my face.
It was all a sham. How
could we have been so gullible?
Oh, this, this, is
going to change everything.
You just had to do it, didn't you?
Me? What did I do?
You just had to go to the surface, had to
enter the Iacon 5000.
You just had to break protocol.
Who cares about protocol?
I do. I care. Because nothing bad happens
when you stay on protocol.
Sentinel Prime has been forcing us to
work in the mines until our gears strip.
And all the while, he's been giving the
energon away to our greatest enemies.
And what do you think he's going to do to
us when he finds out that we know?
I'm not thinking about what he's going to
do. I'm thinking about
what we're going to do.
Well, that's the whole thing. You're
never thinking about anything else.
Just yourself. Fantastic.
Another Orion Pax Master Plan.
I can't wait to hear this.
Don't you want to stop him?
No, I want to kill him!
I want to put Sentinel in chains and
march him through the mines
so everyone can see him for
the false prime that he is.
I want him to suffer and
then to die in darkness.
But we all know that it doesn't matter
what I want, right Pax?
The fact is, we're
just cogless bots, right?
He had limited options.
And now, now we have none.
No son or daughter of
Cybertron is born without a cog.
Oh, yeah. I've been with myself since I
came online, and this
slot's always been empty.
So what are you saying? Are you saying--
No, no way. Nobody could be
that evil. Not even Sentinel.
He removed your cogs
before you came online.
We were born with transformation cogs,
but he took them from us.
What defines a Transformer
is not the cog in his chest,
but the spark that resides in their core.
A spark that gives you the
will to make your world better.
My fellow Primes had that spark, and I
see their strength in you.
Take their cogs and
access your full potential.
Prima.
Onyx.
Alchemist.
Microns.
Warriors of noble spirit.
Loyalty.
Strength.
Their uniqueness enhanced by these.
They were one. You are one. All are one.
We have you. You gave us the
ability to change your world.
How you choose to use
that power is up to you.
They found us.
Oh, yes. Turn the fight back.
No. You must return to
Iacon City and alert everyone.
Embedded in this are the records I assume
you. Use it to reveal the truth.
We will.
This tunnel leads to the mountains.
Cybertron's future is in your hands.
We're out of time. We gotta move.
Wait, wait. We can't just leave you here.
Your fight will come, my friend. Primus
has a purpose for us all.
But this fight... This
fight is mine. Now go.
Stand down, old tire.
Old, you say?
Not too old for you.
We need to hurry.
I still think we have better odds
fighting than outrunning them.
Wait. We have cogs.
They can transform now.
That's right. Everyone ready?
I was born ready.
On three. One.
Fuck!
How do we use these things?
I don't know. Just try.
It's working. It's working!
My head! My head!
Help! Help!
This is not! Faster!
Come on!
Transform!
I've got two wheels! I need wheels!
Oh, wow. We're alive.
Never mind me. That was incredible. See me slide? Oh, please, I am doing this. Yes!
Hey, whoa, buddy. Are you okay?
I'm great. Are you kidding me? We can
transform. We transform.
Oh, wait. I know. We're wasting time. We
have to get back to Iacon.
Looks like the fastest way back to Iacon.
Here, I got to do that.
Whoa, hey, what are you doing?
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, but be careful.
Our proof is inside and
you're spilling it everywhere.
I...
...got... ...it.
Okay.
Follow me.
Alpha, triumph! You are still alive.
Would you look at that.
You look horrible.
Traitor.
You are a disgrace.
Primus will surely...
Uh-huh. Yes, shut up.
I seized an opportunity to
take control of my future.
Anything to get out of working for you
and that boring council of elders.
Seriously, I would watch you, Prime,
spend half the day losing a war,
and the other half sitting around waxing
poetic about loyalty and honor.
Now look at you.
Hear my words.
You will fall.
And a new Prime will rise.
Here you go again.
I don't want to listen
to any more speeches.
There were others in the cave with you.
Who are they?
They are to be your undoing.
You've lost Sentinel.
Nothing can do that.
Oh, didn't I just say no speeches?
You heard me, right?
This is what I'm talking about.
Unbelievable.
All of them are like that.
So disrespectful.
Okay, hunt down the others.
With pleasure.
Hey, buddy.
Oh, hey.
You've been a little quiet.
You all right?
All I can think about is
Sentinel's smirking face.
He must pay for what he's done.
Someone has to do something.
We are.
With Alpha's proof inside that device, we
will show everyone the truth.
You honestly believe it'll be that easy?
Iacon doesn't want to hear the truth.
They worship Sentinel.
There's got to be a
better way to bring him down.
We just have to trust that everyone will
believe what we show.
I trusted Sentinel.
With everything.
I will never trust a
so-called leader ever again.
There's only one body I know I--
Oh, boy.
All right.
Wake them up.
Now, are you spies, or
just incompetent lackeys?
We're not spies.
But he is incompetent.
Scanning electrical emojis.
He speaks the truth.
That just means he believes
himself like any spy would.
No, no, no, no.
Sit down.
Sit down, me.
He wouldn't stop talking.
Even when he was unconscious?
Especially when he was unconscious.
Enough.
Two options for you.
One, we slowly dismantle each of you, one
bolt and screw at a time,
and really make sure you feel it.
Or two, in exchange for a quick death,
you give us intel on the Energon trains,
access to the mines, or anything else
that could hurt your boss Sentinel Prime.
Who exactly are you guys?
The Cybertronian High Guard.
I told you it wasn't tight enough.
Prestigious defenders of Iacon.
Prestigious?
He's right.
I read all about you in the archives.
You are the most legendary
warriors in all of Cybertron.
Look, look, look.
That starscream, and your
shockwave, and soundwave.
Guys, raise your hand
if wave is in your name.
There's a lot of waves.
Silence.
The yellow annoying one is correct.
Woo!
We were once the High Guard.
We witnessed Sentinel's
betrayal, saw the Prime's fall.
Since that day, we've been
fighting from the shadows,
doing whatever we can
to sabotage Sentinel.
That's great.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay.
We're good.
Everyone relax.
I'm just saying we're allies.
We were on our way back to Iacon,
and now with your help, we can unify
Cybertron against Sentinel Prime.
The idea of a unified
Cybertron is a myth.
All that counts is the
strength of one bot over another.
Okay, so these guys are the moon tents?
Yeah, just so I know.
Hey, what are you doing?
I tell you what I'm not doing.
I'm not cowering in some busted ship
playing king of the throne.
I'm not pretending like
I'm making a difference
by throwing one punch and
then running away to hide.
I found out that
Sentinel is rotten today,
and I'm gonna make him pay for it.
Two days!
You think you can
insult me and just walk away?
No one leaves here unless I say so.
Is that right?
Well, how can you say so?
With my head in your teeth.
Dink!
Get me!
Going!
Come on!
Yeah, boy!
You want to see the
strength of one bot over another?
Is that all you've done?
Just cut the cut!
Come on!
I make him!
Stop! D, he's not the enemy!
Bear witness!
This is the last time I show mercy.
Decide, right now!
You can stay here in hiding,
bowing before your pathetic leader,
or follow me as we march on Iacon
and I take down
Sentinel once and for all!
D, 16!
B, come on!
Aah!
Engage all hostile. I've got the bridge.
I don't need it! Get down!
What the hell are you doing?
I feel like someone
dropped a cliff on me.
Or where are the others?
Sentinel's troops took as many prisoners
as they could carry.
They got D, 16 and B.
Oh, no.
And half of those high guard nut jobs.
Our proof. It's gone.
So, what do we do now?
D was right.
About what?
Everything. Look at it, look around.
This is a disaster.
It's all my fault. I
should have stayed on protocol.
Listen to me. I really
want you to hear this.
Are you listening?
I'm better than you.
Yeah, okay. I'm hearing you.
I'm better than you in
every way, except you have hope.
You always have.
If you went back into the mine to rescue
Jaz, you snuck up to the surface to find
the Matrix of Leadership.
Yeah. And how'd that work out?
My point is that your instincts tell you
to break protocol for a reason.
This blind optimism that you have is why
you make such bold and courageous choices
that are also extremely stupid.
First time giving a pep talk?
You're inspiring. You can envision a
better future that no one else can see.
And if we ever want to see B and D-16
again, that is the Orion
packs that we need right now.
Listen to me. We can do this.
Those Energon trains will be heading back
to Iacon. If we intercepted one...
Hell yes. I can re-route
it. What else do we need?
Well, my bold instincts tell me we have
to recruit some nutjobs.
I was afraid you'd say that.
A shockwave sound wave view in the back.
In order to save our captured
friends, we have to act now.
How about I blast you back to Iacon?
She punched me in my eye!
Everyone, shut up! All
of you. Listen to him.
Most likely our friends are being held
captive at the top of Sentinel's tower.
A surprise attack would give
us a chance to rescue them.
Impossible. We do not have enough
soldiers all the way inside.
A leader will get us in,
and I will get more troops.
Why should we follow you?
We will follow you!
Attention, High Guard. Prepare for battle.
What is our first move?
We roll out.
What?
Louder.
Transform and roll out!
I don't understand.
Why are we still alive?
Look at this rowdy bunch! The High Guard!
You know, you guys
have been tough to find.
Every trip to the surface, I've been
searching for you...
Tracking the bots in the
cave led me right to them.
Oh, you captured Starscream!
It was too easy.
I know you ripped you apart, piece by
piece, so that your death is painful, and
you'll regret the day you went...
You sound ridiculous. It's weird.
Oh, D-16. What a tragic story you'll be.
A top the leaderboard in your
sector, and secretly a traitor.
I'm not a traitor. You're the traitor.
Uh-uh. You, all of you, are traitors.
You've been working with the Quintessons
to sabotage my expeditions.
You're the reason why I haven't found the
Matrix of Leadership yet.
None of that is true.
Oh, trust me. It'll be very true when I'm
executing you in front of all of Iacon.
Because down here, the
truth is what I make it.
Well, well. What's this about?
I'm not kneeling in front of you.
Feeling confident, are we?
You don't scare me. You
don't want to know why.
Please?
Because I don't have anything left to
lose. You took it all.
I sure did.
Oh, Megatronus Prime!
Of course you were a fan. Megatronus was
the coolest Prime. The biggest. The
baddest. The toughest.
That's why, after I killed
him, I took his cog for myself.
He was greater than you'll ever be!
I don't know. I'm pretty great.
But I can understand why you'd want to
wear his face over mine.
Here. Let's make sure
it doesn't come off.
[Music]
Okay. For my Iacon to this.
You can't be serious. We just worked 22
shifts without a break. These miners need
rest and time to repair.
Sentinel Prime wants more energon. So get
back in the mines before
I make you get back in.
Wait, what's that? Did
you see what that was?
It can't be anything.
Is that?
It can be.
Orion?
Jazz. Is it really you?
Yeah, I know. I look a little different.
Little? There's nothing little about you.
How is this possible?
Sentinel told us you died
from your race injuries.
Sentinel is a liar.
Look, I know how this will sound coming
from me. I was never
the most focused miner.
But as you can see,
everything is different now.
[Music]
I went to the surface
and I learned the truth.
My friends, we were all born with
transformation cogs.
And then Sentinel, he stole them from us.
He took away our ability to make our own
decisions. He stole our freedom.
[Music]
But now, I'm offering
you your first real choice.
You can work a twenty-third shift and
mine yourself to death.
Or fight back against
Sentinel with me. Right now.
How are we supposed to do that?
We can't fight. We don't have cogs.
What defines a Transformer is not the cog
in its chest, but the spark
that resides in their core.
A spark that gives you the
will to make your world better.
And that spark, Sentinel
can never take from us.
There's not enough of
us. We need an army.
And we have one. Alita is bringing
troops. We are not alone in this.
If we want to be in control of our own
destiny, we will have to fight for it.
Now is the time for us to
stand up. For ourselves.
Stand up for this injustice.
I promise you, this
fight will be worth it.
Follow me. Nothing can stop
us when we stand together.
Together as one.
Orion Pax! Orion Pax! Orion Pax!
Alita, it's time.
You got it. Buckle up,
Blinky. We're going in.
[Music]
Not a good idea.
Dee, stay down.
Well, that's a shame. You
really were a great miner.
We've got a breach. Protect Sentinel.
They spotted us.
It's about to get bumpy.
High Guard! Eject!
[Music]
There's too many. We have to abort!
We're not going to make it.
[Music]
Let them have it miners! Let's break some protocol!
Thanks for the mop up Pax!
That's intense.
You can't win, miner. I see everything.
That's right. You do. Except the tower
we're about to crash into.
Hey!
What has he done to you? This is nothing.
Compared to what I'm
going to do to Sentinel.
Soundwave, I'm entering the prisoners.
I know how to stop you.
Arachnid is the answer.
I'm doing this my way.
D!
Yes!
Whoa! I got a battle mask!
Battle mask! It appeared with this guy.
Try to... Knife
hands? I have knife hands!
Ha ha ha!
BadAssetron!!!
Where's Sentinel?
You pathetic little twits.
Did you really think that you could knock
down everything I've built?
It's over, Sentinel. You
can't escape the truth.
What truth?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
Forced you to mine so that I could pay
off the Quintessons and live like a king?
None of that matters.
Because the truth is...
...is what I make it!
Incoming!!!
He's too strong.
I have a plan. We need Arachnid.
Arachnid?
You need her memory.
Where is she?
Found her!
Alita!
Do not break her. Bring her to the
broadcast station. We'll meet you there.
Easier said than done.
Argh! I said don't break her!
Relax! I'm being very gentle!
Orion! Orion, look! I have knife hands!
I can see that.
I'm gonna cut these guys. Watch!
Come here!
You can jab them later. We gotta go.
Argh!
Uh, excuse me. You can't be in here.
Hey!
Bee?
These are not the bad guys.
Why did you cut the door?
No, I didn't... I
didn't... That wasn't...
It was already like that. Right?
Yes, that's right. It was...
Yeah, it was already like...
Attention, Iacon city.
Stand by for a live
transmission from Sentinel Prime.
What's wrong, D-16?
Rise up!
Mmm...
Ah...
That's why after I killed him. That's why
after I killed him...
I took his cog for myself.
Cog for myself.
What truth that I plucked the cogs from
your newborn chests,
forced you to mine so that I could pay
off the quittissons and live like a king?
What truth that I plucked the cogs from your newborn chests,
forced you to mine so that I could pay off the quittissons and live like a king? That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests,
forced you to mine so that I could pay
off the quittissons and live like a king?
If I'm working my miners as hard as I
can, I swear I will catch you the rest.
[screaming] [screaming]
[screaming] We trusted You! [screaming] Traitor!
Pax! we did it.
[music]
[screaming]
D!
[music]
[more grunting]
(dramatic music)
D-16, we can lead Cybertron together.
Don't do this.
What are you doing?
It's over, D.
Everyone in Iacon knows the truth.
So do I!
He took everything from us.
I have to do this.
No, you don't.
Rebuilding Iacon cannot
begin with an execution.
He deserves to die.
Can't you see that?
We're better than this.
Don't be like Sentinel.
Pax, you need to move out of my way.
Before I move you myself, D, listen.
(dramatic music)
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Why?
Why did you do that?
(dramatic music)
D, no.
I'm done saving you.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
The age of crimes has ended.
No more false prophets.
Follow me and you will
never again be deceived.
Rise up!
Orion Pax, your noble
sacrifice for the greater good
has proven you worthy
in the eyes of Primus.
He entrusts in you
the future of Cybertron
and the matrix of leadership.
I will lead us all into the future.
(dramatic music)
I am Megatron!
Arise!
Optimus Prime.
Run it down!
All of it!
All hail Megatron!
He's gonna kill everyone.
We have to stop him, come on.
No, it's over.
It's over?
When every last one
of his followers are dead!
(dramatic music)
Impossible.
Primus gave you the matrix.
We could have built the future together.
I'll build it myself after I
tear down everyone in my way!
(yelling)
(dramatic music)
(yelling) (dramatic music)
(yelling)
(dramatic music)
We were given the
power to change our world
and you chose to destroy it.
Just like Sentinel, you
have betrayed Cybertron
and its citizens.
And you betrayed me.
(dramatic music)
Go, take the High guard and leave.
You are banished from Iacon.
It didn't have to end this way.
This isn't over, Prime.
High guard, follow me!
(dramatic music)
A line between friend and enemy
is not as clear as I once believed.
Once it's crossed, there's no going back
because some
transformations are permanent.
Hey, Megatronus Prime, nice.
Oh yeah, well, he's my hero.
The greatest Prime to ever live.
I'm D-16.
Orion Pax, you ever mine Energon before?
No, you?
No, I hear it's dangerous.
I'll tell you what, you watch my back,
I promise to watch yours.
All right, thanks, Pax.
(dramatic music)
A new beginning for Cybertron.
And a new leader.
Yes, about that.
I could use some help from the bot
who is better than me in every way.
Who, me?
Oh no, no.
I have a pretty sweet gig
working in waste management.
Well, Captain, I do owe you a promotion.
How's Major Alita sound?
How about Commander?
Even better.
And I'm sorry, Bee, but I
cannot let you go back
to sub level 50.
I may be a Prime now, but
I'm gonna need you by my side.
Are you serious?
This is the greatest day of my life.
I get to work for the government.
Okay, so that's new.
I'm sorry, what is happening?
(dramatic music)
And now we stand here together as one.
Proving we all have
the power to transform,
to become who we were destined to be,
to right wrongs, to
make our world better.
Because here, freedom and autonomy
are the rights of all sentient beings.
Here, all are truly Autobots.
This message is a
warning to all quintessons.
If you dare return to Cybertron,
the Autobots will be waiting.
I will be waiting.
I am Optimus Prime.
(dramatic music)
Hey guys, great news, the Energon's back.
And I have a cog and I can transform.
It's a long story,
I'll fill you in later.
Oh, and here's the best part.
My hands are straight up knives.
Watch this.
Knife hands.
No!
(dramatic music)
Sentinel, the Betrayer is dead.
But his death has
given life to a new enemy,
a stronger enemy, a personal enemy.
We will not be blinded by his deception.
We are the ones who are.
Decepticons rise up!
(dramatic music)