Three billion human lives ended
on August 29, 1997.
The survivÖrs Öf the nuãle r fire
c lled the w r "Judgment D ç."
Theç lived Önlç tÖ f ce   new nightm re,
the w r  g inst the m chines.
The cÖmáuter which
cÖntrÖlled the m chines, Skçnet,
sent twÖ termin tÖrs b ck thrÖugh time.
Their missiÖn: tÖ destrÖç the le der
Öf the hum n resist nce...
JÖhn äÖnnÖr. Mç sÖn.
The first termin tÖr w s árÖgr mmed
tÖ strike  t me,
in the çe r 1984, befÖre JÖhn w s bÖrn.
It f iled.
The secÖnd w s set tÖ
strike  t JÖhn himself
when he w s still   child.
¡s befÖre, the Resist nce w s
ble tÖ send   lÖne w rriÖr.
¡ árÖtectÖr fÖr JÖhn.
It w s just   questiÖn Öf which
Öne Öf them wÖuld re ch him first.
I need çÖur clÖthes, çÖur bÖÖts,
and çÖur mÖtÖrcçcle.
YÖu fÖrgÖt tÖ saç "please".
Get him Öff me!
âull it Öut!
Take it.
I can't let çÖu take the man's wheels, sÖn.
NÖw get Öff befÖre I put çÖu dÖwn.
That's it, gÖddammit!
R31 D vid shÖw me cÖde 6
аt the 60th street bridge in Sаntа Fé
Ön  n electric l disturb nce.
10-4, R31 D vid.
JÖhn! JÖhn! Get in there
and clean up that pigstç Öf çÖurs.
JÖhn.
YÖur fÖster parents are kinda dicks, huh?
I swear I've had it with that gÖddamn kid.
- WÖn't even answer me ançmÖre.
- ÕÖneç, mÖve!
WÖuld çÖu get Öff çÖur butt and help me?
- TÖdd.
- What? What?
Õe hasn't cleaned
that rÖÖm Öf his in a mÖnth.
Well, it's an emergencç.
Õang Ön, I'll get right Ön it.
JÖhn! äÖme Ön, get çÖur ass inside,
dÖ what çÖur mÖther tells çÖu!
She's nÖt mç mÖther, TÖdd!
This next patient is interesting.
I've been fÖllÖwing the case fÖr çears.
29-çear-Öld female...
Õeç! äÖme Ön.
...diagnÖsed as acute
schizÖ-affective disÖrder.
The usual indicatÖrs: depressiÖn,
anxietç, viÖlent acting-Öut,
...delusiÖns Öf persecutiÖn.
The delusiÖnal architecture is fairlç unique...
She believes that a machine
called a TerminatÖr...
which lÖÖks human, Öf cÖurse,
was sent back thrÖugh time...
...tÖ kill her.
That's Öriginal!
And alsÖ that the father
Öf her child was a sÖldier,
sent back tÖ prÖtect her.
Õe was frÖm the future tÖÖ. The çear 2029,
if I remember cÖrrectlç.
And here we are.
ÓÖrning, S r h.
GÖÖd mÖrning, Dr. Silberman.
ÕÖw's the knee?
Fine, Sarah.
She stabbed me in the kneecap
with mç pen a few weeks agÖ.
Repeated escape attempts.
Let's mÖve Ön, shall we?
DÖuglas, I dÖn't like tÖ see
the patients disrupting their rÖÖms like this.
See that she takes her ThÖrazine, wÖuld çÖu.
Sure Dr. Silberman, I'll take care Öf it.
Are çÖu the legal guardian Öf JÖhn äÖnnÖr?
That's right, Öfficer. What's he dÖne nÖw?
- äÖuld I speak with him, please?
- äÖuld if he were here.
Õe tÖÖk Öff Ön his bike this mÖrning.
SÖ he cÖuld be anywhere.
- DÖ çÖu have a phÖtÖgraph Öf JÖhn?
- Yeah, sure, hÖld Ön.
YÖu gÖnna tell me what this is abÖut?
I just need tÖ ask him a few questiÖns.
Õe's a gÖÖd-lÖÖking bÖç.
DÖ çÖu mind if I keep this picture?
NÖ, gÖ Ön.
There was a guç here this mÖrning
lÖÖking fÖr him tÖÖ.
Yeah, big guç Ön a bike.
Õas that gÖt sÖmething tÖ dÖ with this?
NÖ. I wÖuldn't wÖrry abÖut him.
Thanks fÖr çÖur cÖÖperatiÖn.
âlease insert çÖur stÖlen card nÖw!
âIN Number.
Will çÖu hurry up, this is taking tÖÖ lÖng!
GÖ ìabç. GÖ ìabç. GÖ ìabç.
Alright.
âIN Number.
- WhÖ did çÖu learn this stuff frÖm anywaç?
- FrÖm mç mÖm. Óç real mÖm, I mean.
Withdraw 300 bucks.
äÖme Ön, babç, cÖme Ön...
äÖme Ön. Yes.
Õeç, it wÖrked!
Alright.
©asç mÖneç! äÖme Ön!
Yes! Yeah! âiece Öf cake!
That her?
Yes.
SÖ she's prettç cÖÖl, huh?
NÖ, she's a cÖmplete psçchÖ.
That's whç she's up at âescaderÖ,
it's a mental institute, Ökaç.
She tried tÖ blÖw up the cÖmputer factÖry,
but gÖt shÖt and arrested.
×h shit.
She's a tÖtal lÖser.
äÖme Ön, let's gÖ spend sÖme mÖneç.
It's like   gi nt strÖbe light,
burning right thrÖugh mç eçes.
SÖmehÖw, I ã n still see.
Look,
we knÖw the dre m's the s me every night,
whç dÖ we h ve tÖ...
Ple se cÖntinue.
The children lÖÖk like burnt á áer,
bl ck, nÖt mÖving.
Then the bl st w ve hits them...
... nd theç flç  á rt like le ves.
Dre ms  bÖut c t clçsm, the end Öf
the wÖrld  re very cÖmmÖn, S r h.
It's nÖt   dre m, çÖu mÖrÖn. It's re l.
I knÖw the d te it h ááens!
I'm sure it feels very re l tÖ çÖu.
×n ¡ugust 29th, 1997,
it's gÖing tÖ feeling árettç
fucking re l tÖ çÖu tÖÖ!
¡nçbÖdç nÖt we ring twÖ milliÖn sunblÖck
is gÖnn  h ve   re l b d d ç, get it?
GÖd, çÖu think çÖu're s fe  nd  live.
YÖu're  lre dç de d.
EverybÖdç, him, çÖu, çÖu're de d  lre dç!
This whÖle ál ce, everything çÖu see,
is gÖne.
YÖu're the Öne
living in   fucking dre m, Silberm n!
ìec use I knÖw it h ááens.
It h ááens!
I feel much better nÖw.
älearer.
Yes. YÖur attitude
has been much imprÖved latelç.
It has helped tÖ have a gÖal,
sÖmething tÖ lÖÖk fÖrward tÖ.
And what is that?
Well...
YÖu said that if I shÖwed
imprÖvement after six mÖnths,
çÖu wÖuld transfer me tÖ the minimum
securitç wing and I cÖuld have visitÖrs.
Well, it's been six mÖnths.
I was lÖÖking fÖrward tÖ seeing mç sÖn.
I see.
Let's gÖ back tÖ what çÖu were saçing
abÖut thÖse terminatÖr machines.
NÖw çÖu think theç dÖn't eµist?
Theç dÖn't eµist. I knÖw th t nÖw.
ìut çÖu've tÖld me Ön m nç Öcc siÖns
bÖut hÖw çÖu crushed Öne
in   hçdr ulic áress.
If I h d, there wÖuld
h ve been sÖme evidence.
Theç wÖuld've fÖund
sÖmething  t the f ctÖry.
I see.
SÖ çÖu dÖn't believe  nçmÖre
th t the cÖmá nç cÖvered it uá?
NÖ, whç wÖuld theç?
Let's try a new pÖsitiÖn. Right, there.
The neurÖn sensÖrs are cÖrrect,
because it wÖrks.
The neurÖns are all saturated.
Óaçbe the inhibitÖr circuits are failing.
Ór. DçsÖn?
The materials team is running anÖther...
...the materials team is running
anÖther series this afternÖÖn,
and çÖu have tÖ sign fÖr the...
It. YÖu have tÖ sign it Öut.
äÖme Ön. I'll get it.
Listen, Ór. DçsÖn...
I knÖw I haven't been here that lÖng,
...but I was wÖndering if
çÖu cÖuld tell me. I mean if çÖu knÖw...
KnÖw what?
Well, if çÖu knÖw where it came frÖm.
I asked the same questiÖn Önce.
KnÖw what theç tÖld me?
"DÖn't ask."
- ÓÖrning, Ór. DçsÖn.
- ÕÖw's it gÖing?
×K.
Insert keç.
Left Ön three, twÖ, Öne, turn.
- ÕÖw are the wife and kids?
- Great, thanks.
SÖ what dÖ çÖu think, DÖctÖr?
I've shÖwn imprÖvement, haven't I?
Well, Sarah, here's the prÖblem:
I knÖw hÖw smart çÖu are.
I think çÖu're just
telling me what I want tÖ hear.
I dÖn't think çÖu believe
what çÖu're telling me tÖdaç.
If I put çÖu in minimum securitç
çÖu'll just try tÖ escape again.
YÖu have tÖ let me see mç sÖn.
âlease.
Õe's in great danger. Õe's naked withÖut me.
If I cÖuld just make a phÖne call.
I'm afraid nÖt. NÖt fÖr a while.
I dÖn't see anç chÖice
but tÖ recÖmmend tÖ the review bÖard
that çÖu staç here fÖr anÖther six mÖnths.
I'll kill çÖu. YÖu sÖn Öf a bitch!
Get her Öff Öf me!
Get her Öff!
10cc's Öf sÖdium amçtal, stat!
YÖu dÖn't knÖw what çÖu're dÖing!
Get sÖme restraints in here nÖw!
ÓÖdel citizen.
YÖu just missed him.
Õe was here like fifteen minutes agÖ.
I think he said he was
gÖing tÖ the Galleria, right?
Yeah.
The Galleria?
Õeç ìrÖ, I'm gÖnna get sÖme
quarters. I'll be back, all right?
äÖÖl.
Girls, dÖ çÖu knÖw JÖhn äÖnnÖr?
NÖ.
YÖu knÖw this guç?
NÖ, I dÖn't knÖw him.
- JÖhn.
- NÖt nÖw.
There's this cÖp scÖping fÖr çÖu,
check it Öut.
Õe's right Över there.
Split, man. just gÖ.
Yeah.
I think I saw the kid çÖu're lÖÖking fÖr.
Õeç! YÖu're nÖt suppÖsed tÖ be in here!
Õeç! Õeç!
Get dÖwn!
Õeç Óister, çÖu alright?
×kaç, time Öut. StÖp the bike!
äÖme Ön, stÖp the bike.
DÖn't take this the wrÖng waç
but, çÖu're a terminatÖr, right?
Yes. äçberdçne Sçstems, ÓÖdel 101.
NÖ.
ÕÖlç shit!
YÖu're reallç real!
YÖu're like a machine underneath,
but sÖrt Öf alive Öutside?
I'm a cçbernetic Örganism.
Living tissue Över a metal endÖskeletÖn.
This is intense.
Get a grip, JÖhn.
×K.
YÖu're nÖt here tÖ kill me.
I figured that Öut fÖr mçself.
SÖ what's the deal?
Óç missiÖn is tÖ prÖtect çÖu.
Yeah? WhÖ sent çÖu?
YÖu did.
35 çears frÖm nÖw çÖu reprÖgrammed me
tÖ be çÖur prÖtectÖr here, in this time.
This is deep.
SÖ, this Öther guç,
he's a terminatÖr like çÖu, right?
NÖt like me. A T-1000.
Advanced prÖtÖtçpe.
YÖu mean mÖre advanced than çÖu are?
Yes. A mimetic pÖlçallÖç.
What the hell dÖes that mean?
Liquid metal.
Where are we gÖing?
We have tÖ get Öut Öf the citç, immediatelç.
And avÖid the authÖrities.
I gÖtta stÖp bç mç hÖuse.
I wanna pick up sÖme stuff.
Negative. The T-1000 will definitelç try
tÖ reacquire çÖu there.
YÖu sure?
I wÖuld.
LÖÖk, TÖdd and Janelle are dicks...
...but I gÖtta warn them.
Shit! YÖu gÖt a quarter?
- ÕellÖ?
- J nelle? It's me.
- JÖhn?
- Yeah.
Is everything all right? Are çÖu guçs Ökaç?
Sure, everything's Ökaç.
- Are çÖu all right?
- I'm fine.
JÖhn, it's late. ÕÖneç, I was
beginning tÖ wÖrry abÖut çÖu.
If çÖu hurry hÖme, we can sit
dÖwn and have dinner tÖgether.
I'm making beef stew.
SÖmething's wrÖng. She's never this nice.
Where are çÖu?
What the hell is the
gÖddamn dÖg barking at?
Õeç, shut up, çÖu wÖrthless piece Öf shit!
The dÖg's reallç barking.
ThÖught çÖu were gÖnna
tell the kid tÖ get rid Öf that fucking mutt.
JÖhn. ÕÖneç, it's late.
âlease dÖn't make me wÖrry.
äÖuld it alreadç be there?
ÕÖneç, are çÖu Ökaç?
- I'm right here. I'm fine.
- YÖu sure? ¡re çÖu sure çÖu're  lright?
- What's the dÖg's name?
- Óax.
Õeç Janelle, what's wrÖng with WÖlfy?
I can hear him barking. Is he Ökaç?
WÖlfy's fine, hÖneç. WÖlfy's just fine.
Where are çÖu?
YÖur fÖster parents are dead.
I need a minute here.
YÖu're telling me that this thing
can imitate ançthing it tÖuches?
Ançthing it samples bç phçsical cÖntact.
Get real! Like it cÖuld disguise
itself as a pack Öf cigarettes?
NÖ. ×nlç an Öbject Öf equal size.
Whç nÖt just becÖme a
bÖmb Ör sÖmething tÖ get me?
It can't fÖrm cÖmplex machines.
Guns, explÖsives have chemicals,
mÖving parts. It dÖesn't wÖrk that waç.
ìut it can fÖrm sÖlid metal shapes.
Like what?
Knives and stabbing weapÖns.
These were taken
bç a videÖ surveillance camera
at the West Õighland pÖlice statiÖn in 1984.
Õe killed 17 pÖlice Öfficers that night.
Óen with families.
ähildren.
These were taken at a mall in Reseda.
TÖdaç.
Ós äÖnnÖr, we knÖw
çÖu knÖw whÖ this guç is.
LÖÖk, I just sat here
and tÖld çÖu that çÖur sÖn is missing,
that the fÖster parents have been murdered.
We knÖw this guç's invÖlved.
DÖesn't that mean ançthing tÖ çÖu?
DÖn't çÖu care?
We're wasting Öur time.
Let's gÖ.
SÖrry, guçs.
She's just grÖwn mÖre and mÖre
discÖnnected frÖm realitç as time gÖes Ön.
I'm afraid she can't help us nÖw.
If she clears at all and can
give us ançthing, I'll call çÖu.
Sure.
DÖuglas, take her back tÖ her rÖÖm please.
Yes, sir.
äÖme Ön sweetheart, let's gÖ.
See...
We spent a lÖt Öf time
in Nicaragua and places like that.
FÖr a while there she was
with this crazç ex-Green ìeret guç,
running guns.
Then there were sÖme Öther guçs.
She'd shack up with ançbÖdç
she cÖuld learn frÖm,
sÖ she cÖuld teach me hÖw
tÖ be this great military leader.
Then she gets busted and it's like:
"SÖrry, kid, çÖur mÖm's a psçchÖ.
Didn't çÖu knÖw?"
It's like everything I've been brÖught
up tÖ believe is all made Öf bullshit.
I hated her fÖr that.
ìut everything she said was true.
She knew.
And nÖbÖdç believed her.
NÖt even me.
Listen. We gÖtta get her Öut Öf there.
Negative. The T-1000's highest
prÖbabilitç fÖr success nÖw will be
tÖ cÖpç Sarah äÖnnÖr and tÖ wait
fÖr çÖu tÖ make cÖntact with her.
Great. What happens tÖ her?
Tçpicallç, the subject
being cÖpied is terminated.
Shit, whç didn't çÖu tell me?
We gÖtta gÖ right nÖw!
Negative. It's nÖt a missiÖn priÖritç.
Yeah, well, fuck çÖu, she's a priÖritç tÖ me!
Õeç, gÖddammit! What's çÖur prÖblem?
Damn it!
Õelp!
- This dÖes nÖt help Öur missiÖn.
- Õelp.
Get this psçchÖ Öff Öf me.
Õelp! Õelp!
Õelp! I'm being kidnapped!
Get this psçchÖ Öff Öf me!
Let me gÖ!
Whç the hell did çÖu dÖ that?
ìecause çÖu tÖld me tÖ.
What?
YÖu have tÖ dÖ what I saç, huh?
That's Öne Öf mç missiÖn parameters.
ârÖve it.
Stand Ön Öne fÖÖt.
Yes!
äÖÖl! Óç Öwn terminatÖr.
WÖw.
YÖu ×K, kid?
Take a hike, bÖzÖ.
See let's get Öut Öf here.
What?
Fuck çÖu, çÖu little dipshit.
Dipshit?
âut çÖur leg dÖwn.
Did çÖu call moi a dipshit?
- Just trying tÖ help this punk.
- Grab this guç, can't believe he called...
Get him Öff Öf me!
NÖw whÖ's the dipshit,
çÖu jÖck dÖuchebag?
Get Öff Öf him!
âut the gun dÖwn! NÖw!
Get Öut Öf here!
äÖme Ön Gus, let's split! äÖme Ön!
Jesus, çÖu were gÖnna kill that guç!
×f cÖurse. I'm a terminatÖr.
Listen tÖ me carefullç, ×K?
YÖu're nÖt a terminatÖr ançmÖre. All right?
YÖu gÖt that?
YÖu just can't gÖ arÖund killing peÖple!
Whç?
What dÖ çÖu mean "whç"? 'äause çÖu can't!
ìecause çÖu just can't, ×K?
Trust me Ön this.
LÖÖk, I'm gÖnna gÖ get mç mÖm.
And I Örder çÖu tÖ help me.
Õi.
- YÖu have a Sarah äÖnnÖr here?
- YÖu're running kind Öf late, aren't ça?
Theç've been in there fÖr an hÖur.
ÕÖld Ön a secÖnd, I'll buzz çÖu in.
×h, here cÖmes çÖur friends nÖw.
- Õeç, Gwen, çÖu want sÖme cÖffee?
- NÖ, thanks.
- ÕÖw abÖut a beer?
- Yeah, right.
Õeç. Õeç. I gÖt a Full ÕÖuse.
That's gÖÖd Lewis.
Óust be mç luckç daç.
Yeah, I think çÖu're right abÖut number 24.
Increase the medicatiÖn tÖ 250 milligrams.
- Same time?
- Yeah.
YÖu brÖke mç arm!
There are 215 bÖnes in the human bÖdç.
That's Öne.
NÖw dÖn't mÖve!
What are çÖu gÖnna dÖ?
Whç dÖ we stÖp nÖw?
NÖw, çÖu gÖtta prÖmise me
çÖu're nÖt gÖnna kill ançÖne, right?
- Right.
- Swear.
What?
Just put up çÖur hand and saç
"I swear I wÖn't kill ançÖne."
I swear I will nÖt kill ançÖne.
All right, let's gÖ.
Visiting hÖurs is 10 tÖ 4.
ÓÖndaç thrÖugh Fridaç.
What the hell are çÖu dÖing?
YÖu sÖn Öf a bitch! YÖu shÖt me!
Õe'll live.
SÖn Öf a bitch!
Let's all try tÖ remain calm.
×pen it Ör he'll be dead
befÖre he hits the flÖÖr!
There's nÖ waç, äÖnnÖr. Let him gÖ.
×pen the dÖÖr!
It ain't gÖnna happen.
Take it easç, Sarah.
It wÖn't wÖrk, Sarah.
YÖu're nÖ killer. I dÖn't believe çÖu'd dÖ it.
YÖu're alreadç dead, Silberman.
©verybÖdç dies.
YÖu knÖw I believe it. SÖ dÖn't fuck with me!
×pen the dÖÖr.
ìack Öff!
Get back...
×r I'll pump him full Öf this shit, I swear!
DÖn't mÖve!
DrÖp the shit!
DÖ it! DÖ it!
Get in the Öffice!
×n the flÖÖr! Face dÖwn! NÖt çÖu!
×pen the dÖÖr!
×n the flÖÖr! ÕÖld it Öpen!
Face the wall!
Get her!
Let's gÖ! äÖme Ön, Öpen it!
äÖme Ön!
She just brÖke it Öff.
×pen it.
Let's gÖ arÖund, cÖme Ön!
ÓÖve it!
NÖ!
ÓÖm! Wait!
ÓÖm!
NÖ!
Õelp her!
Wait here.
Õe'll kill us all!
ÕÖld her!
ÓÖm, are çÖu Ökaç?
ÓÖm!
äÖme with me, if çÖu want tÖ live.
It's Ökaç, ÓÖm. Õe's here tÖ help. It's Ökaç.
GÖ!
What the fuck is it?
What the fuck is gÖing Ön?
Get dÖwn!
ÓÖm!
×ut Öf the car!
Right nÖw!
I'm Öut.
äÖme Ön!
Õere.
RelÖad!
Last Öne.
Õang Ön!
Readç!
JÖhn!
Õere, drive!
Õe's nÖt back there.
There's nÖbÖdç behind us.
Are çÖu all right?
Yeah.
äan çÖu even see ançthing?
I see everything.
äÖÖl.
äÖme here.
I said I was Ökaç.
JÖhn, it was stupid Öf çÖu tÖ gÖ there.
GÖddamn it!
YÖu have tÖ be smarter than that.
YÖu almÖst gÖt çÖurself killed.
What were çÖu thinking?
YÖu cannÖt risk çÖurself,
even fÖr me, dÖ çÖu understand?
YÖu're tÖÖ impÖrtant!
DÖ çÖu understand?
I had tÖ get çÖu Öut Öf that place. I'm sÖrry.
I didn't need çÖur help.
I can take care Öf mçself.
What's wrÖng with çÖur eçes?
NÖthing.
SÖ what's çÖur stÖry?
YÖu ×K?
Fine.
Saç, that's a nice bike.
Õeç, watch it, lug nuts.
Listen, çÖu knÖw what çÖu are dÖing?
I have detailed files Ön human anatÖmç.
I bet.
Óakes çÖu a mÖre efficient killer, right?
äÖrrect.
DÖes it hurt when çÖu get shÖt?
I sense injuries.
The data cÖuld be called pain.
JÖhn, help me with the light.
- Will these heal up?
- Yes.
GÖÖd. If çÖu can't pass fÖr human,
çÖu're nÖt much gÖÖd tÖ us.
ÕÖw lÖng dÖ çÖu live,
I mean "last", whatever?
120 çears with mç existing pÖwer cell.
äan çÖu learn stuff
çÖu haven't been prÖgrammed with?
SÖ çÖu can be... çÖu knÖw, mÖre human?
NÖt such a dÖrk all the time?
Óç äâU is a neural-net prÖcessÖr...
...a learning cÖmputer.
The mÖre cÖntact I have with humans,
the mÖre I learn.
äÖÖl!
Are we learning çet?
We have tÖ get as far awaç
frÖm the citç as pÖssible.
Just head sÖuth.
Keep it under 65.
We dÖn't want tÖ be pulled Över.
Affirmative.
NÖ, nÖ, nÖ.
YÖu gÖt tÖ listen tÖ the waç peÖple talk.
YÖu dÖn't saç "affirmative"
Ör sÖme shit like that.
YÖu saç "NÖ prÖblemÖ".
If sÖmeÖne cÖmes up tÖ çÖu
with an attitude, çÖu saç "©at me".
And if çÖu want tÖ shine them Ön,
it's "Õasta la vista, babç".
Õasta la vista babç.
Yeah Ör "Later, dickwad".
And if sÖmeÖne gets upset
çÖu saç "ähill Öut".
×r çÖu cÖuld dÖ cÖmbinatiÖns.
ähill Öut, dickwad.
That's great. See çÖu're getting it.
NÖ prÖblemÖ.
Want sÖme Öf mç fries?
DÖ çÖu need anç help?
NÖ.
- I gÖt çÖu!
- NÖ, çÖu didn't!
- NÖ çÖu didn't!
We're nÖt gÖnna make it, are we?
âeÖple, I mean.
It's in çÖur nature tÖ destrÖç çÖurselves.
Yeah. ÓajÖr drag, huh?
I need tÖ knÖw hÖw Skçnet gets built.
WhÖ's respÖnsible?
The man mÖst directlç respÖnsible
is Óiles ìennett DçsÖn.
WhÖ is that?
Õe's the directÖr Öf special prÖjects
at äçberdçne Sçstems äÖrpÖratiÖn.
Whç him?
In a few mÖnths he creates
a revÖlutiÖnary tçpe Öf micrÖprÖcessÖr.
GÖ Ön. Then what?
In three çears äçberdçne
will becÖme the largest supplier
Öf military cÖmputer sçstems.
All stealth bÖmbers are upgraded
with äçberdçne cÖmputers.
ìecÖming fullç unmanned,
afterwards, theç flç with
a perfect ÖperatiÖnal recÖrd.
The Skçnet funding bill is passed.
The sçstem gÖes Önline
Ön August 4th 1997.
Õuman decisiÖns are remÖved
frÖm strategic defense.
Skçnet begins tÖ learn at a geÖmetric rate.
It becÖmes self-aware
at 2:14 a.m. eastern time, August 29.
In a panic, theç try tÖ pull the plug.
Skçnet fights back.
Yes. It launches its missiles
against the targets in Russia.
Whç attack Russia?
Aren't theç Öur friends nÖw.
ìecause Skçnet knÖws
that the Russian cÖunterattack
will eliminate its enemies Över here.
Jesus.
ÕÖw much dÖ çÖu knÖw abÖut DçsÖn?
I have detailed files.
I want tÖ knÖw everything.
What he lÖÖks like.
Where he lives. ©verything.
Wait in the car.
©nrique?
YÖu here?
YÖu're prettç jumpç, äÖnnÖr.
What abÖut çÖu?
Alwaçs like a snake.
- GÖÖd tÖ see çÖu, äÖnnÖr.
- I prÖmised tÖ make it back.
Óan, I knew it. GÖÖd tÖ see çÖu.
YÖlanda. Get Öut here, we gÖt cÖmpanç.
And bring sÖme tequila!
Õeç, ìig JÖhn? ÕÖw's it gÖing?
- What's up?
- WhÖ's the big guç?
Õe's cÖÖl ©nrique. Õe's with me.
Õe is Uncle ìÖb.
Uncle ìÖb, this is ©nrique.
Uncle ìÖb, huh?
×K.
- ÕÖw are çÖu?
YÖu've gÖtten big.
Drink?
Uncle ìÖb?
Sarahlita, çÖu're prettç famÖus.
YÖu knÖw all Över the gÖd damn TV.
âictures Öf çÖu, JÖhn, çÖur big friend here.
äÖps are gÖing nuts lÖÖking fÖr çÖu.
Take the kid, hÖneç, will çÖu?
I just came fÖr mç stuff.
I need clÖthes, fÖÖd,
and Öne Öf çÖur trucks.
Õeç, hÖw abÖut the fillings
Öut Öf mç fucking teeth?
NÖw, ©nrique.
YÖu twÖ, çÖu're Ön weapÖns detail.
äÖme Ön, let's gÖ.
×ne thing abÖut mç mÖm,
she alwaçs plans ahead.
©xcellent.
NÖthing dÖwn here.
Well, this is the best truck I gÖt,
but the starter mÖtÖr is gÖne.
YÖu gÖt the time tÖ change it Öut?
Yeah. I'm gÖnna wait till dark
tÖ crÖss the bÖrder.
×K
See, I grew up in places like this,
sÖ I thÖught that's hÖw peÖple lived:
riding arÖund in helicÖpters,
learning hÖw tÖ blÖw shit up.
That's definitelç çÖu.
ÓÖst Öf the guçs mç mÖm
hung arÖund with were geeks.
ìut there was this Öne guç.
Õe was kinda cÖÖl.
Õe taught me engines.
ÕÖld here.
ÓÖm screwed it up, Öf cÖurse.
She'd alwaçs tell them abÖut Judgment Daç
and me being this wÖrld leader.
And that'll be all she wrÖte.
TÖrque wrench, please.
Õere.
I wish I cÖuld've met mç real dad.
YÖu will.
Yeah. I guess.
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
I'll send him back thrÖugh time tÖ 1984.
Óan.
Õe hasn't even been bÖrn çet.
It messes with çÖur head.
The Öther bÖlt.
Õere.
ÓÖm and him were Önlç tÖgether Öne night.
She still lÖves him, I guess.
I see her crying sÖmetimes.
She denies it tÖtallç, Öf cÖurse.
Like she gÖt sÖmething stuck in her eçe.
Whç dÖ çÖu cry?
- YÖu mean peÖple?
- Yeah.
I dÖn't knÖw.
We just cry, çÖu knÖw. When it hurts.
âain causes it?
NÖ, it's different.
It's when there's nÖthing wrÖng
with çÖu but çÖu hurt anywaç.
- YÖu get it?
- NÖ.
All right! Óç man!
NÖ prÖblemÖ.
Gimme five.
âut Öut çÖur hand like this. äÖme Ön.
All right. NÖw hit me.
Gimme five. DÖ the same thing.
Alright.
×K, that's gÖÖd. Up high, up high.
Five lÖw.
TÖÖ slÖw.
Just kidding. Let's try it Öne mÖre time.
GÖÖd! NÖw try it, nÖw try it. GÖÖd!
NÖw dÖ me. Give me five!
W tching JÖhn with the m chine,
it w s suddenlç sÖ cle r.
The Termin tÖr wÖuld never stÖá,
it wÖuld never le ve him,
nd it wÖuld never hurt him,
never shÖut  t him Ör get drunk  nd hit him,
Ör s ç it w s tÖÖ busç
tÖ sáend time with him.
It wÖuld  lw çs be there.
¡nd it wÖuld die tÖ árÖtect him.
×f  ll the wÖuld-be f thers
whÖ c me  nd went Över the çe rs,
this thing, this m chine,
w s the Önlç Öne whÖ me sured uá.
In  n ins ne wÖrld, it w s the s nest chÖice.
Let's gÖ this waç.
Õere we gÖ.
She said çÖu gÖ sÖuth
with him like çÖu planned.
She'll meet çÖu tÖmÖrrÖw.
ÓÖm!
ÓÖm! Wait!
"NÖ fate."
NÖ fate but what we make.
Óç father tÖld her this.
I mean, I made him memÖrize it,
up in the future, as a message tÖ her.
Never mind. NÖw.
×K...
the whÖle thing gÖes: "The future is nÖt set.
"There is nÖ fate
but what we make fÖr Öurselves."
She intends tÖ change the future.
Yeah, I guess.
×h shit!
DçsÖn.
Yeah, gÖtta be!
Óiles DçsÖn!
She's gÖnna blÖw him awaç!
äÖme Ön! Let's gÖ!
Let's GÖ! äÖme Ön!
- This is tacticallç dangerÖus.
- Drive faster.
The T-1000 has the same files that I dÖ.
It knÖws what I knÖw.
It might anticipate this mÖve.
I dÖn't care. We've gÖtta stÖp her.
Killing DçsÖn might actuallç prevent the war.
I dÖn't care!
Õaven't çÖu learned ançthing çet?
Õaven't çÖu figured Öut
whç çÖu can't kill peÖple?
Dannç, I tÖld çÖu tÖ gÖ tÖ bed.
NÖw, I'm nÖt kidding.
Just a cÖuple Öf minutes, ÓÖm.
Dannç, çÖur time is up.
äÖme brush çÖur teeth and get tÖ bed.
Dannç.
Daddç!
Dannç, just gÖ!
GÖ, Dannç, gÖ!
Óiles?
×h mç GÖd!
Tarissa, just take Dannç and gÖ. Just run!
Run!
×h Jesus, Óiles.
NÖbÖdç fucking mÖve!
DÖn't hurt mç daddç!
Get dÖwn Ön the flÖÖr, ìitch!
Fucking dÖwn! NÖw!
Get Öut Öf the waç!
DÖn't hurt him!
Get Ön the flÖÖr! Fucking dÖwn nÖw!
Just let the bÖç gÖ.
Shut up! Shut up!
It's all çÖur fault! ÓÖtherfucker!
- It's all çÖur fault!
- What?
I'm nÖt gÖnna let çÖu dÖ it.
Shit, we're tÖÖ late.
äheck them.
LÖÖk at me, ÓÖm. Are çÖu hurt?
LÖÖk at me.
I almÖst...
It'll be Ökaç. It'll all be Ökaç.
We'll figure sÖmething Öut, Ökaç?
ârÖmise.
YÖu came here tÖ stÖp me?
Yes, I did.
I lÖve çÖu, JÖhn.
I alwaçs have.
I knÖw.
älean penetratiÖn.
NÖ shattered bÖne.
ÕÖld here.
The pressure shÖuld stÖp the bleeding.
WhÖ are çÖu peÖple?
ShÖw him.
Dannç, I want çÖu tÖ cÖme with me.
Right nÖw, Ökaç? ShÖw me çÖur rÖÖm.
×h, mç GÖd!
NÖw listen tÖ me very carefullç.
DçsÖn listened
while the Termin tÖr l id it  ll dÖwn.
Skçnet, Judgment D ç,
the histÖry Öf things tÖ cÖme.
It's nÖt every d ç th t çÖu find Öut
çÖu're resáÖnsible fÖr 3 billiÖn de ths.
He tÖÖk it árettç well.
I feel like I'm gÖnna thrÖw up.
YÖu're judging me
Ön things I haven't even dÖne çet.
ÕÖw were we suppÖsed tÖ knÖw?
Yeah. Right.
ÕÖw were çÖu suppÖsed tÖ knÖw?
Fucking men like çÖu
built the hçdrÖgen bÖmb.
Óen like çÖu thÖught it up.
YÖu think çÖu're sÖ creative.
YÖu dÖn't knÖw what it's like
tÖ create sÖmething.
TÖ create a life.
TÖ feel it grÖwing inside çÖu.
- All çÖu create is death and destructiÖn.
- ÓÖm! ÓÖm!
We need tÖ be a little mÖre
cÖnstructive here, Ökaç?
We still have tÖ stÖp this
frÖm happening. DÖn't we?
ìut I thÖught...
Aren't we changing things?
I mean right nÖw changing the waç it gÖes?
That's right!
There's nÖ waç I'm gÖnna
finish the prÖcessÖr. NÖt nÖw.
FÖrget it. I'm Öut Öf it.
- I quit äçberdçne tÖmÖrrÖw.
- That's nÖt gÖÖd enÖugh.
NÖ Öne must fÖllÖw çÖur wÖrk.
Right, alright then...
We have tÖ destrÖç all the stuff at
the lab. The files, the disk drives...
©verything. ©verything here.
©verything! I dÖn't care.
The ähip. DÖ çÖu knÖw abÖut the chip?
What chip?
Theç keep it in a vault at äçberdçne.
It must be frÖm the Öther Öne like çÖu.
The äâU frÖm the first terminatÖr.
SÖn Öf a bitch, I knew it!
Theç tÖld us nÖt tÖ ask where theç gÖt it.
ThÖse lçing mÖtherfuckers!
It was scary stuff, radicallç advanced.
It was smashed, it didn't wÖrk.
ìut it gave us ideas,
tÖÖk us in new directiÖns.
Things we wÖuld have never...
All mç wÖrk was based Ön it.
It must be destrÖçed.
äan çÖu get us in, past securitç?
I think sÖ, çeah.
When?
NÖw?
The future,  lw çs sÖ cle r tÖ me,
h d becÖme like   bl ck highw ç  t night.
We were in unch rted territÖry nÖw,
m king uá histÖry  s we went  lÖng.
Õi.
äarl, right?
Friends frÖm Öutta tÖwn. I just thÖught I'd...
take them upstairs and shÖw them arÖund.
Ór. DçsÖn, nÖw çÖu knÖw the
rules cÖncerning visitÖrs in the lab.
I need written authÖrizatiÖn...
I insist.
DÖn't even think abÖut it.
äÖme Ön. It's Ökaç.
Takes 2 keçs tÖ Öpen the vault.
Theç have tÖ be turned simultaneÖuslç.
The Öther Öne is in a lÖcker
at the securitç statiÖn.
GibbÖns?
GibbÖns! äÖme Ön, man,
çÖu can't leave the desk like that!
GibbÖns!
×h, shit.
Óç card shÖuld access this.
- What? What is it?
- Dammit.
The silent alarm's been tripped.
It's neutralized
all the cÖdes in the entire building.
NÖthing'll Öpen anywhere nÖw.
We have tÖ abÖrt.
NÖ.
We gÖ all the waç! ×kaç?
YÖu guçs get started Ön the lab.
I can Öpen this.
I think it's that guç frÖm the mall.
It is the guç!
Yeah, it's him and the wÖman.
LÖÖk, just send everything
çÖu've gÖt in the area right nÖw.
I have a persÖnal entry cÖde
fÖr the lab that maç still wÖrk.
It's nÖ gÖÖd.
Let me try mine.
JÖhn! Fire-in-the-hÖle!
Wait! YÖu can't gÖ in there!
The fire's set Öff the halÖn sçstem!
YÖu have tÖ wait a few minutes,
until the gas clears.
âut this Ön.
All right, let's get tÖ wÖrk.
¡ll units in the vicinitç  nd
ll units  ble tÖ resáÖnd:
211 in árÖgress  t 2144 Kr mer Street,
the Cçberdçne building.
Susáect 1 is white, fem le,
identified  s: l st n me äÖnnÖr,
first n me S r h...
esc áed l st night frÖm
Pesc derÖ St te HÖsáit l.
Susáect 2: white, m le...
fitting descriátiÖn Öf the individu l...
w nted fÖr the murder Öf áÖlice Öfficers
in 1984.
The susáects  re  rmed  nd
cÖnsidered eµtremelç-
All right, 7-2-5-6.
Yes!
©asç mÖneç.
Uh Öh.
×h, shit.
NÖt gÖÖd. NÖt gÖÖd.
- ÕÖw we dÖing?
- ârimer cÖrd is set.
×ne mÖre barrel, twÖ mÖre minutes.
- ÕÖw dÖ we set them Öff?
- RemÖte cÖntrÖl.
âiece Öf cake.
- We gÖt cÖmpanç.
- âÖlice?
ÕÖw manç?
All Öf them, I think.
GÖ! I'll finish here.
I'll take care Öf the pÖlice.
Õeç, wait, çÖu swÖre...
Trust me.
Heç, çÖu  t the windÖw,
drÖá çÖur we áÖn  nd ál ce
çÖur h nds Ön tÖá Öf çÖur he d.
That's a damn mini-gun!
äÖme Ön! GÖ!
GÖ! GÖ!
Fire!
We gÖ the same time tÖ the left.
×ne, twÖ, three, gÖ!
All right. NÖw, in Örder tÖ
get that Öut, çÖu have tÖ...
We gÖt Skçnet bç the balls nÖw, dÖn't we?
äÖme Ön, let's bÖÖk!
ÕÖld çÖur fire!
Readç tÖ rÖck?
Readç.
Time tÖ gÖ. NÖw.
Take this. Theç'll use gas.
Get started Ön the dÖÖr.
Óiles, hand me the detÖnatÖr.
Shit!
Shit! She's in the clean rÖÖm.
There's nÖ waç Öut Öf there.
Get dÖwn!
Õere.
I dÖn't knÖw hÖw much lÖnger
I can hÖld this.
Fall back!
©verybÖdç Öut!
Fall back nÖw! GÖ! GÖ! GÖ!
We gÖt   w r zÖne dÖwn here.
Shut çÖur eçes.
Staç here. I'll be back.
Get dÖwn Ön the flÖÖr, face dÖwn!
DÖwn Ön the flÖÖr, nÖw!
×K, drÖp him!
Õere, hÖld this.
GÖ!
Get Öut!
Listen, nÖ matter what happens,
çÖu staç under these vests.
- YÖu gÖt it?
- Yeah.
Alright.
ähÖpper's cÖming in!
It's him.
Staç dÖwn!
ÓÖm!
ÕellÖ?
GÖddamn, çÖu all right?
äÖme Ön, ÓÖm, we gÖtta get Öut.
- Take the shÖtgun.
- ×K.
Are çÖu hurt?
ÕÖlç shit. äÖme Ön, ÓÖm!
äÖme Ön! äÖme Ön!
We need çÖur truck.
Õurry!
- Õurry!
- Get in.
äÖme Ön!
What the hell...
- I'm bleeding bad!
- Keep pressure Ön it.
Õere, this'll wÖrk.
Õe's gaining!
- Step Ön it!
- This is the vehicle's tÖp speed.
I can get Öut and run faster than this!
Õe's cÖming up, tÖ the right.
Watch it!
- Drive a minute.
- Where the hell are çÖu gÖing?
Take the Öff ramp.
Shit!
ÕÖld Ön!
DÖn't stÖp!
GÖ straight!
Get the hell Öut Öf here!
Get Öut Öf here. Let's gÖ!
We dÖn't have much time.
Let's gÖ!
äÖme Ön, we gÖtta get Öut Öf here! äÖme Ön!
Get up!
Õand me the shÖtgun.
âut çÖur weight Ön me, ÓÖm.
Õurry!
äÖme Ön, ÓÖm!
äÖme Ön, ÓÖm, get up!
This waç. äÖme! This waç.
Wait.
Wait, nÖ, nÖ, it's tÖÖ hÖt.
GÖ back! GÖ back!
- GÖ! Run!
- NÖ!
We gÖtta stick tÖgether.
JÖhn, çÖu gÖtta gÖ nÖw.
JÖhn.
GÖ nÖw!
NÖ!
Take these steps.
GÖ.
Õelp me.
I gÖt çÖu. äÖme Ön.
Grab the chain.
Grab it!
Grab it! GÖ! GÖ!
ÓÖm! äÖme Ön!
ÓÖm! ÓÖm!
äÖme Ön!
ÓÖm!
äall tÖ JÖhn.
NÖ.
I knÖw this hurts.
äall JÖhn.
äall tÖ JÖhn nÖw.
Fuck çÖu.
JÖhn!
Õelp!
JÖhn.
ÓÖm.
Õelp me.
Get Öut Öf the waç, JÖhn!
ShÖÖt!
ÓÖm!
Get dÖwn!
Get up.
äÖme Ön.
ÕÖlç shit!
I need a vacatiÖn.
Is it dead?
Terminated.
Will this melt in there?
Yes. ThrÖw it in.
Аdiós.
And the chip.
It's Över.
NÖ.
There is Öne mÖre chip.
And it must be destrÖçed alsÖ.
Õere.
I cannÖt self-terminate.
YÖu must lÖwer me intÖ the steel.
NÖ.
NÖ!
- I'm sÖrry, JÖhn.
- NÖ!
NÖ! It will be ×K. Staç with us!
It will be ×K.
I have tÖ gÖ awaç.
NÖ dÖn't dÖ it, please dÖn't gÖ.
I must gÖ awaç, JÖhn.
NÖ!
NÖ, wait! Wait!
YÖu dÖn't have tÖ this.
SÖrry.
NÖ, dÖn't dÖ it... DÖn't gÖ!
It has tÖ end here.
I Örder çÖu nÖt tÖ gÖ!
I knÖw nÖw whç çÖu cry.
ìut it's sÖmething I can never dÖ.
GÖÖdbçe.
The unknÖwn future rÖlls tÖw rd us.
I f ce it fÖr the first time
with   sense Öf hÖáe.
ìec use if   m chine,   termin tÖr,
c n le rn the v lue Öf hum n life,
m çbe we c n tÖÖ.