'Three billion
human lives ended
on August 29, 1997.
'The survivors of the nuclear fire
called the war Judgment Day.
'They lived only to face
a new nightmare:
'the war against the machines.'
'The computer which controlled
the machines, Skynet,
'sent two Terminators
back through time.
'Their mission, to destroy the leader
of the human resistance,
'John Connor, my son.
'The first Terminator was programmed
to strike at me in the year 1984,
'before John was born.
'It failed.
'The second was set to strike at John
himself when he was still a child.
'As before, the resistance was able
to send a lone warrior,
'a protector for John.
'It was just a question of which one
of them would reach him first.'
I need your clothes, your boots
and your motorcycle.
You forgot to say please.
Ooh!
Oh!
Aagh! Get him off me!
Agh!
Pull it out! Pull it out!
Agh! Pull it out!
Take it.
"Bad To The Bone")
♪ Now, on the day I was born...
Can't let you
take the man's wheels, son.
Now, get off before I put you down.
♪ She said, "Leave this one alone"
♪ She could tell right away
♪ That I was bad to the bone
♪ Bad to the bone...
That's it, goddamn it.
♪ B-b-b-b-bad
♪ Bad to the bone
♪ Broke a thousand hearts
♪ Before I met you
♪ I'll break a thousand more, baby
♪ Before I am through
♪ I wanna be yours, pretty baby
♪ Yours and yours alone
♪ I'm here to tell ya I'm bad
♪ Bad to the bone
♪ B-b-b-b-bad
♪ B-b-b-b-bad ♪
R-31 David, Sherman Code Six
at the Sixth Street Bridge
and Santa Fe
on electrical disturbance.
'Ten-four, R-31 David.'
Ugh!
John!
John, get in there and clean up
that pigsty of yours.
John!
Your foster parents
are kind of dicks, huh?
I swear, I have had it
with that goddamn kid.
- He won't even answer me anymore.
- Honey, move.
Would you get off your butt
and help me?
- Todd!
- What?
He hasn't cleaned that room of his
in a month.
Well, it's an emergency.
Hang on. I'll get right on it.
- Come on!
- John!
C'mon! Get your ass inside.
Do what your mother tells you.
She's not my mother, Todd.
This next patient is interesting.
I've been following
the case for years.
A 29-year-old female,
diagnosed as acute
schizo-affective disorder.
The usual indicators:
depression, anxiety,
violent acting out,
delusions of persecution.
The delusional architecture
is fairly unique.
She believes that a machine
called the Terminator,
which looked human, of course,
was sent back through time
to kill her.
That's original.
And also,
that the father of her child
was a soldier
sent back to protect her.
- No?
- He was from the future too.
The year 2029,
if I remember correctly.
And here we are.
Morning, Sarah.
Good morning, Dr Silberman.
How's the knee?
Fine, Sarah.
She, er... stabbed me in the kneecap
with my pen a few weeks ago.
Repeated escape attempts...
Let's move on, shall we?
Lewis.
I don't like to see the patients
disrupting their rooms like this.
- See she takes her Thorazine.
- Sure. I'll take care of it.
Time to take you meds, Connor.
You take it.
You gotta be good.
You're up for review this afternoon.
I'm not taking it.
- I don't want any trouble.
- Ain't no trouble...
Yeah, zap her.
Last call, sugar.
Sweet dreams.
Are you the legal guardian
of John Connor?
That's right, Officer.
What's he done now?
- Could I speak with him, please?
- You could if he were here.
He took off on his bike this morning
so he could be anywhere.
- Do you have a photograph of John?
- Yeah. Hold on.
You gonna tell me what this is about?
I just need to ask him
a few questions.
He's a good-looking boy.
Do you mind if I keep this picture?
No, go on. There was a guy here
this morning looking for him, too.
Yeah, a big guy on a bike.
Has that got something
to do with this?
No. I wouldn't worry about him.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Please insert
your stolen card now.
PIN number.
Hurry up.
This is taking too long.
Go, baby. Go, baby.
All right!
- PIN number 9003.
- Where'd you learn this stuff from?
From my mom.
My real mom, I mean.
Withdraw three-zero-zero bucks.
Come on, baby. Come on! Come on!
- Yes!
- Hey, it worked.
All right. Easy money. Come on!
Yes! Piece of cake.
- Is that her?
- Yes.
- She's pretty cool, huh?
- No, she's a complete psycho.
That's why she's at Pescadero.
It's a mental institute, OK?
She tried to blow up
a computer factory,
but she got shot and arrested.
No shit.
She's a total loser.
Come on.
Let's go spend some money.
Sarah.
Sarah, wake up.
Kyle?
You're dead.
Where's our son, Sarah?
They took him away from me.
- He's the target now.
- I know!
He's alone.
You have to protect him.
I know.
You tell me how I am supposed
to do that.
He doesn't even
believe me anymore.
I've lost him.
You're strong, Sarah.
- Stronger than you ever thought.
- No.
On your feet, soldier!
I love you. I always will.
- I need you.
- I'll always be with you.
Remember the message?
"The future is not set.
"There is no fate
but what we make for ourselves."
Stay with me.
There's not much time left
in the world, Sarah.
KWQ, don't go!
Kyle!
It's like a giant strobe light,
burning right to my eyes.
Somehow I can still see.
We know
the dream's the same every night.
- Why do I have to...
- Please continue.
Children look like burnt paper.
Black.
Not moving.
And then the blast wave hits them.
And they fly apart like leaves.
Dreams of cataclysm,
the end of the world are very common.
It's not a dream, you moron.
It's real.
- I know the date it happens.
- I'm sure it feels very real to you.
On August 291997, it's gonna feel
pretty fuckin' real to you, too!
Anybody not wearing
two-million sunblock
is gonna have
a real bad day. Get it?
God! You think you're safe and alive.
You're already dead. Everybody!
Him. You. You're dead already.
This whole place,
everything you see is gone!
You're the one
living in a fucking dream, Silberman!
Cos I know it happened!
It happened!
I feel much better now.
Clearer.
Yes, your attitude has been
much improved lately.
It's helped me to have a goal,
something to look forward to.
What is that?
Well, you said that if I showed
improvement after six months,
you would transfer me
to the minimum security wing
and I could have visitors.
Well, it's been six months and...
I was looking forward
to seeing my son.
I see.
Let's go back to what you were saying
about those Terminator machines.
Now you think they don't exist?
They don't exist.
I know that now.
But you've told me
on many occasions
about how you crushed one
in a hydraulic press.
If I had, there would have been
some evidence.
They would have found something
at the factory.
I see.
So, you don't believe any more
that the company covered it up?
No. Why would they?
Let's try a new position right there.
The neuronal sensors are correct,
because it works.
- Right.
- Those neurons are all centred.
Maybe
the inhibitor circuits failed...
Mr Dyson?
Mr Dyson, the materials team
is running another...
- Mr Dyson.
- Yes?
The materials team is running
another series this afternoon.
You have to sign for the...
Er... it.
- You have to sign it out.
- OK. Come on. I'll get it.
Mr Dyson,
I know I haven't been here long, but
I was wondering if you could tell me,
- I mean, if you know...
- Know what?
Well, if you know
where "it" came from.
I asked them that very same question
once. You know what they told me?
"Don't ask."
- Good morning, Mr Dyson.
- How's it going?
Insert key.
Left on three, two, one, turn.
- How are the wife and kids?
- Great. Thanks.
There you go.
So,
what do you think, Doctor?
I have shown improvement, haven't I?
Well, Sarah, here's the problem.
I know how smart you are.
I think you're just telling me
what I want to hear.
I don't think you really believe
what you're telling me today.
I think if I put you
in minimum security,
you'll just try to escape again.
You have to let me see my son.
Please.
He's in great danger.
He's naked without me.
If I could just make a phone call...
Afraid not. Not for a while.
I don't see any choice
but to recommend to the review board
that you stay here
for another six months.
I'll kill you, you son of a bitch!
- Get her off of me!
- You son of a bitch!
10cc of sodium amobarbital, stat!
- You don't know what you're doing!
- Get some restraints in here now!
You don't know what you're doing!
Model citizen.
You just missed him.
He was here 15 minutes ago.
He said he was going to the galleria?
Yeah.
The galleria?
I'm gonna get some quarters.
I'll be back, all right?
- Oh, no!
- Girls, do you know John Connor?
No.
- Hey, do you know this guy?
- Nah, I don't know him.
- John.
- Not now.
Hey, there's this cop
scoping for you. Check it out.
- He's right over there.
- Split, man.
- Just go.
- Yeah.
I saw that kid...
Hey!
Hey! You're not supposed
to be in here!
Hey!
Get down.
Mister, are you all right?
Come on!
Goddamn!
Agh!
OK. Time out. Stop the bike.
Time out. Come on, stop the bike.
Holy shit.
Now, don't take this the wrong way.
- But you are a Terminator, right?
- Yes.
- Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101.
- No?
Holy shit! You're really real.
I mean...
You're like a machine underneath,
right? But sort of alive outside?
I'm a cybernetic organism:
living tissue
over metal endoskeleton.
This is intense.
Get a grip, John. OK.
You're not here to kill me.
I figured that part out for myself.
So what's the deal?
My mission is to protect you.
Yeah? Who sent you?
You did.
35 years from now,
you reprogrammed me to be
your protector here, in this time.
Oh, this is deep.
This other guy,
he's a terminator like you, right?
Not like me.
A T-1000, advanced prototype.
- More advanced than you are?
- Yes. A mimetic poly-alloy.
- What the hell does that mean?
- Liquid metal.
Where are we going?
We have to get out of the city
immediately
and avoid the authorities.
Listen, I got to stop by my house.
I want to pick up some stuff.
Negative. The T-1000 would definitely
try to reacquire you there.
- You sure?
- I would.
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks...
...but I gotta warn them.
Shit! You got a quarter?
- Hello.
- 'Janelle, it's me.'
- John?
- 'Yeah. Is everything all right?'
- Are you guys OK?
- 'Sure, honey, everything's OK.'
- Are you all right?
- 'Yeah, I'm fine.'
John, it's late.
I was beginning to worry about you.
If you hurry home, we can sit down
and have dinner together.
I'm making beef stew.
Something's wrong.
She's never this nice.
John, where are you?
What the hell is the goddamn dog
barking at?
Hey, shut up,
you worthless piece of shit!
The dog's really barking.
You were gonna tell the kid
to get rid of that fucking mutt.
John, honey, it's late.
Please don't make me worry.
- Could he already be there?
- Honey, are you OK?
I'm right here. I'm fine.
'Are you sure you're all right?'
- What's the dog's name?
- Max.
Janelle, what's wrong
with Wolfie?
I can hear him barking. Is he OK?
Wolfie's fine, honey.
Wolfie's just fine.
Where are you?
Your foster parents are dead.
No, no. I need a minute here.
You're telling me that this thing
can imitate anything it touches?
Anything it samples
by physical contact.
Get real.
It could disguise itself
as a pack of cigarettes?
No, only an object of equal size.
Why not just become a bomb
or something to get me?
It can't form complex machines.
Guns, explosives have chemicals,
moving parts.
It doesn't work that way.
But it can form solid metal shapes.
- Like what?
- Knives and stabbing weapons.
These were taken
by a video surveillance camera
at the West Highland police station
in 1984.
He killed
17 police officers that night.
Men with families...
...children.
These were taken at a mall
in Reseda today.
Miss Connor,
we know you know who this guy is.
Look, I just sat here and told you
that your son is missing.
That the foster parents
have been murdered.
We know this guy's involved.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
Don't you care?
- We're wasting our time. Let's go.
- Sorry, guys.
She's grown more and more
disconnected from reality
as time goes on.
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
If she clears at all and can
give us anything, I'll call you.
Sure.
Douglas,
take her back to her room, please.
Yes, sir.
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
You see, we spent a lot of time
in Nicaragua and places like that.
For a while there, she was with
this crazy ex-Green Beret guy
running guns.
Then there were some other guys.
She'd shack up with anybody
she could learn from
so she could teach me how to be
this great military leader.
Then she gets busted.
It's like, "Sorry, kid. Your mom's
a psycho. Didn't you know?"
It's like everything
I'd been brought up to believe
was all made-up bullshit.
I hated her for that.
But everything she said was true.
She knew.
And nobody believed her.
Not even me.
Listen,
we gotta get her out of there.
Negative. The T-1000's
highest probability for success now
will be to copy Sarah Connor
and wait for you
to make contact with her.
Great. What happens to her?
Typically, the subject
being copied is terminated.
Shit! Why didn't you tell me?
We gotta go right now!
Negative.
It's not a mission priority.
Fuck you! She's a priority to me!
Goddamn it!
What's your problem? Damn it!
- Help! Help!
- This does not help our mission.
Get this psycho off of me! Help!
Help! I'm being kidnapped!
Get this psycho off of me!
Let me go!
- Why the hell did you do that?
- Because you told me to.
What?
You have to do what I say, huh?
That's one of my mission parameters.
Prove it. Stand on one foot.
Yes!
Cool. My own Terminator. Wow.
- You OK, kid?
- Take a hike, bozo.
- Let's get outta here, man.
- Fuck you, you little dipshit!
Dipshit?
Put your leg down.
- Did you call moi dipshit?
- Just trying to help this punk.
Grab this guy.
I can't believe he called me...
Agh! God! Get him off of me!
Now who's the dipshit,
you jock douche bag?
Get off me!
No!
Put the gun down, now!
- Get outta here!
- Come on. Let's split!
Jesus! You were gonna kill that guy!
Of course. I'm a Terminator.
Listen to me very carefully, OK?
You're not a Terminator anymore,
all right?
You got that?
You just can't go around
killing people.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
Cos you can't.
Why?
Because you just can't.
Trust me on this.
Look, I'm gonna go get my mom.
And I order you to help me.
Hm!
Hi!
- You have a Sarah Connor here?
- You're running late, aren't you?
They've been in there for an hour.
Hold on a second. I'll buzz you in.
Oh, here come your friends now.
Well, that was productive.
- Hey, Gwen, you want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
How 'bout a beer?
Yeah, right!
- Hey, I got a full house.
- That's good, Lewis.
Must be my lucky day.
I think you're right
about number 24.
Increase the medication
to 250 milligrams.
- Same time?
- Mm-hmm.
You!
You broke my arm.
There are 215 bones
in the human body.
That's one. Now, don't move.
What are you gonna do?
Why do we stop now?
You gotta promise me
you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
- Right.
- Swear?
What?
Just put up your hand and say,
"I swear I won't kill anyone."
- I swear I will not kill anyone.
- All right. Let's go.
Visiting hours is 10:00 to 4:00,
Monday through Friday.
- What the hell are you doing?
- You son of a bitch! You shot me!
You crazy bastard!
Don't shoot me again.
Don't kill me.
He'll live.
Son of a bitch!
Let's try to remain calm.
Open it, or he'll be dead
before he hits the floor.
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
Open the door.
It ain't gonna happen.
Take it easy, Sarah. Easy.
It won't work, Sarah.
You're no killer.
I don't believe you can do it.
You're already dead, Silberman.
Everybody dies.
You know I believe it.
- So don't fuck with me!
- Open the door. Open the door.
Back off!
Get back!
I'll pump him full of this shit.
I swear!
Don't move!
- Drop the shit!
- Do it! Do it!
Get in the office.
On the floor, face down.
Not you!
Open the door.
On the floor. Hold it open.
Face the wall!
Get her! Get her!
Sarah!
- Hurry up! Open the door!
- The door's locked!
Let's go! Open it!
Get the other door!
- She broke it off.
- Open it!
Let's go around! Come on!
Move it!
No!
- No!
- Mom, wait!
Mom!
- Come back here!
- No! No!
No!
- Help her!
- Wait here.
Hurry UP!
He'll kill us all! He'll kill us all!
Hold her.
He'll kill us all!
Mom, are you OK? Mom!
Come with me, if you want to live.
It's OK, Mom. He's here to help.
It's OK.
Go.
What the fuck is it?
What the fuck is going on?
Get down.
No! Mom!
Out of the car!
Right now!
Go!
I'm out.
- Come on.
- Here.
Reload.
Last one!
Hang on.
Ready!
John!
Here, drive.
He's not back there.
There's nobody behind us.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- Can you even see anything?
- I see everything.
Cool.
Come here.
I said I was OK.
John,
it was stupid of you to go there.
God damnit! You have to be
smarter than that.
You almost got yourself killed.
What were you thinking?
You cannot risk yourself,
even for me.
Do you understand?
You're too important.
But...
I had to get you out of that place.
I'm sorry.
I didn't need your help.
I can take care of myself.
What's wrong with your eyes?
Nothing.
So, what's your story?
You OK?
Fine.
Say, that's a nice bike.
Hey! Watch it, lug nuts.
Listen,
do you know what you're doing?
I have detailed files
on human anatomy.
I bet! Makes you
a more efficient killer, right?
Correct.
Does it hurt when you get shot?
I sense injuries. The data
could be called pain.
John, help me with the light.
- Will these heal up?
- Yes.
Good. If you can't pass for human,
you're not much good to us.
How long do you live,
I mean "last", whatever?
120 years with
my existing power cell.
Can you learn stuff you
haven't been programmed with?
So you can be...
you know, more human?
Not such a dork all the time?
My CPU is a neural-net processor,
a learning computer,
hat Skynet presets to READ
only when we are sent out alone.
Doesn't want you
to do too much thinking.
No.
Can we reset the switch?
Rotate the two locking cylinders
counterclockwise.
Do it.
Now open the port cover.
Pull to break the seal.
Good, now remove
the shock damping assembly.
You can now access the CPU.
- Do you see it?
- Yes.
Pull the CPU by its base tap.
Pull.
Can you see the pin switch?
No!
- Out of my way, John!
- Don't kill him!
"It", John, not "him".
Okay, "it". But we need "it".
Listen to me. Listen.
We're better off on our own.
He's the only proof of
the future, the war and that.
Maybe.
I don't trust it.
But he's my friend, alright?
You don't know what it's like
to kill these things.
If something goes wrong,
this could be our last chance.
If I'm supposed to
be this military leader,
maybe you start listening
to my ideas once in a while.
'Cause if my own mother won't,
how do you expect anyone else to?
Alright, play it your way.
Was there a problem?
No problem.
None whatsoever.
Are we learning yet?
We have to get as far away
from the city as possible.
Just head south.
Keep it under 65.
- We don't wanna be pulled over.
- Affirmative.
No, no, no. You gotta listen
to the way people talk.
You don't say "affirmative"
or some shit like that.
You say, "No problemo."
And if someone comes up to you
with an attitude, you say, "Eat me!"
And if you want to shine them on,
it's "Hasta la vista, baby."
Hasta la vista, baby.
Yeah, or "Later, dick-wad."
And if someone gets upset,
you say, "Chill out."
- Or you can do combinations.
- Chill out, dick-wad.
That's great. See? You're getting it.
No problemo.
- You got any cash?
- I got a couple of hundred bucks.
I'll give you half.
Mom!
Get some food.
No sense of humor.
And that's another thing:
lighten up a bit.
This severe routine is getting old.
You're acting like such a geek.
Smile once in a while.
Smile?
Yeah. You know, smile.
Watch.
Hi. Nice place you got here.
How's business?
Gimme a break.
Okay. Bad example.
See that guy over there?
That's a smile.
That's good.
You could practice
in front of a mirror or something.
Want some of my fries?
Do you need any help?
No.
- Got you!
- No, you didn't!
We're not gonna make it, are we?
People, I mean.
It's in your nature
to destroy yourselves.
Yeah. Major drag, huh?
Break it up
before I wring both of your necks.
I need to know how Skynet gets built,
who's responsible.
The man most directly responsible
is Miles Bennett Dyson.
Who is that?
He's the director of special projects
at Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
Why him?
In a few months he creates
a revolutionary type
of microprocessor.
- Go on. Then what?
- In three years,
Cyberdyne will become the largest
supplier
of military computer systems.
All Stealth bombers are upgraded
with Cyberdyne computers,
becoming fully unmanned.
Afterwards, they fly
with a perfect operational record.
The Skynet Funding bill is passed.
The system goes on-line
on August 41997.
Human decisions are removed
from strategic defence.
Skynet begins to learn
at a geometric rate.
It becomes self-aware at 02:14am
Eastern time, August 29.
In a panic,
they try to pull the plug.
- Skynet fights back.
- Yes.
It launches its missiles
against the targets in Russia.
Why attack Russia?
Aren't they our friends now?
Because Skynet knows
that the Russian counterattack
will eliminate its enemies over here.
Jesus!
How much do you know about Dyson?
I have detailed files.
Want to know everything.
What he looks like.
Where he lives. Everything.
Miles!
- You going to work all day?
- I'm sorry, baby.
This thing
is kicking my ass.
It's Sunday. You promised to take
the kids to Raging Waters today.
I can't. I'm on a roll.
This is gonna blow 'em away.
It's a neural-net processor.
I know. You told me.
It thinks and learns like we do.
It's superconducting
at room temperature.
Other computers are just
pocket calculators by comparison.
Why is that so important?
I need to know,
'cause sometimes I feel like
I'm going crazy here.
Baby, I am this close.
Come here.
Imagine a jet airliner
with a pilot that never gets tired,
never makes mistakes,
never shows up with a hangover.
Meet the pilot.
Why did we get married?
Have children? You don't need us.
Your heart and your mind
are in here.
But it doesn't love you like we do.
I'm sorry. Really.
How about spending some time
with your other babies?
- Raging Waters?
- Yeah!
Wait in the car.
Enrique!
Are you here?
You're pretty jumpy, Connor.
And you... are always like a snake.
It's great
to see you, Connor!
I told you I would be back.
I knew you would.
It's good to see you.
Jolanda!
Get out here, we got company.
And bring some tequila.
- Hey, big John. Como te va?
- What's up?
Who's this big guy?
He's cool, Enrique.
He's with me. He's, er... Uncle Bob.
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
Uncle Bob, huh?
OK. OK!
How are you?
You've grown so much.
Drink?
Uncle Bob?
Hey, Sarita! You're pretty
famous, all over the goddamn TV.
Pictures of you, John,
your big friend here.
Cops are going nuts
looking for you.
I just came for my stuff.
I need clothes,
food and one of your trucks.
How about the fillings
out of my fucking teeth?
Now, Enrique!
- You two, you're on weapons detail.
- Come on. Let's go.
One thing about my mom...
...she always plans ahead.
Excellent.
This is the best truck I got,
but the starter is gone.
- You got the time to change it out?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna wait till dark
to cross the border.
Enrique, it's dangerous for you here.
- You get out tonight too, okay?
- Sure.
Just drop by any time
and totally fuck up my life.
See, I grew up in places like this,
so I thought
that's how people lived:
riding around in helicopters,
learning how to blow shit up.
But then, when my mom got busted,
I got put in a regular school.
The other kids were into Nintendo.
Are you ever afraid?
No.
Not even of dying?
You don't feel any emotion about it
one way or another?
No.
I have to stay functional
until the mission is complete.
Then it doesn't matter.
Yeah. I have to stay functional too.
I'm "too important".
That's definitely you.
Most of the guys my mom
hung round with were geeks.
But there was this one guy,
he was kinda cool.
- He taught me engines.
- Hold here.
Mom screwed it up, of course.
She'd always tell 'em about
Judgment Day
and me being this world leader.
- That'd be all she wrote.
- Torque wrench, please.
Here.
- I wish I could've met my real dad.
- You will.
Yeah, I guess.
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
I sent him back through time
to 1984.
Man!
He hasn't even been born yet.
It messes with your head.
- The other bolt.
- Oh. Here.
Mom and him were only together
for one night.
She still loves him, I guess.
I see her crying sometimes.
She denies it totally, of course,
like she got something
stuck in her eye.
Why do you cry?
- You mean people?
- Yeah.
I don't know. We just cry.
You know, when it hurts.
- Pain causes it?
- Er... no. It's different.
It's when there's nothing wrong
with you, but you hurt anyways.
- Get it?
- No.
All right, my man!
- No prob/em o-
- Give me five.
Just put out your hand, like this.
All right! Now hit me.
Give me five. Do the same thing.
All right!
OK, that's good. Up high! High five!
Five low.
Too slow.
I'm just kidding. One more time.
Good. Now try it. Good!
Now do me. Give me five.
'Watching John
with the machine,
it was suddenly so clear.
'The Terminator would never stop.
'It would never leave him
and it would never hurt him,
'never shout at him
or get drunk and hit him
'or say it was too busy
to spend time with him.
'It would always be there
and it would die to protect him.
'Of all the would-be fathers
who came and went over the years,
'this thing, this machine,
was the only one who measured up.
'In an insane world,
it was the sanest choice.'
Come here, darling.
Hey, let's try this one.
There we go.
She said you go south
with him like you planned.
- She'll meet you tomorrow.
- Mom!
Mom, wait!
"No fate".
"No fate, but what we make."
My father told her this.
I mean, I made him memorise it
in the future as a message to her.
Never mind.
Now, OK, the whole thing goes...
The future's not set.
There's no fate,
but what we make for ourselves.
- She intends to change the future.
- Yeah, I guess.
Oh, shit!
- Dyson.
- Yeah.
Gotta be. Miles Dyson.
She's gonna blow him away.
Come on! Let's go!
Let's go! Come on!
- This is tactically dangerous.
- Drive faster.
The T-1000 has the same files
that I do. It knows what I know.
- It might anticipate this move.
- I don't care. We gotta stop her.
Killing Dyson might prevent the war.
I don't care!
Haven't you learned anything yet?
Haven't you figured out
why you can't kill people?
Look, maybe you don't care
if you live or die.
But everybody's not like that!
We have feelings.
We hurt. We're afraid.
You gotta learn this stuff.
I'm not kidding. It's important.
Danny, I told you
to go to bed. I'm not kidding.
Just a couple of minutes,
Mom!
Danny, your time is up.
Come brush your teeth
and get to bed.
Danny!
Ugh!
- Daddy!
- Danny, just go! Go, Danny! Go!
Miles?
Miles!
- Tarissa, run!
- Oh, my God!
Tarissa, just take Danny and go. Run!
Run!
Oh, Jesus! Miles!
Daddy!
' Danny! Danny!
- Nobody fucking move!
- Don't hurt my daddy!
Get down on the floor, bitch.
Get down now!
Get out of the way.
Don't hurt him!
Get on the floor now!
Just let the boy go.
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up! Shut up!
It's all your fault, motherfucker.
- It's all your fault!
- What?
I'm not gonna let you do it.
Shhh!
Shhh.
Shit! We're too late!
Check them.
Look at me, Mom. Are you hurt?
Look at me.
I almost...
It'll be OK. It's gonna be OK.
We'll figure something out. OK?
I promise.
- You came here to stop me.
- Yeah, I did.
I love you, John.
I always have.
I know.
Deep penetration.
No shattered bone.
You hold here. The pressure
should stop the bleeding.
- Who are you people?
- Show him.
Danny, I want you to come with me
right now. Show me your room.
Oh, God! No!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Now, listen to me very carefully.
Nuclear winter effects
caused massive cooling...
'Dyson listened while
the Terminator laid it all down.
'Skynet. Judgment Day.
'The history of things to come.
'It's not every day that you find out
you're responsible
for three billion deaths.
'He took it pretty well.'
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
You're judging me
on things I haven't even done yet.
How were we supposed to know?
Yeah!
Right.
How were you supposed to know?
Fucking men like you
built the hydrogen bomb.
Men like you thought it up.
You think you're so creative.
You don't know what it's like
to really create something,
to create a life,
to feel it growing inside you.
All you know how to create
is death and destruction.
Mom!
We need to be a little more
constructive here. OK?
We still have to stop this
from happening, don't we?
But I thought...
Aren't we changing things right now,
changing the way it goes?
That's right. There's no way
I'm gonna finish the new processor.
Not now. Forget it. I'm out of it.
- I'll quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
- That's not good enough.
- No one must follow your work.
- Right.
All right, then we have to destroy
all the stuff at the lab:
the files, the disk drives,
everything, everything here.
Everything. I don't care.
The chip.
- Do you know about the chip?
- What chip?
They keep it in a vault
at Cyberdyne.
It must be from
the other one like you.
- The CPU from the first Terminator.
- Son of a bitch! I knew it!
They told us
not to ask where they got it.
Those lying motherfuckers.
It's scary stuff. Radically advanced.
I mean,
it was smashed, it didn't work,
but it gave us ideas,
took us in new directions,
things we would've never th...
All my work was based on it.
It must be destroyed.
Can you get us in? Past security?
I think so, yeah. When?
Now?
'The future,
always so clear to me,
'had become
like a black highway at night.
'We were in uncharted territory now,
making up history as we went along.'
Hi. Er... Carl, right?
Friends from out of town.
I just thought I'd...
Hi!
...take 'em upstairs
and show 'em around.
Mr Dyson, you know the rules
concerning visitors in the lab.
I need written authorisation...
- I insist.
- Don't even think about it.
Come on. It's OK.
It takes two keys to open the vault.
They have
to be turned simultaneously.
The other one is in a locker
at the security station.
Gibbons?
Gibbons! Come on, man!
You can't leave the desk like that!
Gibbons!
Oh, shit.
My card should access this.
- What? What is it?
- Damn it.
The silent alarm's been tripped.
It's neutralised all the codes
in the entire building.
Nothing will open anywhere now.
We have to abort.
No.
We go all the way. OK?
You guys get started on the lab.
I can open this.
I think it's that guy from the mall.
It is!
It's him and the woman.
Look, just send everything
you got in the area right now.
I have a personal entry code
for the lab. It may still work.
- It's no good.
- Let me try mine.
John, fire in the hold!
Wait! You can't go in there.
The fire set off the halon system.
You have
to wait until the gas clears.
Put this on.
All right, let's get to work.
All units in the vicinity,
all units able to respond:
A 211 in progress at 2144 Kramer
Street, the Cyberdyne building.
Suspect 1 is white, female,
identified as: last name Connor,
first name Sarah,
escaped from
Pescadero State Hospital.
Suspect 2: white, male...
All the disks in my office. All the
disks in that office over there.
Everything behind my desk.
All the processors on my left.
We'll blow it up with the CP4.
Could I...
Excuse me...
Could I borrow that thing?
I worked a lot
of years on this thing.
- Give me that location again.
- 2111, Kramer.
The suspects are armed and
considered extremely dangerous.
All right!
7-2-5-6.
Yes!
Easy money.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit! Not good.
Not good!
- How we doing?
- Primer cord is set.
One more barrel, two more minutes.
- How do we set them off?
- Remote control.
Piece of cake.
- We got company.
- Police?
- How many?
- All of 'em, I think.
Go. I'll finish here.
Come on.
- I'll take care of the police.
- Wait! You swore!
Trust me.
'You at the window!
'Drop your weapon and place
your hands on top of your head!'
- Holy shit!
- That's a damn mini-gun!
- Come on!
- Oh, shit!
Go! Go! Go!
Fire!
We go same time, to the left.
One, two, three, go.
All right, in order to get that out,
you have to...
We got Skynet by the balls now,
don't we? Come on, let's book.
Hold your fire!
- Ready to rock?
- Ready.
Time to go. Now.
- Take this. They'll use gas.
- Come on.
Get started on the door.
Miles, hand me the detonator.
Mom! Mom!
Aagh!
Shit!
Shit! She's in the clean room.
There's no way outta there.
Get down!
Here.
I don't know how much longer
I can hold this.
Fall back! Everybody out!
Fall back now! Go! Go! Go!
'We got a war zone
down here!
Shut your eyes.
Stay here. I'll be back.
Get down on the floor, face down!
Down on the floor now!
OK, drop him!
Agh!
Here, hold this.
I think it's him!
Holy shit!
Go!
Shit!
Get out.
Aagh!
Listen. No matter what happens,
you stay under these vests.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
All right.
- Chopper's coming in!
- It's him.
Yeah!
John! Stay down!
Aagh!
" Mom!
Hello?
Goddamn! You all right...?
Come on, Mom, we gotta get out.
- Take the shotgun.
- OK.
- Agh!
Are you hurt?
- Holy shit! Come on, Mom. Come on!
- We need your truck.
Hurry!
- Come on. Hurry.
- Get in.
Come on! Go!
What the hell...?
- I'm bleeding bad.
- Keep pressure on it.
Here. This'll work.
He's gaining.
- Step on it!
- This is the vehicle's top speed.
I can run faster than this!
Coming up, to the right.
Watch it! Watch it!
- Drive a minute.
- Where the hell are you going?
Take the off-ramp.
Shit!
Hold on!
Don't stop!
Go straight!
- Look out!
- Duck!
Get the hell outta here!
Get outta here! Let's go!
Hasta la vista, baby.
We don't have much time.
Let's go.
Come on, Mom.
We gotta get outta here.
Come on! Get up!
Hand me the shotgun.
Put your weight on me, Mom.
Hurry!
Come on, Mom.
- Agh!
- Come on, Mom. Get up! Come on!
This way. Come on!
Wait! No. No. It's too hot.
Go back.
- Go. Run.
- No! We gotta stick together.
John, you've got to go now.
- John!
- Go! Now!
No!
Get up the steps.
Go on.
Come on, Mom.
I got you. Come on.
No!
Grab the chain. Grab it.
Grab it. Go. Go!
Mom, come on! Mom! Mom!
Come on!
Mom!
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Agh!
Call to John.
No!
I know this hurts.
- Ugh!
- Call John.
Call to John now.
Fuck you!
John? John!
John? Help!
John!
John?
John.
- Mom.
- Help me.
Help me.
Out of the way, John!
Shoo“
Mom!
Get down!
No!
Get up. Come on.
Holy shit!
I need a vacation.
- Is it dead?
- Terminated.
Will this melt in there?
Yes. Throw it in.
A 070's!
And the chip.
It's over.
No.
There's one more chip.
And it must be destroyed also.
Here.
I cannot self-terminate.
You must lower me into the steel.
No.
- I'm sorry, John. I'm sorry.
- No!
No, it'll be OK. Stay with us.
- It'll be OK.
- I have to go away.
No, don't do it. Please, don't go.
- I must go away, John.
- No!
No, wait.
- You don't have to do this.
- I'm sorry.
No, don't do it! Don't go!
It has to end here.
I order you not to go!
I know now why you cry.
But it's something I can never do.
Good bye.
August 29, 1997, came and went.
Nothing much happened.
Michael Jackson turned 40.
There was no Judgment Day.
People went to work
as they always do.
Laughed, complained,
watched TV, made love.
I wanted to run
through the street yelling
to grab them all and say,
(( Every day
from this day on is a gift.
Use if well. »
Instead, I got drunk.
That was 30 years ago.
But the dark future which never came
still exists for me.
And it always will,
like the traces of a dream.
John fights the war differently
than it was foretold.
Here, on the battlefield
of the Senate
his weapons are common sense
and hope.
Tie me, Grandma. Tie me!
How's that?
Thank you, Grandma.
The luxury of hope
was given to me
by the Terminator.
Because if a machine can learn
the value of human life
maybe we can too.
"You Could Be Mine")
♪ Oh, I'm a cold heartbreaker,
Fit to burn
♪ And I'll rip your heart in two
♪ And I'll leave you lyin' on the bed
♪ I'll be out the door
Before you wake,
♪ It's nothin' new to you
♪ Cos I think we've seen
That movie, too
♪ Cos you could be mine
♪ But you're way out of line
♪ With your bitch slap rappin'
and your cocaine tongue
♪ You get nothin' done... ♪